<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foreign Policy on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/foreign-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foreign Policy on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/foreign-policy/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying about Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lying about Libya,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; appeared today in &lt;i&gt;Mises Daily&lt;/i&gt;, a publication of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Ludwig von Mises Institute&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;You can read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s1600/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s320/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What was sold to the American public as a humanitarian intervention morphed almost immediately into unreserved support of one side in Libya&amp;rsquo;s civil war and a commitment to overthrowing Libya&amp;rsquo;s existing government.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;To decide whether a military action undertaken in our name is prudent and just, we must adopt a skeptical stance toward politicians&amp;rsquo; stories and rationalizations. We must attempt to see through these to the reality of the situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;Stories can change, and new excuses can be spun, but once a war is launched there is no predicting the course it will take or the consequences it will have. Wars rarely go according to plan; they set in motion a course of events that no one person or group of people can hope to control.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the entire article.  Please consider posting it on Facebook or Twitter, or otherwise passing it along to others if you enjoy it.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Libya War on &#39;Russia Today&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rt.com/news/sanctions-showdown-syria-libya/&#34;&gt;Russia Today&lt;/a&gt; (RT) yesterday to discuss the U.S./NATO intervention in Libya as well as the situation in Syria - feel free to check it out if you are interested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/by444eRvSSI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My related article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Rolling the Dice in Libya&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another, unrelated op-ed of mine appeared yesterday as well in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;Michigan Education Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;National standards will stifle innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  In it, I argue that &amp;ldquo;strict standards risk forcing students and teachers alike into a curricular straitjacket, alienating creative teachers and sapping the motivation of students.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find links to all of my online publications at my homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;www.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling the dice in Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Rolling the dice in Libya,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. If you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or emailing it to a friend. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rolling the dice in Libya&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Barack Obama won the Democratic nomination in 2008 partly by reminding the party’s base of his early, prescient criticisms of the ill-fated decision to invade Iraq. “What I am opposed to is a dumb war … a rash war,” then-Senator Obama explained in 2002.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama was right to call the Iraq War “dumb” and “rash”: the Bush administration’s decision to invade Iraq was based not just on an “intelligence failure,” but on flagrant hubris, ignorance of geography and history, and unawareness of the limits of American power in the 21st century. And yet the Obama administration demonstrated each of these failings  in deciding to involve the U.S. in Libya’s civil war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Much ado was made about the U.S. “handing over” the Libya mission to NATO after dominating the first stage of the operation. But NATO is best understood as a multilateral cloak for American power; the U.S. has a military far larger and more advanced than any of its NATO allies, and it is by far the largest contributor to NATO’s budget.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The U.S.-NATO mission in Libya, we are told again and again, is nothing more than a temporary “humanitarian” operation to protect civilians. Since we are still bombing away at Col. Moammar Gadhafi’s military, one would think that Gadhafi’s forces are still on the verge of massacring defenseless civilians in rebel-held cities. But then we learn of “progress” in the war: under the cover of U.S./NATO-provided air power, rebels have taken cities from Gadhafi’s forces and advanced closer to Tripoli.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apparently, “protecting civilians” means attempting to crush the Libyan government forces and turn the tide of the civil war in the rebels’ favor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Defenders of the intervention appeal to our sense of decency by warning of the “genocide” that might have occurred had events in Libya been permitted to run their course, but this is nothing more than conjecture. It is possible to defend any course of action by asserting that a worst-case scenario would have occurred had the action not been taken. However, our worst fears usually do not turn out to be accurate predictors of the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the Obama administration’s protests to the contrary, what was sold as an effort to protect Libyan civilians has quickly developed into an unstated commitment to regime-change in Libya, with all the long-term challenges, obligations, and uncertainties that entails. It has also morphed into a full embrace of the Libyan rebels, though no one is sure exactly what the rebels stand for, or whether they have a workable plan to restore stability and govern the country democratically in a post-Gadhafi era.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like Bush’s decision to invade Iraq, Obama’s decision to intervene in Libya relied upon wishful thinking about the post-intervention course of events. Bush assured us that the conflict in Iraq would be swift, decisive, and relatively painless for the U.S.; Obama assured us that the mission in Libya would not require ground troops or a sustained American commitment and that it would be over in “days, not weeks.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But as political scientist Robert Pape has shown, air power alone is rarely, if ever, sufficient to achieve a state’s aims in war. And the “days” of U.S. involvement have already become “weeks” and will soon become “months,” as they tend to do in wars—which are, after all, unpredictable and uncontrollable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Obama has joined the long line of presidents who have been blinded by U.S. power and failed to perceive the limits of that power. He is likely to fail in Libya—or pay a high price for a very limited and temporary success—because he chose to ignore the advice of the great strategist Carl von Clausewitz, who wrote: “War is the realm of chance. … Chance makes everything more uncertain and interferes with the whole course of events.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The hopes and expectations of war supporters are routinely dashed by the complexity of reality. War plans often rely on best-case scenarios and assume that the planners are gifted with such foresight and judgment that they can realistically project how events will unfold. But the human actors driving these events on the ground often respond quite unpredictably to changes in their situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prudent policymakers and citizens should expect hasty wars of choice based on rose-eyed assumptions to fail and to have unforeseen consequences that last decades. This is not the outcome we hope for in the Libya war, but it is the outcome we can most safely bet on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Should Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning.  In it, I make the case that any honest examination of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s policy options regarding North Korea must begin with the acknowledgment that, first, war is not an option, and second, that the strategies of isolation and sanctions have been tried and have failed for 60 years.  Accordingly, our only chance for a resolution of the North Korean issue is through direct talks with the North aimed at a comprehensive peace settlement and an official end to the Korean War.  This is not a pleasant option, but it is the right one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read the article and the argument &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; please feel free to comment directly on the site, through a letter to the editor, or via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryan.mccarl@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.  If you enjoy the article, please link to it or forward it to others who might be interested in reading it.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
