<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joseph Campbell on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/joseph-campbell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Joseph Campbell on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 22:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/joseph-campbell/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Krakauer, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wanders eastward, toward the sun, he comes to a mountain.  A voice calls: are you near a mountain?  Yes, he answers, I&amp;rsquo;m standing near a mountain.  Then the voice says: That mountain you are standing near is my foot; I am lying bound in the uttermost part of the earth, come set me free!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, when he came to think about it, he acknowledged that those hours had had a significance for him that no one could realize, and if it was true - as had just been said - that at times his writing &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;sparkled&lt;/span&gt;, then it was his memories of that time that had kindled the spark; it was a reflection of the happiness his two playmates had bestowed on him in his childhood.  For that reason they could claim a large share in his achievements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But his days varied, the good alternating with the bad, and sometimes he would be working at his best when a thought, a pair of eyes, a word from the past would strike him, quenching his inspiration.  Then he would get up and begin to pace his room from wall to wall; he had done this so often, he had worn a white path across the floor, and the path grew daily whiter&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so it turned out that only a life similar to the life of those around us, merging with it without a ripple, is genuine life, and that an unshared happiness is not happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boris Pasternak&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Doctor Zhivago&lt;/span&gt; (quoted in Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because I was alone, however, even the mundane seemed charged with meaning.  The ice looked colder and more mysterious, the sky a cleaner shade of blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy, when you are young, to believe that what you desire is no less than what you deserve, to assume that if you want something badly enough, it is your God-given right to have it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jon Krakauer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The universal triumph of the secular state has thrown all religious organizations into such a definitely secondary, and finally ineffectual, position that religious pantomime is hardly more today than a sanctimonious exercise for Sunday morning, whereas business ethics and patriotism stand for the remainder of the week.  Such a monkey-holiness is not what the functioning world requires&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A single song is being inflected through all the colorations of the human choir.  General propaganda for one or another of the local solutions is superfluous - or much rather, a menace.  The way to become human is to learn to recognize the lineaments of God in all of the wonderful modulations of the face of man.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
