<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capitalism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/capitalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capitalism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/capitalism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Hemingway, O&#39;Connor, and K. Shapiro</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s heart tightened as the trout moved.  He felt all the old feeling.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His muscles ached and the day was hot, but Nick felt happy.  He had left everything behind, the need for thinking, the need to write, other needs.  It was all back of him.  From the time he had gotten down off the train and the baggage man had thrown his pack out of the open car door things had been different.  Seney was burned, the country was burned over and changed, but it did not matter.  It could not all be burned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The road ran on, dipping occasionally, but always climbing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inside the tent the light came through the brown canvas.  It smelled pleasantly of canvas.  Already there was something mysterious and homelike.  Nick was happy as he crawled inside the tent.  He had not been unhappy all day.  This was different though.  Now things were done.  There had been this to do.  Now it was done.  It had been a hard trip.  He was very tired.  That was done.  He had made his camp.  He was settled.  Nothing could touch him.  It was a good place to camp.  He was there, in the good place.  He was in his home where he had made it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nick laughed.  It made a good ending to the story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Big Two-Hearted River: Part I&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;.  They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tide of darkness seemed to sweep him back to her, postponing from moment to moment his entry into the world of guilt and sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery O&amp;rsquo;Connor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Everything That Rises Must Converge&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But no appeal has yet been made to the vast American middle class, the majority class, to detach itself from our competitive industrial insanity.  It is indeed our industrial way of life that lends sanction to militarism and colonialism, Preparedness and suppression of human rights.  Our enemy, strange as it may sound to American ears, is the Standard of Living.  We worship at the altar of the White Rhinoceros, the American kitchen.  Standard of Living is the holy of holies in whose name every other evil is committed.  To lower this standard or to equalize it among the peoples of the world is our greatest need.  And the first step is to disassociate ourselves from the industrial-scientific madness which rules our lives twenty-four hours a day.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To remove ourselves from the world of competition is of paramount importance to the individual and to the nation.  Competition is the most terrible vice of modern society.  Competition is the disease of the West and is the source of our violence.  Non-violence means non-competition.  &amp;hellip;It cannot be employed by governments because governments are by definition committed to violence.  Nonviolence is not a prerogative of governments but of men, even of one man.  One nonviolent man, like Gandhi or Christ, can change history.  Governments can only keep history on the march.  &lt;em&gt;Ahimsa&lt;/em&gt; can stop history.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Vinoba Bhave, the greatest living disciple of Gandhi, who travels throughout India asking for land for the peasantry from the great landlords and receiving it, says: &amp;ldquo;I desire to humiliate neither the rich nor the poor&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  This is the opposite of communist expropriation or of capitalist competition.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Instead of class war and hatred as preached by the communists or industrial-scientific competition as preached by us, to survive we must behave nonviolently and in the spirit of love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Shapiro&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;To Revive Anarchism&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Creative Glut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
