<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christianity on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/christianity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christianity on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/christianity/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jacques Barzun, &#39;From Dawn to Decadence&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jacques-barzun-from-dawn-to-decadence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jacques-barzun-from-dawn-to-decadence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Note: The excerpts below are related to issues outside of education; I will post education-related excerpts from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060928832?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0060928832&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;From Dawn to Decadence&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widawamin-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0060928832&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, my education blog. You can find these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2011/03/education-related-excerpts-from-jacques.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PNtVFwECE4s/TXGx_OfcLYI/AAAAAAAABBM/48lZ9HY2N4Q/s1600/dawntodecadence.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;172&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PNtVFwECE4s/TXGx_OfcLYI/AAAAAAAABBM/48lZ9HY2N4Q/s320/dawntodecadence.jpg&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are a few excerpts from what I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In any art a new technical power leads to uses and ideas not suspected at first.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Another singularity in Petrarch&amp;rsquo;s life was that he climbed a high hill in southern France in order to admire the view. If it was done before him, it was not recorded. Nature had been endlessly discussed, but as a generality, not as &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y47FlKE0hMI/TXGzHSrRQ-I/AAAAAAAABBk/JQRq9kBlJo8/s1600/barzun-time%2Bmontage-56-97.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y47FlKE0hMI/TXGzHSrRQ-I/AAAAAAAABBk/JQRq9kBlJo8/s320/barzun-time%2Bmontage-56-97.jpg&#34; width=&#34;243&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inquisition as such, that is, apart from methods and severity of results, has remained a live institution. The many dictatorships of the 20th century have relied on it and in free countries it thrives ad hoc - hunting down German sympathizers during the First World War, interning Japanese-Americans during the second, and pursuing Communist fellow-travelers during the Cold War.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Heretics are given us so that we might not remain in infancy. They question, there is discussion, and definitions are arrived at to make an organized faith.&amp;rdquo; -St. Augustine&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It takes hundreds of the gifted to make half a dozen of the great.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Why is fame so capricious a goddess? In any country its favor depends on attention by one group of critics rather than another, or again by the fanatical devotion that goes to the right man at the right time. Some element of the work must chime in with some concern of the moment.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;rdquo;(Smoking) is a custom loathful to the eye, hateful to the nose, harmful to the brain, dangerous to the lungs; and the black, stinking fumes thereof nearest resembling the horrible stygian smoke of the pit that is bottomless.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;James I of England (1604)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Desire must be dammed up to be self-renewing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mankind does nothing save through initiatives on the part of inventors, great or small, and imitation by the rest of us. Individuals show the way, set the patterns, The rivalry of the patterns is the history of the world.&amp;rdquo; -William James (1908)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Where in the scheme of things do I belong? Who am I, anyway? Such questions made up the &amp;lsquo;identity crisis&amp;rsquo; studied by psychiatrists whose patients had not &amp;lsquo;found themselves.&amp;rsquo; &amp;hellip;Finding oneself was a misnomer; a self is not found but made; and the anti-hero, anti-history bias was an obstacle to making it, because a starting point from the past was missing; it had to be made from scratch.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In Geneva under Calvin people had to go to church twice daily. &amp;hellip;If stubborn and persistent in sin, the dear soul must be turned over to the civil authorities. Adultery might mean death, quite as if Jesus had not dealt rather differently with the woman taken in adultery. Blasphemy, that curious crime of &amp;lsquo;damaging God by bringing Him into ill-repute,&amp;rsquo; was even more unforgivable. &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Calvinism, it has been said, makes every man the enemy of every other, as well as his own. Certainly its rigor accounts for the agonizing fear of sin that has been recorded in many lives&amp;hellip;. The number of plain people, especially adolescents, whose minds were tortured by Calvinist sermons in England in America may be imagined.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Luther wrote that &amp;lsquo;the Christian man is dead to the world,&amp;rsquo; yet, as we saw, he relished life. The ailing Calvin was not a relisher; his advice is contradictory and leaves nature a rather narrow crack through which to manifest God&amp;rsquo;s goodness.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bliss was it in that dawn to be alive,&lt;br /&gt;But to be young was very heaven.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Wordsworth remembering the French Revolution&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Montaigne lived in an age full of people who knew that they, and they alone, had the truth, direct from God - and these truth-bearers all disagreed. Reflecting on a far wider set of facts and with greater self-knowledge, Montaigne was at pains to make the point that Cromwell later phrased so superbly: &amp;lsquo;By the bowels of Christ, bethink ye that ye may be mistaken.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Erasmus loved travel and the good things of life, including the rapid, flashing conversation of learned friends in Paris, Oxford, and&amp;hellip;Basel.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The welfare ideal did not merely see to it that the poor should be able to survive, but that everybody should be safe and at ease in a hundred ways. Besides providing health care, pensions (&amp;ldquo;social security&amp;rdquo;), and workmen&amp;rsquo;s compensation for accidents, it undertook to protect every employee by workplace regulations and every consumer by laws against harm from foods, drugs, and the multiform dangers that industry creates. All appliances were subject to design control and inspection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;At the same time, it was also held that the state had the duty of supporting art and science, medical research, and the integrity of the environment, while it must also make sure that all children were not simply literate but educated up to and through college - rules, rules, definitions, classifications, and exceptions = indignation - and litigation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;The cost of welfare in money was huge and in mental effort exorbitant. &amp;hellip;The task of distributing benefits was alone overwhelming. High taxes were unavoidable, and so was waste. Add to it corruption, also inevitable when inspectors are afoot, and it should have been no surprise to the contemporaries that the program fell short of its aim. There was still poverty, derelicts on the street, unattended illness, and complaints of &amp;lsquo;not enough&amp;rsquo; from every welfared group in turn - workers, farmers, businessmen, doctors, artists, scientists, teachers, prisoners, and the homeless.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jacques Barzun &lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060928832?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0060928832&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;From Dawn to Decadence: 500 Years of Western Cultural Life, 1500 to the Present&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widawamin-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0060928832&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A limited ecumenism</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;A limited ecumenism,&amp;rdquo; appeared today in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt;, the newsletter of the Martin Marty Center at the University of Chicago Divinity School.  It discusses the Catholic Church&amp;rsquo;s recent outreach to traditionalist Anglicans.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is a free online publication sent out twice a week to over 7,000 scholars, ministers, students, and others interested in the intersection of religion and public life; you can subscribe to it at the Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.uchicago.edu/web/info/sightings&#34;&gt;subscription page&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is also online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&#34;&gt;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/archive_2009/1105.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Limited Ecumenism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As reported in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; last Monday, the Vatican announced two weeks ago that it was setting up a new canonical structure, or Apostolic Constitution, to facilitate the conversion of disaffected Anglican traditionalists to Catholicism; the converts will be able to “enter full communion with the Catholic Church while preserving elements of the distinctive Anglican spiritual and liturgical patrimony,” in the Vatican’s words.  Married former Anglican clergy will be allowed to become Catholic Priests, though not Bishops.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Vatican portrayed the move as a response to requests from Anglicans and as representative of its broader “commitment to ecumenical dialogue.” Rowan Williams, the Archbishop of Canterbury and symbolic leader of the Anglican Church, and Vincent Nichols, the Catholic Archbishop of Westminster, released a statement confirming the Vatican’s narrative: “The Apostolic Constitution is further recognition of the substantial overlap in faith, doctrine and spirituality between the Catholic Church and the Anglican tradition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But what leaders of the two churches depicted as an historic, ecumenical move toward Christian unity, others saw as something considerably more complex.  Andrew Sullivan, a Catholic writer who has often been critical of Pope Benedict XVI’s leadership, used economic analogies in describing the move as a power grab.  “Married priests are fine…as long as they help build market share,” he wrote, paraphrasing what he sees as the Vatican’s new position on clerical chastity.  The move “essentially junks an entire tradition of ecumenical dialogue in favor of a quick and sudden merger and acquisition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Such analogies, while jarring, may be worth exploring further.  Organizations and societies learn from each other’s successful practices, and religious organizations are no exception.  The language and efficiency of the Vatican’s announcement made the policy appear to be as carefully scripted and “rolled-out” as a new product by an electronics manufacturer or a new policy by a political leader.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Holy See demonstrated that it, too, can masterfully employ the techniques of “spin,” omnipresent in both consumer and political marketing.  And still other political analogies may apply:  Is the Vatican practicing religious realpolitik, strengthening itself at the expense of a weakened and divided adversary?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, this development may tell us more about the contemporary Catholic Church than about divisions in the Anglican Church.  Perhaps most interestingly, the Vatican&amp;rsquo;s plan suggests that current Catholic leadership sees liturgical procedures and even the chastity of priests as somewhat flexible, but its stands against homosexuality and the ordainment of women as fixed and beyond debate – indeed, even as a source of common ground with other socially conservative Christian groups.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of the Christian churches place a high value on reconciliation and unity.  But few see unification as an aim that trumps the aims of conscience, that is, of right doctrine and right orientation toward God.  In evaluating the Vatican’s move, observers will have to ask themselves whether reconciliation ought to come at the price of continuing and even strengthening the exclusion of women and gays from full and equal membership in the Church.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;References:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donadio, Rachel and Laurie Goodstein, “Vatican Bidding to Get Anglicans to Join Its Fold,” New York Times, 10/21/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Holy See Press Office, “Note of the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith about Personal Ordinariates for Anglicans Entering the Catholic Church,” 10/20/09. Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en.&#34;&gt;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nichols, Vincent and Rowan Williams, “Joint Statement by The Archbishop of Westminster and The Archbishop of Canterbury,” 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sullivan, Andrew, “Married Priests Are Fine…,” The Daily Dish, 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/2009/10/married-priests-are-fine-.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Solomon&#39;s &#39;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s1600-h/judaism.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5394862253055997906&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s400/judaism.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 215px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 200px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin Buber and Emanuel Levinas put their faith in the God of relationships.  &lt;em&gt;Alles Leben ist Begegnung&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;all life is encounter&amp;rsquo;), declared Buber, and the important thing is to get your relationship with God and with people right (I-Thou, rather than I-It); from that relationship, which is the essence of Revelation, ethical action flows; laws and rules are feeble attempts to capture revelation, and doomed to inadequacy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Genesis 1:27 states clearly enough: &amp;lsquo;So God created humankind in his own image; in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&amp;rsquo; This implies that in using our concept of God to model human behavior we should not distinguish between male and female.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Emil Fackenheim grounds his theology in the actual resistance of Shoah [Holocaust] victims to whom no realistic hope remained: &amp;lsquo;A philosophical Tikkun [&amp;lsquo;repair&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restoration&amp;rsquo;] is possible after the Holocaust because a philosophical Tikkun already took place, however fragmentarily, during the Holocaust itself&amp;rsquo;; the rebirth of Israel, and a new constructive dialogue with a self-critical Christianity, are essential to this process.  Fackenheim is also noted for his statement that there should be a 614th commandment, surplus to the 613 of tradition - to survive as Jews, to remember, never to despair of God, lest we hand Hitler a posthumous victory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Is there such a thing as a &amp;lsquo;just war&amp;rsquo;, and if so, what are the conditions of engagement?  Out of this debate emerged the novel concept of &lt;em&gt;tohar ha-nesheq&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;purity of arms&amp;rsquo;), which demands &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt; that the fighting force take special risks to avoid harm to non-combatants and to minimize enemy casualties.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Many Jews, including secular ones, see Israel as the fulfilment of the &amp;lsquo;national&amp;rsquo; aspirations of the Jewish people; after thousands of years of minority status, of being alienated from the host societies, and in many  cases actually prevented from becoming full citizens of the lands in which they lived, they feel that they have at last &amp;lsquo;come home&amp;rsquo; and are able to control their own destiny within the normal limitations of independent statehood.  Israel is perceived as a secure haven for persecuted Jews; had Israel existed during the years of the Holocaust, Jews would have had somewhere to turn to.  Moreover, Israel provides the opportunity to live a fulfilling Jewish life free from the inhibitions and restrictions of minority status.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Large numbers of men and women have abandoned organized religion, some because they have found it intellectually untenable, more because they have found it emotionally unsatisfying, most because they have found that its demands inhibit the personal freedom which they regard as a fundamental human right.  If Western Christianity has been most strongly affected, Western Judaism runs it a close second, for both have their home in the lands which modernity and the Enlightenment were nurtured.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The downside of the emphasis on family values is the danger of marginalizing the stranger, the single, and the unattached.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;. They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/html/staff/hjs/nsolomon.html&#34;&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CAwQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJudaism-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions%2Fdp%2F0192853902&amp;amp;ei=4GXeSo_3FYOk8AaKwvVy&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAV2jscXmj3uoFSGTQwfG8MHXsPA&#34;&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Charles Taylor and Erich Auerbach</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One way to put the question I want to answer here is this: why was it virtually impossible not to believe in God in, say, 1500 in our Western society, while in 2000 many of us find this not only easy, but even inescapable?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Important as science is to our present outlook, we mustn&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate its causal role here, and make it the main motor of the transformation.  Our encasing in secular time is also something we have brought about in the way we live and order our lives.  It has been brought about by the same social and ideological changes which have wrought disenchantment.  In particular, the disciplines of our modern civilized order have led us to measure and organize time as never before in human history.  Time has become a precious resource, not to be &amp;ldquo;wasted&amp;rdquo;.  The result has been the creation of a tight, ordered time environment.  This has enveloped us, until it comes to seem like nature.  We have constructed an environment in which we live a uniform, univocal secular time, which we try to measure and control in order to get things done.  This &amp;ldquo;time frame&amp;rdquo; deserves, perhaps more than any other facet of modernity, Weber&amp;rsquo;s famous description of a &amp;ldquo;stahlhartes Gehäuse&amp;rdquo; (iron cage).  It occludes all higher times, makes them even hard to conceive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Augustine sees ordinary time as dispersal, distensio, losing the unity, being cut off from our past and out of touch with our future.  We get lost in our little parcel of time.  But we have an irrepressible craving for eternity, and so we strive to go beyond this.  Unfortunately, this all too often takes the form of our trying to invest our little parcel with eternal significance, and therefore divinising things, and therefore falling deeper into sin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If it is true that man is capable of everything horrible, it is also true that the horrible always engenders counterforces and that in most epochs of atrocious occurrences the great vital forces of the human soul reveal themselves: love and sacrifice, heroism in the service of conviction, and the ceaseless search for possibilities of a purer existence.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To write history is so difficult that most historians are forced to make concessions to the technique of legend.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Old Testament, in so far as it is concerned with human events, ranges through all three domains: legend, historical reporting, and interpretative historical theology.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Homeric poems, then, though their intellectual, linguistic, and above all syntactical culture appears to be so&amp;hellip;highly developed, are yet comparatively simple in their picture of human beings; and no less so in relation to the real life which they describe in general.  Delight in physical existence is everything to them, and their highest aim is to make that delight perceptible to us.  &amp;hellip;(The Homeric heroes) wake every morning as if it were the first day of their lives: their emotions, though strong, are simple and find expression instantly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Far from seeking, like Homer, merely to make us forget our own reality for a few hours, (the Bible) seeks to overcome our reality: we are to fit our own life into its world, feel ourselves to be elements in its structure of universal history.  This becomes increasingly difficult the further our historical environment is removed from that of the Biblical books; and if these nevertheless maintain their claim to absolute authority, it is inevitable that they themselves be adapted through interpretative transformation.  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy to separate the historical from the legendary in general.  Their structure is different.  Even where the legendary does not immediately betray itself by elements of the miraculous, by the repetition of well-known standard motives, typical patterns and themes, through neglect of clear details of time and place, and the like, it is generally recognizable by its composition.  It runs far too smoothly.  All cross-currents, all friction, all that is casual, secondary to the main events and themes, everything unresolved, truncated, and uncertain, which confuses the clear progress of the action and the simple orientation of the actors, has disappeared.  The historical event which we witness, or learn from the testimony of those who witnessed it, runs much more variously, contradictorily, and confusedly&amp;hellip;.  Legend arranges its material in a simple and straightforward way; it detaches it from its contemporary historical context, so that the latter will not confuse it; it knows only clearly outlined men who act from few and simple motives and the continuity of whose feelings and actions remains uninterrupted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Auerbach&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Mimesis: The Representation of Reality in Western Literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But how? Genius in the Sperm Whale? Has the Sperm Whale ever written a book, spoken a speech? No, his great genius is declared in his doing nothing particular to prove it. It is moreover declared in his pyramidical silence. &amp;hellip;If hereafter any highly cultured, poetical nation shall lure back to their birth-right, the merry May-day gods of old; and livingly enthrone them again in the now egotistical sky; in the now unhaunted hill; then be sure, exalted to Jove&amp;rsquo;s high seat, the great Sperm Whale shall lord it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It was a terrific, most pitiable, and maddening sight. The whale was now going head out, and sending his spout before him in a continual tormented jet; while his one poor fin beat his side in an agony of fright. Now to this hand, now to that, he yawed in his faltering flight, and still at every billow that he broke, he spasmodically sank in the sea, or sideways rolled towards the sky his one beating fin. So have I seen a bird with clipped wing, making affrighted broken circles in the air, vainly striving to escape the piratical hawks. But the bird has a voice, and with plaintive cries will make known her fear; but the fear of this vast dumb brute of the sea, was chained up and enchanted in him; he had no voice, save that choking respiration through his spiracle, and this made the sight of him unspeakably pitiable; while still, in his amazing bulk, portcullis jaw, and omnipotent tail, there was enough to appal the stoutest man who so pitied.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seems it credible that by three such thin threads the great Leviathan was suspended like the big weight to an eight day clock.  Suspended? and to what?  To three bits of board.  Is this the creature of whom it was once so triumphantly said - &amp;lsquo;Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish-spears? The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold, the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon: he esteemeth iron as straw; the arrow cannot make him flee; darts are counted as stubble; he laugheth at the shaking of a spear!&amp;rsquo;  This the creature? this he?  Oh! that unfulfillments should follow the prophets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As strange misgrown masses gather in the knot-holes of the noblest oaks when prostrate, so from the points which the whale&amp;rsquo;s eyes had once occupied, now protruded blind bulbs, horribly pitiable to see.  But pity there was none.  For all his old age, and his one arm, and his blind eyes, he must die the death and be murdered, in order to light the gay bridals and other merry-makings of men, and also to illuminate the solemn churches that preach unconditional inoffensiveness by all to all.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For young whales, in the highest health, and swelling with noble aspirations, prematurely cut off in the warm flush and May of life, with all their panting lard about them; even these brawny, buoyant heroes do sometimes sink.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Czeslaw Milosz&#39;s &#39;Milosz&#39;s ABC&#39;s&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s1600-h/Milosz.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s400/Milosz.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5349520508899521426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made it, but I have always tried to remember that I owe it to my lucky star, not to myself, and that right next door are entire neighborhoods of unfortunates.  I will say even more: the thought of their grueling labor and unfulfilled hope, of the gigantic prison system in which the unneeded are kept, taught me to look skeptically at (America&amp;rsquo;s) decorations - those well-kept houses amidst the suburbs&amp;rsquo; greenery.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In our deepest convictions, reaching into the very depths of our being, we deserve to live forever.  We experience our transitoriness and mortality as an act of violence perpetrated against us.  Only Paradise is authentic; the world is inauthentic, and only temporary.  That is why the story of the Fall speaks to us so emotionally, as if summoning an old truth from our slumbering memory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;People go to church because they are divided beings.  They wish, for a moment at least, to find themselves in a reality other than the one that surrounds them and claims to be the only true reality.  This daily reality is unyielding, brutal, cruel, and hard to bear.  The human &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; is soft in the center and feels every moment that its adaptation to the world is doubtful.  &amp;hellip;Participating in the Mass we once again deny a world without meaning and without mercy; we enter into a dimension where what matters are goodness, love, and forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If to participate in the Mass it were necessary to have a strong faith and a consciousness that we act in life as our religion requires us to, all the churchgoing faithful would deserve to be called hypocrites and Pharisees.  In truth, however, strong faith is a rare gift, and as for acts, the liturgy reminds us that we are all sinners.  Attending church is not, therefore, for the elect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The needs of the individual determine church attendance, and knowledge of the catechism or even familiarity with the so-called truths of the faith are not the most important matters, although they are advisable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Miloszs-ABCs-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374527954&#34;&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from C. Taylor, J.T. Johnson, and the US Catholic Bishops</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Faith does not insulate us from the challenges of life; rather, it intensifies our desire to help solve them&amp;hellip;.  From the resources of our faith we wish to provide hope and strength to all who seek a world free of the nuclear threat.  Hope sustains one&amp;rsquo;s capacity to live with danger without being overwhelmed by it; hope is the will to struggle against obstacles even when they appear insuperable.  Ultimately our hope rests in the God who gave us life, sustains the world by his power and has called us to revere the lives of every person and all peoples.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As Americans, citizens of the nation which was first to produce atomic weapons, which has been the only one to use them and which today is one of the handful of nations capable of decisively influencing the course of the nuclear age, we have grave human, moral, and political responsibilities to see that a &amp;ldquo;conscious choice&amp;rdquo; is made to save humanity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;United States Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response - The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The definition of combatancy and noncombatancy follows from direct involvement in prosecuting the war, not from one&amp;rsquo;s citizenship or one&amp;rsquo;s personal preference among the belligerents.  It is action that matters, not attitude.  For this reason, I regard the use of the term &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; in the Protocols to the Geneva Conventions as misleading: it is not civilian status that matters, as irregular soldiers may technically be civilians; what matters is whether people are engaged in combatant activity or not.  The relevant moral term is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;noncombatant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, even though the language of the protocols uses &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, and this usage has seeped into the moral debate at times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James Turner Johnson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The War to Oust Saddam Hussein: Just War and the New Face of Conflict&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;In the following chapters, I will be making a continuing polemic against what I call &amp;ldquo;subtraction stories.&amp;rdquo;  Concisely put, I mean by this stories of modernity in general, and secularity in particular, which explain them by human beings having lost, or sloughed off, or liberated themselves from certain earlier, confining horizons, or illusions, or limitations of knowledge.  What emerges from this process - modernity or secularity - is to be understood in terms of underlying features of human nature which were there all along, but had been impeded by what is now set aside.  Against this kind of story, I will steadily be arguing that Western modernity, including its secularity, is the fruit of new inventions, newly constructed self-understandings and related practices, and can&amp;rsquo;t be explained in terms of perennial features of human life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P., Richard John Neuhaus</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/r.i.p.-richard-john-neuhaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 23:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/r.i.p.-richard-john-neuhaus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great American public intellectual has died: Richard John Neuhaus, the founding editor of &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://firstthings.com/&#34;&gt;First Things&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;Neuhaus was a liberal Lutheran minister active in the Civil Rights and antiwar movements of the 1960s who converted to Roman Catholicism and became a staunch, vocal social conservative.  I disagreed with him about most things, but I have the highest respect for his talents as a writer, and &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;First Things&lt;/span&gt; is the best conservative magazine available on the intersection of religion and culture.  (Recommended liberal religious magazines: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christiancentury.org/&#34;&gt;Christian Century&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tikkun.org/&#34;&gt;Tikkun&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sojourners.com/&#34;&gt;Sojourners&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Amichai, Laxness, Mendelssohn, &amp; Yoder</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch how the cloud sings&lt;br /&gt;All you wanted to say or find.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Let the Coin Decide&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents&lt;br /&gt;Has not subsided in me.  My blood goes on sloshing&lt;br /&gt;Between my ribs, long after the vessel has come to rest.&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents has not subsided in me.&lt;br /&gt;Winds of long time over stones.  Earth&lt;br /&gt;Forgets the steps of those who trod her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;And the Migration of My Parents&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who will love the things that are naught and in vain?&lt;br /&gt;I, who stand in the world like water in the rain,&lt;br /&gt;I love the things that are naught and in vain.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The most wandering thing is a heart that stopped wandering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;At Right Angles: Hebrew Quatrains&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Has the horse been spoken to?&amp;rdquo; asked the old man; and as it had not yet been done, he took an ear in each hand and whispered to it, according to ancient custom, for horses understood these things:  &amp;ldquo;You carry a coffin today.  You carry a coffin today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The coffin was carried straight into the church in compliance with the minister&amp;rsquo;s request and the bells were rung.  Feeble was the sound they made, feeble their intrusion on frozen nature&amp;rsquo;s winter omnipotence, their peal reminiscent of nothing so much as the jingle of a child&amp;rsquo;s toy.  And the folk came trailing out of the drifting snow and into the church, timid in the face of death, which never seems so irrevocable as when bells of such a kind tinkle so helplessly in the cold, white spaces of declining day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Halldor Laxness&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day of our life together&lt;br /&gt;Ecclesiastes erases a verse of his book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Six Poems For Tamar&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do I think he would be &amp;lsquo;saved&amp;rsquo;?  I fancy that whosoever leads men to virtue in this life cannot be damned in the next.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moses Mendelssohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Reply to Johann Kaspar Lavater,&amp;rdquo; 1769.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before the invention of the machine, the only wealth of a people was constituted by the soil and the flocks.  This is what today would be called capital.  Evidently Jesus accepted voluntary poverty for the sake of the kingdom and he ordered his disciples to practice the jubilary redistribution of their capital: &amp;ldquo;all of these things, it is the Gentiles of the world who seek them.  Your Father knows that you need them.  Seek rather the kingdom of God and all these things will be added to you.  Do not fear, little flock, because your Father has chosen to give you the kingdom; sell all that you have and give it as alms&amp;rdquo; (Luke 12:30-33).  No one doubts that he said this.  All that has been debated is whether this redistribution of capital was commanded by Jesus for all Christians at all times and in all places or whether it was just a &amp;ldquo;counsel of perfection&amp;rdquo; directed to the saints.  Traditionally the Church has chosen the second solution, the easy one.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Comparing one day the generosity of the wealthy, who ostentatiously were throwing large offerings in the temple treasury, with that of the poor widow, Jesus exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;This poor widow has put in more than all of them.  They put in from their overflow but she from her poverty has given all that she had to live!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In modern language we can translate: &amp;ldquo;The quantity of money that one gives is of little importance.  What is important is what one gives.   If it only is a part of one&amp;rsquo;s income, then this is not yet righteousness, goodness, and good faith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Howard Yoder&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Politics of Jesus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on Easter, Just War Theory, and Japanese lit</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The resurrection of Jesus is the sign to the world that God indeed does reign, does give life in death and that the love of God is stronger even than death (Rom. 8:36-39).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;At the center of the church&amp;rsquo;s teaching on peace and at the center of all Catholic social teaching, are the transcendence of God and the dignity of the human person.  The human person is the clearest reflection of God&amp;rsquo;s presence in the world; all of the church&amp;rsquo;s work in pursuit of both justice and peace is designed to protect and promote the dignity of every person.  For each person not only reflects God, but is the expression of God&amp;rsquo;s creative work and the meaning of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemptive ministry.  Christians approach the problem of war and peace with fear and reverence.  God is the Lord of life, and so each human life is sacred; modern warfare threatens the obliteration of human life on a previously unimaginable scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;U.S. Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response (The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace, 1983)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us.  &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28140&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28141&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romans 8:37-39&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The aggressor is always peace-loving; he would prefer to take over our country unopposed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Carl Von Clausewitz, quoted in J.T. Turner, &amp;ldquo;Threats, Values and Defense: Does the Defense of Values by Force Remain a Moral Possibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;***&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His desire for a woman was not of a sort to make him want this particular woman - it was something to be taken care of lightly and with no sense of guilt.  This woman was too clean.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The window of the waiting-room was clear for an instant as the train started to move.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s face glowed forth, and as quickly disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But this love would leave behind it nothing so definite as a piece of Chijimi.  Though cloth to be worn is among the most short-lived of craftworks, a good piece of Chijimi, if it has been taken care of, can be worn quite unfaded a half-century and more after weaving.  As Shimamura thought absently how human intricacies have not even so long a life, the image of Komako as the mother of another man&amp;rsquo;s children suddenly floated into his mind.  He looked around, startled.  Possibly he was tired.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He leaned against the brazier, provided against the coming of the snowy season, and thought how unlikely it was that he would come again once he had left.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Komako had come up to him, he did not know when.  She took his hand.  He looked around at her but said nothing.  She gazed at the fire, the pulse of the fire beating on her intent, slightly flushed face.  Shimamura felt a violent rising in his chest.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s hair was coming undone, and her throat was bare and arched.  His fingers trembled from the urge to touch it.  His hand was warm, but Komako&amp;rsquo;s was still warmer.  He did not know why he should feel that a separation was forcing itself upon them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kawabata Yasunari&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Snow Country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously he did not much enjoy reading and discussing a typical month&amp;rsquo;s production of Japanese literature.  In a 1935 essay Kobayashi expressed his annoyance with authors who complained that he had not been sufficiently kind in his reviews, and asked sardonically what kindness contemporary authors have ever shown their critics.  The only kindness a critic really wants from authors is that they will supply him with the basis for writing decent criticism; but present-day authors do precisely the opposite.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donald Keene&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Dawn to the West: A History of Japanese Literature (Vol. 4)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on psychology, religion, and politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in mundane situations, the individual must &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; in order to discover what he is and he must act in order to continue experiencing aspects of himself which he values and enjoys.  If he thinks of himself as a businessman, a parent, an athlete, an intellectual, he must engage in behavior appropriate to this self-image.  If he does not, he must redefine himself, or he will be left feeling anxious and needful.  (Here is the reason for the psychological shock of retirement; the man who has retired may find that suddenly he can no longer &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;that which he most valued himself for being.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Past actions through which he sought to know and to accept the self are not capable of satisfying this need in the present.  Recalling the past can only remind the individual of what he used to be.  The erstwhile football hero who is still reliving the big game fifteen years later, or the ex-campus queen who tries to give meaning to her life by clinging to her reign over the prom of a decade ago, are pathetic figures.  As the existentialists have pointed out, man must act in order to be, and what he becomes is largely the summation of his actions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Paradoxical though it may seem, it is when the individual is with others that he is best able to enjoy and expand many aspects of himself, to refine and verify his self-image.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Men hate in others those things - and only those things - which they despise in themselves.  It is possible to disapprove of other people in a rational and dispassionate manner, but to hate them is an irrational and impassioned act.  The passion betrays the underlying self-contempt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Distance enables the lover to see his beloved purely in terms of the projections he hangs on her.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The general rule is that people who enjoy life enjoy marriage. Some people would be unhappy with any spouse, for they do not allow themselves happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snell Putney and Gail J. Putney&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Adjusted American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That hatred springs more from self-contempt than from a legitimate grievance is seen in the intimate connection between hatred and a guilty conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Eric Hoffer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Insanity in individuals is something rare - but in groups, parties, nations, and epochs, it is the rule.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If our faith is real, it must encroach upon our life. The Christian Confession in its original Church form will always be exposed to the misunderstanding that the Christian regards the Creed as a matter of heart and conscience, but that here on earth and in the world other truths hold good. The world lives in this misunderstanding; it regards the whole of Christianity as a friendly &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo;, connected with the &amp;lsquo;realm of religion&amp;rsquo;, which is respected and which ought to be left untampered with; and so we get rid of the matter! But this misunderstanding might even have come from within; a Christian might quite well wish to have this realm for himself and to guard faith like a sensitive plant. The relationship between the Church and the world has been widely understood as a question of a fixing of frontiers, whereby each secured itself behind its own frontier, although from time to time it came to a skirmish. From the Church&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, however, such a fixing of frontiers can never exhaust its task. By the very nature of the Christian Church there is only one task, to make the Confession heard in the sphere of the world as well.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us beware of remaining stuck where we are and refusing to advance to meet worldly attitudes. For instance, in Germany in 1933 there was plenty of serious, profound and living Christianity and confession&amp;hellip;. But unfortunately this faith and confession of the German Church remained embedded in the language of the Church, and did not translate what was being excellently said in the language of the Church into the political attitude demanded at the time; in which it would have become clear that the Evangelical Church had to say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to National Socialism, &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; from its very roots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Barth&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Dogmatics in Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on religion and culture</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He who refuses to embrace a unique opportunity loses the prize as surely as if he tried and failed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our errors are surely not such awfully solemn things. In a world where we are so certain to incur them in spite of all our caution, a certain lightness of heart seems healthier than this excessive nervousness on their behalf.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us give the name &lt;em&gt;hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; to anything that may be proposed to our belief; and just as the electricians speak of live and dead wires, let us speak of any hypothesis as either &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;dead&lt;/em&gt;. A live hypothesis is one which appears as a real possibility to him to whom it is proposed. If I ask you to believe in the Mahdi, the notion makes no electric connection with your nature, - it refuses to scintillate with any credibility at all. As an hypothesis it is completely dead. To an Arab, however (even if he be not one of the Mahdi&amp;rsquo;s followers), the hypothesis is among the mind&amp;rsquo;s possibilities: it is alive. This shows that deadness and liveness in an hypothesis are not intrinsic properties, but relations to the individual thinker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Will to Believe&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The distance, and as it were the space around man, grows with the strength of his intellectual vision and insight: his world becomes profounder; new stars, new enigmas, and notions are ever coming into view. Perhaps everything on which the intellectual eye has exercised its acuteness and profundity has just been an occasion for its exercise, something of a game, something for children and childish minds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Beyond Good and Evil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The perspective of the &amp;lsquo;unbeliever&amp;rsquo; on the traditional forms of belief has seldom been welcomed with any enthusiasm inside the communities of faith, but in spite of that it has provided an invaluable service to them. If one were to write the history of modern reform movements within the several world religions, the critical outsider would have to be accorded a substantial position in such a history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jaroslav Pelikan&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The World Treasury of Modern Religious Thought&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of today’s churches have bought the culture’s lie that religion is not about sex or anything else of much importance. But, as theologian Sarah Coakley has so brilliantly said, ancient Christian reflection on desire shows that Freud is exactly wrong: Talk about God is not repressed talk about sexuality; talk about sex is, in fact, repressed talk about God. To paraphrase C.S. Lewis, porn users are not to be rebuked for desiring too much but for desiring too little.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jason Byassee, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/article.php3?id_article=6105&#34;&gt;Not Your Father&amp;rsquo;s Pornography&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;First Things, &lt;/em&gt;January 2008)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief isn&#39;t for the unimaginative; let kids see &#39;The Golden Compass&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/belief-isnt-for-the-unimaginative-let-kids-see-the-golden-compass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/belief-isnt-for-the-unimaginative-let-kids-see-the-golden-compass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philly.com/inquirer/opinion/20071210_Belief_isnt_for_the_unimaginative__let_kids_see_The_Golden_Compass.html&#34;&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; was published in this morning&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philadelphia Inquirer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was thrilled to learn that The Golden Compass, the first book in Philip Pullman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; trilogy, was going to be released as a movie on Friday. I read the trilogy first in middle school and again in high school, and it was my favorite story for a long time. It is filled with imagination and erudition, and it is a significant cut above the vast majority of works aimed at young adults.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the story&amp;rsquo;s greatest strength - its infusion with ideas - is as much a threat to pundits and &amp;ldquo;protect-the-children&amp;rdquo; types as it is a joy to readers. Pullman is an atheist, and the books reflect his negative view of organized religion. Some religious advocacy groups are, accordingly, up in arms over the release of the movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have already received my first mass e-mail warning me about the dangers of The Golden Compass and advising me to keep my kids inside, with doors locked. The movie will, I am told, &amp;ldquo;kill God in the minds of children&amp;rdquo;; its objective is to &amp;ldquo;bash Christianity and promote atheism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell atheism to kids.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But Pullman&amp;rsquo;s real quarrel is less with belief itself than with the intolerance that organized belief systems sometimes foster, an intolerance demonstrated every time some busybody condemns a book without having actually read it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are a lot of sophisticated theological and philosophical ideas woven into the &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; narrative. The story speaks as positively about religious concepts such as soul, spiritual existence and love as it speaks negatively about intolerance and bigotry. It opens a window in the reader&amp;rsquo;s mind and invites him or her to investigate all of these ideas further.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless, there is no doubt that &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; will threaten some readers&amp;rsquo; identities and beliefs. To listen to and take seriously alternative viewpoints is to make oneself vulnerable; it raises the possibility that our certainty is not as justified as we had thought.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Complaints about Pullman&amp;rsquo;s books and calls for a boycott of the movie are based on several seriously flawed assumptions: that parents should shelter teenagers from views that don&amp;rsquo;t seem in accord with those of the parent; that young adults cannot or should not think critically and engage in dialogue about serious ideas; and that imaginative fiction threatens religious belief.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In fact, great stories are the stuff of which religious belief is made. Literature shapes and expands our imagination, and imagination is critically important to our ability to believe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In religious practice, for example, we are asked to internalize symbols, such as the cross, seeing them not as mere shapes or designs but as signs that point toward the infinite. We are asked to believe in unseen forces that never register on scientific instruments. We are asked to imagine ourselves as part of a human community larger than ourselves and our families, and we are asked to imagine our lives not as isolated, meaningless evolutionary aberrations but as part of a grander narrative of creation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Belief is not for the unimaginative. If it were, perhaps religious wisdom would be passed down through history in some more concrete form than the symbols, stories, myths and parables we have inherited.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Parents who want their children to grow up with faith should take them to the fiction section of the local library or bookstore and give them free rein to explore. It is in literature that they will find the most convincing evidence for eternal things, and it is through exposure to literature that they will develop the imagination that belief requires.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl is a masters student in international relations at the University of Chicago and a freelance writer.  His blog is &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Paul Tillich and a poem by Mark Strand</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And, certainly, the way to maturity in thinking is a difficult path.  Much must be left behind: early dreams, poetic imaginations, cherished legends, favored doctrines, accustomed laws and ritual traditions.  Some of them must be restored on a deeper level, some must be given up.  Despite this price, maturity can be gained - a manly, self-critical, convincing faith, not produced by reasoning, but reasonable, and at the same time rooted in the message of the divine foolishness, the ultimate source of wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From century to century it has become more and more evident that knowledge without wisdom produces external and internal self-destruction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He who has encountered the mystery of life has reached the source of wisdom.  In encountering it with awe and longing, he experiences the infinite distance of his being from that which is the ground of his being.  He experiences the limits of his being, his finitude in face of the infinite.  He learns that acceptance of one&amp;rsquo;s limits is the decisive step towards wisdom.  The fool rebels against the limits set by his finitude.  He wants to be unlimited in power and knowledge.  He who is wise accepts his finitude.  He knows that he is not God.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;  &amp;ndash;The Eternal Now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man in Black&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was walking downtown&lt;br /&gt;when I noticed a man in black,&lt;br /&gt;black cape and black boots, coming toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His arms out in front of him,&lt;br /&gt;his fingers twinkling with little rings,&lt;br /&gt;he looked like a summer night full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was summer.  The night was full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;the tall buildings formed a hallway down which I walked.&lt;br /&gt;The man in black came toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The waxed tips of his mustache shone&lt;br /&gt;like tiny spears and his teeth glistened.&lt;br /&gt;I offered him my hand which he did not take.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt like a fool and stood in his black wake,&lt;br /&gt;shaken and small, and my tears&lt;br /&gt;swung back and forth in the sultry air like chandeliers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mark Strand&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
