<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Languages on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Languages on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/languages/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent posts on education at Wide Awake Minds</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few of my recent posts at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, in case you missed them:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/few-of-things-you-can-do-in-great.html&#34;&gt;A few of the things you can do in a great university&lt;/a&gt;, in which I argue that if students want to make the most of their school years in general and their college years in particular, they must take ownership of their education and elect to do what is difficult.  I propose a few of the ways in which college students can do so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/thinking-critically-about-critical.html&#34;&gt;Thinking critically about critical pedagogy&lt;/a&gt;, in which I encourage my readers to recognize the reality and complexity of cultural and institutional racism, but also to think critically about the theoretical lenses of critical pedagogy (a framework aimed at correcting racism and other power disparities).  This post sparked a great discussion in the comment section as well as some fruitful email exchanges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/beyond-preparing-our-kids-for-21st.html&#34;&gt;Beyond &amp;ldquo;preparing our kids for 21st-century jobs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - a call to do away with sloganeering about education as job-preparation, and a brief sketch of the case for universal liberal education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/quotes-from-deborah-meiers-in-schools.html&#34;&gt;Ideas about education from Deborah Meier&lt;/a&gt;, one of the greatest progressive educators of our time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/building-collection-of-language_09.html&#34;&gt;On language learning textbooks&lt;/a&gt; - A personal account of my love of language learning textbooks, and what I have learned from them about how and why we should learn world languages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to link to it on your blog or social network or pass it along to someone who might be interested in reading it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal update: spring quarter</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is turning out to be one of the busiest times of my life, so I won’t be posting very much over the next nine weeks.  For one thing, my coursework is forcing me to put most of my personal reading list on the back-burner, so I’ll have fewer excerpts to share.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the academic stress, however, things are better than ever.  My classes are awesome – a Ph.D.-level seminar in Japanese literature of the 1920s and 30s taught from a Marxist perspective (the first time I’ve really had to grapple with critical theory), the third quarter of elementary Norwegian (which I’m taking in the hope of traveling to Norway and studying Knut Hamsun and other Norwegian writers in the original language), the third quarter of fourth-year modern Japanese (which amounts to taking a course with a top-notch private tutor, as there are only three of us in the class), and Jean-Bethke Elshtain’s course on the Just War tradition – a Divinity School course offering a perspective on war and peace that is completely different from the realist perspective of the political science department that I’m used to hearing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than that, I am finishing my M.A. (on the consequences of China’s rise for East Asian security), meeting new people, exploring the city, and spending as much time as possible with my friends.  Spring is here, the quads are full of students, and my last quarter at the U of C is shaping up to be one of the best.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hermann Hesse&#39;s &#39;Beneath the Wheel&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hermann-hesses-beneath-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hermann-hesses-beneath-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematics, as far as he was concerned, was a Sphinx charged with deceitful puzzles whose cold malicious gaze transfixed her victims, and he gave the monster a wide berth.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What would many happy citizens and trustworthy officials have become but unruly, stormy innovators and dreamers of useless dreams, if not for the effort of their schools?  In young beings there is something wild, ungovernable, uncultured which first has to be tamed.  It is like a dangerous flame that has to be controlled or it will destroy.  Natural man is unpredictable, opaque, dangerous, like a torrent cascading out of uncharted mountains.  At the start, his soul is a jungle without paths or order.  And, like a jungle, it must first be cleared and its growth thwarted.  Thus it is the school&amp;rsquo;s task to subdue and control man with force and make him a useful member of society, to kindle those qualities in him whose development will bring him to triumphant completion.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For he was aware that in the academy he would have to be even more ambitious if he wanted to outstrip his new fellow students.  Why did he want to surpass them actually?  He didn&amp;rsquo;t really know himself.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This magnificent monastery, hidden behind hills and woods, has long been reserved for the exclusive use of the students of the Protestant Theological Academy in order that their receptive young spirits will be surrounded by an atmosphere of beauty and grace.  Simultaneously the young people are removed from the distracting influence of their towns and families and are preserved from the harmful sight of the active life.  So it is possible to let them live under the definite impression that their life&amp;rsquo;s goal consists exclusively of the study of Hebrew and Greek and sundry subjects and to turn the thirst of young souls toward pure and ideal studies and enjoyments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If someone else were to approach him and vigorously seek to win his friendship, he would respond gladly.  Like a wallflower he stayed in the background waiting for someone to fetch him, someone more courageous and stronger than himself to tear him away and force him into happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Hesse&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beneath the Wheel&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two weeks in Tokyo</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-weeks-in-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 23:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-weeks-in-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rt4jEijEbVI/AAAAAAAAAE8/fAd1oaGpHrA/s1600-h/tokyo_shinjuku_bright_lights.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5106557588385066322&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rt4jEijEbVI/AAAAAAAAAE8/fAd1oaGpHrA/s400/tokyo_shinjuku_bright_lights.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thursday at 1 p.m., I will be on a plane bound for Minneapolis, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll fly direct from Minneapolis to Tokyo-Narita.  It&amp;rsquo;s a 12-hour flight and a 13-hour difference from eastern time, so I&amp;rsquo;ll arrive in Tokyo around 4 pm on Thursday.  Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll figure out how to ride the bus from Narita to Shinjuku, the district in the photo, and at Shinjuku I&amp;rsquo;ll meet up with my friend Ai.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I became friends with Ai when she was an exchange student in my hometown of Muskegon, MI, during my senior year of high school; although I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen her in over three years, we&amp;rsquo;ve kept in touch through letters and emails.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be staying with Ai and making the most of Tokyo for two weeks, seeing as much as I can and improving my Japanese as much as possible in the process. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On Sunday, I&amp;rsquo;ll also spend the day with the Takada family, the wonderful host parents and sisters I stayed with for six weeks as an exchange student near Tokyo in the summer before my senior year of high school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Naturally, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend any of this precious time typing in English and surfing the Internet.  So the blog is on hiatus until September 20th or so.  Thank you, as always, for reading, and feel free to browse the archives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As always, I will take hundreds of photos and keep a detailed travel journal these next two weeks, and I will post some of that on this blog when I return.  Until then:  &lt;em&gt;Ja, ne.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
