<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mythology on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/mythology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mythology on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/mythology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Krakauer, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wanders eastward, toward the sun, he comes to a mountain.  A voice calls: are you near a mountain?  Yes, he answers, I&amp;rsquo;m standing near a mountain.  Then the voice says: That mountain you are standing near is my foot; I am lying bound in the uttermost part of the earth, come set me free!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, when he came to think about it, he acknowledged that those hours had had a significance for him that no one could realize, and if it was true - as had just been said - that at times his writing &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;sparkled&lt;/span&gt;, then it was his memories of that time that had kindled the spark; it was a reflection of the happiness his two playmates had bestowed on him in his childhood.  For that reason they could claim a large share in his achievements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But his days varied, the good alternating with the bad, and sometimes he would be working at his best when a thought, a pair of eyes, a word from the past would strike him, quenching his inspiration.  Then he would get up and begin to pace his room from wall to wall; he had done this so often, he had worn a white path across the floor, and the path grew daily whiter&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so it turned out that only a life similar to the life of those around us, merging with it without a ripple, is genuine life, and that an unshared happiness is not happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boris Pasternak&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Doctor Zhivago&lt;/span&gt; (quoted in Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because I was alone, however, even the mundane seemed charged with meaning.  The ice looked colder and more mysterious, the sky a cleaner shade of blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy, when you are young, to believe that what you desire is no less than what you deserve, to assume that if you want something badly enough, it is your God-given right to have it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jon Krakauer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The universal triumph of the secular state has thrown all religious organizations into such a definitely secondary, and finally ineffectual, position that religious pantomime is hardly more today than a sanctimonious exercise for Sunday morning, whereas business ethics and patriotism stand for the remainder of the week.  Such a monkey-holiness is not what the functioning world requires&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A single song is being inflected through all the colorations of the human choir.  General propaganda for one or another of the local solutions is superfluous - or much rather, a menace.  The way to become human is to learn to recognize the lineaments of God in all of the wonderful modulations of the face of man.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts: Jung, Rilke, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fact that an intellectual formula never has been and never will be devised which could embrace and express the manifest possibilities of life must lead to the inhibition or exclusion of other activities and ways of living that are just as important. &amp;hellip;Doubtless there are exceptional people who are able to sacrifice their entire life to a particular formula, but for most of us such exclusiveness is impossible in the long run. Sooner or later&amp;hellip;the potentialities repressed by the intellectual attitude will make themselves indirectly felt by disturbing the conscious conduct of life. &amp;hellip; The first function to be affected by the conscious inhibition is feeling, since it is the most opposed to the rigid intellectual formula and is therefore repressed the most intensely. No function can be entirely eliminated - it can only be greatly distorted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jung, &amp;ldquo;General Descriptions of the Types&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke, tr. Leishman &amp;amp; Spender:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;And before&lt;br /&gt;A single pain has got within range of your ever-&lt;br /&gt;galloping heart, comes the tingling&lt;br /&gt;in the soles of your feet, ahead of the spring that it wells from,&lt;br /&gt;chasing into your eyes a few physical tears.&lt;br /&gt;And, in spite of all, blindly,&lt;br /&gt;your smile&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Angel: suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a place we know nothing about, and there,&lt;br /&gt;on some indescribable carpet, lovers showed all that here&lt;br /&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re for ever unable to manage - their daring&lt;br /&gt;lofty figures of heart-flight,&lt;br /&gt;their towers of pleasure, their ladders,&lt;br /&gt;long since, where ground never was, just quiveringly&lt;br /&gt;propped by each other&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pillars, pylons, the Sphinx, all the striving thrust,&lt;br /&gt;grey, from fading or foreign town, of the spire!&lt;br /&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t all this a miracle? Angel, gaze, for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;-&lt;br /&gt;O mightiness, tell them that &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;were capable of it - my breath&amp;rsquo;s&lt;br /&gt;too short for this celebration. So, after all, we have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;failed to make use of the spaces, these generous spaces, these,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;our &lt;/em&gt;spaces. (How terribly big they must be,&lt;br /&gt;when, with thousands of years of our feeling, they&amp;rsquo;re not over-crowded.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Seventh Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The multitude of men and women choose the less adventurous way of the comparatively unconscious civic and tribal routines. But these seekers, too, are saved - by virtue of the inherited symbolic aids of society, the rites of passage, the grace-yielding sacraments, given to manking of old by the redeemers and handed down through milleniums. It is only those who know neither an inner call nor an outer doctrine whose plight truly is desperate: that is to say, most of us today, in this labyrinth without and within the heart.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
