<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academia on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/academia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academia on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/academia/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great lines from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to think - seriously - with words like Classicism, Romanticism, Humanism, Realism. &amp;hellip;One does not get drunk nor does one quench one&amp;rsquo;s thirst with bottle labels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Paul Valery, quoted in C. Milosz, &lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beauty is momentary in the mind -&lt;br /&gt;The fitful tracing of a portal;&lt;br /&gt;But in the flesh it is immortal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Peter Quince at the Clavier&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At no moment during my work did I feel boredom; indeed, I was playing more than toiling, and several passages preserve, I hope, a trace of my smile.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright, green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, in the isolation of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;At evening, casual flocks of pigeons make&lt;br /&gt;Ambiguous undulations as they sink,&lt;br /&gt;Downward to darkness, on extended wings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I got away with half my heart - no more.&lt;br /&gt;Barely a trace of my old gaiety.&lt;br /&gt;The crowd like market cattle bore&lt;br /&gt;Me along. The world was loathsome to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyprian Norwid&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Nerves&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With nothing can one approach a work of art so little as with critical words: they always come down to more or less happy misunderstandings.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This above all - ask yourself in the stillest hour of the night: &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; I write? Delve into yourself for a deep answer. And if this should be affirmative, if you may meet this question with a strong and simple &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I must&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; then build your life according to this necessity; your life even into its most indifferent and slightest hour must be a sign of this urge and a testimony to it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Therefore save yourself from these general themes and seek those which your own everyday life offers you; describe your sorrows and desires, passing thoughts and the belief in some sort of beauty - describe all these with loving, quiet, humble sincerity, and use, to express yourself, the things in your environment, the images from your dreams, and the objects of your memory. If your daily life seems poor, do not blame it; blame yourself, tell yourself that you are not poet enough to call forth its riches; for to the creator there is no poverty and no poor indifferent place. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A work of art is good if it has sprung from necessity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Live a while in these books, learn from them what seems to you worth learning, but above all love them. This love will be repaid you a thousand and a thousand times, and however your life may turn, - it will, I am certain of it, run through the fabric of your growth as one of the most important threads among all the threads of your experiences, disappointments and joys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Letters to a Young Poet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
