<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Realism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/realism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Realism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 18:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/realism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A limited ecumenism</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;A limited ecumenism,&amp;rdquo; appeared today in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt;, the newsletter of the Martin Marty Center at the University of Chicago Divinity School.  It discusses the Catholic Church&amp;rsquo;s recent outreach to traditionalist Anglicans.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is a free online publication sent out twice a week to over 7,000 scholars, ministers, students, and others interested in the intersection of religion and public life; you can subscribe to it at the Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.uchicago.edu/web/info/sightings&#34;&gt;subscription page&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is also online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&#34;&gt;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/archive_2009/1105.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Limited Ecumenism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As reported in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; last Monday, the Vatican announced two weeks ago that it was setting up a new canonical structure, or Apostolic Constitution, to facilitate the conversion of disaffected Anglican traditionalists to Catholicism; the converts will be able to “enter full communion with the Catholic Church while preserving elements of the distinctive Anglican spiritual and liturgical patrimony,” in the Vatican’s words.  Married former Anglican clergy will be allowed to become Catholic Priests, though not Bishops.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Vatican portrayed the move as a response to requests from Anglicans and as representative of its broader “commitment to ecumenical dialogue.” Rowan Williams, the Archbishop of Canterbury and symbolic leader of the Anglican Church, and Vincent Nichols, the Catholic Archbishop of Westminster, released a statement confirming the Vatican’s narrative: “The Apostolic Constitution is further recognition of the substantial overlap in faith, doctrine and spirituality between the Catholic Church and the Anglican tradition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But what leaders of the two churches depicted as an historic, ecumenical move toward Christian unity, others saw as something considerably more complex.  Andrew Sullivan, a Catholic writer who has often been critical of Pope Benedict XVI’s leadership, used economic analogies in describing the move as a power grab.  “Married priests are fine…as long as they help build market share,” he wrote, paraphrasing what he sees as the Vatican’s new position on clerical chastity.  The move “essentially junks an entire tradition of ecumenical dialogue in favor of a quick and sudden merger and acquisition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Such analogies, while jarring, may be worth exploring further.  Organizations and societies learn from each other’s successful practices, and religious organizations are no exception.  The language and efficiency of the Vatican’s announcement made the policy appear to be as carefully scripted and “rolled-out” as a new product by an electronics manufacturer or a new policy by a political leader.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Holy See demonstrated that it, too, can masterfully employ the techniques of “spin,” omnipresent in both consumer and political marketing.  And still other political analogies may apply:  Is the Vatican practicing religious realpolitik, strengthening itself at the expense of a weakened and divided adversary?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, this development may tell us more about the contemporary Catholic Church than about divisions in the Anglican Church.  Perhaps most interestingly, the Vatican&amp;rsquo;s plan suggests that current Catholic leadership sees liturgical procedures and even the chastity of priests as somewhat flexible, but its stands against homosexuality and the ordainment of women as fixed and beyond debate – indeed, even as a source of common ground with other socially conservative Christian groups.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of the Christian churches place a high value on reconciliation and unity.  But few see unification as an aim that trumps the aims of conscience, that is, of right doctrine and right orientation toward God.  In evaluating the Vatican’s move, observers will have to ask themselves whether reconciliation ought to come at the price of continuing and even strengthening the exclusion of women and gays from full and equal membership in the Church.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;References:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donadio, Rachel and Laurie Goodstein, “Vatican Bidding to Get Anglicans to Join Its Fold,” New York Times, 10/21/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Holy See Press Office, “Note of the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith about Personal Ordinariates for Anglicans Entering the Catholic Church,” 10/20/09. Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en.&#34;&gt;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nichols, Vincent and Rowan Williams, “Joint Statement by The Archbishop of Westminster and The Archbishop of Canterbury,” 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sullivan, Andrew, “Married Priests Are Fine…,” The Daily Dish, 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/2009/10/married-priests-are-fine-.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Mearsheimer&#39;s &#39;The Tragedy of Great Power Politics&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-mearsheimers-the-tragedy-of-great-power-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-mearsheimers-the-tragedy-of-great-power-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In international politics, God helps those who help themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because Americans dislike realpolitik, public discourse about foreign policy in the United States is usually couched in the language of liberalism.  Hence the pronouncements of the policy elites are heavily flavored with optimism and moralism.  &amp;hellip;Behind closed doors, however, the elites who make national security policy speak mostly the language of power, not that of principle, and the United States acts in the international system according to the dictates of realist logic.  In essence, a discernible gap separates public rhetoric from the actual conduct of American foreign policy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For better or worse, states are rarely willing to expend blood and treasure to protect foreign populations from gross abuses, including genocide.  For instance, despite claims that American foreign policy is filled with moralism, Somalia (1992-93) is the only instance during the past one hundred years in which U.S. soldiers were killed in action on a humanitarian mission.  And in that case, the loss of a mere eighteen soldiers in an infamous firefight in October 1993 so traumatized American policymakers that they immediately pulled all U.S. troops out of Somalia and then refused to intervene in Rwanda in the spring of 1994, when ethnic Hutu went on a genocidal rampage against their Tutsi neighbors.  Stopping that genocide would have been relatively easy and it would have had virtually no effect on the position of the United States in the balance of power.  Yet nothing was done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But sometimes the pursuit of non-security goals conflicts with balance-of-power logic, in which case states usually act according to the dictates of realism.  For example, despite the U.S. commitment to spreading democracy across the globe, it helped overthrow democratically elected governments and embraced a number of authoritarian regimes during the Cold War, when American policymakers felt that these actions would help contain the Soviet Union.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is difficult to imagine a modern political leader openly asking the public to fight and die to improve the balance of power.  No European or American leader did so during their world war or the Cold War.  Most people prefer to think of fights between their own state and rival states as clashes between good and evil, where they are on the side of the angels and their opponents are aligned with the devil.  Thus, leaders tend to portray war as a moral crusade or an ideological contest, rather than as a struggle for power.  Realism is a hard sell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John J. Mearsheimer, &lt;em&gt;The Tragedy of Great Power Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
