<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solitude on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/solitude/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solitude on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/solitude/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from David Damrosch, Kahlil Gibran, &amp; Paul Tillich</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 02:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Goethe comments that the Church erred in closing the canon of scripture, as God&amp;rsquo;s creative work still continues, notably in the activity of great spirits like Mozart, Raphael, and Shakespeare, &amp;ldquo;who can draw their lesser contemporaries higher.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For the first time in history, authors of highly successful works can hope to have them translated into twenty or thirty languages within a few years of publication, and foreign countries may even provide the primary readership for writers who have small audiences at home or who are censored by their governments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; works cease to be the exclusive products of their original culture once they are translated; all become works that only &amp;ldquo;began&amp;rdquo; in their original language.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Society melts away in the vast echo chamber of (literary critic Harold) &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Bloom&#34;&gt;Bloom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s mind, replaced by the warring voices of the few great titans of the literary universe.  The fewer the better: &amp;hellip;Bloom continually narrows his authors&amp;rsquo; already narrow circle.  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1573225142&#34;&gt;The Western Canon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; treats twenty-six writers, but what need twenty-six?  &amp;ldquo;Most simply, the Canon is Plato and Shakespeare&amp;rdquo; (34).  What need even two?  &amp;ldquo;At once no one and everyone, nothing and everything, Shakespeare is the Western Canon&amp;rdquo; (71).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet even Bloom finally relents.  Having spent almost five hundred pages extolling the greatness of the few greatest writers at the heart of his version of the Western canon, he closes with an appendix listing several &lt;em&gt;thousand&lt;/em&gt; works by more than eight hundred and fifty writers whom he considers to be the key figures in the Western canon as a whole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Damrosch&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/What-World-Literature-Translation-Transnation/dp/0691049866/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1204791136&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;What is World Literature&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How shall I go in peace and without sorrow? Nay, not without a wound in the spirit shall I leave this city.  Long were the days of pain I have spent within its walls, and long were the nights of aloneness; and who can depart from his pain and his aloneness without regret?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Too many fragments of the spirit have I scattered in these streets, and too many are the children of my longing that walk naked among these hills, and I cannot withdraw from them without a burden and an ache.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is not a garment I cast off this day, but a skin that I tear with my own hands.  Nor is it a thought I leave behind me, but a heart made sweet with hunger and with thirst.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet I cannot tarry longer.  The sea that calls all things unto her calls me, and I must embark.&lt;br /&gt;For to stay, though the hours burn in the night, is to freeze and crystallize and be bound in a mould. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fain would I take with me all that is here. But how shall I?  A voice cannot carry the tongue and the lips that give it wings. Alone must it seek the ether.  And alone and without his nest shall the eagle fly across the sun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kahlil Gibran&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Prophet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sociological analyses of the present period have pointed to the importance of anxiety as a group phenomenon.  Literature and art have made anxiety a main theme of their creations, in content as well as in style.  The effect of this has been the awakening of at least the educated groups to an awareness of their own anxiety, and a permeation of the public consciousness by ideas and symbols of anxiety.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The first assertion about the nature of anxiety is this: anxiety is the state in which a being is aware of its possible nonbeing.  &amp;hellip;It is not the realization of universal transitoriness, not even the experience of the death of others, but the impression of these events on the always latent awareness of our own having to die that produces anxiety.  Anxiety is finitude, experienced as one&amp;rsquo;s own finitude.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and poems by Goethe, Coleridge, and A. Daniel</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am more and more convinced that poetry is the universal possession of mankind&amp;hellip;the epoch of world literature is at hand, and everyone must strive to hasten its approach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Goethe (quoted in Damrosch, &lt;em&gt;What is World Literature?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White Towels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been studying the difference&lt;br /&gt;between solitude and loneliness,&lt;br /&gt;telling the story of my life&lt;br /&gt;to the clean white towels taken warm from the dryer.&lt;br /&gt;I carry them through the house&lt;br /&gt;as though they were my children&lt;br /&gt;asleep in my arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Jones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May God, the Chosen, by whom were absolved the sins of the blind Longinus, wish if it please him, that I and my lady lie within one chamber where we shall make a rich covenant, whereon great joy attendeth; where, with laughter and caresses, she shall disclose to me her fair body, with the glamor of the lamplight about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duty Surviving Self-Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unchanged within, to see all changed without,&lt;br /&gt;Is a blank lot and hard to bear, no doubt.&lt;br /&gt;Yet why at others&amp;rsquo; wanings should&amp;rsquo;st thou fret ?&lt;br /&gt;Then only might&amp;rsquo;st thou feel a just regret,&lt;br /&gt;Hadst thou withheld thy love or hid thy light&lt;br /&gt;In selfish forethought of neglect and slight.&lt;br /&gt;O wiselier then, from feeble yearnings freed,&lt;br /&gt;While, and on whom, thou may&amp;rsquo;st&amp;ndash;shine on! nor heed&lt;br /&gt;Whether the object by reflected light&lt;br /&gt;Return thy radiance or absorb it quite :&lt;br /&gt;And tho&amp;rsquo; thou notest from thy safe recess&lt;br /&gt;Old Friends burn dim, like lamps in noisome air,&lt;br /&gt;Love them for what they are ; nor love them less,&lt;br /&gt;Because to thee they are not what they were.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But when I consider how she is the summit of worth, much do I love myself the more for having ever dared to desire her, for now do I know that my heart and my wit will make me to make to their whim a rich conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And since she is of such worth, do not think that my firm will can disperse itself or flow away or divide, for by that God who manifested himself in the dove, I am neither mine nor hers if I leave her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on psychology, religion, and politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in mundane situations, the individual must &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; in order to discover what he is and he must act in order to continue experiencing aspects of himself which he values and enjoys.  If he thinks of himself as a businessman, a parent, an athlete, an intellectual, he must engage in behavior appropriate to this self-image.  If he does not, he must redefine himself, or he will be left feeling anxious and needful.  (Here is the reason for the psychological shock of retirement; the man who has retired may find that suddenly he can no longer &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;that which he most valued himself for being.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Past actions through which he sought to know and to accept the self are not capable of satisfying this need in the present.  Recalling the past can only remind the individual of what he used to be.  The erstwhile football hero who is still reliving the big game fifteen years later, or the ex-campus queen who tries to give meaning to her life by clinging to her reign over the prom of a decade ago, are pathetic figures.  As the existentialists have pointed out, man must act in order to be, and what he becomes is largely the summation of his actions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Paradoxical though it may seem, it is when the individual is with others that he is best able to enjoy and expand many aspects of himself, to refine and verify his self-image.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Men hate in others those things - and only those things - which they despise in themselves.  It is possible to disapprove of other people in a rational and dispassionate manner, but to hate them is an irrational and impassioned act.  The passion betrays the underlying self-contempt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Distance enables the lover to see his beloved purely in terms of the projections he hangs on her.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The general rule is that people who enjoy life enjoy marriage. Some people would be unhappy with any spouse, for they do not allow themselves happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snell Putney and Gail J. Putney&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Adjusted American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That hatred springs more from self-contempt than from a legitimate grievance is seen in the intimate connection between hatred and a guilty conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Eric Hoffer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Insanity in individuals is something rare - but in groups, parties, nations, and epochs, it is the rule.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If our faith is real, it must encroach upon our life. The Christian Confession in its original Church form will always be exposed to the misunderstanding that the Christian regards the Creed as a matter of heart and conscience, but that here on earth and in the world other truths hold good. The world lives in this misunderstanding; it regards the whole of Christianity as a friendly &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo;, connected with the &amp;lsquo;realm of religion&amp;rsquo;, which is respected and which ought to be left untampered with; and so we get rid of the matter! But this misunderstanding might even have come from within; a Christian might quite well wish to have this realm for himself and to guard faith like a sensitive plant. The relationship between the Church and the world has been widely understood as a question of a fixing of frontiers, whereby each secured itself behind its own frontier, although from time to time it came to a skirmish. From the Church&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, however, such a fixing of frontiers can never exhaust its task. By the very nature of the Christian Church there is only one task, to make the Confession heard in the sphere of the world as well.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us beware of remaining stuck where we are and refusing to advance to meet worldly attitudes. For instance, in Germany in 1933 there was plenty of serious, profound and living Christianity and confession&amp;hellip;. But unfortunately this faith and confession of the German Church remained embedded in the language of the Church, and did not translate what was being excellently said in the language of the Church into the political attitude demanded at the time; in which it would have become clear that the Evangelical Church had to say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to National Socialism, &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; from its very roots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Barth&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Dogmatics in Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Krakauer, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wanders eastward, toward the sun, he comes to a mountain.  A voice calls: are you near a mountain?  Yes, he answers, I&amp;rsquo;m standing near a mountain.  Then the voice says: That mountain you are standing near is my foot; I am lying bound in the uttermost part of the earth, come set me free!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, when he came to think about it, he acknowledged that those hours had had a significance for him that no one could realize, and if it was true - as had just been said - that at times his writing &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;sparkled&lt;/span&gt;, then it was his memories of that time that had kindled the spark; it was a reflection of the happiness his two playmates had bestowed on him in his childhood.  For that reason they could claim a large share in his achievements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But his days varied, the good alternating with the bad, and sometimes he would be working at his best when a thought, a pair of eyes, a word from the past would strike him, quenching his inspiration.  Then he would get up and begin to pace his room from wall to wall; he had done this so often, he had worn a white path across the floor, and the path grew daily whiter&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so it turned out that only a life similar to the life of those around us, merging with it without a ripple, is genuine life, and that an unshared happiness is not happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boris Pasternak&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Doctor Zhivago&lt;/span&gt; (quoted in Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because I was alone, however, even the mundane seemed charged with meaning.  The ice looked colder and more mysterious, the sky a cleaner shade of blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy, when you are young, to believe that what you desire is no less than what you deserve, to assume that if you want something badly enough, it is your God-given right to have it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jon Krakauer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The universal triumph of the secular state has thrown all religious organizations into such a definitely secondary, and finally ineffectual, position that religious pantomime is hardly more today than a sanctimonious exercise for Sunday morning, whereas business ethics and patriotism stand for the remainder of the week.  Such a monkey-holiness is not what the functioning world requires&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A single song is being inflected through all the colorations of the human choir.  General propaganda for one or another of the local solutions is superfluous - or much rather, a menace.  The way to become human is to learn to recognize the lineaments of God in all of the wonderful modulations of the face of man.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Petterson, &#39;Out Stealing Horses&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t switch on the ceiling light at once but leave the room in twilight so the yellow flames in the stove flicker brightly over the floor and walls. The sight of them slows my breathing down and makes me calm as it must have done for men through thousands of years: let the wolves howl, here by the fire it’s safe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But each time he came home he had changed a little, and I had to concentrate hard to hold on to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My father looked almost happy then, and I could see by the way he looked at me that I did, too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And she waves briefly and slams the car door and it starts to roll down the slope. I go up the steps and turn off the yard light and walk through the hall to the kitchen. Lyra is at my heels, but even when she is behind me the room feels a bit empty. I look out at the yard, but there is nothing but my own reflection in the dark glass.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He is watching the news. I don’t know when I last watched the news. I did not bring a television set out here with me, and I regret it sometimes when the evenings get long, but my idea was that living alone you can soon get stuck to those flickering images and to the chair you will sit on far into the night, and then time merely passes as you let others do the moving. I do not want that. I will keep myself company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;‘Would you rather I hadn’t come?’ she says again, insistently.&lt;br /&gt;‘I don’t know,’ I say, and that is also true; I don’t know what to think of her coming out here, it was not part of my plan, and then it strikes me: now she will go away and never come back. That thought fills me with such sudden terror that I quickly say:&lt;br /&gt;‘No, that’s not true. Don’t go.’&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I get up. Six fifteen. Lyra leaves her place beside the stove and goes to the kitchen door to wait. She turns her head and looks at me, and there is a trustfulness in that look I probably do not deserve. But maybe that is not the point, to deserve it or not, perhaps it just exists, that trust, disconnected from who you are and what you have done, and is not to be measured in any way. That’s a nice thought. Good dog, Lyra, I think, good dog.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Per Petterson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Out Stealing Horses &lt;/em&gt;(highly recommended; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1197353675&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon.com)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Hamsun, Akhmatova, and Lawrence</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-hamsun-akhmatova-and-lawrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-hamsun-akhmatova-and-lawrence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He read no books, but his thoughts were often with God; it was natural, coming of simplicity and awe. The stars in the sky, the wind in the trees, the solitude and the wide-spreading snow, the might of earth and over earth filled him many times a day with a deep earnestness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He did not return, even after his death, to&lt;br /&gt;That ancient city he was rooted in.&lt;br /&gt;Going away, he did not pause for breath&lt;br /&gt;Nor look back. My song is for him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anna Akhmatova&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Heaven and Earth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so I cross into another world&lt;br /&gt;shyly and in homage linger for an invitation&lt;br /&gt;from this unknown that I would trespass on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am very glad, and all alone in the world,&lt;br /&gt;all alone, and very glad, in a new world&lt;br /&gt;where I am disembarked at last.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For when it is quite, quite nothing, then it is everything.&lt;br /&gt;When I am trodden quite out, quite, quite out,&lt;br /&gt;every vestige gone, then I am here&lt;br /&gt;risen, and setting my foot on another world&lt;br /&gt;risen, not born again, but risen, body the same as before,&lt;br /&gt;new beyond knowledge of newness, alive beyond life,&lt;br /&gt;proud beyond inkling or furthest conception of pride,&lt;br /&gt;living where life was never yet dreamed of, nor hinted at,&lt;br /&gt;here, in the other world, still terrestrial&lt;br /&gt;myself, the same as before, yet unaccountably new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ah no, I cannot tell you what it is, the new world.&lt;br /&gt;I cannot tell you the mad, astounded rapture of its discovery.&lt;br /&gt;I shall be mad with delight before I have done,&lt;br /&gt;and whosoever comes after will find me in the new world&lt;br /&gt;a madman in rapture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;D.H. Lawrence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And in the night, he lay wanting her, and she was willing. She did not go away next morning; all that day she did not go, but helped about the place; milked the goats, and scoured pots and things with fine sand, and got them clean. She did not go away at all. Inger was her name. And Isak was his name. &amp;hellip; She did not run away. When he had been out, and came home again, there was Inger at the hut; the two were one, the woman and the hut.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ho, they were getting well-to-do, with this hut of theirs, this farm of theirs; why, &amp;lsquo;twas good enough for anyone. Aye, they&amp;rsquo;d as good as all they could wish for already. Oh, that Inger; he loved her and she loved him again; they were frugal folk; they lived in primitive wise, and lacked for nothing. &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go to sleep!&amp;rdquo; And they went to sleep. And wakened in the morning to another day, with things to look at, matters to see to, once again; aye, toil and pleasure, ups and downs, the way of life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knut Hamsun&#39;s &#39;Pan&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/knut-hamsuns-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/knut-hamsuns-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RrWND9ughiI/AAAAAAAAAEM/_4c5MCTKreE/s1600-h/Knut_Hamsun.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5095133652688340514&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RrWND9ughiI/AAAAAAAAAEM/_4c5MCTKreE/s400/Knut_Hamsun.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I just finished the best novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a very long time. I am stunned at how beautiful &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knut_Hamsun&#34;&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s writing is, and cannot believe that he is not a household name in America. He was a very flawed man - like Martin Heidegger, Carl Schmitt, and too many others, he abused his considerable intellectual gifts in support of Nazism, and it is understandable that this removed his right to a full place in the Great Books pantheon. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All the same, however, he is an incredible writer whose work deserves to be a standard on classics lists. &lt;em&gt;Pan &lt;/em&gt;was a truly special read, and I am going to read as many of his novels as I can get my hands on. Here are some excerpts to give you a taste:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a big, white-washed house down by the sea, I met someone who for a short while filled my thoughts. She is no longer always in my memory, not now - no, I have quite forgotten her. But I do recall the other things, the cries of the sea birds, the hunting in the forest, my nights, and all the warm hours of the summer. It was in any case by sheer chance that I met her; and had it not been for that chance she would never have lain in my thoughts for a single day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For it is within ourselves that the sources of joy and sorrow lie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There was a boulder outside my hut, a big grey boulder. It always seemed by its expression to be well-disposed towards me; it was as if it saw me as I came past and knew me again. I used to like making my way past this boulder when I went out in the mornings, and it was as though I left a good friend there who would be waiting when I got back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For some days a chill atmosphere of unrest hung over the earth; rotten branches snapped and the crows collected in flocks and squawked. But it was not for long, the sun was near; one morning it rose up behind the forest. A sweet pang strikes through me when the sun comes; I throw my gun on my shoulder in silent rejoicing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I followed every bend, taking my time; there was no hurry and nobody was waiting for me at home. Free as a king I went my way in the peace of the forest, as leisurely as I pleased.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everywhere the sky was open and pure. I gazed into the clear sea and it was as if I lay face to face with the depths of the earth, and as if my beating heart went out to those depths and was at home there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;More excerpts to come; all of the above beauties were in the first ten pages of the 192 page book. A &lt;/em&gt;New Yorker&lt;em&gt; article about Hamsun can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/archive/2005/12/26/051226crat_atlarge&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the book can be purchased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pan-Knut-Hamsun/dp/1406937932/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-0086905-3665754?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1186303891&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I give it my highest recommendation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
