<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 07:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/teaching/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a teacher and a Michigan Wolverine</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to report that I have decided to enter the University of Michigan School of Education&amp;rsquo;s Secondary MAC (MA in Education with Secondary Certification) program in mid-June.  The program is 12 months long and includes over 1,000 hours of classroom experience as a student teacher and substitute teacher, resulting in full certification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I look forward to finding unique ways to show my students the importance of learning and reading as well as the value of informed engagement with current events and politics.  I also want to grow into a caring and effective mentor.  And, finally, I hope to learn from my classroom experience in order to become a more informed and articulate advocate for education reform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am very, very sad to be moving from Chicago after living here for five years.  I will miss my tiny apartment in East Lakeview and having easy access to my favorite places - the lakefront, Mickey&amp;rsquo;s Grille, Avenue Tavern, and Stella&amp;rsquo;s Diner in East Lakeview, the Noble Tree Cafe in Lincoln Park, the Grind and the Old Town School of Folk Music in Lincoln Square, the Pub and Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books in Hyde Park, Myopic Books in Wicker Park, Lao Beijing in Chinatown, and the Borders on Michigan Ave., among others.  But I will be visiting at least once a month over the next year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next three weeks will be incredibly busy.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be packing, moving, finding a subletter in Chicago and a temporary place to stay in Ann Arbor, working for a few more weeks, and spending as much time as possible with my friends in Chicago.  But I am thrilled to be entering the program and stepping into the next stage of my life and career.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
