<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Relations on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/international-relations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Relations on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/international-relations/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two cents about COIN</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Two cents about COIN,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. It discusses the the growing faith of U.S. political and military leaders in the military doctrine of COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below; if you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or linking to it on your blog. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Cents About COIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The war in Afghanistan, according to Gen. Stanley McChrystal’s recent assessment, is &amp;ldquo;a situation that defies simple solutions or quick fixes.  Success demands a comprehensive counterinsurgency (COIN) campaign.&amp;rdquo;  McChrystal and other American leaders calling for a &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; of additional U.S. troops into Afghanistan to mirror the alleged success of the &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; in Iraq are voicing their belief that the doctrinal framework for the original surge – COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare – is a widely-applicable tool in asymmetric warfare that the U.S. ought to employ in Afghanistan. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Top decisionmakers in the U.S. military, including Gen. McChrystal and Gen. David Petraeus, continue to express their faith in the doctrine, which they played major roles in creating.  Prominent Republicans in Congress, who almost unanimously support sending more troops to Afghanistan, have endorsed a nation-building strategy that relies heavily on COIN over a counterterrorism strategy that focuses on targeting al-Qaeda and other militants from a distance.  Several key figures in the Obama administration also appear to favor that approach. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It may be true that, as military expert Stephen Biddle said in recent Congressional testimony, &amp;ldquo;the U.S. is an unusually experienced counterinsurgent force today,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the new Army/Marine counterinsurgency doctrine…is the product of a nearly unprecedented degree of internal debate, external vetting, historical analysis, and direct recent combat experience.&amp;rdquo;   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But these very factors that have encouraged so many highly capable U.S. leaders to sign on to &amp;ldquo;COIN&amp;rdquo; should cause observers to be wary of the doctrine and the currency it increasingly enjoys in the American political debate.  After all, the more enthusiastic we are about the potential of COIN warfare, the more blind we will be to its costs, which are enormous. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We can and must think about contemporary problems – such as what strategy the U.S. should pursue in Afghanistan – through the lenses of relevant theories and historical analogies.  But it is foolish to think within the box of a single analogy, such as the Iraq &amp;ldquo;surge,&amp;rdquo; or a single theory, such as the idea that we can succeed at counterinsurgency and nation-building by deploying generous numbers of ground troops and focusing on winning the &amp;ldquo;hearts and minds&amp;rdquo; of local communities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our need to make quick decisions and cope with a complex world creates a powerful incentive for us to create &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; default beliefs, habits, choices, or courses of action that we adopt almost without thinking.  And yet when those in the halls of power make major decisions on the basis of such &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; the results can sometimes be disastrous.  It behooves political observers to be aware of new decision-making habits, and the spread of some new piece of &amp;ldquo;conventional wisdom,&amp;rdquo; in their leaders. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to remember that military leaders have a major incentive to endorse a COIN approach in Afghanistan.  According to General Petraeus and other experts, most successful COIN operations require very high numbers of U.S. troops on the ground – numbers that may be politically and logistically impossible for the Obama administration to accept. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because the number of troops that can be reasonably demanded for a COIN operation is essentially limitless, mission failure can be blamed on the executive branch for not sending enough troops rather than on military leaders, the combat environment, or the COIN playbook itself.  As Gen. McChrystal wrote in his assessment: &amp;ldquo;Success is not ensured by additional forces alone, but continued underresourcing will likely cause failure.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Organizational psychology and the logic of bureaucracies provide more clues into the wave of COIN-fever that appears to have struck so many of our political and military leaders.  Simply put, it was neither easy nor cheap for the military to develop COIN doctrine as we attempted to salvage the war in Iraq in recent years, and now COIN feels like hard-won wisdom that we should put to the test in another theater of war.  It’s a classic case of sunk costs: it is felt that we paid too much for COIN to abandon it now. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Policymakers’ belief in the power of COIN may encourage them to see military solutions where none exist.  If the U.S. opts to send tens of thousands of additional ground troops to Afghanistan in order to pursue a comprehensive COIN strategy, it will be taking on a great deal of risk and incurring substantial additional costs in pursuit of a highly uncertain outcome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/www.ryanmccarl.com&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator. He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Should Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning.  In it, I make the case that any honest examination of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s policy options regarding North Korea must begin with the acknowledgment that, first, war is not an option, and second, that the strategies of isolation and sanctions have been tried and have failed for 60 years.  Accordingly, our only chance for a resolution of the North Korean issue is through direct talks with the North aimed at a comprehensive peace settlement and an official end to the Korean War.  This is not a pleasant option, but it is the right one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read the article and the argument &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; please feel free to comment directly on the site, through a letter to the editor, or via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryan.mccarl@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.  If you enjoy the article, please link to it or forward it to others who might be interested in reading it.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of Range: The ethics of U.S. drone strikes in Pakistan</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;Out of Range&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared in this morning&amp;rsquo;s edition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/index1234.html&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I explore the ethical dilemma of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s ongoing campaign of drone strikes in Pakistan.  This is shaping up to be one of the hottest contemporary debates in foreign policy circles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I write: &amp;ldquo;Technology and wealth have made it possible for the U.S. to exercise decisive military power anywhere in the world.  But our technology and our wealth often outrun our wisdom, our prudence, and our moral sensibilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;With the exception of the pacifist and nonviolent traditions, most of our moral thinking about war acknowledges that there are at least some circumstances under which violence and killing, including organized political violence (or war), is morally acceptable.  But are our theories about the ethics of warmaking up to the task of determining when, if ever, it is permissible to kill a relatively impotent enemy from a safe and anonymous distance, by robot or missile?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;For their operators, controlling these &amp;lsquo;drones&amp;rsquo; must not be so different from playing a video game – something almost fictional, bearing at most a tangential relationship to the reality of face-to-face killing and dying that informed our ability to understand the depth of the tragedies of previous wars we have fought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;op-ed&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to pass it along to others who might be interested.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other columnists featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; today: University of Chicago international relations theorist &lt;a href=&#34;http://mearsheimer.uchicago.edu/&#34;&gt;John J. Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt; (also my former M.A. thesis advisor!), legendary New Left activist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tomhayden.com/&#34;&gt;Tom Hayden&lt;/a&gt;, University of Michigan historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juancole.com/&#34;&gt;Juan Cole&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Editor at Time.com &lt;a href=&#34;http://tonykaron.com/&#34;&gt;Tony Karon&lt;/a&gt;, and Salon.com contributor and Constitutional lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Greenwald&#34;&gt;Glenn Greenwald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Reading Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  At the end of each of the past three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post listing the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the course of the year in order to bring these books to the attention of others.  My lists from 2007 and 2006 are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2007/12/2007-book-recommendations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve put the titles of the five books most important to me this year in bold, and I&amp;rsquo;ve linked each book to its Amazon.com page.  Enjoy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Arons, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Compelling-Belief-Culture-American-Schooling/dp/0870235249/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899752&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Compelling Belief: The Future of American Schooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (education/religion/politics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doniger, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Implied-Spider-Wendy-Doniger/dp/0231111711/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899795&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics and Theology in Myth&lt;/a&gt; (religion / mythology)&lt;br /&gt;Du Bois, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899814&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt; (history / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frank, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899838&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt; (economics / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frankel, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Faith-Freedom-Religious-Liberty-Critical/dp/0809015757/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Faith and Freedom: Religious Liberty in America&lt;/a&gt; (religion / politics / law)&lt;div&gt;Gibran, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prophet-Kahlil-Gibran/dp/000100039X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900039&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; philosophy / religion)&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900186&amp;amp;sr=1-3&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Harrison, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Returning-Earth-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802143318/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harrison, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;br /&gt;Hemingway, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; literature)&lt;br /&gt;Kerouac, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dharma-Bums-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/0143039601/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900162&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Laxness, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Independent-People-Halldor-Laxness/dp/0679767924/ref=pd_sim_b_1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Independent People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Mann, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Milosz, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Native-Realm-Self-Definition-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374528306/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900582&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Native Realm: A Search for Self-Definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (memoirs / literature / history)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Putney &amp;amp; Putney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Adjusted-American-Neurosis-Individual-Society/dp/0060900954/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900593&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Adjusted American: Normal Neurosis in the Individual and Society&lt;/a&gt; (psychology)&lt;br /&gt;Salomon &amp;amp; Valdez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900612&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt; (design / environment)&lt;br /&gt;Walzer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Unjust-Wars-Historical-Illustrations/dp/0465037070/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900722&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Just and Unjust Wars&lt;/a&gt; (3rd reading; politics / international relations)    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard Zinn on World War II</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve intended to read Howard Zinn&amp;rsquo;s revisionist history of the United States - &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; - for years, and I finally buckled down and started it this week. It is an excellent and eye-opening book, to say the least, and I found myself becoming absorbed in and largely agreeing with the narrative of the first few chapters - his interpretation of the &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; and colonization of America. Although I&amp;rsquo;m usually not willing to follow Zinn to his ultimate conclusions, I find his eagerness to tear down the myths and falsehoods surrounding the idea of &amp;ldquo;American exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; refreshing - especially after the nationalist fervor of a Presidential election season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zinn reminds us that Americans are fallible human beings like any others, capable of acts of greatness as well as acts of shame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I skipped ahead to find out what Zinn had to say about World War II - the war most often held up in America as an example of America&amp;rsquo;s unique greatness, of America-as-savior-and-beacon-of-hope. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from what I found:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, if the entrance of the United States into World War II was (as so many Americans believed at the time, observing the Nazi invasions) to defend the principle of nonintervention in the affairs of other countries, the nation&amp;rsquo;s record cast doubt on its ability to uphold that principle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;As Bruce Russett says: &amp;ldquo;Throughout the 1930s the United States government had done little to resist the Japanese advance on the Asian continent.&amp;rdquo; But: &amp;ldquo;The Southwest Pacific area was of undeniable economic importance to the United States - at the time most of America&amp;rsquo;s tin and rubber came from there, as did substantial qualities of other raw materials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A State Department memorandum on Japanese expansion, a year before Pearl Harbor, did not talk of the independence of China or the principle of self-determination. It said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;our general diplomatic and strategic position would be considerably weakened - by our loss of Chinese, Indian, and South Seas markets (and by our loss of much of the Japanese market for our goods, as Japan would become more and more self-sufficient) as well as by insurmountable restrictions upon our access to the rubber, tin, jute, and other vital materials of the Asian and Oceanic regions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The plight of Jews in German-occupied Europe, which many people thought was at the heart of the war against the Axis, was not a chief concern of Roosevelt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Was the war being fought to establish that Hitler was wrong in his ideas of white Nordic supremacy over &amp;ldquo;inferior&amp;rdquo; races? The United States&amp;rsquo; armed forces were segregated by race.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In one of its policies, the United States came close to direct duplication of Fascism. This was in its treatment of the Japanese-Americans living on the West Coast. After the Pearl Harbor attack, anti-Japanese hysteria spread in the government. One Congressman said: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m for catching every Japanese in America, Alaska, and Hawaii now and putting them in concentration camps&amp;hellip;. Damn them! Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of them!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt did not share this frenzy, but he calmly signed Executive Order 9066, in February 1942, giving the army the power, without warrants or indictments or hearings, to arrest every Japanese-American on the West Coast - 110,000 men, women, and children - to take them from their homes, transport them to camps far into the interior, and keep them there under prison conditions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hatred against the enemy, against the Japanese particularly, became widespread. Racism was clearly at work. &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; magazine, reporting the battle of Iwo Jima, said: &amp;ldquo;The ordinary unreasoning Jap is ignorant. Perhaps he is human. Nothing&amp;hellip;indicates it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, there was a mass base of support for what became the heaviest bombardment of civilians ever undertaken in any war: the aerial attacks on German and Japanese cities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Italy had bombed cities in the Ethiopian war; Italy and germany had bombed civilians in the Spanish Civil War; at the start of World War II German planes dropped bombs on Rotterdam in Holland, Convetry in England, and elsewhere. Roosevelt had described these as &amp;ldquo;inhuman barbarism that has profoundly shocked the conscience of humanity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These German bombings were very small compared with the British and American bombings of German cities. &amp;hellip;The English flew at night with no pretense of aiming at &amp;ldquo;military&amp;rdquo; targets; the Americans flew in the daytime and pretended precision, but bombing from high altitudes made that impossible. The climax of this terror bormbing was the bombing of Dresden in early 1945, in which the tremendous heat generated by the bombs created a vacuum into which fire leaped swiftly in a great firestorm through the city. More than 100,000 died in Dresden. [See Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slaughterhouse Five&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out Zinn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/A-Peoples-History-of-the-United-States/Howard-Zinn/e/9780060838652/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nuclear Peace and its Consequences for China&#39;s Rise</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just put the finishing touches on my M.A. thesis, bringing one of the most stressful months of my life to a satisfying close.  10,181 words, 45 pages, three entirely different drafts, and an ungodly amount of writing and revision.  I am happy with the finished product and will turn it in tomorrow morning, then post a link to it online.  My faculty advisor was &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Mearsheimer&#34;&gt;John Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt;, the best professor I&amp;rsquo;ve had at the U of C and one of the most influential international relations scholars in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thesis:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I argue that security conflict between the U.S. and China can be managed short of war, regardless of how strong China becomes. This is the case because of the phenomenon known as the “nuclear peace”; because every great power in the contemporary international system possesses a secure, second-strike nuclear capability, the best prediction we can make is that every possible conflict between the U.S. and China - or any pair of contemporary great powers - will be stopped short of war because of nuclear deterrence, which raises the costs of war to unacceptably high levels, outweighing all potential political gains to be had by conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this behind me, I&amp;rsquo;m turning my mind away from school and on to other things, with the exception of my Japanese and Norwegian coursework.  I still need to finish Thomas Mann&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading several books on education: Alfie Kohn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;What Does It Mean to Be Well Educated?, &lt;/em&gt;Nel Nodding&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Education&lt;/em&gt;, and Myron Lieberman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Educational Morass, &lt;/em&gt;among others.  I am extremely excited for this weekend, as I am going home to Muskegon, MI to hang out with my wonderful family for the first time since March.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel as though an enormous burden has been lifted from me.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Two Mules: A Fable for the Nations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-two-mules-a-fable-for-the-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-two-mules-a-fable-for-the-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SAvWAdMfPaI/AAAAAAAAAIE/CP49F6lxN84/s1600-h/cooperation-two-mules.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5191478298799979938&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SAvWAdMfPaI/AAAAAAAAAIE/CP49F6lxN84/s400/cooperation-two-mules.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(Saw this in Richard Layard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on Easter, Just War Theory, and Japanese lit</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The resurrection of Jesus is the sign to the world that God indeed does reign, does give life in death and that the love of God is stronger even than death (Rom. 8:36-39).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;At the center of the church&amp;rsquo;s teaching on peace and at the center of all Catholic social teaching, are the transcendence of God and the dignity of the human person.  The human person is the clearest reflection of God&amp;rsquo;s presence in the world; all of the church&amp;rsquo;s work in pursuit of both justice and peace is designed to protect and promote the dignity of every person.  For each person not only reflects God, but is the expression of God&amp;rsquo;s creative work and the meaning of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemptive ministry.  Christians approach the problem of war and peace with fear and reverence.  God is the Lord of life, and so each human life is sacred; modern warfare threatens the obliteration of human life on a previously unimaginable scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;U.S. Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response (The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace, 1983)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us.  &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28140&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28141&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romans 8:37-39&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The aggressor is always peace-loving; he would prefer to take over our country unopposed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Carl Von Clausewitz, quoted in J.T. Turner, &amp;ldquo;Threats, Values and Defense: Does the Defense of Values by Force Remain a Moral Possibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;***&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His desire for a woman was not of a sort to make him want this particular woman - it was something to be taken care of lightly and with no sense of guilt.  This woman was too clean.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The window of the waiting-room was clear for an instant as the train started to move.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s face glowed forth, and as quickly disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But this love would leave behind it nothing so definite as a piece of Chijimi.  Though cloth to be worn is among the most short-lived of craftworks, a good piece of Chijimi, if it has been taken care of, can be worn quite unfaded a half-century and more after weaving.  As Shimamura thought absently how human intricacies have not even so long a life, the image of Komako as the mother of another man&amp;rsquo;s children suddenly floated into his mind.  He looked around, startled.  Possibly he was tired.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He leaned against the brazier, provided against the coming of the snowy season, and thought how unlikely it was that he would come again once he had left.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Komako had come up to him, he did not know when.  She took his hand.  He looked around at her but said nothing.  She gazed at the fire, the pulse of the fire beating on her intent, slightly flushed face.  Shimamura felt a violent rising in his chest.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s hair was coming undone, and her throat was bare and arched.  His fingers trembled from the urge to touch it.  His hand was warm, but Komako&amp;rsquo;s was still warmer.  He did not know why he should feel that a separation was forcing itself upon them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kawabata Yasunari&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Snow Country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously he did not much enjoy reading and discussing a typical month&amp;rsquo;s production of Japanese literature.  In a 1935 essay Kobayashi expressed his annoyance with authors who complained that he had not been sufficiently kind in his reviews, and asked sardonically what kindness contemporary authors have ever shown their critics.  The only kindness a critic really wants from authors is that they will supply him with the basis for writing decent criticism; but present-day authors do precisely the opposite.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donald Keene&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Dawn to the West: A History of Japanese Literature (Vol. 4)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2007 book recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following list includes the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year that I enjoyed the most and that had the biggest effect on me.  I give the highest recommendation to all of them, and I&amp;rsquo;ve bolded the top five.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Akhmatova, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Anna-Akhmatova/dp/0939010615/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804019&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Bonhoeffer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Letter-Papers-Prison-Dietrich-Bonhoeffer/dp/0684838273/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Letters and Papers From Prison&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Cumings, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Koreas-Place-Sun-History-Updated/dp/0393327027/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804099&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Korea’s Place in the Sun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;de Bary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0231121393/ref=pd_cp_b_1?pf_rd_p=317711001&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=center-41&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0231086040&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=1FDVCJHA9ZCSZ7N3WY39&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Sources of Japanese Tradition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frye, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Imagination-Cbc-Massey-Lectures/dp/0887845983/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805497&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Educated Imagination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gilpin, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Change-World-Politics-Robert-Gilpin/dp/0521273765/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805537&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;War and Change in World Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pan-Knut-Hamsun/dp/1426422571/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Pan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Soil-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0394717813/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805602&amp;amp;sr=1-7&#34;&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Victoria-Penguin-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0143039377/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198806948&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hardy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Penguin-Classics-Thomas/dp/0140436995/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ienaga, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pacific-War-1931-1945-Saburo-Ienaga/dp/0394734963/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807106&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pacific War 1931-1945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Into-Wild-Jon-Krakauer/dp/0307387178/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807224&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;McCann, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Columbia Anthology of Modern Korean Poetry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Petterson, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807402&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Out Stealing Horses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pieper, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;H&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hope-History-Josef-Pieper/dp/0898704650/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807583&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;ope and History&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rilke, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Duino-Elegies-Sonnets-Orpheus-Rainer/dp/0395250587/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807628&amp;amp;sr=1-8&#34;&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rowling, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Harry-Potter-Deathly-Hallows-Book/dp/0545010225/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/East-Eden-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142004235/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807783&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;East of Eden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pearl-Centennial-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142000698/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807841&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pearl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Travels-Charley-Search-America-Steinbeck/dp/0140053204/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807914&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Walker, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prompt-Utter-Destruction-Truman-Against/dp/080785607X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807943&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Prompt and Utter Destruction: Truman and the Use of Atomic Bombs&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;If you are interested in checking out last year&amp;rsquo;s list of recommended books, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Meredith, Apollinaire, and Delors</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-meredith-apollinaire-and-delors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-meredith-apollinaire-and-delors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Fables about Error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is as wrong as the uninstructed heart?&lt;br /&gt;Left to its ends, it clutches things and creatures&lt;br /&gt;That can&amp;rsquo;t be held, or held, will slip their natures;&lt;br /&gt;It lives to hoard or to protect a hoard.&lt;br /&gt;To school, to school! Teach the poor organ skill&lt;br /&gt;That all its ignorant, nervous will&lt;br /&gt;Does not unpage us like old calendars.&lt;br /&gt;A life should be all gathering and art.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let there be academies of everything,&lt;br /&gt;That the trap in the warm kitchen yield to guile,&lt;br /&gt;That grackles leave a fire single file&lt;br /&gt;And swallows find their true halves the first spring.&lt;br /&gt;The mind should be, like art, a gathering&lt;br /&gt;Where the red heart that fumes in the chest&lt;br /&gt;Saying &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;kill, kill, kill&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;love, love, love,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Gentled of the need to be possessed,&lt;br /&gt;Can study a little the things that it dreams of.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;William Meredith&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a need for urgency, for history does not wait.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jacques Delors, &amp;ldquo;A Necessary Union&amp;rdquo; (in Nelsen &amp;amp; Stubb, eds., &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The European Union: Readings on the Theory and Practice of European Integration&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Rhenish Night&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My glass is filled with a wine that trembles like flame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Guillaume Apollinaire (tr. William Meredith)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quotes from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We keep the wall between us as we go.&lt;br /&gt;To each the boulders that have fallen to each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mending Wall&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World peace cannot be safeguarded without the making of creative efforts proportionate to the dangers which threaten it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Schumann&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Schumann Declaration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I asked her, urgently, if she could see my face, and she said: &amp;ldquo;See it?&amp;rdquo; And, smiling: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s reflected in my eyes, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(じゃ、私の顔が見えるかいと一心に聞くと、見えるかいって、そら、そこに、写ってるじゃありませんかと、にこりと笑ってみせた。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Natsume Soseki&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;The First Night&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And home, where passion lived and died,&lt;br /&gt;Becomes a place where she can hide,&lt;br /&gt;While all the town and harbor side&lt;br /&gt;Vibrate with her seclusion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin Arlington Robinson&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Eros Turannos&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite all of these examples of colloquialism and apparent simplicity in Frost&amp;rsquo;s poetry, we should not be deceived into thinking of Frost as a rustic or a primitive.  On the contrary, Frost was a sophisticated writer who was well versed in Latin poetry and who knew as well as any poet of his time how to make effective use of formal and rhetorical strategies.  From his early career on, Frost prided himself on being &amp;ldquo;one of the most notable craftsmen of my time,&amp;rdquo; as he wrote in his 1913 letter to John Bartlett.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Christopher Beach&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Twentieth-Century American Poetry&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;In Those Days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In those days - they were long ago -&lt;br /&gt;The snow was cold, the night was black.&lt;br /&gt;I licked from my cracked lips&lt;br /&gt;A snowflake, as I looked back&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Through branches, the last uneasy snow.&lt;br /&gt;Your shadow, there in the light, was still.&lt;br /&gt;In a little the light went out.&lt;br /&gt;I went on, stumbling - till at last the hill&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hid the house.  And, yawning,&lt;br /&gt;In bed in my room, alone,&lt;br /&gt;I would look out: over the quilted&lt;br /&gt;Rooftops, the clear stars shone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How poor and miserable we were,&lt;br /&gt;How seldom together!&lt;br /&gt;And yet after so long one thinks:&lt;br /&gt;In those days everything was better.&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes on religion, love, and int&#39;l relations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-on-religion-love-and-intl-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-on-religion-love-and-intl-relations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every summer he&amp;rsquo;s on the prarie harvesting wheat and every winter in the Wisconsin forests chopping cordwood. That&amp;rsquo;s his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A life maybe as good as any other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &amp;ldquo;On the Prarie&amp;rdquo; (from &lt;em&gt;Tales of Love and Loss&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The theological dimension is needed both for interpreting and for solving present day problems in human society.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pope John Paul II, &lt;em&gt;Centesimus Annus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The human being is made for love and cannot live without love. When it is manifested as the total gift of two persons in their complementarities, love cannot be reduced to emotions or feelings, much less to mere sexual expression. In a society that tends more and more to relativize and trivialize the very experience of love and sexuality, exalting its fleeting aspects and obscuring its fundamental values, it is more urgent than ever to proclaim and bear witness that the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; of conjugal love and sexuality exist where there is a full and total gift of persons, with the characteristics of &lt;em&gt;unity &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;fidelity&lt;/em&gt;. This truth, a source of joy, hope, and life, remains impenetrable and unattainable as long as people close themselves off in relativism and skepticism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pontifical Council for Justice and Peace, &lt;em&gt;Compendium of the Social Doctrine of the Church&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We lived through much happiness and unhappiness,&lt;br /&gt;Separations, miraculous rescues. And now, this ash.&lt;br /&gt;And the sea battering the shore when I walk the empty boulevard.&lt;br /&gt;And the sea battering the shore. And ordinary sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz, &lt;em&gt;from &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;On Parting With my Wife, Janina&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enemy images have a long pedigree, and some states continue to position each other in such terms today. The Greeks represented the Persians as &amp;ldquo;barbarians&amp;rdquo;; the Crusaders perceived the Turks as &amp;ldquo;infidels&amp;rdquo;; medieval Europeans feared their defeat at Liegnitz at the hands of the Mongols heralded Armageddon; later Europeans treated the peoples of the Americas as savages; conservatives thought civilization was threatened by the French Revolution; and, in our own century, we have the Armenian genocide, the Holocaust, the early Cold War, Northern Ireland, Pol Pot, Palestinian and Israeli fundamentalists, the Bosnian Civil War, Hutus and Tutsis - all based on representations of the Other as intent on destroying or enslaving the Self.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to recognize that this concept implies nothing about whether enemy images are justified. Some enemies are &amp;ldquo;real,&amp;rdquo; in that the Other really does existentially threaten the Self, as the Nazis did the Jews, and others are &amp;ldquo;chimeras,&amp;rdquo; as the Jews were to the Nazis. &amp;hellip;Real or imagined, if actors think enemies are real then they are real in their consequences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Alexander Wendt, &lt;em&gt;Social Theory of International Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
