<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/environment/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Edward Abbey and John Cheever</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-edward-abbey-and-john-cheever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-edward-abbey-and-john-cheever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We make the coffee with river water, dipping a canful from among the rocks and letting it set for a time until the silt settles to the bottom.  For entertainment we have the murmur of the river, the drone of cicada and amphibians, the show of nighthawks plunging through the evening gulping bugs.  Afterwards we sit by the fire until the fire gives out, listening, smoking, analyzing socioeconomic problems:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look here, Newcombe,&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;do you think it&amp;rsquo;s fitting that you and I should be here in the wilds, risking our lives amidst untold hardships, while our wives nad loved ones lounge at their ease back in Albuquerque, enjoying the multifold comforts, benefits and luxuries of modern contemporary twentieth century American urban civilization?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edward Abbey&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Desert Solitaire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The light there was like a blow, and the air smelled as if many wonderful girls had just wandered across the lawn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Common Day&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had already put on the football uniform, and the weight of it, the heaviness of the pants and the shoulder guards, had worked a change in me, as if in putting on these old clothes I had put off the reasonable anxieties and troubles of my life.  It felt as if we had both returned to the years before our marriage, the years before thew war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Chucky Ewing had got hold of a balloon and was trying to organize a scrimmage line in the middle of the floor.  The others were dancing a samba.  And I knew that Lawrence was looking bleakly at the party as he had looked at the weather-beaten shingles on our house, as if he saw here an abuse and a distortion of time; as if in wanting to be brides and football players we exposed the fact that, the lights of youth having been put out in us, we had been unable to find other lights to go by and, destitute of faith and principle, had become foolish and sad.  And that he was thinking this about so many kind and happy and generous people had me angry, made me feel for him such an unnatural abhorrence that I was ashamed, for he is my brother and a Pommeroy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever&lt;br /&gt;  -&amp;ldquo;Goodbye, My Brother&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Hemingway, O&#39;Connor, and K. Shapiro</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s heart tightened as the trout moved.  He felt all the old feeling.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His muscles ached and the day was hot, but Nick felt happy.  He had left everything behind, the need for thinking, the need to write, other needs.  It was all back of him.  From the time he had gotten down off the train and the baggage man had thrown his pack out of the open car door things had been different.  Seney was burned, the country was burned over and changed, but it did not matter.  It could not all be burned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The road ran on, dipping occasionally, but always climbing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inside the tent the light came through the brown canvas.  It smelled pleasantly of canvas.  Already there was something mysterious and homelike.  Nick was happy as he crawled inside the tent.  He had not been unhappy all day.  This was different though.  Now things were done.  There had been this to do.  Now it was done.  It had been a hard trip.  He was very tired.  That was done.  He had made his camp.  He was settled.  Nothing could touch him.  It was a good place to camp.  He was there, in the good place.  He was in his home where he had made it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nick laughed.  It made a good ending to the story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Big Two-Hearted River: Part I&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;.  They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tide of darkness seemed to sweep him back to her, postponing from moment to moment his entry into the world of guilt and sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery O&amp;rsquo;Connor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Everything That Rises Must Converge&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But no appeal has yet been made to the vast American middle class, the majority class, to detach itself from our competitive industrial insanity.  It is indeed our industrial way of life that lends sanction to militarism and colonialism, Preparedness and suppression of human rights.  Our enemy, strange as it may sound to American ears, is the Standard of Living.  We worship at the altar of the White Rhinoceros, the American kitchen.  Standard of Living is the holy of holies in whose name every other evil is committed.  To lower this standard or to equalize it among the peoples of the world is our greatest need.  And the first step is to disassociate ourselves from the industrial-scientific madness which rules our lives twenty-four hours a day.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To remove ourselves from the world of competition is of paramount importance to the individual and to the nation.  Competition is the most terrible vice of modern society.  Competition is the disease of the West and is the source of our violence.  Non-violence means non-competition.  &amp;hellip;It cannot be employed by governments because governments are by definition committed to violence.  Nonviolence is not a prerogative of governments but of men, even of one man.  One nonviolent man, like Gandhi or Christ, can change history.  Governments can only keep history on the march.  &lt;em&gt;Ahimsa&lt;/em&gt; can stop history.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Vinoba Bhave, the greatest living disciple of Gandhi, who travels throughout India asking for land for the peasantry from the great landlords and receiving it, says: &amp;ldquo;I desire to humiliate neither the rich nor the poor&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  This is the opposite of communist expropriation or of capitalist competition.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Instead of class war and hatred as preached by the communists or industrial-scientific competition as preached by us, to survive we must behave nonviolently and in the spirit of love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Shapiro&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;To Revive Anarchism&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Creative Glut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More excerpts from Laxness&#39;s &#39;Independent People&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-excerpts-from-laxnesss-independent-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-excerpts-from-laxnesss-independent-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SaitkjQQVsI/AAAAAAAAAuY/MOSJmmUHAp0/s1600-h/independentpeople.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SaitkjQQVsI/AAAAAAAAAuY/MOSJmmUHAp0/s400/independentpeople.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5307683004306446018&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I recently finished Halldor Laxness&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sjálfstætt fólk&lt;/em&gt;), and it was one of the top ten novels I have ever read.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A few more excerpts (I&amp;rsquo;ve posted others &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2008/12/excerpts-from-laxness.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2008/12/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;One has grown weary of one&amp;rsquo;s house before it has finished building; strange that mankind should need to live in a house, instead of remaining content with the house of wishes.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Come what may and go what may, a man always has the memories of his dogs. Of these at least no one can deprive him, though both the prosperity of world war and the fulfilment of important people&amp;rsquo;s ideals have proved to be no more than a cloud of dust that has swirled up to obscure the lone worker&amp;rsquo;s vision.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To be able to look forward is to live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Human life isn&amp;rsquo;t long enough for a peasant to become a man of means.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He had never asked for any other joy than the joy of knowing that the sheep were breeding with good result in their regular season, and of seeing them weather the winter strong enough to struggle out of the bogs in spring.  Perhaps that is the true joy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And yet he did not find the happiness he had dreamed of, nor the peace he had so much desired, and she understood him, and loved him for that very reason, that he had found neither happiness nor peace.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And to be able to look forward to the morrow in joyful expectation is good fortune indeed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;They groped involuntarily for one another&amp;rsquo;s hand, fearful that they might be alone; what more was it really possible to do?  Thus they stood, holding hands and shivering as the moon disappeared into a deeper and deeper gloom; they were wanting coffee, they were cold.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Halldor Laxness&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Sjálfstætt fólk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Kohak&#39;s &#39;The Embers and the Stars&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s1600-h/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 128px; height: 194px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s400/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5302889589404206306&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I recently discovered the work of Erazim Kohak, a Czech philosopher and Professor Emeritus at Boston University who has written extensively on environmental ethics.  I am 30 pages into Kohak&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/span&gt;, and it is incredible so far.  A few excerpts below, with more to come.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Reflection and speculation remain no more than cunningly devised fables if they are not grounded in what, paraphrasing Calvin Schrag, we could call the prephilosophical and prescientific matrix of self-understanding and world-comprehension.  Though philosophy must do much else as well, it must, initially, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;see&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; and, thereafter, ground its speculation ever anew in seeing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;It is, surely, good that there are synthetic medicines to ease the surplus of pain, telephones to break through loneliness, and electric lights to keep the wayfarer from stumbling.  There is, though, something wrong when we use medicine to deaden our sensitivity, when we obliterate solitude with electronics and blind ourselves with the very lights we devised to help us see.  There is nothing wrong with our artifacts; there &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;something wrong with us: we have lost sight of the sense, the purpose of our production and our products.  Artifacts, finally, are good only extrinsically, as tools.  They have no intrinsic sense of their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;My primary tool has been the metaphor, not the argument, and the product of my labors is not a doctrine but an invitation to look and see.  With Husserl, I have sought not to instruct but to point out, to recall what we have forgotten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Contrary to Descartes, long before the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; of reflection there is the goodness and the truth of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;. [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; as in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito ergo sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, &amp;ldquo;I think, therefore I am&amp;rdquo;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= togetherness, &amp;ldquo;we are&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Humans have to dehumanize their world in their imagination in order to be able to exploit it ruthlessly in their actions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Our world of artifacts may be no more than the thinnest of layers covering the rhythm of living nature, but it is that layer that we confront in our daily experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Though the theoretical construct of [nature as] a mechanically ordered matter in motion may bear little resemblance to the living nature of the field and the forest and so may never have appeared convincing before, it is a faithful reflection of a world of artifacts and as such compelling to a humanity whose experience with nature is restricted to contact with artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The technical reason which produces the machine cannot teach us its human use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The logic of&amp;hellip;production and consumption, however, grows ever more elusive.  Through the ages of humanity&amp;rsquo;s precarious survival on this earth, the meeting of basic survival needs provided a ready justification for productive activity.  Were we inclined so to direct our energies, it might still do so: there is more than enough hunger and sheer dismal misery still with us.  For the most part, though, we manage to ignore such need.  The logic of our production is not that of need but of affluence with lacks such automatic justification.  If affluence is to be justified, it cannot be by need but by some greater good, be it meeting the needs of others, caring for the natural world, or creating higher values of culture.  &amp;hellip;Yet individually and collectively we sacrifice precious life and resources to producing and paying for [items such as ever-larger television sets] - and we are constantly assured that we must do so to &amp;ldquo;stimulate the economy.&amp;rdquo;  Production itself has become the justification of ever more absurd consumption: we consume to proudce, produce to consume; all other considerations must stand aside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The heavens may still declare the glory of God, but we look up not at the heavens but at neon reflected on smog; we walk not on the good earth but on asphalt.  Our estrangement from nature is no longer conceptual only: it has acquired an experiential grounding.  Figuratively, we are all in the position of the child who has never seen, never mind milked, a cow, and whose lived experience constantly provides an experiential confirmation for the assumption that milk comes from a supermarket cooler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;If the products of human &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;techne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; become philosophically and experientially problematic, it is, I would submit, because we come to think of them as autonomous of the purpose which led to their production and gives them meaning.  We become, in effect, victims of a self-forgetting, losing sight of the moral sense which is the justification of technology.  Quite concretely, the purpose of electric light is to help humans see.  When it comes to blind them to the world around them, it becomes counterproductive.  The task thus is not to abolish technology but to see through it to the human meaning which justifies it and directs its use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Erazim Kohak  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic; &#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GvI0xlwoMesC&amp;amp;dq=the+embers+and+the+stars&amp;amp;source=gbs_summary_s&amp;amp;cad=0&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Reading Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  At the end of each of the past three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post listing the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the course of the year in order to bring these books to the attention of others.  My lists from 2007 and 2006 are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2007/12/2007-book-recommendations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve put the titles of the five books most important to me this year in bold, and I&amp;rsquo;ve linked each book to its Amazon.com page.  Enjoy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Arons, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Compelling-Belief-Culture-American-Schooling/dp/0870235249/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899752&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Compelling Belief: The Future of American Schooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (education/religion/politics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doniger, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Implied-Spider-Wendy-Doniger/dp/0231111711/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899795&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics and Theology in Myth&lt;/a&gt; (religion / mythology)&lt;br /&gt;Du Bois, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899814&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt; (history / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frank, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899838&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt; (economics / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frankel, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Faith-Freedom-Religious-Liberty-Critical/dp/0809015757/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Faith and Freedom: Religious Liberty in America&lt;/a&gt; (religion / politics / law)&lt;div&gt;Gibran, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prophet-Kahlil-Gibran/dp/000100039X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900039&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; philosophy / religion)&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900186&amp;amp;sr=1-3&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Harrison, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Returning-Earth-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802143318/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harrison, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;br /&gt;Hemingway, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; literature)&lt;br /&gt;Kerouac, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dharma-Bums-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/0143039601/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900162&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Laxness, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Independent-People-Halldor-Laxness/dp/0679767924/ref=pd_sim_b_1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Independent People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Mann, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Milosz, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Native-Realm-Self-Definition-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374528306/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900582&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Native Realm: A Search for Self-Definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (memoirs / literature / history)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Putney &amp;amp; Putney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Adjusted-American-Neurosis-Individual-Society/dp/0060900954/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900593&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Adjusted American: Normal Neurosis in the Individual and Society&lt;/a&gt; (psychology)&lt;br /&gt;Salomon &amp;amp; Valdez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900612&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt; (design / environment)&lt;br /&gt;Walzer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Unjust-Wars-Historical-Illustrations/dp/0465037070/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900722&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Just and Unjust Wars&lt;/a&gt; (3rd reading; politics / international relations)    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Harrison&#39;s &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to finally know that the spirit was everywhere rather than a separate thing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clare fed our leftover sandwiches to a stray mutt, who didn&amp;rsquo;t chew the proper thirty-two times.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All of my jobs had kept me grounded in actual life whereas simply sitting in my room with my studies tended to make me unstable.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In New York City the endless blocks of huge buildings say to us, I&amp;rsquo;m serious and within me serious people are doing serious things even though five thousand people in a building might only be playing with the market edge.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a local euphemism in the U.P. that you&amp;rsquo;re not lost, you just can&amp;rsquo;t find your vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A local politician rejecting foreign languages in a school budget had said, &amp;lsquo;If English was good enough for Jesus Christ it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for our kids.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I agreed with K on the addition of what is called a &amp;lsquo;space blanket&amp;rsquo; to the survival kits I put together and distribute for Mexicans intending to migrate north.  Space blankets are sheets of material used by campers to protect them from cold and dampness but I thought they could also defend against the summer heat of the ground, which reaches over one hundred and fifty degrees.  ..The packet was in a Velcro latched bag and could be attached to a waiste belt and weighed a little less than five pounds.  I distributed these free of charge to workers&amp;rsquo; groups and through left-leaning Catholic priests.  I was opposed by many on both sides of the border for political reasons, which didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except for the legal expenses I incurred avoiding prosecution by the United States.  My raison d&amp;rsquo;etre was simple on the surface.  Estimates of crossing deaths along the entire nineteen-hundred-mile border with Mexico went as high as two thousand a year.  I had learned to be goofy rather than logically argumentative with my opponents.  I&amp;rsquo;d ask, If you could prevent twenty major airline disasters each year, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;By common consent we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything more serious than the food and music, which in themselves have become more serious as I get older.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He needed Montana but he also needed Chicago for her museums, libraries, theaters, bookstores, and most of all classical music, which he preferred to hear live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;After a passing glance I averted my eyes from a photo of Carla and me at the cabin and then I fixed on it.  Was I ever that young?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There are no damaged goods when everyone is damaged goods.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The best thing about travel, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be consumed by the past against the backdrop of a fresh landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;I was sorry to hear about Donald.  There was a man who could put in a day&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rsquo; I shook his hand as he offered this ultimate compliment of the north.  His hand felt like a semipetrified baseball mitt.  &amp;lsquo;You might not remember me.  Donny and me played football way back when, then worked together.  The name&amp;rsquo;s Teddy.&amp;rsquo;  He bowed, his face reddening, and walked away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;You were the left tackle,&amp;rsquo; I called out and he turned and grinned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On all levels the main reason to live is because you&amp;rsquo;re already alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While we were out on the park bench a small bank of clouds came across the sun turning our mood somber.  He said, &amp;lsquo;After all, the fact of death is the most brutal thing we humans are forced to accept,&amp;rsquo; but then the sun came out again and I told him that the day after the burial Herald had said, &amp;lsquo;Mother, it can&amp;rsquo;t be awful if it happens to every living thing.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buy Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True North&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/Returning-to-Earth/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802143310/?itm=3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/True-North/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802142061/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;True North&#39; and &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/jim-harrisons-true-north-and-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/jim-harrisons-true-north-and-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made plenty of discoveries this year - a love for banjo and bluegrass, a greater appreciation for the outdoors and concern for the environment, a new appreciation for the upper Midwest, the desire (if not yet the discipline) to live more simply and learn to cook - but one of the best recent discoveries I&amp;rsquo;ve made is the fiction of Jim Harrison.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished his &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=wW5CXWQNt6IC&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - a novel about a very physically-oriented man who comes down with Lou Gehrig&amp;rsquo;s disease in his early 40s - and I cannot recommend it enough.  It is a sequel of sorts to Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=pAVWwx2g9CAC&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and these two books are the first I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year to make my list of fiction favorites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVs4Z9CtTI/AAAAAAAAAgU/UxfZ_-ewCW8/s1600-h/returning+to+earth.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVs4Z9CtTI/AAAAAAAAAgU/UxfZ_-ewCW8/s200/returning+to+earth.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227856320312626&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsxC9H-lI/AAAAAAAAAgM/JxugjoVWP-A/s1600-h/truenorth.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsxC9H-lI/AAAAAAAAAgM/JxugjoVWP-A/s200/truenorth.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227729887558226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsqCXCI3I/AAAAAAAAAgE/15eFmT9sDZk/s1600-h/jimharrison.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsqCXCI3I/AAAAAAAAAgE/15eFmT9sDZk/s320/jimharrison.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227609468707698&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following links are also worth checking out:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/01/25/books/25harr.html&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Jim Harrison: &amp;ldquo;Pleasures of the Hard-Worn Life&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Harrison&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article &lt;/a&gt;on Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/11/books/review/Blythe.t.html?_r=1&amp;pagewanted=2&amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; (warning: gives a lot away).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;True North&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jim-harrisons-true-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jim-harrisons-true-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main feature of the Kingston Plains was the thousands of acres of white pine stumps, some of them very large, which had been cut at waist or chest height probably during the winter when it was easier to skid the trees out on snow-covered trails which they dampened to form ice so that the draft horse-drawn log sleighs could be more easily pulled. &amp;hellip;I swiveled around until I had completed a 360-degree view, suppressing any anger I felt over the idea that they might have left a few trees for those in the future to look at. Maybe to try to imagine the trees was like asking a contemporary Lakota to imagine a million buffalo.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It occurred to me that you could explain everything away but the behavior remained.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Frankly I wanted to be useful in this life and that could be defined only by work, not good intentions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I felt absurdly happy when I entered Michigan just north of Toledo, though I was already lonely for Riva.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Being at the university through the deaths of Robert Kennedy and Martin Luther King Jr. ending with the more recent Kent State butchery had often made academic studies seem problematical and remote. How upsetting to see your professor break down in tears in your Chaucer class the day after King was murdered. My return to religion was a defense against the insanity of the time, a way to avoid standing there simply screaming like the girl in the famous Kent State photograph. I recalled the day when I was a junior at Michigan State and Cynthia had called to say that she had heard our ex-paper boy had died in Vietnam. He was a poor kid and never seemed dressed warmly enough in winter when below-zero winds blew in off Lake Superior. &amp;hellip;He put a face on an insane war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;How soiled and tawdry poor Jesus was compared to the theological school where the self-interest of the human intelligence smothered prayer, and the abstractions in the history of theology were a virtual fire extinguisher on the Gospels.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Every location has its classic Greek chorus muttering, chattering, moaning in the background.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Fred says that when he sees a politician who has further crushed the poor pray in public he wants to pick up a gun.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I was cold and exhausted and went back to the motel room, drew an easy chair up to the window, then fell asleep staring at the frightening whiteness of the world. It was clearly a blank canvas on which you could paint your life if you cared to. Just before sleep I imagined sitting at the cabin window and painted the interior of what would be my cabin, including the front window from which the only visible thing was Lake Superior and the line of the horizon, but there was the nagging idea Fred had explained that as a putative Christian I had to learn how to function in the world before I earned the right to retreat.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We were jittery when we rigged our fly rods and flipped a coin for the first cast. Glenn won and caught a two-pounder and then it became apparent that the fish weren&amp;rsquo;t gun-shy so we could both cast. We caught a dozen before dark and released all but two which we kept for a midnight snack and ate with a six-pack of beer Glenn had stowed in the cold creek. The northern lights were astounding, whirling sheets and cones of rose and green and bluish lights so strong they gave off a tinny metallic sound.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Naturally during the act of love you&amp;rsquo;re undisturbed by reality, a grace note I also found in trout fishing, but then lovemaking and fishing don&amp;rsquo;t manage to dominate your life like you wished they could.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We gave up our heavy talk and spent two days rowing. In my own life strength has come from unfolding, subtracting, rather than adding.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clarence said a striking thing about rowing that I&amp;rsquo;ve always valued, the upshot of which was that he liked rowing because you were approaching life backward. You could clearly see the past, and you glanced quickly at the future over your shoulder mostly so you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t run into anything destructively immovable. Too much of the future was predestined by the behavior of others for you to be in control. The most you could hope for is to be ready and attentive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1202245476&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I picked up&lt;/em&gt; True North&lt;em&gt; at the Dawn Treader Book Shop (one of my favorites) in Ann Arbor, MI yesterday, and it has sucked me in and engrossed me in a way that hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened in awhile.  I read 50 pages in one sitting last night and another 150 pages on the train from Ann Arbor to Chicago this morning.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know how it ends yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
