<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josef Pieper on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/josef-pieper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Josef Pieper on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 15:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/josef-pieper/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Josef Pieper on the virtues of the human heart</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/josef-pieper-on-the-virtues-of-the-human-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/josef-pieper-on-the-virtues-of-the-human-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Josef Pieper is a German, Catholic theologian in the Thomist tradition, and his writing is beautiful - curious readers of any faith (or none) will find something to appreciate in his insights. I&amp;rsquo;ve read three of his books -&lt;em&gt; The Four Cardinal Principles&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Divine Madness: Plato&amp;rsquo;s Case Against Secular Humanism&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;A Brief Reader on the Virtues of the Human Heart&lt;/em&gt;. All three are published by Ignatius Press, which produces perhaps the most beautifully bound paperback books I am familiar with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Brief-Reader-Virtues-Human-Heart/dp/0898703034/ref=pd_bbs_sr_11/102-1512953-1785758?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1179432200&amp;sr=8-11&#34;&gt;A Brief Reader on the Virtues of the Human Heart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a mere 54 pages of thoughts and fragments, so it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to start if you are interested in finding out what Pieper has to say about human life and morality. He must be read patiently, because his style is a bit windy and filled with classicisms. Here are a few excerpts:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The virtue of fortitude protects a person from loving his life in such a way that he loses it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The basic attitude of conformity to being, of impartiality, and of objectivity, which is expressed in the classical teaching on prudence, was summarized in the Middle Ages in the marvelously simple sentence, &amp;ldquo;A man is wise when all things taste to him as they really are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The man who does good follows the lines of an architectural plan that has not been devised by himself or even totally understood by himself in all its components.  This plan is revealed to him moment by moment only through a narrow cleft and a tiny gap; in his transient condition, he never perceives the specific plan for himself in its global and definitive form.  Concerning conscience, which to an extent is prudence itself, Paul Claudel says that it is the &amp;ldquo;forbearing lamp that characterizes for us not the future but the immediate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thus, the world reveals itself to the silent listener and only to him; the more silently he listens, the more purely is he able to perceive reality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of the most central concepts from the moral philosophy of the High Middle Ages is that of&lt;/em&gt; acedia&lt;em&gt;, which we, very ambiguously, are accustomed to translate as &amp;ldquo;laziness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; Acedia&lt;em&gt;, however, means this: that man denies his effective assent to his true essence, that he closes himself off to the demand that arises from his own dignity, that he is not inclined to claim for himself the grandeur that is imposed on him with his essence&amp;rsquo;s God-given nobility of being.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &amp;ldquo;concupiscence of the eyes&amp;rdquo; reaches its utmost destructive and extirpative power at the point where it has constructed for itself a world in its own image and likeness, where it has surrounded itself with the restlessness of a ceaseless film of meaningless objects for show and with a literally deafening noise of nothing more than impressions and sensations that roar in an uninterrupted chase around every window of the senses. Behind their papery facade of ostentation lies absolute nothingness, a &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; of at most one-day constructs that often become insipid after just one-quarter of an hour and are thrown out like a newspaper that has been read or a magazine that has been paged through; a world which, before the revealing gaze of a sound spirit uninfected by its contagion, shows itself to be like a metropolitan entertainment district in the harsh clarity of a winter morning: barren, bleak, and ghostly to the point of pushing one to despair. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
