<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cruelty on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/cruelty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cruelty on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/cruelty/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But how? Genius in the Sperm Whale? Has the Sperm Whale ever written a book, spoken a speech? No, his great genius is declared in his doing nothing particular to prove it. It is moreover declared in his pyramidical silence. &amp;hellip;If hereafter any highly cultured, poetical nation shall lure back to their birth-right, the merry May-day gods of old; and livingly enthrone them again in the now egotistical sky; in the now unhaunted hill; then be sure, exalted to Jove&amp;rsquo;s high seat, the great Sperm Whale shall lord it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It was a terrific, most pitiable, and maddening sight. The whale was now going head out, and sending his spout before him in a continual tormented jet; while his one poor fin beat his side in an agony of fright. Now to this hand, now to that, he yawed in his faltering flight, and still at every billow that he broke, he spasmodically sank in the sea, or sideways rolled towards the sky his one beating fin. So have I seen a bird with clipped wing, making affrighted broken circles in the air, vainly striving to escape the piratical hawks. But the bird has a voice, and with plaintive cries will make known her fear; but the fear of this vast dumb brute of the sea, was chained up and enchanted in him; he had no voice, save that choking respiration through his spiracle, and this made the sight of him unspeakably pitiable; while still, in his amazing bulk, portcullis jaw, and omnipotent tail, there was enough to appal the stoutest man who so pitied.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seems it credible that by three such thin threads the great Leviathan was suspended like the big weight to an eight day clock.  Suspended? and to what?  To three bits of board.  Is this the creature of whom it was once so triumphantly said - &amp;lsquo;Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish-spears? The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold, the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon: he esteemeth iron as straw; the arrow cannot make him flee; darts are counted as stubble; he laugheth at the shaking of a spear!&amp;rsquo;  This the creature? this he?  Oh! that unfulfillments should follow the prophets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As strange misgrown masses gather in the knot-holes of the noblest oaks when prostrate, so from the points which the whale&amp;rsquo;s eyes had once occupied, now protruded blind bulbs, horribly pitiable to see.  But pity there was none.  For all his old age, and his one arm, and his blind eyes, he must die the death and be murdered, in order to light the gay bridals and other merry-makings of men, and also to illuminate the solemn churches that preach unconditional inoffensiveness by all to all.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For young whales, in the highest health, and swelling with noble aspirations, prematurely cut off in the warm flush and May of life, with all their panting lard about them; even these brawny, buoyant heroes do sometimes sink.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
