<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/business/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for Facebook and social networking</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Facebook currently has over 200 million active users, many people continue to doubt the value of social networking in general and Facebook in particular.  Critics argue that Facebook and other social networking and Web 2.0 tools - including blogs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - are symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;solipsism&amp;rdquo; (meaning, in this context, the self-absorption of users) of the contemporary Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, Facebook can be an enormous time-waster and procrastination tool, as can any medium or Internet resource.  I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected a lot about my own use of the site over the past six years or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself whether it is a worthwhile use of my time and an appropriate way - one among others, obviously - to communicate with my friends, family, colleagues, and acquaintances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate was largely settled for me a few months ago when I heard a remarkable lecture by Clara Shih, social networking expert and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefacebookera.com/&#34;&gt;The Facebook Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shih spoke in April at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Booth School of Business, and I was in attendance to sell copies of her book.  (I was working as a manager at a bookstore at the time).  I went in with low expectations, as I generally take a dim view of the overcrowded genre of popular business books in general and books on making money through technology in particular.  But Shih&amp;rsquo;s presentation blew me away; she made me see Facebook and social networking in an entirely different light, and she helped me understand the many complex issues involved with social networking, and the utility social networking tools can have for those willing to critically evaluate and monitor their use of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The core reason for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s popularity, according to Shih, is that it lowers the cost of keeping in touch.  Keeping in touch with people you&amp;rsquo;ve met is a difficult and time-consuming process.  Facebook makes it much, much easier.  And it can help us keep in touch in a more meaningful way: there is less need to small talk with distant friends about where they are working, what they are studying, where they are living, and so forth - it&amp;rsquo;s all out there on their Facebook page, and so we can keep track of people we&amp;rsquo;ve met as they move through their lives.  When we think of them, we can think of who they are and what they are doing &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; rather than who they were when we met them years before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This powerful idea was brought home to me again this month, as the host family I lived with in Italy for ten weeks in my sophomore year of college joined Facebook and &amp;ldquo;Friended&amp;rdquo; me.  It takes a lot of effort to write a letter in Italian, put it in an envelope, wait in line at the post office to buy international postage, and finally send it - but it takes ten seconds to write on their &amp;ldquo;walls.&amp;rdquo;  And so I am much more likely to do the latter than the former, and our relationship need not be weakened by our falling out of touch.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, Shaman Drum</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/farewell-shaman-drum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/farewell-shaman-drum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SkqxpFXuMQI/AAAAAAAAAxo/uwJXw33jMRY/s1600-h/shamandrum2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 281px; height: 320px;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SkqxpFXuMQI/AAAAAAAAAxo/uwJXw33jMRY/s320/shamandrum2.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5353286426457682178&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Skqxo9_23jI/AAAAAAAAAxg/sbGLdZWUa-8/s1600-h/shamandrum.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 213px; height: 320px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Skqxo9_23jI/AAAAAAAAAxg/sbGLdZWUa-8/s320/shamandrum.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5353286424478539314&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shamandrum.com/bookshop/&#34;&gt;Shaman Drum&lt;/a&gt; of Ann Arbor, MI, one of the best independent bookstores in the Midwest, permanently shut its doors today.  It is a major loss for Ann Arbor and for book-lovers everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Independent and used bookstores need your support.  Shop at them.  Go to their events.  Buy their gift certificates as holiday gifts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Independent bookstores must fight back against the challenging economic environment by doing everything they can to improve their businesses.  Here are a few ideas:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Keep a constant flow of new inventory, and mark down unsaleable material to maintain a high-quality bibliography;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Follow the lead of chain bookstores in taking full advantage of the &amp;ldquo;retail calendar&amp;rdquo; of holidays through decorations and displays of recommended holiday-related books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Create a pleasant, shoppable atmosphere.  I personally look for classical music and places to sit while I look over a pile of books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Stock or display local art and photography as well as books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Stock books and periodicals for book-lovers, especially the stuff that is harder to find at chain stores.  Out-of-print titles that remain relevant; major and local literary journals and serious newspapers; complete backlists of major, second-tier, and local literary writers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Sell coffee from a pot for $1 a cup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Become an integral part of your community by hosting frequent author events and becoming a local arts hub.  Create a space for gatherings such as writers&amp;rsquo; groups and reading groups.  Stock the newspapers and arts magazines of local high schools and colleges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can keep track of the independent book business by reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indiebound.org/&#34;&gt;Indiebound&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://shelf-awareness.com/&#34;&gt;Shelf Awareness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For many in Chicago, driving is a necessity, not a luxury</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My most recent op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/cgi-bin/mag/article.pl?articleId=32083&#34;&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (registration required) was published today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;Chicagobusiness.com&lt;/a&gt; and will appear in this week&amp;rsquo;s issue of &lt;em&gt;Crain&amp;rsquo;s Chicago Business&lt;/em&gt;.  You can find the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as reprinted below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is exceedingly difficult for many commuters living on the North Side to find free parking after they return from work. After an often agonizing rush-hour commute, they must circle around their neighborhood until they find a parking space; if they arrive too late, they must choose between parking at a meter and interrupting their lives every two hours to feed it, or parking a mile or more away from their homes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But if the North Side parking situation is a nightmare today, imagine what it will look like when the city installs meters along the entire lakefront, effectively eliminating a major artery of free parking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I commute every workday between my apartment near Belmont Avenue in East Lakeview and Hyde Park. If I drive, I spend around 50 minutes per day, including time spent finding parking, on the road. If I take public transportation, the same round trip can take as long as three hours. That adds an extra two hours to my workday, significantly reducing my time for leisure, exercise, relationships and everything else that is important in life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, for me and for many other commuters, driving is essential to maintaining a high quality of life in Chicago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many users of the free lakefront spots are commuters who do not have access to, cannot afford or choose not to purchase a space in a garage or a residential street parking permit. These commuters, like myself, look for free spots to park in overnight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new lakefront meters, which are scheduled to be in place by the fall, will mean that thousands of drivers will be competing for far fewer free spaces. Many commuters will spend more frustrated and stressful time on the road driving in circles in search of parking. Some will resort to paying an outrageous price to park in a garage. Others will give up driving and double or triple their commuting time by turning to public transit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For many Chicagoans, driving to work — and finding free or affordable parking after work — is a necessity, not a luxury. Contrary to the inclinations of Mayor Richard M. Daley and the city, it is not a vice that ought to be subject to endless taxation and fees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By significantly reducing the availability of free parking in lakefront neighborhoods without creating affordable alternatives for commuters, the new meters will make much of the city more expensive and inconvenient for everyone, including working families. They may boost the city&amp;rsquo;s revenue, but they will do so at the direct expense of the well-being and quality of life of thousands of its residents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Ryan McCarl is a freelance writer.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on certainty, racism, and foreign policy</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Today&amp;rsquo;s Maroon &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;column&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Certainty is a luxury none of us has.&amp;rdquo;  Religious fundamentalists and secular fundamentalists are all-too-alike in their belief that they, and only they, have answers to the biggest questions in the human dialogue.  What unites us all is doubt and searching.  Read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Must-read: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/10/16/principal-of-citys-arabic-school-says-she-was-forced-out/index.html?ex=1350273600&amp;amp;en=5fc98d5704a026df&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;Principal of Arabic School Says She was Forced Out&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  This is what racist, nativist hysteria looks like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-From an Economist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/displayStory.cfm?story_id=9973918&amp;amp;fsrc=RSS&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the new Fox Business Channel: &lt;em&gt;Mr Murdoch apparently wants his channel to be more “pro-capitalism” than CNBC—which is hardly a pinko outfit—and, sure enough, there was soon a discussion about the pharmaceutical industry entitled &amp;ldquo;Capitalism cures cancer&amp;rdquo;, which—let’s be “fair and balanced”, as the Fox News slogan puts it—it does&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-MIT international relations scholar Barry Posen on &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the-american-interest.com/ai2/article.cfm?Id=331&amp;amp;MId=16&#34;&gt;the case for restraint&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in U.S. foreign policy.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t read this yet, but I generally like what Posen has to say.  Responses from Francis Fukuyama, Stephen Krasner, G. John Ikenberry, and others are also online.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quotes on education and business</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-on-education-and-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 21:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-on-education-and-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After all, I got into teaching for the same reason, I suspect, that many people did: because I thought it was a high-stakes affair, a pursuit in which souls are won and lost.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the ways we&amp;rsquo;ve tried to be attractive is by loosening up.  We grade much more genially than our colleagues in the sciences.  In English and history, we don&amp;rsquo;t give many D&amp;rsquo;s, or C&amp;rsquo;s, either.  (The rigors of Chem 101 may create almost as many humanities majors per year as the splendors of Shakespeare.)  A professor at Stanford explained that grades were getting better because the students were getting smarter every year.  Anything, I suppose, is possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I read the reviews, I thought of a story I&amp;rsquo;d heard about a Columbia University instructor who issued a two-part question at the end of his literature course.  Part one: What book in the course did you most dislike?  Part two: What flaws of intellect or character does that dislike point up in you?  The hand that framed those questions may have been slightly heavy.  But at least they compelled the students to see intellectual work as a confrontation between two people, reader and author, where the stakes mattered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Mark Edmundson, &lt;em&gt;Why Read?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best businessperson in the world can&amp;rsquo;t sell something the world isn&amp;rsquo;t ready to use.  People don&amp;rsquo;t buy inventions.  They don&amp;rsquo;t buy technology.  They buy a solution to a perceived problem.  And if you have the greatest solution in the world and people don&amp;rsquo;t perceive it as the solution to their problem, they are not going to buy it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Dean Kamen, in Kurtzman, ed., &lt;em&gt;MBA in a Box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[Lord] Acton&amp;rsquo;s learning and culture, like his ideas, were neither casually acquired nor casually expended.  The languages he assimilated from his multilingual, multinational family were deliberately refined by years of careful study, and were cultivated as scholarly tools rather than as social graces.  It was this seriousness and dedication of purpose that characterized the whole of his life, that made of his library not the cultured gentleman&amp;rsquo;s lounge but the crowded workshop of the professional historian.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Gertrude Himmelfarb, &lt;em&gt;Lord Acton: A Study in Conscience and Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
