<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 16:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/art/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New short fiction: &#39;The Day-Trader&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Day-Trader,&amp;rdquo; my most recent short story, is being featured in the July issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/06/the-day-trader/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a lot of great stuff in this issue - fiction, poetry, a short film, visual art, a music album, and an essay - so be sure to check out the other pieces as well.  If you like what you see, you can support &lt;em&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/em&gt; by linking to it, passing it along to others, and making a &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/donations/&#34;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, Shaman Drum</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/farewell-shaman-drum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/farewell-shaman-drum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SkqxpFXuMQI/AAAAAAAAAxo/uwJXw33jMRY/s1600-h/shamandrum2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 281px; height: 320px;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SkqxpFXuMQI/AAAAAAAAAxo/uwJXw33jMRY/s320/shamandrum2.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5353286426457682178&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Skqxo9_23jI/AAAAAAAAAxg/sbGLdZWUa-8/s1600-h/shamandrum.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 213px; height: 320px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Skqxo9_23jI/AAAAAAAAAxg/sbGLdZWUa-8/s320/shamandrum.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5353286424478539314&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shamandrum.com/bookshop/&#34;&gt;Shaman Drum&lt;/a&gt; of Ann Arbor, MI, one of the best independent bookstores in the Midwest, permanently shut its doors today.  It is a major loss for Ann Arbor and for book-lovers everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Independent and used bookstores need your support.  Shop at them.  Go to their events.  Buy their gift certificates as holiday gifts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Independent bookstores must fight back against the challenging economic environment by doing everything they can to improve their businesses.  Here are a few ideas:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Keep a constant flow of new inventory, and mark down unsaleable material to maintain a high-quality bibliography;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Follow the lead of chain bookstores in taking full advantage of the &amp;ldquo;retail calendar&amp;rdquo; of holidays through decorations and displays of recommended holiday-related books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Create a pleasant, shoppable atmosphere.  I personally look for classical music and places to sit while I look over a pile of books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Stock or display local art and photography as well as books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Stock books and periodicals for book-lovers, especially the stuff that is harder to find at chain stores.  Out-of-print titles that remain relevant; major and local literary journals and serious newspapers; complete backlists of major, second-tier, and local literary writers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Sell coffee from a pot for $1 a cup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Become an integral part of your community by hosting frequent author events and becoming a local arts hub.  Create a space for gatherings such as writers&amp;rsquo; groups and reading groups.  Stock the newspapers and arts magazines of local high schools and colleges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can keep track of the independent book business by reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indiebound.org/&#34;&gt;Indiebound&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://shelf-awareness.com/&#34;&gt;Shelf Awareness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great lines from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to think - seriously - with words like Classicism, Romanticism, Humanism, Realism. &amp;hellip;One does not get drunk nor does one quench one&amp;rsquo;s thirst with bottle labels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Paul Valery, quoted in C. Milosz, &lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beauty is momentary in the mind -&lt;br /&gt;The fitful tracing of a portal;&lt;br /&gt;But in the flesh it is immortal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Peter Quince at the Clavier&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At no moment during my work did I feel boredom; indeed, I was playing more than toiling, and several passages preserve, I hope, a trace of my smile.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright, green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, in the isolation of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;At evening, casual flocks of pigeons make&lt;br /&gt;Ambiguous undulations as they sink,&lt;br /&gt;Downward to darkness, on extended wings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I got away with half my heart - no more.&lt;br /&gt;Barely a trace of my old gaiety.&lt;br /&gt;The crowd like market cattle bore&lt;br /&gt;Me along. The world was loathsome to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyprian Norwid&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Nerves&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With nothing can one approach a work of art so little as with critical words: they always come down to more or less happy misunderstandings.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This above all - ask yourself in the stillest hour of the night: &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; I write? Delve into yourself for a deep answer. And if this should be affirmative, if you may meet this question with a strong and simple &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I must&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; then build your life according to this necessity; your life even into its most indifferent and slightest hour must be a sign of this urge and a testimony to it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Therefore save yourself from these general themes and seek those which your own everyday life offers you; describe your sorrows and desires, passing thoughts and the belief in some sort of beauty - describe all these with loving, quiet, humble sincerity, and use, to express yourself, the things in your environment, the images from your dreams, and the objects of your memory. If your daily life seems poor, do not blame it; blame yourself, tell yourself that you are not poet enough to call forth its riches; for to the creator there is no poverty and no poor indifferent place. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A work of art is good if it has sprung from necessity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Live a while in these books, learn from them what seems to you worth learning, but above all love them. This love will be repaid you a thousand and a thousand times, and however your life may turn, - it will, I am certain of it, run through the fabric of your growth as one of the most important threads among all the threads of your experiences, disappointments and joys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Letters to a Young Poet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
