<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iraq on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/iraq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iraq on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 20:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/iraq/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the letters of Justice William O. Douglas</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discovering-the-letters-of-justice-william-o.-douglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discovering-the-letters-of-justice-william-o.-douglas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was sorting through some books in my closet yesterday, and I discovered a fantastic book which drew me away from my regular reading: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Douglas-Letters-Selections-Private-Justice/dp/0917561465&#34;&gt;The Douglas Letters: Selections from the Private Papers of William O. Douglas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Melvin I. Urkofsky.  William O. Douglas was a brilliant, contrarian Associate Justice on the Supreme Court as well as a transformative environmentalist and New Dealer who crusaded against rampant speculation and corruption in the financial industry.  His writing is insightful and often hilarious.  Here are a few samples:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsey_Clark&#34;&gt;Ramsey Clark&lt;/a&gt;, 4/28/70:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On my visit to Baghdad, I went to the University with my interpreter to see what books, if any, they had on our Constitution or Bill of Rights or Jefferson, Madison, democracy, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That library was bare on those subjects.  So when I returned, I prepared what I called the Douglas Eight Foot Shelf which I thought should be in every underdeveloped nation.  I thought then - and still think - that those ideas are more important than military missions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To Max Radin (professor at Berkeley Law School), 5/27/46:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;If you are willing, I will ask you to find me a law clerk each year&amp;hellip;.I need not only a bright chap, but also a hard-working fellow with a smell for facts as well as for law.  I do not want a hide-bound, conservative fellow.  What I want is a Max Radin - a fellow who can hold his own in these sophisticated circles and who is not going to end up as a stodgy, hide-bound lawyer.  I want the kind of fellow for whom this work would be an exhilaration, who will be going into teaching or into practice of the law for the purpose of promoting the public good.  I do not want to fill the big law offices of the country with my law clerks&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the&lt;/em&gt; Wall Street Journal, 10/16/78&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To the Editors:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Notice of my demise has been emanating from several sources recently, not least of which is your Journal.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please be advised that I am today joining the ranks of citizens known as octogenarians and I assure you that I was never in a position to be resurrected in order to achieve such standing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To Edward L.R. Elson, 12/7/77:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Concerning my funeral arrangements&amp;hellip;From my hobo days, I knew the famous songwriter Woody Guthrie who wrote a song called &amp;ldquo;This Land is Your Land, This Land is My Land.&amp;rdquo;  It reflects not a socialist dream of mine, but many of the freedoms that are explicit or implicit in the Constitution, such as the right to move from place to place to look for a job or establish a new home, and the right to move interstate without payment of a fee, as some states within the last thirty years have tried to impose.  In other words, it expresses the vagrancy issue as I have expressed it and as it has become in-grained in the law. (See my opinion in &lt;em&gt;Papachristou et al v. City of Jacksonville&lt;/em&gt;, 405 U.S. 156 [1972].)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.umich.edu/historyandtraditions/faculty/Faculty_Lists/Alpha_Faculty/Pages/PeterKWesten.aspx&#34;&gt;Peter K. Westen&lt;/a&gt; (Douglas&amp;rsquo; law clerk, now a highly-respected professor at the University of Michigan Law School), 10/1/68:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(After chewing him out for various mistakes)&lt;/em&gt;: You might think these things over, because the first case we have to dispose of when I get back is the case of P.K. Westen.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
