<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poverty on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/poverty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poverty on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/poverty/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Czeslaw Milosz&#39;s &#39;Milosz&#39;s ABC&#39;s&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s1600-h/Milosz.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s400/Milosz.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5349520508899521426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made it, but I have always tried to remember that I owe it to my lucky star, not to myself, and that right next door are entire neighborhoods of unfortunates.  I will say even more: the thought of their grueling labor and unfulfilled hope, of the gigantic prison system in which the unneeded are kept, taught me to look skeptically at (America&amp;rsquo;s) decorations - those well-kept houses amidst the suburbs&amp;rsquo; greenery.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In our deepest convictions, reaching into the very depths of our being, we deserve to live forever.  We experience our transitoriness and mortality as an act of violence perpetrated against us.  Only Paradise is authentic; the world is inauthentic, and only temporary.  That is why the story of the Fall speaks to us so emotionally, as if summoning an old truth from our slumbering memory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;People go to church because they are divided beings.  They wish, for a moment at least, to find themselves in a reality other than the one that surrounds them and claims to be the only true reality.  This daily reality is unyielding, brutal, cruel, and hard to bear.  The human &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; is soft in the center and feels every moment that its adaptation to the world is doubtful.  &amp;hellip;Participating in the Mass we once again deny a world without meaning and without mercy; we enter into a dimension where what matters are goodness, love, and forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If to participate in the Mass it were necessary to have a strong faith and a consciousness that we act in life as our religion requires us to, all the churchgoing faithful would deserve to be called hypocrites and Pharisees.  In truth, however, strong faith is a rare gift, and as for acts, the liturgy reminds us that we are all sinners.  Attending church is not, therefore, for the elect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The needs of the individual determine church attendance, and knowledge of the catechism or even familiarity with the so-called truths of the faith are not the most important matters, although they are advisable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Miloszs-ABCs-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374527954&#34;&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Amichai, Laxness, Mendelssohn, &amp; Yoder</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch how the cloud sings&lt;br /&gt;All you wanted to say or find.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Let the Coin Decide&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents&lt;br /&gt;Has not subsided in me.  My blood goes on sloshing&lt;br /&gt;Between my ribs, long after the vessel has come to rest.&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents has not subsided in me.&lt;br /&gt;Winds of long time over stones.  Earth&lt;br /&gt;Forgets the steps of those who trod her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;And the Migration of My Parents&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who will love the things that are naught and in vain?&lt;br /&gt;I, who stand in the world like water in the rain,&lt;br /&gt;I love the things that are naught and in vain.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The most wandering thing is a heart that stopped wandering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;At Right Angles: Hebrew Quatrains&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Has the horse been spoken to?&amp;rdquo; asked the old man; and as it had not yet been done, he took an ear in each hand and whispered to it, according to ancient custom, for horses understood these things:  &amp;ldquo;You carry a coffin today.  You carry a coffin today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The coffin was carried straight into the church in compliance with the minister&amp;rsquo;s request and the bells were rung.  Feeble was the sound they made, feeble their intrusion on frozen nature&amp;rsquo;s winter omnipotence, their peal reminiscent of nothing so much as the jingle of a child&amp;rsquo;s toy.  And the folk came trailing out of the drifting snow and into the church, timid in the face of death, which never seems so irrevocable as when bells of such a kind tinkle so helplessly in the cold, white spaces of declining day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Halldor Laxness&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day of our life together&lt;br /&gt;Ecclesiastes erases a verse of his book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Six Poems For Tamar&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do I think he would be &amp;lsquo;saved&amp;rsquo;?  I fancy that whosoever leads men to virtue in this life cannot be damned in the next.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moses Mendelssohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Reply to Johann Kaspar Lavater,&amp;rdquo; 1769.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before the invention of the machine, the only wealth of a people was constituted by the soil and the flocks.  This is what today would be called capital.  Evidently Jesus accepted voluntary poverty for the sake of the kingdom and he ordered his disciples to practice the jubilary redistribution of their capital: &amp;ldquo;all of these things, it is the Gentiles of the world who seek them.  Your Father knows that you need them.  Seek rather the kingdom of God and all these things will be added to you.  Do not fear, little flock, because your Father has chosen to give you the kingdom; sell all that you have and give it as alms&amp;rdquo; (Luke 12:30-33).  No one doubts that he said this.  All that has been debated is whether this redistribution of capital was commanded by Jesus for all Christians at all times and in all places or whether it was just a &amp;ldquo;counsel of perfection&amp;rdquo; directed to the saints.  Traditionally the Church has chosen the second solution, the easy one.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Comparing one day the generosity of the wealthy, who ostentatiously were throwing large offerings in the temple treasury, with that of the poor widow, Jesus exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;This poor widow has put in more than all of them.  They put in from their overflow but she from her poverty has given all that she had to live!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In modern language we can translate: &amp;ldquo;The quantity of money that one gives is of little importance.  What is important is what one gives.   If it only is a part of one&amp;rsquo;s income, then this is not yet righteousness, goodness, and good faith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Howard Yoder&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Politics of Jesus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell and Knut Hamsun</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-and-knut-hamsun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-and-knut-hamsun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I lie in my own bed,&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;He whispers, &amp;ldquo;dreaming&amp;rdquo;; and he thinks to wake.&lt;br /&gt;The old mistake.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;A Field Hospital&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We read our mail and counted up our missions-&lt;br /&gt;In bombers named for girls, we burned&lt;br /&gt;The cities we had learned about in school-&lt;br /&gt;Till our lives wore out; our bodies lay among&lt;br /&gt;The people we had killed and never seen.&lt;br /&gt;When we lasted long enough they gave us medals;&lt;br /&gt;When we died they said, &amp;ldquo;Our casualties were low.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;They said, &amp;ldquo;Here are the maps&amp;rdquo;; we burned the cities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;Losses&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A machine-gun away&lt;br /&gt;Are men with our faces.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;Jews at Haifa&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here too, though death is hushed, though joy&lt;br /&gt;Obscures, like night, their wars,&lt;br /&gt;The beings of this world are swept&lt;br /&gt;By the Strife that moves the stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;The Breath of Night&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Note: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randall_Jarrell&#34;&gt;Jarrell&lt;/a&gt; was an American control tower operator during World War II.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The letter shot through me like a stream of light, and I heard myself give a little cry, a meaningless sound of joy: the letter was from the editor, my piece was accepted, being set in type immediately!  &amp;ldquo;A few minor changes&amp;hellip;a couple of typographical errors corrected&amp;hellip;shows real ability&amp;hellip;will appear tomorrow&amp;hellip;ten kroner.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I laughed and cried, leaped in the air and ran down the street, stopped and beat my legs, swore wholesale at no one about nothing.  And time went by.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For a few minutes I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a single sad thought.  I forgot my troubles and felt peaceful looking at the harbor that lay serene and lovely in the dusk.  I had the habit of cheering myself up by reading through the article I had just written, which always seemed to my afflicted brain the very best piece I had done.  I pulled my my manuscript out of my pocket, held it up close to my eyes, and read through one page after the other.  Finally I grew tired and put the papers in my pocket.  Everything was still; the sea stretched away like bluish mother-of-pearl, and small birds flew silently past me, going from one place to another.  A policeman walked up and down a little way off.  Otherwise, not a person could be seen, and the entire harbor was silent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Hunger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from the week&#39;s reading, part 1</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;How It Should Be in Heaven&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How it should be in Heaven I know, for I was there.&lt;br /&gt;By its river.  Listening to its birds.&lt;br /&gt;In its season: in summer, shortly after sunrise.&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;Peace eternal&lt;br /&gt;Could have no mornings and no evenings,&lt;br /&gt;Such a deficiency speaks against it.&lt;br /&gt;And that’s too hard a nut for a theologian to crack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A business that makes nothing but money is a poor kind of business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Joel Kurtzman, &lt;em&gt;MBA in a Box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is every reason to help the poor man who happens to be a farmer, not because he is a farmer but because he is poor.  The program, that is, should be designed to help people as people, not as members of particular occupational groups, age groups, wage-rate groups, labor organizations, or industries.  … The arrangement that recommends itself on purely mechanical grounds is a negative income tax…. The advantages of this arrangement are clear.  It is directed specifically at  the problem of poverty.  It gives help in the form most useful to the individual, namely, cash.  It is general and could be substituted for the host of special measures now in effect.  It makes explicit the cost borne by society.  Like any other measures to alleviate poverty, it reduces the incentives of those helped to help themselves, but it does not eliminate that incentive entirely, as a system of supplementing incomes up to some fixed minimum would.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Milton Friedman, &lt;em&gt;Capitalism and Freedom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Yet The Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And yet the books will be there on the shelves, separate beings,&lt;br /&gt;That appeared once, still wet&lt;br /&gt;As shining chestnuts under a tree in autumn,&lt;br /&gt;And, touched, coddled, began to live&lt;br /&gt;In spite of fires on the horizon, castles blown up,&lt;br /&gt;Tribes on the march, planets in motion.&lt;br /&gt;“We are,” they said, even as their pages&lt;br /&gt;Were being torn out, or a buzzing flame&lt;br /&gt;Licked away their letters.  So much more durable&lt;br /&gt;Than we are, whose frail warmth&lt;br /&gt;Cools down with memory, disperses, perishes.&lt;br /&gt;I imagine the earth when I am no more:&lt;br /&gt;Nothing happens, no loss, it’s still a strange pageant,&lt;br /&gt;Women’s dresses, dewy lilacs, a song in the valley.&lt;br /&gt;Yet the books will be there on the shelves, well born,&lt;br /&gt;Derived from people, but also from radiance, heights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Relics of the Past&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dust raised by the royal cavalry has long since settled.&lt;br /&gt;One by one, poets and historians, the standard-bearers of culture,&lt;br /&gt;have gone silently to their graves.  Of what use is the purple&lt;br /&gt;and fine linen now, the baubles that women love?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Akhtarul Iman, tr. R. Parthsarathy&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
