<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy of Law on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/philosophy-of-law/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy of Law on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 13:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/philosophy-of-law/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hugo Black and Lon L. Fuller</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hugo-black-and-lon-l.-fuller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hugo-black-and-lon-l.-fuller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every departure from the principles of the law&amp;rsquo;s inner morality is an affront to man&amp;rsquo;s dignity as a responsible agent.  To judge his actions by unpublished or retrospective laws, or to order him to do an act that is impossible, is to convey to him your indifference to his powers of self-determination.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I believe that if we were forced to select the principle that supports and infuses all human aspiration we would find it in the objective of maintaining communication with our fellows.  &amp;hellip;How and when we accomplish communication with one another can expand or contract the boundaries of life itself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lon_L._Fuller&#34;&gt;Lon L. Fuller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Morality of Law&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Court&amp;rsquo;s justification for consulting its own notions rather than following the original meaning of the Constitution, as I would, apparently is based on the belief of the majority of the Court that for this Court to be bound by the original meaning of the Constitution is an intolerable and debilitating evil; that our Constitution should not be &amp;ldquo;shackled to the political theory of a particular era,&amp;rdquo; and that to save the country from the original Constitution the Court must have constant power to renew it and keep it abreast of this Court&amp;rsquo;s more enlightened theories of what is best for our society. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It seems to me that this is an attack not only on the great value of our Constitution itself but also on the concept of a written constitution which is to survive through the years as originally written unless changed through the amendment process which the Framers wisely provided. Moreover, when a &amp;ldquo;political theory&amp;rdquo; embodied in our Constitution becomes outdated, it seems to me that a majority of the nine members of this Court are not only without constitutional power but are far less qualified to choose a new constitutional political theory than the people of this country proceeding in the manner provided by Article V.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Hugo Black&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Harper v. Virginia State Board of Education&lt;/em&gt; (dissent); 383 U.S. 663 (1966)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No one may be compelled against his conscience to render war service involving the use of arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Basic Law for the Federal Republic of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Article IV&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I cannot consider the Bill of Rights to be an outworn 18th Century &amp;lsquo;strait jacket&amp;rsquo; as the Twining opinion did. Its provisions may be thought outdated abstractions by some. And it is true that they were designed to meet ancient evils. But they are the same kind of human evils that have emerged from century to century wherever excessive power is sought by the few at the expense of the many. In my judgment the people of no nation can lose their liberty so long as a Bill of Rights like ours survives and its basic purposes are conscientiously interpreted, enforced and respected so as to afford continuous protection against old, as well as new, devices and practices which might thwart those purposes. I fear to see the consequences of the Court&amp;rsquo;s practice of substituting its own concepts of decency and fundamental justice for the language of the Bill of Rights as its point of departure in interpreting and enforcing that Bill of Rights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Hugo Black&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Adamson v. California&lt;/em&gt; (dissent); 332 U.S. 46 (1946) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All excerpts from Lloyd,&lt;/em&gt; Introduction to Jurisprudence (4th ed., 1979).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A vacation and a reading list: a personal update</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-vacation-and-a-reading-list-a-personal-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-vacation-and-a-reading-list-a-personal-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe how quickly things happen.  My summer term - roughly six hours a day, five days a week of education classes - is drawing to a close, and as of Friday afternoon I&amp;rsquo;ll be free for an entire month (the life of a student is good - certainly beats two or three weeks of vacation over the course of a year).  I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Colorado (Boulder, Telluride, Denver) for almost two weeks, in Chicago for one, and in Muskegon for one - as well as a few days of camping in Northern Michigan with friends.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Whenever I prepare to travel, my thoughts quickly turn to the question of what books I will bring along and read.  I always make absurdly ambitious reading lists and pack way, way more than I could ever hope to finish, and this time is no exception.  I am bringing four:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Secular-Age-Charles-Taylor/dp/0674026764&#34;&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  About the rise of secularism in Western society.  Considered one of the most important books in the field of religious studies in recent decades.  Weighs in at a hefty 776 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/John-Cheever-Collected-Stories-Writings/dp/1598530348/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1248827741&amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;Collected Stories and Other Writings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Cheever is one of the best short fiction writers of the 20th century.  969 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Auerbach, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mimesis-Representation-Reality-Western-Literature/dp/069111336X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1248826434&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Mimesis: The Representation of Reality in Western Literature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Publishers Weekly&lt;/em&gt; says: &amp;ldquo;The author, beginning with Homer and the Bible, traces the imitation of life in literature through the ages &amp;hellip;touching upon every major literary figure in western culture on the way.&amp;rdquo;  A key work in 20th-century literary criticism.  574 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dennis Lord Lloyd of Hampstead, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/work/3078393/details&#34;&gt;Introduction to Jurisprudence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  A vast, out-of-print, fantastically rich collection of writings on the philosophy of law and political philosophy - a mangled old book I believe I picked up for free in the box outside of the Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books in Hyde Park, Chicago.  981 pages (but I&amp;rsquo;ll skip writings that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to read for whatever reason).  From the &lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/obituary-lord-lloyd-of-hampstead-1477249.html&#34;&gt;obituary&lt;/a&gt; of Lloyd: &amp;ldquo;As important to generations of students has been his encyclopaedic Introduction to Jurisprudence (1959). Lloyd was working on the sixth edition when he died. It was through this book that law students in much of the English- speaking world came to read Kelsen, Olivecrona, Savigny, Geny, Pashukanis, giants of continental juristic thought otherwise largely inaccessible. The recipe of wise text and suitably chosen extract remains a model guide to the study of legal thought. To the text he brought his own philosophical training, his culture and his erudition. The Introduction has its detractors but it remains the standard student text on the subject.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Will I succeed in finishing all of these, or any of them?  Most likely not.  If history is any guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll buy some other book or books during vacation and distract myself with those, or I&amp;rsquo;ll get heavily involved with my writing, almost as a way of avoiding my reading with a good conscience.  But if I restrict my book-reading to these four tomes and read around 118 pages a day for 27 days, I could do it - so that&amp;rsquo;s the bar I&amp;rsquo;m setting for myself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait.  Two more days of finishing my summer projects, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be free to travel, read, and write without restrictions for an entire month.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
