<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Herman Melville on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/herman-melville/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Herman Melville on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 18:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/herman-melville/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Should we finish the books we begin?  It depends.</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/should-we-finish-the-books-we-begin--it-depends./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/should-we-finish-the-books-we-begin--it-depends./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2009/jul/24/edge-closing-the-book-on-a-bad-read/?page=2&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; published in Friday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Washington Times&lt;/em&gt;, economist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marginalrevolution.com/&#34;&gt;Tyler Cowen&lt;/a&gt; makes several interesting and provocative arguments about reading and books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  &amp;ldquo;What should you do when, 20, 50 or 100 pages in, you realize you just don&amp;rsquo;t like a book?&amp;rdquo;  Cowen says: &amp;ldquo;Give up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  &amp;ldquo;We should treat books a little more like we treat TV channels,&amp;rdquo; (Cowen) argues. No one has trouble flipping away from a boring series.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  &amp;ldquo;(Cowen) notes that many up-and-coming writers complain they can&amp;rsquo;t break through in a best-seller-driven marketplace. &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;re also making markets more efficient,&amp;rdquo; Mr. Cowen says. &amp;ldquo;If you can sample more books, you&amp;rsquo;re giving more people a chance.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The article goes on to discuss several other readers who advocate quitting &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo; books: &amp;ldquo;One of her online friends reminded her there&amp;rsquo;s even an abandonment rule: The &amp;lsquo;Deduct Your Age From 100 and Read That Many Pages Before Giving Up on a Book&amp;rsquo; rule&amp;rdquo;; and &amp;ldquo;Having an e-book reader has made Ms. Wendell more ruthless. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m holding 100+ books on one device. If one isn&amp;rsquo;t floating my boat, I can move on to something else by pressing one button,&amp;rdquo; she points out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So should we finish the books we begin?  The short answer: it depends.  On what?  That&amp;rsquo;s more difficult, but it depends on something more than how much we are &lt;em&gt;enjoying&lt;/em&gt; the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why did you pick up the book in the first place?  If you are reading for pure entertainment, it makes sense to put the book down if you aren&amp;rsquo;t feeling entertained after giving the book a fair shot.  But surely most readers read for more than pure entertainment; if &amp;ldquo;entertainment&amp;rdquo; were the ultimate goal, there would be no reason to prefer an entertaining book over an equally or more entertaining movie, television show, or video game.  In fact, I suspect that the widespread idea that books are primarily sources of entertainment is partially responsible for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nea.gov/news/news04/ReadingAtRisk.Html&#34;&gt;decline of book-reading&lt;/a&gt;, especially among young people, in recent decades.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I choose and read books that are rewarding and that will enrich my understanding of the world, of myself, and of the human condition.  If they are entertaining or exciting at the same time, so much the better, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t the primary goal.  In fact, my idea of what is &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo; has shifted.  I have conditioned myself to prefer forms of leisure - i.e., reading good books, practicing banjo and listening to music, engaging in good conversation, watching good movies - that are rewarding and educative.  So even if I am reading a book that I must struggle to get through, that to me is often more entertaining than reading, say, &lt;em&gt;Angels and Demons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are, in short, problems with considering a book&amp;rsquo;s excitement and ease the most important factors in deciding whether to read it or finish it.  We build our literacy and expand our understanding by reading material that challenges us, just as a musician continually improves his or her proficiency in an instrument not by playing the same basic tunes over and over, but by constantly pushing his or her limits by tackling new, more frustrating and difficult works and techniques.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have as much trouble as anyone with finishing books, but some books are worth finishing regardless of whether I feel like finishing them.  The other week, I completed &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; after a slow, gradual, four-month effort.  &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; would certainly fail the &amp;ldquo;entertainment&amp;rdquo; test for the vast majority of readers, including me.  And yet it is now one of my favorite books, because Melville&amp;rsquo;s incredible use of language and his insights into religion, human nature, and life itself made &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; matter to me: I read it in the hope that it might change the way I write, think, and see the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck writes in &lt;em&gt;East of Eden&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You can start reading if you want and it will raise up your lid a little.&amp;rdquo;  That&amp;rsquo;s as good a statement as any of what good books are for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Hat tip for the link to the Washington Times article: &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/&#34;&gt;Andrew Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell, Herman Melville, and John D. Caputo</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Next Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wisdom, said William James,&lt;br /&gt;Is learning what to overlook.  And I am wise&lt;br /&gt;If that is wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;Yet somehow, as I buy All from these shelves&lt;br /&gt;And the boy takes it to my station wagon,&lt;br /&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve become&lt;br /&gt;Troubles me even if I shut my eyes.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Imaginings within my imagining,&lt;br /&gt;I too have taken&lt;br /&gt;The chance of life.  Now the boy pats my dog&lt;br /&gt;And we start home.  Now I am good.&lt;br /&gt;The last mistaken,&lt;br /&gt;Ecstatic, accidental bliss, the blind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness that, bursting, leaves upon the palm&lt;br /&gt;Some soap and water -&lt;br /&gt;It was so long ago&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The overt Godlessness of our world is a latent Godliness.  To an eye keen for things theological, religion is most present where it is least visible.  That &amp;ldquo;secularism&amp;rdquo; blinds us to the theological order everywhere implicit in the secular order is the &amp;ldquo;central&amp;rdquo; player in (Mark C.) Taylor&amp;rsquo;s dialectic.  &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; is full of illuminating narratives generated by this hypothesis, the central story being how much &amp;ldquo;modernity&amp;rdquo; goes back to the Reformation: Luther&amp;rsquo;s assertion of subjectivity, his rejection of tradition in favor of personal experience, his media-savvy insistence on the vernacular and use of the printing press&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John D. Caputo&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;Review of Mark C. Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Academy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; 77:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look not too long in the face of the fire, O man! Never dream with thy hand on the helm! Turn not thy back to the compass; accept the first hint of the hitching tiller; believe not the artificial fire, when its redness makes all things look ghastly. To-morrow, in the natural sun, the skies will be bright; those who glared like devils in the forking flames, the morn will show in far other, at least gentler, relief; the glorious, golden, glad sun, the only true lamp - all others but liars!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless the sun hides not Virginia&amp;rsquo;s Dismal Swamp, nor Rome&amp;rsquo;s accursed Campagna, nor wide Sahara, nor all the millions of miles of deserts and of griefs beneath the moon. The sun hides not the ocean, which is the dark side of this earth, and which is two thirds of this earth. So, therefore, that mortal man who hath more of joy than sorrow in him, that mortal man cannot be true - not true, or undeveloped. With books the same. The truest of all men was the Man of Sorrows, and the truest of all books is Solomon&amp;rsquo;s, and Ecclesiastes is the fine hammered steel of woe. &amp;ldquo;All is vanity.&amp;rdquo; ALL.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There is a wisdom that is woe; but there is a woe that is madness. And there is a Catskill eagle in some souls that can alike dive down into the blackest gorges, and soar out of them again and become invisible in the sunny spaces. And even if he for ever flies within the gorge, that gorge is in the mountains; so that even in his lowest swoop the mountain eagle is still higher than other birds upon the plain, even though they soar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Herman Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;90 North&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I see at last that all the knowledge&lt;br /&gt;I wrung from the darkness - that the darkness flung me -&lt;br /&gt;Is worthless as ignorance: nothing comes from nothing,&lt;br /&gt;The darkness from the darkness.  Pain comes from the darkness&lt;br /&gt;And we call it wisdom.  It is pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But how? Genius in the Sperm Whale? Has the Sperm Whale ever written a book, spoken a speech? No, his great genius is declared in his doing nothing particular to prove it. It is moreover declared in his pyramidical silence. &amp;hellip;If hereafter any highly cultured, poetical nation shall lure back to their birth-right, the merry May-day gods of old; and livingly enthrone them again in the now egotistical sky; in the now unhaunted hill; then be sure, exalted to Jove&amp;rsquo;s high seat, the great Sperm Whale shall lord it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It was a terrific, most pitiable, and maddening sight. The whale was now going head out, and sending his spout before him in a continual tormented jet; while his one poor fin beat his side in an agony of fright. Now to this hand, now to that, he yawed in his faltering flight, and still at every billow that he broke, he spasmodically sank in the sea, or sideways rolled towards the sky his one beating fin. So have I seen a bird with clipped wing, making affrighted broken circles in the air, vainly striving to escape the piratical hawks. But the bird has a voice, and with plaintive cries will make known her fear; but the fear of this vast dumb brute of the sea, was chained up and enchanted in him; he had no voice, save that choking respiration through his spiracle, and this made the sight of him unspeakably pitiable; while still, in his amazing bulk, portcullis jaw, and omnipotent tail, there was enough to appal the stoutest man who so pitied.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seems it credible that by three such thin threads the great Leviathan was suspended like the big weight to an eight day clock.  Suspended? and to what?  To three bits of board.  Is this the creature of whom it was once so triumphantly said - &amp;lsquo;Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish-spears? The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold, the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon: he esteemeth iron as straw; the arrow cannot make him flee; darts are counted as stubble; he laugheth at the shaking of a spear!&amp;rsquo;  This the creature? this he?  Oh! that unfulfillments should follow the prophets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As strange misgrown masses gather in the knot-holes of the noblest oaks when prostrate, so from the points which the whale&amp;rsquo;s eyes had once occupied, now protruded blind bulbs, horribly pitiable to see.  But pity there was none.  For all his old age, and his one arm, and his blind eyes, he must die the death and be murdered, in order to light the gay bridals and other merry-makings of men, and also to illuminate the solemn churches that preach unconditional inoffensiveness by all to all.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For young whales, in the highest health, and swelling with noble aspirations, prematurely cut off in the warm flush and May of life, with all their panting lard about them; even these brawny, buoyant heroes do sometimes sink.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SevlYahAQRI/AAAAAAAAAuo/nBhOE7jOm-A/s1600-h/moby-dick.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 300px; height: 400px;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SevlYahAQRI/AAAAAAAAAuo/nBhOE7jOm-A/s400/moby-dick.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5326603191893115154&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Let the most absent-minded of men be plunged in his deepest reveries - stand that man on his legs, set his feet a-going, and he will infallibly lead you to water, if water there be in all that region.  &amp;hellip;Yes, as every one knows, meditation and water are wedded for ever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;What of it, if some old hunks of a sea-captain orders me to get a broom and sweep down the decks?  What does that indignity amount to, weighed, I mean, in the scales of the New Testament?  Do you think the archangel Gabriel thinks anything the less of me, because I promptly and respectfully obey that old hunks in that particular instance?  Who aint a slave?  Tell me that.  Well, then, however the old sea-captains may order me about - however they may thump and punch me about, I have the satisfaction of knowing that it is all right; that everybody else is one way or other served in much the same way - either in a physical or metaphysical point of view, that is; and so the universal thump is passed around, and all hands should rub each other&amp;rsquo;s shoulder-blades, and be content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;As for me, I am tormented with an everlasting itch for things remote.  I love to sail forbidden seas, and land on barbarous coasts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Each silent worshipper seemed purposely sitting apart from the other, as if each silent grief were insular and incommunicable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;But Faith, like a jackal, feeds among the tombs, and even from those dead doubts she gathers her most vital hope.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I began to be sensible of strange feelings.  I felt a melting in me.  No more my splintered heart and maddened hand were turned against the wolfish world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;One most perilous and long voyage ended, only begins a second; and a second ended, only begins a third, and so on, for ever and for aye.  Such is the endlessness, yea, the intolerableness of all earthly effort.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Now then, thou not only wantest to go a-whaling, to find out by experience what whaling is, buy ye also want to go in order to see the world?  Was not that what ye said?  I thought so.   Well then, just step forward there, and take a peep over the weather-bow, and then back to me and tell me what ye see there.&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Going forward and glancing over the weather bow, I perceived that the ship swinging to her anchor with the flood-tide, was now obliquely pointing towards the open ocean.  The prospect was unlimited, but exceedingly monotonous and forbidding; not the slightest variety that I could see.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Well, what&amp;rsquo;s the report?&amp;rsquo; said Peleg when I came back; &amp;lsquo;what did ye see?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Not much,&amp;rsquo; I replied - &amp;lsquo;nothing but water; considerable horizon though, and there&amp;rsquo;s a squall coming up, I think.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Well, what dost thou think then of seeing the world?  Do ye wish to go round Cape Horn to see any more of it, eh?  Can&amp;rsquo;t ye see the world where you stand?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Herman Melville&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
