<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 05:49:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/personal/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a language-learning program (high-frequency sentence identifier)</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/2015/10/09/developing-a-language-learning-program-high-frequency-sentence-identifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 05:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/2015/10/09/developing-a-language-learning-program-high-frequency-sentence-identifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I devoted most of my nights and weekends this year to building the program described below with the help of Kostyantyn Grinchenko, an excellent Ukrainian freelance developer. Then, after realizing that we had stumbled upon a breakthrough idea that could revolutionize language learning and help many people become fluent readers of their target language, I assembled a remote team of freelance and volunteer developers, designers, native-speaker audio recorders, and translators to help me develop it into a webapp (and future mobile app): &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordBrewery.com&lt;/a&gt;. Please help WordBrewery grow by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;trying it out&lt;/a&gt;, joining our &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbrewery.us12.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=de5def825a669f96078a614d4&amp;amp;id=ccf98da72c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email list&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://feeds.feedburner.com/LanguageUntapped&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;subscribing&lt;/a&gt; to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, following us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/WordBrewery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WordBrewery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or taking a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1VLYcHdI5-FLlr5hMRJ1DzhLKDUzfkPvyI8Bx3bvvk3w/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;beta tester survey&lt;/a&gt;. Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:admin@wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in supporting the WordBrewery project as a donor, investor, advocate, or volunteer. Thank you for your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past two months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with outsourcing small personal digital projects to overseas freelancers on Upwork. The experience has been very positive so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to devote a post to each of the tasks I outsource to give readers a sense of how freelancers and virtual assistants can both make one&amp;rsquo;s life easier in various ways and enable one to pursue projects and ideas despite lacking the time, expertise, or patience to implement them without outside help and delegation. I find Upwork and similar programs to be fascinating&amp;ndash;a fantastic, unambiguously positive example of open markets and the division of labor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in finding efficient ways to learn things, especially languages. Language vocabulary is an example of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pareto Principle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (also known as the &amp;ldquo;80-20 rule&amp;rdquo;), according to which, &amp;ldquo;for many events, roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes.&amp;rdquo; In the context of language learning, the rule fits the fact that the most common 1,000 words or so in a language account for about 90% of spoken speech in that language. Thus, the best way to quickly develop one&amp;rsquo;s practical vocabulary in a second language is to focus on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://fluent-forever.com/the-method/vocabulary/#.VhdQRBNViko&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;core vocabulary list&lt;/a&gt; of high-frequency words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This insight, however, most be paired with another well-established principle of literacy and language learning: it is far better to learn vocabulary by studying it in context rather than in the form of isolated words in a list or on flash cards. Accordingly, language learners should study sentences, not words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thus came up with the idea for a language learning tool that identifies sentences with numerous high-frequency words: such sentences are especially valuable for language learners. But I could not find any program or tool that does this seemingly straightforward task. I know some basic computer programming, but for the near future I will lack the time and expertise to create such a tool from scratch myself. So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to partially &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.upwork.com/jobs/~0160ccc97b753712cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;outsource it&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found several overseas programmers who appear to be very capable of creating the program as I envision it. Here is the job as posted on Upwork:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_Language learning tool: High-frequency sentence identifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose: allow language learners to identify and collect sentences that are particularly valuable to study and memorize because they use several high-frequency words and do not include any obscure words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested mode of operation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-For each language, the program would draw upon data from at least two sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) a spreadsheet (CSV) or other easily manipulable data storage mechanism in which the 10,000 or 20,000 most column words of a language are pasted. In column one, assign the word a frequency score: the higher the frequency, the higher the score. So, for example, if the list has 500 words, the least common (most obscure) word in that list could be assigned a score of &amp;ldquo;1,&amp;rdquo; and the most common word in the list could be assigned a score of 500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) a list or corpus of example sentences, whether scraped in real-time from Wikipedia or other websites (e.g. Project Gutenberg, Tatoeba), or manually created and made available in a text file. For example, an Anki deck of example sentences (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1715094364&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1715094364&lt;/a&gt;) can be exported into a text file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-El ministro ha informado a la nación sobre la guerra. (The prime minister has informed the nation about the war.)
-Él tragaba sus bebidas rápidamente. (He used to gulp his drinks too quickly.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would iterate over the target-language example sentences, scoring each sentence for its potential value to the language-learner. Sentences that use several high-frequency words would receive a higher score&amp;ndash;and thus be more likely to be presented to the user. Sentences that include an uncommon or obscure word that does not appear on the frequency list at all (e.g., a word that is not among the 20,000 most common words of a language) would be penalized and less likely to be presented to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would have some mechanism for avoiding or reducing repetitiveness so that it brings in diverse sentences that do not repeat the same high-frequency words over and over. Ideally, this would be flexible so it does not completely disqualify a sentence just because one of its words was already used: this would disqualify too many sentences. But the program could somehow penalize sentences that use words that have already appeared in sentences the program has selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would produce a CSV or text file of the sentences it has selected. The user should be able to instruct the program to return a certain number of sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-To avoid repetitive results in repeat uses, the program should include an element of randomness in selecting sentences for presentation to the user. Ideally, the user should be able to set the randomness level. A randomness level of 0, for example, could remove all randomness and simply return the highest-scoring sentences, while a randomness level of 100 could return a completely random set of sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical necessities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program needs to be able to handle non-English characters and words such as French/Spanish/Portuguese accented characters as well as Japanese, Chinese, Korean, and Thai. For the Asian languages, the program will also need to be able to cope with sentences that do not separate words with spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program must be able to handle sentence data formatted in varying ways from diverse sources. For example, it should use regular expressions or other tools to automatically identify the delimiters that signal where each sentence begins and ends. Whether the program is iterating over a text file exported from Anki or a messy webpage, the program should return only sentences&amp;ndash;not single words, multiple sentences, translations, HTML tags, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I would like the scoring mechanism to be flexible so I can experiment with different ways of scoring the sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-It would be a bonus if the program could somehow be used to identify sentences that use a particular grammatical pattern or construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-It would further be helpful if the search mechanism accepted close matches to words on the frequency list to account for different verb conjugations, spelling variations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I would like it if the program could, at the user&amp;rsquo;s option, show its work by: (1) showing or hiding each sentence&amp;rsquo;s frequency score in its results, and (2) returning not only sentences, but also&amp;ndash;for each sentence&amp;ndash;the high-frequency words the program found in that sentence, and those words&amp;rsquo; frequency score._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryan.mccarl@gmail.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; if you have suggestions or would like to help out with creating the program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I found helpful during the first year of law school (1L)</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/books-i-found-helpful-during-the-first-year-of-law-school-1l/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/books-i-found-helpful-during-the-first-year-of-law-school-1l/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last summer and fall, I did a bit of research to try and identify books and study aids that might be helpful during my first year of law school. &amp;nbsp;There are hundreds of products out there, and some are considerably more useful than others. &amp;nbsp;I wanted to put together a list of the books I found to be most valuable for any incoming law students (or self-educators interested in reading about law) who might be interested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(* = essential/most valuable)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;General&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;Ward Farnsworth, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0226238350?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0226238350&amp;amp;qid=1337458831&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Legal Analyst: A Toolkit for Thinking About the Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard M. Fischl and Jeremy Paul,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0226238350?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0226238350&amp;amp;qid=1337458831&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Getting to Maybe: How to Excel on Law School Exams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dennis J. Tonsing, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/083773813X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=083773813X&amp;amp;qid=1337458869&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1000 Days to the Bar but the Practice of Law Begins Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steven Emanuel, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735526745?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735526745&amp;amp;qid=1337458918&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Steve Emanuel&amp;rsquo;s First Year&amp;nbsp;Questions and Answers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Randy Barnett, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0198297297?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0198297297&amp;amp;qid=1337458933&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Structure of Liberty: Justice and the Rule of Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LexisNexis &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lexisnexis.com/lawschool/study/outlines/default.asp&#34;&gt;Area of Law Outlines&lt;/a&gt; (free)&lt;br /&gt;Black&amp;rsquo;s Law Dictionary - &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/blacks-law-dictionary-9th/id312542731?mt=8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iPhone app version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Legal Writing:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brian Garner, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0226284182?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0226284182&amp;amp;qid=1337458994&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Legal Writing in Plain English&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ross Guberman, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0195394879?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0195394879&amp;amp;qid=1337459091&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Point Made: How to Write Like the Nation&amp;rsquo;s Top Legal Advocates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Civil Procedure&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Glannon, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735570337?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735570337&amp;amp;qid=1337458969&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Civil Procedure: Examples and Explanations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Freer, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735578303?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735578303&amp;amp;qid=1337459107&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Civil Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Freer, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314199780?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314199780&amp;amp;qid=1337459107&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_2&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Law School Legends: Civil Procedure&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(audio)&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arthur R. Miller, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Substance-Audio-Procedure-Substance-Audio-Series/dp/031426180X/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1337459137&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Civil Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (audio) - out-of-date but still worthwhile&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Torts&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;William Prosser, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314748806?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314748806&amp;amp;qid=1337460333&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prosser and Keeton on Torts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Glannon, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735588740?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735588740&amp;amp;qid=1337460180&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Torts: Examples and Explanations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steven Finz,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314926968?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314926968&amp;amp;qid=1337459139&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_14&amp;amp;sr=8-14&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Torts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(audio)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contracts&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;Brian A. Blum, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/073558852X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=073558852X&amp;amp;qid=1337460344&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contracts: Examples and Explanations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Marvin Chirelstein, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1599417766?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1599417766&amp;amp;qid=1337460823&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contracts and Case Analysis in the Law of Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Epstein, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314160841?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314160841&amp;amp;qid=1337460438&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(audio)&lt;br /&gt;Randy Barnett, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0199740186?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0199740186&amp;amp;qid=1337460394&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_2&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oxford Introductions to U.S. Law: Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Criminal Law&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;Joshua Dressler, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1422429873?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1422429873&amp;amp;ref_=pd_sim_b_37&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Understanding&amp;nbsp;Criminal Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joshua Dressler, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314266917?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314266917&amp;amp;qid=1337459139&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_12&amp;amp;sr=8-12&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Criminal Law&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(audio)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Property:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John G. Sprankling, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1422498735?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1422498735&amp;amp;qid=1337460835&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Understanding Property Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Linda H. Edwards, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735549524?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393177&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735549524&amp;amp;qid=1337460673&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_sc_3&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-3-spell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Estates in Land and Future Interests: A Step-by-Step Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Julian C. Juergensmeyer, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314264922?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314264922&amp;amp;qid=1337459163&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_30&amp;amp;sr=8-30&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Property&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(audio)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Constitutional Law:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erwin Chemerinsky, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735598975?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735598975&amp;amp;ref_=pd_sim_b_31&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Constitutional Law: Principles and Policies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mary Cheh, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0314180834?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=shr&amp;amp;camp=213733&amp;amp;creative=393185&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0314180834&amp;amp;qid=1337459137&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_2&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sum and Substance: Constitutional Law&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(audio)*&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Libya War on &#39;Russia Today&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rt.com/news/sanctions-showdown-syria-libya/&#34;&gt;Russia Today&lt;/a&gt; (RT) yesterday to discuss the U.S./NATO intervention in Libya as well as the situation in Syria - feel free to check it out if you are interested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/by444eRvSSI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My related article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Rolling the Dice in Libya&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another, unrelated op-ed of mine appeared yesterday as well in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;Michigan Education Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;National standards will stifle innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  In it, I argue that &amp;ldquo;strict standards risk forcing students and teachers alike into a curricular straitjacket, alienating creative teachers and sapping the motivation of students.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find links to all of my online publications at my homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;www.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling the dice in Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Rolling the dice in Libya,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. If you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or emailing it to a friend. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rolling the dice in Libya&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Barack Obama won the Democratic nomination in 2008 partly by reminding the party’s base of his early, prescient criticisms of the ill-fated decision to invade Iraq. “What I am opposed to is a dumb war … a rash war,” then-Senator Obama explained in 2002.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama was right to call the Iraq War “dumb” and “rash”: the Bush administration’s decision to invade Iraq was based not just on an “intelligence failure,” but on flagrant hubris, ignorance of geography and history, and unawareness of the limits of American power in the 21st century. And yet the Obama administration demonstrated each of these failings  in deciding to involve the U.S. in Libya’s civil war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Much ado was made about the U.S. “handing over” the Libya mission to NATO after dominating the first stage of the operation. But NATO is best understood as a multilateral cloak for American power; the U.S. has a military far larger and more advanced than any of its NATO allies, and it is by far the largest contributor to NATO’s budget.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The U.S.-NATO mission in Libya, we are told again and again, is nothing more than a temporary “humanitarian” operation to protect civilians. Since we are still bombing away at Col. Moammar Gadhafi’s military, one would think that Gadhafi’s forces are still on the verge of massacring defenseless civilians in rebel-held cities. But then we learn of “progress” in the war: under the cover of U.S./NATO-provided air power, rebels have taken cities from Gadhafi’s forces and advanced closer to Tripoli.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apparently, “protecting civilians” means attempting to crush the Libyan government forces and turn the tide of the civil war in the rebels’ favor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Defenders of the intervention appeal to our sense of decency by warning of the “genocide” that might have occurred had events in Libya been permitted to run their course, but this is nothing more than conjecture. It is possible to defend any course of action by asserting that a worst-case scenario would have occurred had the action not been taken. However, our worst fears usually do not turn out to be accurate predictors of the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the Obama administration’s protests to the contrary, what was sold as an effort to protect Libyan civilians has quickly developed into an unstated commitment to regime-change in Libya, with all the long-term challenges, obligations, and uncertainties that entails. It has also morphed into a full embrace of the Libyan rebels, though no one is sure exactly what the rebels stand for, or whether they have a workable plan to restore stability and govern the country democratically in a post-Gadhafi era.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like Bush’s decision to invade Iraq, Obama’s decision to intervene in Libya relied upon wishful thinking about the post-intervention course of events. Bush assured us that the conflict in Iraq would be swift, decisive, and relatively painless for the U.S.; Obama assured us that the mission in Libya would not require ground troops or a sustained American commitment and that it would be over in “days, not weeks.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But as political scientist Robert Pape has shown, air power alone is rarely, if ever, sufficient to achieve a state’s aims in war. And the “days” of U.S. involvement have already become “weeks” and will soon become “months,” as they tend to do in wars—which are, after all, unpredictable and uncontrollable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Obama has joined the long line of presidents who have been blinded by U.S. power and failed to perceive the limits of that power. He is likely to fail in Libya—or pay a high price for a very limited and temporary success—because he chose to ignore the advice of the great strategist Carl von Clausewitz, who wrote: “War is the realm of chance. … Chance makes everything more uncertain and interferes with the whole course of events.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The hopes and expectations of war supporters are routinely dashed by the complexity of reality. War plans often rely on best-case scenarios and assume that the planners are gifted with such foresight and judgment that they can realistically project how events will unfold. But the human actors driving these events on the ground often respond quite unpredictably to changes in their situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prudent policymakers and citizens should expect hasty wars of choice based on rose-eyed assumptions to fail and to have unforeseen consequences that last decades. This is not the outcome we hope for in the Libya war, but it is the outcome we can most safely bet on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with the University of Chicago Magazine</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/interview-with-the-university-of-chicago-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/interview-with-the-university-of-chicago-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UChiBLOGo, the blog of the &lt;em&gt;University of Chicago Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed me about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt; and the idea of self-education today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://uchiblogo.uchicago.edu/archives/2009/08/wide_awake_mind.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and please pass the interview along to others if you enjoy reading it.  Thanks for helping to spread the word about self-education!&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent posts on education at Wide Awake Minds</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few of my recent posts at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, in case you missed them:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/few-of-things-you-can-do-in-great.html&#34;&gt;A few of the things you can do in a great university&lt;/a&gt;, in which I argue that if students want to make the most of their school years in general and their college years in particular, they must take ownership of their education and elect to do what is difficult.  I propose a few of the ways in which college students can do so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/thinking-critically-about-critical.html&#34;&gt;Thinking critically about critical pedagogy&lt;/a&gt;, in which I encourage my readers to recognize the reality and complexity of cultural and institutional racism, but also to think critically about the theoretical lenses of critical pedagogy (a framework aimed at correcting racism and other power disparities).  This post sparked a great discussion in the comment section as well as some fruitful email exchanges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/beyond-preparing-our-kids-for-21st.html&#34;&gt;Beyond &amp;ldquo;preparing our kids for 21st-century jobs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - a call to do away with sloganeering about education as job-preparation, and a brief sketch of the case for universal liberal education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/quotes-from-deborah-meiers-in-schools.html&#34;&gt;Ideas about education from Deborah Meier&lt;/a&gt;, one of the greatest progressive educators of our time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/building-collection-of-language_09.html&#34;&gt;On language learning textbooks&lt;/a&gt; - A personal account of my love of language learning textbooks, and what I have learned from them about how and why we should learn world languages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to link to it on your blog or social network or pass it along to someone who might be interested in reading it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for Facebook and social networking</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Facebook currently has over 200 million active users, many people continue to doubt the value of social networking in general and Facebook in particular.  Critics argue that Facebook and other social networking and Web 2.0 tools - including blogs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - are symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;solipsism&amp;rdquo; (meaning, in this context, the self-absorption of users) of the contemporary Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, Facebook can be an enormous time-waster and procrastination tool, as can any medium or Internet resource.  I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected a lot about my own use of the site over the past six years or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself whether it is a worthwhile use of my time and an appropriate way - one among others, obviously - to communicate with my friends, family, colleagues, and acquaintances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate was largely settled for me a few months ago when I heard a remarkable lecture by Clara Shih, social networking expert and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefacebookera.com/&#34;&gt;The Facebook Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shih spoke in April at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Booth School of Business, and I was in attendance to sell copies of her book.  (I was working as a manager at a bookstore at the time).  I went in with low expectations, as I generally take a dim view of the overcrowded genre of popular business books in general and books on making money through technology in particular.  But Shih&amp;rsquo;s presentation blew me away; she made me see Facebook and social networking in an entirely different light, and she helped me understand the many complex issues involved with social networking, and the utility social networking tools can have for those willing to critically evaluate and monitor their use of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The core reason for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s popularity, according to Shih, is that it lowers the cost of keeping in touch.  Keeping in touch with people you&amp;rsquo;ve met is a difficult and time-consuming process.  Facebook makes it much, much easier.  And it can help us keep in touch in a more meaningful way: there is less need to small talk with distant friends about where they are working, what they are studying, where they are living, and so forth - it&amp;rsquo;s all out there on their Facebook page, and so we can keep track of people we&amp;rsquo;ve met as they move through their lives.  When we think of them, we can think of who they are and what they are doing &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; rather than who they were when we met them years before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This powerful idea was brought home to me again this month, as the host family I lived with in Italy for ten weeks in my sophomore year of college joined Facebook and &amp;ldquo;Friended&amp;rdquo; me.  It takes a lot of effort to write a letter in Italian, put it in an envelope, wait in line at the post office to buy international postage, and finally send it - but it takes ten seconds to write on their &amp;ldquo;walls.&amp;rdquo;  And so I am much more likely to do the latter than the former, and our relationship need not be weakened by our falling out of touch.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New short fiction: &#39;The Day-Trader&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Day-Trader,&amp;rdquo; my most recent short story, is being featured in the July issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/06/the-day-trader/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a lot of great stuff in this issue - fiction, poetry, a short film, visual art, a music album, and an essay - so be sure to check out the other pieces as well.  If you like what you see, you can support &lt;em&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/em&gt; by linking to it, passing it along to others, and making a &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/donations/&#34;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War: The More We Spend on It, the More We Get</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/war-the-more-we-spend-on-it-the-more-we-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/war-the-more-we-spend-on-it-the-more-we-get/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/14/war-the-more-we-spend/&#34;&gt;War: The More We Spend on It, the More We Get&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In it, I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;President Obama and Defense Secretary Gates’ $534 billion defense budget proposal is aimed at building a &amp;ldquo;21st-century military,&amp;rdquo; that is, a military designed to fight asymmetrical &amp;ldquo;small wars,&amp;rdquo; conduct anti-terrorism operations, and battle insurgencies. It shuffles a significant number of pieces around the chessboard, to be sure, but like its predecessors, it is an enormous waste of resources and wealth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we took a radically different, need-based approach to defense funding, and asked ourselves about the legitimate, just, and necessary aims of American power, and how much money we must allocate to defense to accomplish those aims, it is unlikely that we would wind up where we are now, with 20 percent of our national budget allocated to defense and accounting for a shameful 45 percent of the world’s spending on war and preparation for war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Insofar as Obama and Gates are shaking up the military-industrial status quo, they deserve some credit. But the simple fact that their defense budget represents an increase in an already criminal level of funding for warmaking and its instruments demonstrates that whatever special interests are threatened by the new budget, this budget will create new special interests of its own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is needed is a dramatic cut in defense spending. To think that this would represent a decrease, rather than an increase, in America’s security is a reflex rather than the product of reflection; the safest world is one in which spending on war is minimized as much as possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read the whole article &lt;a href=http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/14/war-the-more-we-spend/&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For many in Chicago, driving is a necessity, not a luxury</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My most recent op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/cgi-bin/mag/article.pl?articleId=32083&#34;&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (registration required) was published today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;Chicagobusiness.com&lt;/a&gt; and will appear in this week&amp;rsquo;s issue of &lt;em&gt;Crain&amp;rsquo;s Chicago Business&lt;/em&gt;.  You can find the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as reprinted below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is exceedingly difficult for many commuters living on the North Side to find free parking after they return from work. After an often agonizing rush-hour commute, they must circle around their neighborhood until they find a parking space; if they arrive too late, they must choose between parking at a meter and interrupting their lives every two hours to feed it, or parking a mile or more away from their homes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But if the North Side parking situation is a nightmare today, imagine what it will look like when the city installs meters along the entire lakefront, effectively eliminating a major artery of free parking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I commute every workday between my apartment near Belmont Avenue in East Lakeview and Hyde Park. If I drive, I spend around 50 minutes per day, including time spent finding parking, on the road. If I take public transportation, the same round trip can take as long as three hours. That adds an extra two hours to my workday, significantly reducing my time for leisure, exercise, relationships and everything else that is important in life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, for me and for many other commuters, driving is essential to maintaining a high quality of life in Chicago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many users of the free lakefront spots are commuters who do not have access to, cannot afford or choose not to purchase a space in a garage or a residential street parking permit. These commuters, like myself, look for free spots to park in overnight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new lakefront meters, which are scheduled to be in place by the fall, will mean that thousands of drivers will be competing for far fewer free spaces. Many commuters will spend more frustrated and stressful time on the road driving in circles in search of parking. Some will resort to paying an outrageous price to park in a garage. Others will give up driving and double or triple their commuting time by turning to public transit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For many Chicagoans, driving to work — and finding free or affordable parking after work — is a necessity, not a luxury. Contrary to the inclinations of Mayor Richard M. Daley and the city, it is not a vice that ought to be subject to endless taxation and fees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By significantly reducing the availability of free parking in lakefront neighborhoods without creating affordable alternatives for commuters, the new meters will make much of the city more expensive and inconvenient for everyone, including working families. They may boost the city&amp;rsquo;s revenue, but they will do so at the direct expense of the well-being and quality of life of thousands of its residents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Ryan McCarl is a freelance writer.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of Range: The ethics of U.S. drone strikes in Pakistan</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;Out of Range&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared in this morning&amp;rsquo;s edition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/index1234.html&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I explore the ethical dilemma of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s ongoing campaign of drone strikes in Pakistan.  This is shaping up to be one of the hottest contemporary debates in foreign policy circles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I write: &amp;ldquo;Technology and wealth have made it possible for the U.S. to exercise decisive military power anywhere in the world.  But our technology and our wealth often outrun our wisdom, our prudence, and our moral sensibilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;With the exception of the pacifist and nonviolent traditions, most of our moral thinking about war acknowledges that there are at least some circumstances under which violence and killing, including organized political violence (or war), is morally acceptable.  But are our theories about the ethics of warmaking up to the task of determining when, if ever, it is permissible to kill a relatively impotent enemy from a safe and anonymous distance, by robot or missile?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;For their operators, controlling these &amp;lsquo;drones&amp;rsquo; must not be so different from playing a video game – something almost fictional, bearing at most a tangential relationship to the reality of face-to-face killing and dying that informed our ability to understand the depth of the tragedies of previous wars we have fought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;op-ed&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to pass it along to others who might be interested.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other columnists featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; today: University of Chicago international relations theorist &lt;a href=&#34;http://mearsheimer.uchicago.edu/&#34;&gt;John J. Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt; (also my former M.A. thesis advisor!), legendary New Left activist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tomhayden.com/&#34;&gt;Tom Hayden&lt;/a&gt;, University of Michigan historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juancole.com/&#34;&gt;Juan Cole&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Editor at Time.com &lt;a href=&#34;http://tonykaron.com/&#34;&gt;Tony Karon&lt;/a&gt;, and Salon.com contributor and Constitutional lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Greenwald&#34;&gt;Glenn Greenwald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we must remember Iraq</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;The Next Forgotten War&lt;/a&gt;,” an op-ed of mine, was published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In it, I argue that we must keep the memory of the Iraq War, and the individuals caught up in its maelstroms, alive:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Iraq recedes from the headlines and slips from the public’s mind to make room for the next &amp;lsquo;crisis,&amp;rsquo; we have a responsibility to give some thought to the two million Iraqi refugees displaced by the war and the tens of thousands of Americans and Iraqis killed or maimed as a consequence of the war. And what we should remember is not statistics or grand narratives, but individual stories and the weight they lend to the principles of prudence, humanism, and nonviolence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the article, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/As%20Iraq%20recedes%20from%20the%20headlines%20and%20slips%20from%20the%20public%E2%80%99s%20mind%20to%20make%20room%20for%20the%20next%20%22crisis,%22%20we%20have%20a%20responsibility%20to%20give%20some%20thought%20to%20the%20two%20million%20Iraqi%20refugees%20displaced%20by%20the%20war%20and%20the%20tens%20of%20thousands%20of%20Americans%20and%20Iraqis%20killed%20or%20maimed%20as%20a%20consequence%20of%20the%20war.%20And%20what%20we%20should%20remember%20is%20not%20statistics%20or%20grand%20narratives,%20but%20individual%20stories%20and%20the%20weight%20they%20lend%20to%20the%20principles%20of%20prudence,%20humanism,%20and%20nonviolence.&#34;&gt;linking to it&lt;/a&gt; or sharing it with others you think may be interested.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Reading Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  At the end of each of the past three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post listing the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the course of the year in order to bring these books to the attention of others.  My lists from 2007 and 2006 are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2007/12/2007-book-recommendations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve put the titles of the five books most important to me this year in bold, and I&amp;rsquo;ve linked each book to its Amazon.com page.  Enjoy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Arons, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Compelling-Belief-Culture-American-Schooling/dp/0870235249/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899752&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Compelling Belief: The Future of American Schooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (education/religion/politics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doniger, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Implied-Spider-Wendy-Doniger/dp/0231111711/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899795&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics and Theology in Myth&lt;/a&gt; (religion / mythology)&lt;br /&gt;Du Bois, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899814&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt; (history / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frank, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899838&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt; (economics / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frankel, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Faith-Freedom-Religious-Liberty-Critical/dp/0809015757/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Faith and Freedom: Religious Liberty in America&lt;/a&gt; (religion / politics / law)&lt;div&gt;Gibran, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prophet-Kahlil-Gibran/dp/000100039X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900039&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; philosophy / religion)&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900186&amp;amp;sr=1-3&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Harrison, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Returning-Earth-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802143318/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harrison, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;br /&gt;Hemingway, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; literature)&lt;br /&gt;Kerouac, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dharma-Bums-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/0143039601/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900162&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Laxness, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Independent-People-Halldor-Laxness/dp/0679767924/ref=pd_sim_b_1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Independent People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Mann, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Milosz, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Native-Realm-Self-Definition-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374528306/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900582&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Native Realm: A Search for Self-Definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (memoirs / literature / history)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Putney &amp;amp; Putney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Adjusted-American-Neurosis-Individual-Society/dp/0060900954/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900593&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Adjusted American: Normal Neurosis in the Individual and Society&lt;/a&gt; (psychology)&lt;br /&gt;Salomon &amp;amp; Valdez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900612&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt; (design / environment)&lt;br /&gt;Walzer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Unjust-Wars-Historical-Illustrations/dp/0465037070/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900722&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Just and Unjust Wars&lt;/a&gt; (3rd reading; politics / international relations)    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
