<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liberalism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/liberalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liberalism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/liberalism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard Zinn on World War II</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve intended to read Howard Zinn&amp;rsquo;s revisionist history of the United States - &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; - for years, and I finally buckled down and started it this week. It is an excellent and eye-opening book, to say the least, and I found myself becoming absorbed in and largely agreeing with the narrative of the first few chapters - his interpretation of the &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; and colonization of America. Although I&amp;rsquo;m usually not willing to follow Zinn to his ultimate conclusions, I find his eagerness to tear down the myths and falsehoods surrounding the idea of &amp;ldquo;American exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; refreshing - especially after the nationalist fervor of a Presidential election season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zinn reminds us that Americans are fallible human beings like any others, capable of acts of greatness as well as acts of shame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I skipped ahead to find out what Zinn had to say about World War II - the war most often held up in America as an example of America&amp;rsquo;s unique greatness, of America-as-savior-and-beacon-of-hope. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from what I found:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, if the entrance of the United States into World War II was (as so many Americans believed at the time, observing the Nazi invasions) to defend the principle of nonintervention in the affairs of other countries, the nation&amp;rsquo;s record cast doubt on its ability to uphold that principle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;As Bruce Russett says: &amp;ldquo;Throughout the 1930s the United States government had done little to resist the Japanese advance on the Asian continent.&amp;rdquo; But: &amp;ldquo;The Southwest Pacific area was of undeniable economic importance to the United States - at the time most of America&amp;rsquo;s tin and rubber came from there, as did substantial qualities of other raw materials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A State Department memorandum on Japanese expansion, a year before Pearl Harbor, did not talk of the independence of China or the principle of self-determination. It said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;our general diplomatic and strategic position would be considerably weakened - by our loss of Chinese, Indian, and South Seas markets (and by our loss of much of the Japanese market for our goods, as Japan would become more and more self-sufficient) as well as by insurmountable restrictions upon our access to the rubber, tin, jute, and other vital materials of the Asian and Oceanic regions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The plight of Jews in German-occupied Europe, which many people thought was at the heart of the war against the Axis, was not a chief concern of Roosevelt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Was the war being fought to establish that Hitler was wrong in his ideas of white Nordic supremacy over &amp;ldquo;inferior&amp;rdquo; races? The United States&amp;rsquo; armed forces were segregated by race.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In one of its policies, the United States came close to direct duplication of Fascism. This was in its treatment of the Japanese-Americans living on the West Coast. After the Pearl Harbor attack, anti-Japanese hysteria spread in the government. One Congressman said: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m for catching every Japanese in America, Alaska, and Hawaii now and putting them in concentration camps&amp;hellip;. Damn them! Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of them!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt did not share this frenzy, but he calmly signed Executive Order 9066, in February 1942, giving the army the power, without warrants or indictments or hearings, to arrest every Japanese-American on the West Coast - 110,000 men, women, and children - to take them from their homes, transport them to camps far into the interior, and keep them there under prison conditions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hatred against the enemy, against the Japanese particularly, became widespread. Racism was clearly at work. &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; magazine, reporting the battle of Iwo Jima, said: &amp;ldquo;The ordinary unreasoning Jap is ignorant. Perhaps he is human. Nothing&amp;hellip;indicates it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, there was a mass base of support for what became the heaviest bombardment of civilians ever undertaken in any war: the aerial attacks on German and Japanese cities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Italy had bombed cities in the Ethiopian war; Italy and germany had bombed civilians in the Spanish Civil War; at the start of World War II German planes dropped bombs on Rotterdam in Holland, Convetry in England, and elsewhere. Roosevelt had described these as &amp;ldquo;inhuman barbarism that has profoundly shocked the conscience of humanity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These German bombings were very small compared with the British and American bombings of German cities. &amp;hellip;The English flew at night with no pretense of aiming at &amp;ldquo;military&amp;rdquo; targets; the Americans flew in the daytime and pretended precision, but bombing from high altitudes made that impossible. The climax of this terror bormbing was the bombing of Dresden in early 1945, in which the tremendous heat generated by the bombs created a vacuum into which fire leaped swiftly in a great firestorm through the city. More than 100,000 died in Dresden. [See Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slaughterhouse Five&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out Zinn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/A-Peoples-History-of-the-United-States/Howard-Zinn/e/9780060838652/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Frank on inequality in America</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-frank-on-inequality-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-frank-on-inequality-in-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started exploring the ideas of liberal economists - those economists who advise and formulate policy for Democratic candidates.  I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded a few fantastic lectures by &lt;a href=&#34;http://robertreich.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Robert Reich&lt;/a&gt;, Secretary of Labor under President Clinton.  And I recently read a book on inequality by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.robert-h-frank.com/&#34;&gt;Robert Frank&lt;/a&gt;, professor of economics at Cornell.  The book - &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200970979&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - is one of the most interesting policy essays I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time.  I highly recommend it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His basic argument is this: since 1979, the trend in America has been for an enormous increase in the incomes of those in the top 1%-5% of earners and a much, much smaller increase in the incomes of everyone else.  Flush with cash, the top earners have been spending wildly on &amp;ldquo;positional goods&amp;rdquo; - goods that display status and wealth, that demonstrate that one is a &amp;ldquo;player,&amp;rdquo; someone to be reckoned with.  Meanwhile, the near-rich emulate the spending patterns of the rich, and so on down the income ladder.  This is the &amp;ldquo;expenditure cascade.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The problem is that the farther down the income ladder one goes, the less capable individuals are of affording to participate in these &amp;ldquo;positional arms races,&amp;rdquo; as Frank calls them.  Individuals in the middle are forced to keep up by spending large portions of their income on positional goods - which include things like housing and education - while increasingly neglecting unseen, nonpositional goods like saving money and buying insurance. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The primary motive for status-spending isn&amp;rsquo;t envy, he argues; rather, middle-class families feel forced to spend heavily on positional goods in order to feel accepted and be recognized as successful.  People take out jumbo mortgages to buy oversized houses they can&amp;rsquo;t afford not because they necessarily believe that more house leads to more happiness, but because they want to send their children to the best schools and have them grow up in &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; neighborhoods - the sort of neighborhoods where housing prices are often beyond their ability to comfortably pay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frank cites research showing that higher income inequality is associated with lower societal happiness, more health problems, and higher rates of crime, homicide, suicide, and depression.  He lambasts the Bush tax cuts, which disproportionately rewarded individuals at the top of the income scale, and argues for making income taxes more progressive or switching to a progressive consumption tax.  This would involve making savings tax-exempt: taxable income in a given year would equal a family&amp;rsquo;s earnings minus its savings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do we want to spend our money on better teachers, better roads, and enhanced national security?  Or do we want to spend it on more expensive watches, more elaborate gas grills, and bigger mansions?  Tired slogans about government waste won&amp;rsquo;t help us make this decision more intelligently.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200970979&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to check out the book on Amazon.com.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortimer J. Adler on war and peace</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our view of war, then, must be broadened to include both armed conflict and battles of diplomacy, economic aid, and propaganda. War is war, whether it is &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cold.&amp;rdquo; The struggle for power and prestige among the nations goes on all the time. Only the means vary, and whether these be armed force or diplomatic pressure or other nonviolent means depends on the occasion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It follows, then, that peace is not merely a negative thing - the absence of armed conflict. What real, positive peace among the nations would be we may see by considering the state of affairs in local, state, and national communities. In our civil society, peace and order, not war, are the normal state of things. The whole meaning and purpose of civil society is peace and order. Civil government creates civil peace. Individuals who violate the law are disturbers of the peace and are dealt with accordingly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Contrary to a lot of loose talk, it is peace and not war that is proper to human nature. Cicero and many other thinkers rightly point out that fighting and snarling are the way of brute beasts, while talking things over and listening to reason are the proper way for men. Peace is required not only for our material survival but also for a really human existence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mortimer J. Adler, &lt;em&gt;Great Ideas from the Great Books&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from the weekend&#39;s reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The (National Assessment of Educational Progress economics exam), taken by a representative sample of twelfth graders at public and private high schools, tested students on micro- and macroeconomic principles and international trade. What, for example, is the effect of breaking down trade barriers between countries? A majority correctly said that goods would become less expensive. They chose this over &amp;ldquo;the quality of goods available would decrease.&amp;rdquo; Maybe John Edwards should hire more teenagers for his Presidential campaign.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/The%20exam,%20taken%20by%20a%20representative%20sample%20of%20twelfth%20graders%20at%20public%20and%20private%20high%20schools,%20tested%20students%20on%20micro-%20and%20macroeconomic%20principles%20and%20international%20trade.%20What,%20for%20example,%20is%20the%20effect%20of%20breaking%20down%20trade%20barriers%20between%20countries?&#34;&gt;The Kids Are All Right&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 10-10-07&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ms. Rodham skates earnestly on the surface of life, raising more questions than answers. “Last week I decided that even if life is absurd why couldn’t I spend it absurdly happy?” she wrote in November of her junior year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times, &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/29/us/politics/29letter.html?ex=1187150400&amp;en=a261bdf200dc7c3e&amp;amp;ei=5070&#34;&gt;In the &amp;lsquo;60s, a Future Candidate Poured Her Heart Out in Letters&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 7-29-07 (must-read - the best article I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in this entire campaign cycle, and it made me a lot more enthusiastic about the Clinton campaign. I continue, however, to support Obama.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, Eleseus was sent to town after all; Inger managed that. &amp;hellip;Now and again he asked for money, something towards his expenses. A watch and chain, for instance, he must have, so as not to oversleep himself in the morning and be late at the office; money for a pipe and tobacco also, such as the other young clerks in the town always had. And for something he called pocket-money, and something he called evening classes, where he learned drawing and gymnastics and other matters proper to his rank and position. Altogether, it was no light matter to keep Eleseus going in a berth in town.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pocket money?&amp;rdquo; said Isak. &amp;ldquo;Is that money to keep in your pocket, maybe?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There was trouble in his mind, like enough, but he bore it silently, and made no scene. Oh, there was something great about Isak; as it might be Israel, promised and ever deceived, but still believing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later in the year Inger was sent for down to the village, to do dressmaking for some of the great folks there.  Inger could not go; she had a household to look after, and animals besides, all the work of a home, and she had no servant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Had no what?  Servant!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She spoke to Isak one day.  &amp;ldquo;If only I had someone to help me, I could put in more time sewing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak did not understand.  &amp;ldquo;Help?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, help in the house - a servant-girl.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak must have been taken aback at this; he laughed a little in his iron beard, and took it as a jest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
