<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Great Books on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/great-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Great Books on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/great-books/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortimer J. Adler on war and peace</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our view of war, then, must be broadened to include both armed conflict and battles of diplomacy, economic aid, and propaganda. War is war, whether it is &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cold.&amp;rdquo; The struggle for power and prestige among the nations goes on all the time. Only the means vary, and whether these be armed force or diplomatic pressure or other nonviolent means depends on the occasion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It follows, then, that peace is not merely a negative thing - the absence of armed conflict. What real, positive peace among the nations would be we may see by considering the state of affairs in local, state, and national communities. In our civil society, peace and order, not war, are the normal state of things. The whole meaning and purpose of civil society is peace and order. Civil government creates civil peace. Individuals who violate the law are disturbers of the peace and are dealt with accordingly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Contrary to a lot of loose talk, it is peace and not war that is proper to human nature. Cicero and many other thinkers rightly point out that fighting and snarling are the way of brute beasts, while talking things over and listening to reason are the proper way for men. Peace is required not only for our material survival but also for a really human existence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mortimer J. Adler, &lt;em&gt;Great Ideas from the Great Books&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
