<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/finance/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Harrison&#39;s &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to finally know that the spirit was everywhere rather than a separate thing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clare fed our leftover sandwiches to a stray mutt, who didn&amp;rsquo;t chew the proper thirty-two times.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All of my jobs had kept me grounded in actual life whereas simply sitting in my room with my studies tended to make me unstable.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In New York City the endless blocks of huge buildings say to us, I&amp;rsquo;m serious and within me serious people are doing serious things even though five thousand people in a building might only be playing with the market edge.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a local euphemism in the U.P. that you&amp;rsquo;re not lost, you just can&amp;rsquo;t find your vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A local politician rejecting foreign languages in a school budget had said, &amp;lsquo;If English was good enough for Jesus Christ it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for our kids.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I agreed with K on the addition of what is called a &amp;lsquo;space blanket&amp;rsquo; to the survival kits I put together and distribute for Mexicans intending to migrate north.  Space blankets are sheets of material used by campers to protect them from cold and dampness but I thought they could also defend against the summer heat of the ground, which reaches over one hundred and fifty degrees.  ..The packet was in a Velcro latched bag and could be attached to a waiste belt and weighed a little less than five pounds.  I distributed these free of charge to workers&amp;rsquo; groups and through left-leaning Catholic priests.  I was opposed by many on both sides of the border for political reasons, which didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except for the legal expenses I incurred avoiding prosecution by the United States.  My raison d&amp;rsquo;etre was simple on the surface.  Estimates of crossing deaths along the entire nineteen-hundred-mile border with Mexico went as high as two thousand a year.  I had learned to be goofy rather than logically argumentative with my opponents.  I&amp;rsquo;d ask, If you could prevent twenty major airline disasters each year, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;By common consent we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything more serious than the food and music, which in themselves have become more serious as I get older.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He needed Montana but he also needed Chicago for her museums, libraries, theaters, bookstores, and most of all classical music, which he preferred to hear live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;After a passing glance I averted my eyes from a photo of Carla and me at the cabin and then I fixed on it.  Was I ever that young?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There are no damaged goods when everyone is damaged goods.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The best thing about travel, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be consumed by the past against the backdrop of a fresh landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;I was sorry to hear about Donald.  There was a man who could put in a day&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rsquo; I shook his hand as he offered this ultimate compliment of the north.  His hand felt like a semipetrified baseball mitt.  &amp;lsquo;You might not remember me.  Donny and me played football way back when, then worked together.  The name&amp;rsquo;s Teddy.&amp;rsquo;  He bowed, his face reddening, and walked away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;You were the left tackle,&amp;rsquo; I called out and he turned and grinned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On all levels the main reason to live is because you&amp;rsquo;re already alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While we were out on the park bench a small bank of clouds came across the sun turning our mood somber.  He said, &amp;lsquo;After all, the fact of death is the most brutal thing we humans are forced to accept,&amp;rsquo; but then the sun came out again and I told him that the day after the burial Herald had said, &amp;lsquo;Mother, it can&amp;rsquo;t be awful if it happens to every living thing.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buy Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True North&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/Returning-to-Earth/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802143310/?itm=3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/True-North/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802142061/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of happiness</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from Richard Layard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The extra happiness provided by extra income is greatest when you are poor, and declines steadily as you get richer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Required income&amp;rdquo; varies strongly with the actual income that an individual currently experiences.  A dollar rise in experienced income causes a rise of at least a forty cents in &amp;ldquo;required income.&amp;rdquo;  So when I earn an extra dollar this year, it makes me happier, but next year I shall measure my income from a benchmark that is forty cents higher.  In this sense at least 40% of this year&amp;rsquo;s gain is &amp;ldquo;wiped out&amp;rdquo; next year.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Differences in family situation cause a huge difference in happiness.  If someone is divorced, that person&amp;rsquo;s happiness falls by 5 (percentage) points.  This is more than double the effect of losing a third of one&amp;rsquo;s income.  &amp;hellip;The year of divorce is the worst.  After that year men return on average to their baseline level of happiness, but women continue to suffer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If our goals are too low, we get bored.  But if they are too high, we get frustrated.  The secret is to have goals that are stretching enough, but not too stretching.  Unattainable goals are a well-known cause of depression.  But so too is boredom.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The typical Briton watches television for three and a half hours a day - roughly twenty-five hours a week.  Over a lifetime a typical Briton spends more time watching television than doing paid work.  The figures are much the same in the United States.  &amp;hellip; This viewing time has to come from somewhere, and it mainly comes from social life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;So how does the content of television affect our feelings about life, and our behavior?  If television simply mirrored life as it is, it would be unlikely to have much effect.  However, it does not simply mirror life - that would be boring.  Television focuses far more on the extremes.  It contains far more violence, sex, and chaotic relationships than ordinary life does, and it contains far more wealth and beauty.  &amp;hellip;Chaos on the screen tends to desensitize - to make people more willing to engage in violence themselves and in illicit sex.  At the same time wealth and beauty create discontent with what people have - an itch to earn or steal more wealth, or to find a more beautiful partner.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On one estimate an extra hour a week watching television causes you to spend an extra $4 a week - on &amp;ldquo;keeping up with the Joneses.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;It reduces our happiness with our possessions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Viewing may also reduce our happiness with our bodies, and with our spouses.  The psychologist Douglas Kenrick showed women a series of female models.  He evaluated their mood before and after they looked at the pictures.  After seeing the models, the women&amp;rsquo;s mood fell.  So how must women&amp;rsquo;s moods be affected by television?  In three hours of viewing television each day you cannot fail to see a parade of beautiful women.  What about the effect on men?  As part of the same series of experiments, pictures of models were shown to a sample of men.  Kenrick evaluated their feelings about their wives before and after each presentation.  After seeing the models, most men felt less good about their wives.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Trustworthiness is crucial in any venture, and no long-term contract can flourish except on the basis of commitment to the common goal.  This applies in business, in friendship or in marriage.  Unfortunately, the growth of individualism has encouraged a short-term version of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;contractarian&lt;/span&gt; thinking, where more and more decisions are conducted on the basis of a short-term quid pro quo. &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this environment of continuous reoptimization, it is not surprising that, as we have seen, people are less satisfied with their marriages.  There is also clear evidence that when spouses arrange their lives on the basis of quid pro quo, they are less satisfied with the marriage than when it is based on the concept of giving.  &amp;hellip;The evidence also shows that when one spouse does something and the other spouse reciprocates, the first gets less satisfaction than when no direct reciprocation occurs.  This is because giving confers satisfaction, and can confer more satisfaction than taking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Above all, we need to know that our partner has sufficient emotional commitment to the enterprise.  If so, we know the partner will stick to the relationship, even when short-term advantage would say &amp;ldquo;Out.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;If both parties know that the other is really committed, each will invest more and the probability of success will rise.  In all walks of life, good behavior by one person elicits good behavior by others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Layard&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dewey, Hoyt, and Freud</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the past provide the only means at command for understanding the present.  &amp;hellip;The institutions and customs that exist in the present and that give rise to present social ills and dislocations did not arise overnight.  They have a long history behind them.  Attempt to deal with them simply on the basis of what is obvious in the present is bound to result in adoption of superficial measures which in the end will only render existing problems more acute and more difficult to solve.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Growth depends upon the presence of difficulty to be overcome by the exercise of intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Dewey&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Experience and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts from a history of the Great Depression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching had investigated college athletics earlier in the year (1929) and found them to be the same across the country - &amp;ldquo;sodden with commercialism.&amp;rdquo;  Of 112 schools investigated, only 28 did not offer improper subsidies to athletes.  But instead of hanging their heads in shame, many colleges defended their athletic activities.  A Brown University professor attacked the foundation for meddling.  &amp;hellip;The Big Ten&amp;rsquo;s commissioner of athletics defended the practice of buying college players.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One telephone operator in one of the city&amp;rsquo;s largest hotels wore a new sealskin coat.  Her spending was typical.  She was playing the stock market on a broker&amp;rsquo;s margin account, and boasted neither a bank savings account, insurance, nor a penny in the world except what she earned from week to week.  But would she take her profits and convert them to bonds, as President Hoover wanted her and all Americans to do?  She would not even consider it, for the gambling fever had her, as it had a million other Americans.  The fever had her and them in red-cheeked, bright-eyed frenzy. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For billions of dollars were lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thursday&#34;&gt;that day&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the young telephone operator in the New York hotel who had invested everything she owned in her sealskin coat and in a margin account on the stock exchange.  A hotel resident, unable to complete a telephone call that night, had gone to the switchboard himself, to overhear her talking to her broker, her voice breaking and eyes bathed in tears.  All the telephone operator had left at the end of this Black Thursday was her sealskin coat and her job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;That night the relatives of Abraham Germansky, a wealthy real estate man who lived in Mount Vernon, New York, put in a frantic call to police to help them find Germansky.  He had last been seen late Thursday on Wall Street, tearing up ticker tape and scattering it along the sidewalk.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hunger was not debatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin P. Hoyt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Tempering Years &lt;/span&gt;(a history of America between 1929 and 1939)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is clear that in their play children repeat everything that has made a great impression on them in real life, and that in doing so they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/abreact&#34;&gt;abreact&lt;/a&gt; the strength of the impression and, as one might put it, make themselves master of the situation.  But on the other hand, it is obvious that all their play is influenced by a wish that dominates them the whole time - the wish to be grown-up and to be able to do what grown-up people do.  It can also be observed that the unpleasurable nature of an experience does not always unsuit it for play.  If the doctor looks down a child&amp;rsquo;s throat or carries out some small operation on him, we may be quite sure that these frightening experiences will be the subject of the next game; but we must not in that connection overlook the fact that their is a yield of pleasure from another source.  As the child passes over from the passivity of the experience to the activity of the game, he hands on the disagreeable experience to one of his playmates and in this way revenges himself on a substitute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beyond the Pleasure Principle&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Gilpin on the case for free trade</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-gilpin-on-the-case-for-free-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-gilpin-on-the-case-for-free-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economists of every persuasion are convinced that free trade is superior to trade protection. In fact, they consider free trade to be the best policy for a country even if all other countries should practice trade protection, arguing that if other countries resort to trade protection, the economy that remained open would still gain more from cheaper imports than it would lose in denied export markets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Underlying this liberal commitment to free trade is the belief that the purpose of economic activity is to benefit the consumer and maximize global wealth. Free trade also maximizes consumer choice, reduces prices, and facilitates efficient use of the world&amp;rsquo;s scarce resources.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Economists have strongly disputed the alleged benefits of trade protection. Trade protection, they point out, reduces both national and international economic efficiency by preventing countries from exporting those goods and services in which they have a comparative advantage and from importing those goods and services in which they lack comparative advantage. Protection also decreases the incentive of firms to innovate and thus climb the technological ladder; it also discourages shifting natural resources to their most profitable use.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Most American economists have&amp;hellip; attributed almost all of the relative decline in the wages of low-skilled American workers to technological changes within the American economy itself. Technological changes such as the computer and information economy, they have argued, significantly decreased the demand for low-skilled workers and greatly increased the demand for skilled, especially college-educated, workers. Furthermore, these economists have noted that the relatively small trade flows between the United States and low-wage economies cannot possibly explain the roughly 30 percent difference in wages between skilled/college-educated and unskilled workers in America. Instead, this decline in the wages of low-skilled workers has been due to such technological changes as automation, lean production techniques, and computerization.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is certain that trade protection is not a wise solution to the problems of stagnant wages, income inequality, and job insecurity. The solution lies in job-training programs and other programs to aid adjustment to rapidly changing economic and technological developments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Trade, however, does create losers as well as winners in the areas of both wages and employment. Economic sectors in which a nation possesses or wins a comparative advantage gain from trade, while sectors in which a nation loses comparative advantage suffer. As losers frequently feel the pain more acutely than winners feel the gain, both ethical and political reasons make it necessary that national policy assist or compensate workers and others harmed by trade liberalization. In any case, the worst response a nation can make to inevitable shifts in comparative advantage is to close itself off from the stimulus of trade competition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Gilpin, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Global-Political-Economy-Understanding-International/dp/8125023062/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9384903-0615323?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1187804857&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Global Political Economy: Understanding the International Economic Order&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, ch. 8.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief readings on home, travel, and finance</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/brief-readings-on-home-travel-and-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/brief-readings-on-home-travel-and-finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Short History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Corn planted us; tamed cattle made us tame.&lt;br /&gt;Thence hut and citadel and kingdom came.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let us not fool ourselves. What we knew is dead, and maybe the greatest part of what we were is dead. What&amp;rsquo;s out there is perhaps good, but it&amp;rsquo;s nothing we know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The place of my origin had changed, and having gone away I had not changed with it. In my memory it stood as it once did and its outward appearance confused and angered me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;For C.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After the clash of elevator gates&lt;br /&gt;And the long sinking, she emerges where,&lt;br /&gt;A slight thing in the morning&amp;rsquo;s crosstown glare,&lt;br /&gt;She looks up toward the window where he waits,&lt;br /&gt;Then in a fleeting taxi joins the rest&lt;br /&gt;Of the huge traffic bound forever west.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, financial analysts in pin-striped suits do not like being compared with bare-assed apes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Burton Malkiel, &lt;em&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When a stranger addresses Charley in baby talk, Charley avoids him. For Charley is not a human; he&amp;rsquo;s a dog, and he likes it that way. He feels that he is a first-rate dog and has no wish to be a second-rate human.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The public, it seemed, would buy anything. &amp;hellip;The prize&amp;hellip;must surely goe to the unknown soul who started &amp;ldquo;A Company for carrying on an undertaking of great advantage, but nobody to know what it is.&amp;rdquo; The prospectus promised unheard-of rewards. At nine o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, when the subscription books opened, crowds of people from all walks of life practically beat down the door in an effort to subscribe. Within five hours 1,000 investors handed over their money for shares in the company. Not being greedy himself, the promoter promptly closed up shop and set off for the Continent. He was never heard from again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Burton Malkiel, &lt;em&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Current events: a hilarious, brilliantly written &lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/08/01/business/media/01carr.html?_r=1&amp;hp&amp;amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on Rupert Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s sadly successful takeover of the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; and its parent, the Dow Jones Company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from the week&#39;s reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weeks-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weeks-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For whom, he thought, that splendor?  For me alone?&lt;br /&gt;Yet it will be here long after I perish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Czeslaw Milosz, from &amp;ldquo;Study of Loneliness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do not neglect to show hospitality to strangers, for thereby some have entertained angels unawares.  Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them; and those who are ill-treated, since you are also in the body.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Hebrews 13:1-3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The behavior of individual consumers and producers in the rational pursuit of their objectives is governed by the principle of marginal utility, or marginality.  On the demand side of the economy, according to marginal-utility analysis, as consumers consume more and more of a good they experience diminishing utility; that is, while the first ice cream sundae consumed may be devoured with great pleasure, each additional sundae provides less pleasure (decreasing utility) and the demand of the individual for more sundaes decreases.  &amp;hellip; The one possible exception to the principle of marginal utility, at least for most individuals, is the desire for wealth itself, a desire that appears insatiable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Robert Gilpin, &lt;em&gt;Global Political Economy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sense of belonging that bound the villagers to their village community was reinforced by social and economic factors.  Population movements among the rural population were slight.  Most families had lived in their villages as far back as memory could stretch, and membership in the village was a kind of birthright.  This population stability over generations created a sense of local roots that is now unimaginable in highly mobile American society, where people change jobs and houses at the drop of a hat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Peter Duus, &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Modern Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now faith is the assurance of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Hebrews 11:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;day draws near&lt;br /&gt;another one&lt;br /&gt;do what you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Czeslaw Milosz, from &amp;ldquo;On Angels&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just because people were diligent did not mean they had to be abstemious.  Enjoyment was not to be repressed, a notion associated with traditional American attitudes toward work and achievement, but rather to be put in its proper place.  The pursuit of pleasure, sexual and otherwise, was regarded as natural and inevitable, to be condemned only when it threatened to put diligence and frugality behind it.  Thus it was possible, as one recent observer has noted, for the Japanese to be Protestant by day and Mediterranean by night, an enviable cultural compromise.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Peter Duus, &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Modern Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietrich Bonhoeffer&#39;s &#39;Letters and Papers from Prison&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/dietrich-bonhoeffers-letters-and-papers-from-prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/dietrich-bonhoeffers-letters-and-papers-from-prison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After finishing Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;East of Eden &lt;/span&gt;this week, I turned my attention to Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Letters and Papers from Prison&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dietrich_Bonhoeffer&#34;&gt;Bonhoeffer&lt;/a&gt; was an incredible man with an incredible story.  He was an innovative theologian and an erudite scholar, and he wrote several highly influential books before his thirtieth birthday.  Refusing to escape the fate of his family, friends, and church, Bonhoeffer - a German - turned down an invitation to repatriate to America in 1939.  In Spring 1943, he was imprisoned by the Nazis, and two years later, on April 9, 1945, he was executed.  During his two years in prison, he corresponded with his family and a friend on the Italian front; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Letters-Papers-Prison-Dietrich-Bonhoeffer/dp/0334028361/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/104-4601658-5091105?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1181506557&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;letters&lt;/a&gt; are some of the most inspirational documents I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read, and they display an incredible level of humility, patience, and strength in adversity.  One needn&amp;rsquo;t be a Christian to find peace and reassurance in Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s writings.  Here are a few of the many passages that I found worth remembering:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;And though the world outside be mad,&lt;br /&gt;Christian or unchristian,&lt;br /&gt;Yet the world, the beautiful world&lt;br /&gt;Is utterly indestructible&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All I need to bring that home to me is a few autumn flowers, the view from my cell window, and half an hour&amp;rsquo;s exercise in the courtyard.  But in the last resort, the world, for me at any rate, consists of those few we would like to see, and whose company we long to share.  &amp;hellip;And if I could also hear a good sermon on Sundays - I often here fragments of the chorales carried up here on the breeze - it would be better still.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As we were all lying on the floor [during an air raid] yesterday, someone muttered &amp;ldquo;O God, O God&amp;rdquo; - he is normally a frivolous sort of chap - but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to offer him any Christian encouragement or comfort.  All I did was to glance at my watch and say: &amp;ldquo;It won&amp;rsquo;t last any more than ten minutes now.&amp;rdquo;  There was nothing premeditated about it; it came quite automatically, though perhaps I had a feeling that it was wrong to force religion down his throat just then.  Incidentally, Jesus himself did not try to convert the two thieves on the cross; he waited until one of them turned to him.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As compared with marriage and the ties of kindred, friendship has no generally recognized rights, and is therefore wholly dependent on its own inherent quality.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The idea that we could have avoided many of life&amp;rsquo;s difficulties if we had taken things more quietly is one that cannot be taken seriously for a moment.  As I look back on your past I am sure that everything has turned out for the best, and so we have every reason to hope that what is happening at the present can only be for the best too.  To renounce a full life and all its joys in order to escape pain is neither Christian nor human&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nothing can make up for the absence of someone whom we love, and it would be wrong to try to find a substitute; we must simply hold out and see it through. That sounds very hard at first, but at the same time it is a great consolation, for the gap, as long as it remains unfilled, preserves the bonds between us. It is nonsense to say that God fills the gap; God does not fill it, but on the contrary, God keeps it empty and so helps us keep alive our former communion with each other, even at the cost of pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dearer and richer our memories, the more difficult the separation. But gratitude changes the pangs of memory into a tranquil joy. The beauties of the past are borne, not as a thorn in the flesh, but as a precious gift in themselves. We must take care not to wallow in our memories or to hand ourselves over to them, just as we do not gaze all the time at a valuable present, but only at special times, and apart from these keep it simply as a hidden treasure that is ours for certain. In this way the past gives us lasting joy and strength.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Another point, I am sure it is best not to talk to strangers about our feelings; that only makes matters worse, though we should always be ready to listen to the troubles of others.  Above all, we must never give way to self-pity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;We ought to love God in our &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;lives&lt;/span&gt; and in all the blessings he sends us.  We should trust him in our lives, so that when our time comes, but not before, we may go to him in love and trust and joy.  But, speaking frankly, to long for the transcendent when you are in your wife&amp;rsquo;s arms is, to put it mildly, a lack of taste, and it is certainly not what God expects of us.  We ought to find God  and love him in the blessings he sends us.  If he pleases to grant us some overwhelming earthly bliss, we ought not to try and be more religious than God himself.  &amp;hellip;Once a man has found God in his earthly bliss and has thanked him for it, there will be plenty of opportunities for him to remind himself that these earthly pleasures are only transitory, and that it is good for him to accustom himself to the idea of eternity, and there will be many hours in which he can say with all sincerity, &amp;ldquo;I would that I were home.&amp;rdquo;  But everything in its season, and the important thing is to keep step with God, and not get a step or two in front of him&amp;hellip;.  It is arrogance to want to have everything at once - matrimonial bliss, and the cross, and the heavenly Jerusalem.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In a word, live together in the forgiveness of your sins, for without it no human fellowship, least of all a marriage, can survive.  Don&amp;rsquo;t insist on your rights, don&amp;rsquo;t blame each other, don&amp;rsquo;t judge or condemn each other, don&amp;rsquo;t find fault with each other, but take one another as you are, and forgive each other every day from the bottom of your hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I have just read this in Jean Paul: &amp;ldquo;The only joys which can stand the fires of adversity are the joys of home.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;I wish you a happy day from the bottom of my heart, and shall be with you in spirit.  May your thoughts about me be confined to happy memories of the past and hopes for the future.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
