<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theology on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theology on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 22:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/theology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Milosz, Balthasar, and Stevens</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many definitions of Communism, perhaps one would be the most apt: enemy of orchards. For the disappearance of villages and the remodeling of the terrain necessitated cutting down the orchards once surrounding every house and hut. The idea of collective farming - grain factories instead of little peasant lots - was rational, but with a vengeance, and a similar vengeance lurking in practically every project of the planned economy brought about the downfall of the Soviet system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Orchards under Communism had no chance, but in all fairness let us concede that they are antique by their very nature. Only the passion of a gardener can delight in growing a great variety of trees, each producing a small crop of fruit whose tastes pleases the gardener himself and a few connoisseurs. Market laws favor a few species that are easy to preserve and correspond to basic standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Much was going on inside me, and I was stunned by the strength of that current for which no name seemed adequate. It was like waking up from a long dream and becoming again the person whom I have never ceased to be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Happiness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One would like to astound the world, to save the world, but one can do neither. We are summoned to deeds that are of moment only to our village.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Who Was I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I am not wise, then why must I pretend to be? If I am lost, why must I pretend to have ready counsel for my contemporaries? But perhaps the value of communication depends on the acknowledgment of one&amp;rsquo;s own limits, which, mysteriously, are also limits common to many others; and aren&amp;rsquo;t these the same limits of a hundred or a thousand years ago? And when the air is filled with the clamor of analysis and conclusion, would it be entirely useless to admit you do not understand?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have read many books, but to place all those volumes on top of one another and stand on them would not add a cubit to my stature. Their learned terms are of little use when I try to seize naked experience, which eludes all accepted ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;My Intention&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The man who stakes his all on this one thing wins all, but he must of course reckon with the loss of everything else excluded by this one thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hans Urs von Balthasar&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Moment of Christian Witness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;Divinity must live within herself:&lt;br /&gt;Passions of rain, or moods in falling snow;&lt;br /&gt;Grievings in loneliness, or unsubdued&lt;br /&gt;Elations when the forest blooms; gusty&lt;br /&gt;Emotions on wet roads on autumn nights;&lt;br /&gt;All pleasures and all pains, remembering&lt;br /&gt;The bough of summer and the winter branch.&lt;br /&gt;These are the measures destined for her soul.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shall our blood fail? Or shall it come to be&lt;br /&gt;The blood of paradise? And shall the earth&lt;br /&gt;Seem all of paradise that we shall know?&lt;br /&gt;The sky will be much friendlier then than now,&lt;br /&gt;A part of labor and a part of pain,&lt;br /&gt;And next in glory to enduring love,&lt;br /&gt;Not this dividing and indifferent blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on Easter, Just War Theory, and Japanese lit</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The resurrection of Jesus is the sign to the world that God indeed does reign, does give life in death and that the love of God is stronger even than death (Rom. 8:36-39).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;At the center of the church&amp;rsquo;s teaching on peace and at the center of all Catholic social teaching, are the transcendence of God and the dignity of the human person.  The human person is the clearest reflection of God&amp;rsquo;s presence in the world; all of the church&amp;rsquo;s work in pursuit of both justice and peace is designed to protect and promote the dignity of every person.  For each person not only reflects God, but is the expression of God&amp;rsquo;s creative work and the meaning of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemptive ministry.  Christians approach the problem of war and peace with fear and reverence.  God is the Lord of life, and so each human life is sacred; modern warfare threatens the obliteration of human life on a previously unimaginable scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;U.S. Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response (The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace, 1983)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us.  &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28140&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28141&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romans 8:37-39&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The aggressor is always peace-loving; he would prefer to take over our country unopposed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Carl Von Clausewitz, quoted in J.T. Turner, &amp;ldquo;Threats, Values and Defense: Does the Defense of Values by Force Remain a Moral Possibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;***&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His desire for a woman was not of a sort to make him want this particular woman - it was something to be taken care of lightly and with no sense of guilt.  This woman was too clean.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The window of the waiting-room was clear for an instant as the train started to move.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s face glowed forth, and as quickly disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But this love would leave behind it nothing so definite as a piece of Chijimi.  Though cloth to be worn is among the most short-lived of craftworks, a good piece of Chijimi, if it has been taken care of, can be worn quite unfaded a half-century and more after weaving.  As Shimamura thought absently how human intricacies have not even so long a life, the image of Komako as the mother of another man&amp;rsquo;s children suddenly floated into his mind.  He looked around, startled.  Possibly he was tired.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He leaned against the brazier, provided against the coming of the snowy season, and thought how unlikely it was that he would come again once he had left.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Komako had come up to him, he did not know when.  She took his hand.  He looked around at her but said nothing.  She gazed at the fire, the pulse of the fire beating on her intent, slightly flushed face.  Shimamura felt a violent rising in his chest.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s hair was coming undone, and her throat was bare and arched.  His fingers trembled from the urge to touch it.  His hand was warm, but Komako&amp;rsquo;s was still warmer.  He did not know why he should feel that a separation was forcing itself upon them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kawabata Yasunari&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Snow Country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously he did not much enjoy reading and discussing a typical month&amp;rsquo;s production of Japanese literature.  In a 1935 essay Kobayashi expressed his annoyance with authors who complained that he had not been sufficiently kind in his reviews, and asked sardonically what kindness contemporary authors have ever shown their critics.  The only kindness a critic really wants from authors is that they will supply him with the basis for writing decent criticism; but present-day authors do precisely the opposite.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donald Keene&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Dawn to the West: A History of Japanese Literature (Vol. 4)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from David Damrosch, Kahlil Gibran, &amp; Paul Tillich</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 02:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Goethe comments that the Church erred in closing the canon of scripture, as God&amp;rsquo;s creative work still continues, notably in the activity of great spirits like Mozart, Raphael, and Shakespeare, &amp;ldquo;who can draw their lesser contemporaries higher.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For the first time in history, authors of highly successful works can hope to have them translated into twenty or thirty languages within a few years of publication, and foreign countries may even provide the primary readership for writers who have small audiences at home or who are censored by their governments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; works cease to be the exclusive products of their original culture once they are translated; all become works that only &amp;ldquo;began&amp;rdquo; in their original language.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Society melts away in the vast echo chamber of (literary critic Harold) &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Bloom&#34;&gt;Bloom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s mind, replaced by the warring voices of the few great titans of the literary universe.  The fewer the better: &amp;hellip;Bloom continually narrows his authors&amp;rsquo; already narrow circle.  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1573225142&#34;&gt;The Western Canon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; treats twenty-six writers, but what need twenty-six?  &amp;ldquo;Most simply, the Canon is Plato and Shakespeare&amp;rdquo; (34).  What need even two?  &amp;ldquo;At once no one and everyone, nothing and everything, Shakespeare is the Western Canon&amp;rdquo; (71).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet even Bloom finally relents.  Having spent almost five hundred pages extolling the greatness of the few greatest writers at the heart of his version of the Western canon, he closes with an appendix listing several &lt;em&gt;thousand&lt;/em&gt; works by more than eight hundred and fifty writers whom he considers to be the key figures in the Western canon as a whole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Damrosch&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/What-World-Literature-Translation-Transnation/dp/0691049866/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1204791136&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;What is World Literature&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How shall I go in peace and without sorrow? Nay, not without a wound in the spirit shall I leave this city.  Long were the days of pain I have spent within its walls, and long were the nights of aloneness; and who can depart from his pain and his aloneness without regret?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Too many fragments of the spirit have I scattered in these streets, and too many are the children of my longing that walk naked among these hills, and I cannot withdraw from them without a burden and an ache.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is not a garment I cast off this day, but a skin that I tear with my own hands.  Nor is it a thought I leave behind me, but a heart made sweet with hunger and with thirst.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet I cannot tarry longer.  The sea that calls all things unto her calls me, and I must embark.&lt;br /&gt;For to stay, though the hours burn in the night, is to freeze and crystallize and be bound in a mould. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fain would I take with me all that is here. But how shall I?  A voice cannot carry the tongue and the lips that give it wings. Alone must it seek the ether.  And alone and without his nest shall the eagle fly across the sun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kahlil Gibran&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Prophet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sociological analyses of the present period have pointed to the importance of anxiety as a group phenomenon.  Literature and art have made anxiety a main theme of their creations, in content as well as in style.  The effect of this has been the awakening of at least the educated groups to an awareness of their own anxiety, and a permeation of the public consciousness by ideas and symbols of anxiety.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The first assertion about the nature of anxiety is this: anxiety is the state in which a being is aware of its possible nonbeing.  &amp;hellip;It is not the realization of universal transitoriness, not even the experience of the death of others, but the impression of these events on the always latent awareness of our own having to die that produces anxiety.  Anxiety is finitude, experienced as one&amp;rsquo;s own finitude.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Frost, Tillich, O&#39;Hara, and Pound</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 01:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Desert Places&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They cannot scare me with their empty spaces&lt;br /&gt;Between stars - on stars where no human race is.&lt;br /&gt;I have it in me so much nearer home&lt;br /&gt;To scare myself with my own desert places.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One cannot remove anxiety by arguing it away.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The affirmation of one&amp;rsquo;s essential being in spite of desires and anxieties creates joy.  Lucillus is exhorted by Seneca to make it his business &amp;ldquo;to learn how to feel joy.&amp;rdquo;  It is not the joy of fulfilled desires to which he refers, for real joy is a &amp;ldquo;severe matter&amp;rdquo;; it is the happiness of a soul which is &amp;ldquo;lifted above every circumstance.&amp;rdquo;  Joy accompanies the self-affirmation of our essential being in spite of the inhibitions coming from the accidental elements in us.  Joy is the emotional expression of the courageous Yes to one&amp;rsquo;s own true being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the Harbormaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I wanted to be sure to reach you&lt;br /&gt;though my ship was on the way it got caught&lt;br /&gt;in some moorings. I am always tying up&lt;br /&gt;and then deciding to depart. In storms and&lt;br /&gt;at sunset, with the metallic coils of the tide&lt;br /&gt;around my fathomless arms, I am unable&lt;br /&gt;to understand the forms of my vanity&lt;br /&gt;or I am hard alee with my Polish rudder&lt;br /&gt;in my hand and the sun sinking. To&lt;br /&gt;you I offer my hull and the tattered cordage&lt;br /&gt;of my will. The terrible channels where&lt;br /&gt;the wind drives me against the brown lips&lt;br /&gt;of the reeds are not all behind me. Yet&lt;br /&gt;I trust the sanity of my vessel; and&lt;br /&gt;if it sinks it may well be in answer&lt;br /&gt;to the reasoning of the eternal voices,&lt;br /&gt;the waves which have kept me from reaching you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Frank O&amp;rsquo;Hara&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sceptical age hungers after the definite, after something it can pretend to believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;You read, as a child who has listened to ghost stories goes into a dark room; it is no accurate information about historical things that you seek, it is the thrill which mere reality would never satisfy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of literary criticism is largely the history of a vain struggle to find a terminology which will define something.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is dawn at Jerusalem while midnight hovers above the Pillars of Hercules.  All ages are contemporaneous.  The Middle Ages are in Russia.  The future stirs already in the minds of the few.  This is especially true of literature, where the real time is independent of the apparent, and where many dead men are our grandchildren&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries, while many of our contemporaries have been already gathered into Abraham&amp;rsquo;s bosom, or some more fitting receptacle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of an art is the history of masterwork, not of failures, or mediocrity.  The ominscient historian would display the masterpieces, their causes and their inter-relation.  The study of literature is hero-worship.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Good art never bores one.  By that I mean that it is the business of the artist to prevent ennui; in the literary art, to relieve, refresh, revive the mind of the reader - at reasonable intervals - with some form of ecstasy, by some splendor of thought, some presentation of sheer beauty, some lightning turn of phrase - laughter is no mean ecstasy.  Good art begins with an escape from dullness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ezra Pound&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Spirit of Romance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on psychology, religion, and politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in mundane situations, the individual must &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; in order to discover what he is and he must act in order to continue experiencing aspects of himself which he values and enjoys.  If he thinks of himself as a businessman, a parent, an athlete, an intellectual, he must engage in behavior appropriate to this self-image.  If he does not, he must redefine himself, or he will be left feeling anxious and needful.  (Here is the reason for the psychological shock of retirement; the man who has retired may find that suddenly he can no longer &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;that which he most valued himself for being.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Past actions through which he sought to know and to accept the self are not capable of satisfying this need in the present.  Recalling the past can only remind the individual of what he used to be.  The erstwhile football hero who is still reliving the big game fifteen years later, or the ex-campus queen who tries to give meaning to her life by clinging to her reign over the prom of a decade ago, are pathetic figures.  As the existentialists have pointed out, man must act in order to be, and what he becomes is largely the summation of his actions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Paradoxical though it may seem, it is when the individual is with others that he is best able to enjoy and expand many aspects of himself, to refine and verify his self-image.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Men hate in others those things - and only those things - which they despise in themselves.  It is possible to disapprove of other people in a rational and dispassionate manner, but to hate them is an irrational and impassioned act.  The passion betrays the underlying self-contempt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Distance enables the lover to see his beloved purely in terms of the projections he hangs on her.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The general rule is that people who enjoy life enjoy marriage. Some people would be unhappy with any spouse, for they do not allow themselves happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snell Putney and Gail J. Putney&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Adjusted American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That hatred springs more from self-contempt than from a legitimate grievance is seen in the intimate connection between hatred and a guilty conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Eric Hoffer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Insanity in individuals is something rare - but in groups, parties, nations, and epochs, it is the rule.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If our faith is real, it must encroach upon our life. The Christian Confession in its original Church form will always be exposed to the misunderstanding that the Christian regards the Creed as a matter of heart and conscience, but that here on earth and in the world other truths hold good. The world lives in this misunderstanding; it regards the whole of Christianity as a friendly &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo;, connected with the &amp;lsquo;realm of religion&amp;rsquo;, which is respected and which ought to be left untampered with; and so we get rid of the matter! But this misunderstanding might even have come from within; a Christian might quite well wish to have this realm for himself and to guard faith like a sensitive plant. The relationship between the Church and the world has been widely understood as a question of a fixing of frontiers, whereby each secured itself behind its own frontier, although from time to time it came to a skirmish. From the Church&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, however, such a fixing of frontiers can never exhaust its task. By the very nature of the Christian Church there is only one task, to make the Confession heard in the sphere of the world as well.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us beware of remaining stuck where we are and refusing to advance to meet worldly attitudes. For instance, in Germany in 1933 there was plenty of serious, profound and living Christianity and confession&amp;hellip;. But unfortunately this faith and confession of the German Church remained embedded in the language of the Church, and did not translate what was being excellently said in the language of the Church into the political attitude demanded at the time; in which it would have become clear that the Evangelical Church had to say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to National Socialism, &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; from its very roots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Barth&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Dogmatics in Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on religion and culture</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He who refuses to embrace a unique opportunity loses the prize as surely as if he tried and failed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our errors are surely not such awfully solemn things. In a world where we are so certain to incur them in spite of all our caution, a certain lightness of heart seems healthier than this excessive nervousness on their behalf.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us give the name &lt;em&gt;hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; to anything that may be proposed to our belief; and just as the electricians speak of live and dead wires, let us speak of any hypothesis as either &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;dead&lt;/em&gt;. A live hypothesis is one which appears as a real possibility to him to whom it is proposed. If I ask you to believe in the Mahdi, the notion makes no electric connection with your nature, - it refuses to scintillate with any credibility at all. As an hypothesis it is completely dead. To an Arab, however (even if he be not one of the Mahdi&amp;rsquo;s followers), the hypothesis is among the mind&amp;rsquo;s possibilities: it is alive. This shows that deadness and liveness in an hypothesis are not intrinsic properties, but relations to the individual thinker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Will to Believe&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The distance, and as it were the space around man, grows with the strength of his intellectual vision and insight: his world becomes profounder; new stars, new enigmas, and notions are ever coming into view. Perhaps everything on which the intellectual eye has exercised its acuteness and profundity has just been an occasion for its exercise, something of a game, something for children and childish minds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Beyond Good and Evil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The perspective of the &amp;lsquo;unbeliever&amp;rsquo; on the traditional forms of belief has seldom been welcomed with any enthusiasm inside the communities of faith, but in spite of that it has provided an invaluable service to them. If one were to write the history of modern reform movements within the several world religions, the critical outsider would have to be accorded a substantial position in such a history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jaroslav Pelikan&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The World Treasury of Modern Religious Thought&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of today’s churches have bought the culture’s lie that religion is not about sex or anything else of much importance. But, as theologian Sarah Coakley has so brilliantly said, ancient Christian reflection on desire shows that Freud is exactly wrong: Talk about God is not repressed talk about sexuality; talk about sex is, in fact, repressed talk about God. To paraphrase C.S. Lewis, porn users are not to be rebuked for desiring too much but for desiring too little.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jason Byassee, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/article.php3?id_article=6105&#34;&gt;Not Your Father&amp;rsquo;s Pornography&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;First Things, &lt;/em&gt;January 2008)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;True North&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jim-harrisons-true-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jim-harrisons-true-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main feature of the Kingston Plains was the thousands of acres of white pine stumps, some of them very large, which had been cut at waist or chest height probably during the winter when it was easier to skid the trees out on snow-covered trails which they dampened to form ice so that the draft horse-drawn log sleighs could be more easily pulled. &amp;hellip;I swiveled around until I had completed a 360-degree view, suppressing any anger I felt over the idea that they might have left a few trees for those in the future to look at. Maybe to try to imagine the trees was like asking a contemporary Lakota to imagine a million buffalo.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It occurred to me that you could explain everything away but the behavior remained.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Frankly I wanted to be useful in this life and that could be defined only by work, not good intentions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I felt absurdly happy when I entered Michigan just north of Toledo, though I was already lonely for Riva.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Being at the university through the deaths of Robert Kennedy and Martin Luther King Jr. ending with the more recent Kent State butchery had often made academic studies seem problematical and remote. How upsetting to see your professor break down in tears in your Chaucer class the day after King was murdered. My return to religion was a defense against the insanity of the time, a way to avoid standing there simply screaming like the girl in the famous Kent State photograph. I recalled the day when I was a junior at Michigan State and Cynthia had called to say that she had heard our ex-paper boy had died in Vietnam. He was a poor kid and never seemed dressed warmly enough in winter when below-zero winds blew in off Lake Superior. &amp;hellip;He put a face on an insane war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;How soiled and tawdry poor Jesus was compared to the theological school where the self-interest of the human intelligence smothered prayer, and the abstractions in the history of theology were a virtual fire extinguisher on the Gospels.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Every location has its classic Greek chorus muttering, chattering, moaning in the background.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Fred says that when he sees a politician who has further crushed the poor pray in public he wants to pick up a gun.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I was cold and exhausted and went back to the motel room, drew an easy chair up to the window, then fell asleep staring at the frightening whiteness of the world. It was clearly a blank canvas on which you could paint your life if you cared to. Just before sleep I imagined sitting at the cabin window and painted the interior of what would be my cabin, including the front window from which the only visible thing was Lake Superior and the line of the horizon, but there was the nagging idea Fred had explained that as a putative Christian I had to learn how to function in the world before I earned the right to retreat.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We were jittery when we rigged our fly rods and flipped a coin for the first cast. Glenn won and caught a two-pounder and then it became apparent that the fish weren&amp;rsquo;t gun-shy so we could both cast. We caught a dozen before dark and released all but two which we kept for a midnight snack and ate with a six-pack of beer Glenn had stowed in the cold creek. The northern lights were astounding, whirling sheets and cones of rose and green and bluish lights so strong they gave off a tinny metallic sound.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Naturally during the act of love you&amp;rsquo;re undisturbed by reality, a grace note I also found in trout fishing, but then lovemaking and fishing don&amp;rsquo;t manage to dominate your life like you wished they could.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We gave up our heavy talk and spent two days rowing. In my own life strength has come from unfolding, subtracting, rather than adding.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clarence said a striking thing about rowing that I&amp;rsquo;ve always valued, the upshot of which was that he liked rowing because you were approaching life backward. You could clearly see the past, and you glanced quickly at the future over your shoulder mostly so you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t run into anything destructively immovable. Too much of the future was predestined by the behavior of others for you to be in control. The most you could hope for is to be ready and attentive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1202245476&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I picked up&lt;/em&gt; True North&lt;em&gt; at the Dawn Treader Book Shop (one of my favorites) in Ann Arbor, MI yesterday, and it has sucked me in and engrossed me in a way that hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened in awhile.  I read 50 pages in one sitting last night and another 150 pages on the train from Ann Arbor to Chicago this morning.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know how it ends yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2007 book recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following list includes the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year that I enjoyed the most and that had the biggest effect on me.  I give the highest recommendation to all of them, and I&amp;rsquo;ve bolded the top five.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Akhmatova, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Anna-Akhmatova/dp/0939010615/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804019&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Bonhoeffer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Letter-Papers-Prison-Dietrich-Bonhoeffer/dp/0684838273/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Letters and Papers From Prison&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Cumings, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Koreas-Place-Sun-History-Updated/dp/0393327027/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804099&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Korea’s Place in the Sun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;de Bary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0231121393/ref=pd_cp_b_1?pf_rd_p=317711001&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=center-41&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0231086040&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=1FDVCJHA9ZCSZ7N3WY39&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Sources of Japanese Tradition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frye, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Imagination-Cbc-Massey-Lectures/dp/0887845983/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805497&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Educated Imagination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gilpin, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Change-World-Politics-Robert-Gilpin/dp/0521273765/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805537&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;War and Change in World Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pan-Knut-Hamsun/dp/1426422571/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Pan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Soil-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0394717813/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805602&amp;amp;sr=1-7&#34;&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Victoria-Penguin-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0143039377/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198806948&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hardy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Penguin-Classics-Thomas/dp/0140436995/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ienaga, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pacific-War-1931-1945-Saburo-Ienaga/dp/0394734963/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807106&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pacific War 1931-1945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Into-Wild-Jon-Krakauer/dp/0307387178/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807224&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;McCann, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Columbia Anthology of Modern Korean Poetry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Petterson, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807402&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Out Stealing Horses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pieper, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;H&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hope-History-Josef-Pieper/dp/0898704650/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807583&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;ope and History&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rilke, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Duino-Elegies-Sonnets-Orpheus-Rainer/dp/0395250587/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807628&amp;amp;sr=1-8&#34;&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rowling, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Harry-Potter-Deathly-Hallows-Book/dp/0545010225/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/East-Eden-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142004235/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807783&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;East of Eden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pearl-Centennial-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142000698/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807841&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pearl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Travels-Charley-Search-America-Steinbeck/dp/0140053204/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807914&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Walker, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prompt-Utter-Destruction-Truman-Against/dp/080785607X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807943&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Prompt and Utter Destruction: Truman and the Use of Atomic Bombs&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;If you are interested in checking out last year&amp;rsquo;s list of recommended books, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief isn&#39;t for the unimaginative; let kids see &#39;The Golden Compass&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/belief-isnt-for-the-unimaginative-let-kids-see-the-golden-compass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/belief-isnt-for-the-unimaginative-let-kids-see-the-golden-compass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philly.com/inquirer/opinion/20071210_Belief_isnt_for_the_unimaginative__let_kids_see_The_Golden_Compass.html&#34;&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; was published in this morning&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philadelphia Inquirer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was thrilled to learn that The Golden Compass, the first book in Philip Pullman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; trilogy, was going to be released as a movie on Friday. I read the trilogy first in middle school and again in high school, and it was my favorite story for a long time. It is filled with imagination and erudition, and it is a significant cut above the vast majority of works aimed at young adults.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the story&amp;rsquo;s greatest strength - its infusion with ideas - is as much a threat to pundits and &amp;ldquo;protect-the-children&amp;rdquo; types as it is a joy to readers. Pullman is an atheist, and the books reflect his negative view of organized religion. Some religious advocacy groups are, accordingly, up in arms over the release of the movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have already received my first mass e-mail warning me about the dangers of The Golden Compass and advising me to keep my kids inside, with doors locked. The movie will, I am told, &amp;ldquo;kill God in the minds of children&amp;rdquo;; its objective is to &amp;ldquo;bash Christianity and promote atheism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell atheism to kids.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But Pullman&amp;rsquo;s real quarrel is less with belief itself than with the intolerance that organized belief systems sometimes foster, an intolerance demonstrated every time some busybody condemns a book without having actually read it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are a lot of sophisticated theological and philosophical ideas woven into the &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; narrative. The story speaks as positively about religious concepts such as soul, spiritual existence and love as it speaks negatively about intolerance and bigotry. It opens a window in the reader&amp;rsquo;s mind and invites him or her to investigate all of these ideas further.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless, there is no doubt that &amp;ldquo;His Dark Materials&amp;rdquo; will threaten some readers&amp;rsquo; identities and beliefs. To listen to and take seriously alternative viewpoints is to make oneself vulnerable; it raises the possibility that our certainty is not as justified as we had thought.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Complaints about Pullman&amp;rsquo;s books and calls for a boycott of the movie are based on several seriously flawed assumptions: that parents should shelter teenagers from views that don&amp;rsquo;t seem in accord with those of the parent; that young adults cannot or should not think critically and engage in dialogue about serious ideas; and that imaginative fiction threatens religious belief.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In fact, great stories are the stuff of which religious belief is made. Literature shapes and expands our imagination, and imagination is critically important to our ability to believe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In religious practice, for example, we are asked to internalize symbols, such as the cross, seeing them not as mere shapes or designs but as signs that point toward the infinite. We are asked to believe in unseen forces that never register on scientific instruments. We are asked to imagine ourselves as part of a human community larger than ourselves and our families, and we are asked to imagine our lives not as isolated, meaningless evolutionary aberrations but as part of a grander narrative of creation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Belief is not for the unimaginative. If it were, perhaps religious wisdom would be passed down through history in some more concrete form than the symbols, stories, myths and parables we have inherited.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Parents who want their children to grow up with faith should take them to the fiction section of the local library or bookstore and give them free rein to explore. It is in literature that they will find the most convincing evidence for eternal things, and it is through exposure to literature that they will develop the imagination that belief requires.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl is a masters student in international relations at the University of Chicago and a freelance writer.  His blog is &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Paul Tillich and a poem by Mark Strand</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And, certainly, the way to maturity in thinking is a difficult path.  Much must be left behind: early dreams, poetic imaginations, cherished legends, favored doctrines, accustomed laws and ritual traditions.  Some of them must be restored on a deeper level, some must be given up.  Despite this price, maturity can be gained - a manly, self-critical, convincing faith, not produced by reasoning, but reasonable, and at the same time rooted in the message of the divine foolishness, the ultimate source of wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From century to century it has become more and more evident that knowledge without wisdom produces external and internal self-destruction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He who has encountered the mystery of life has reached the source of wisdom.  In encountering it with awe and longing, he experiences the infinite distance of his being from that which is the ground of his being.  He experiences the limits of his being, his finitude in face of the infinite.  He learns that acceptance of one&amp;rsquo;s limits is the decisive step towards wisdom.  The fool rebels against the limits set by his finitude.  He wants to be unlimited in power and knowledge.  He who is wise accepts his finitude.  He knows that he is not God.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;  &amp;ndash;The Eternal Now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man in Black&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was walking downtown&lt;br /&gt;when I noticed a man in black,&lt;br /&gt;black cape and black boots, coming toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His arms out in front of him,&lt;br /&gt;his fingers twinkling with little rings,&lt;br /&gt;he looked like a summer night full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was summer.  The night was full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;the tall buildings formed a hallway down which I walked.&lt;br /&gt;The man in black came toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The waxed tips of his mustache shone&lt;br /&gt;like tiny spears and his teeth glistened.&lt;br /&gt;I offered him my hand which he did not take.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt like a fool and stood in his black wake,&lt;br /&gt;shaken and small, and my tears&lt;br /&gt;swung back and forth in the sultry air like chandeliers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mark Strand&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes on religion, love, and int&#39;l relations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-on-religion-love-and-intl-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-on-religion-love-and-intl-relations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every summer he&amp;rsquo;s on the prarie harvesting wheat and every winter in the Wisconsin forests chopping cordwood. That&amp;rsquo;s his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A life maybe as good as any other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &amp;ldquo;On the Prarie&amp;rdquo; (from &lt;em&gt;Tales of Love and Loss&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The theological dimension is needed both for interpreting and for solving present day problems in human society.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pope John Paul II, &lt;em&gt;Centesimus Annus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The human being is made for love and cannot live without love. When it is manifested as the total gift of two persons in their complementarities, love cannot be reduced to emotions or feelings, much less to mere sexual expression. In a society that tends more and more to relativize and trivialize the very experience of love and sexuality, exalting its fleeting aspects and obscuring its fundamental values, it is more urgent than ever to proclaim and bear witness that the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; of conjugal love and sexuality exist where there is a full and total gift of persons, with the characteristics of &lt;em&gt;unity &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;fidelity&lt;/em&gt;. This truth, a source of joy, hope, and life, remains impenetrable and unattainable as long as people close themselves off in relativism and skepticism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pontifical Council for Justice and Peace, &lt;em&gt;Compendium of the Social Doctrine of the Church&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We lived through much happiness and unhappiness,&lt;br /&gt;Separations, miraculous rescues. And now, this ash.&lt;br /&gt;And the sea battering the shore when I walk the empty boulevard.&lt;br /&gt;And the sea battering the shore. And ordinary sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz, &lt;em&gt;from &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;On Parting With my Wife, Janina&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enemy images have a long pedigree, and some states continue to position each other in such terms today. The Greeks represented the Persians as &amp;ldquo;barbarians&amp;rdquo;; the Crusaders perceived the Turks as &amp;ldquo;infidels&amp;rdquo;; medieval Europeans feared their defeat at Liegnitz at the hands of the Mongols heralded Armageddon; later Europeans treated the peoples of the Americas as savages; conservatives thought civilization was threatened by the French Revolution; and, in our own century, we have the Armenian genocide, the Holocaust, the early Cold War, Northern Ireland, Pol Pot, Palestinian and Israeli fundamentalists, the Bosnian Civil War, Hutus and Tutsis - all based on representations of the Other as intent on destroying or enslaving the Self.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to recognize that this concept implies nothing about whether enemy images are justified. Some enemies are &amp;ldquo;real,&amp;rdquo; in that the Other really does existentially threaten the Self, as the Nazis did the Jews, and others are &amp;ldquo;chimeras,&amp;rdquo; as the Jews were to the Nazis. &amp;hellip;Real or imagined, if actors think enemies are real then they are real in their consequences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Alexander Wendt, &lt;em&gt;Social Theory of International Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on certainty, racism, and foreign policy</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Today&amp;rsquo;s Maroon &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;column&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Certainty is a luxury none of us has.&amp;rdquo;  Religious fundamentalists and secular fundamentalists are all-too-alike in their belief that they, and only they, have answers to the biggest questions in the human dialogue.  What unites us all is doubt and searching.  Read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Must-read: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/10/16/principal-of-citys-arabic-school-says-she-was-forced-out/index.html?ex=1350273600&amp;amp;en=5fc98d5704a026df&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;Principal of Arabic School Says She was Forced Out&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  This is what racist, nativist hysteria looks like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-From an Economist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/displayStory.cfm?story_id=9973918&amp;amp;fsrc=RSS&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the new Fox Business Channel: &lt;em&gt;Mr Murdoch apparently wants his channel to be more “pro-capitalism” than CNBC—which is hardly a pinko outfit—and, sure enough, there was soon a discussion about the pharmaceutical industry entitled &amp;ldquo;Capitalism cures cancer&amp;rdquo;, which—let’s be “fair and balanced”, as the Fox News slogan puts it—it does&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-MIT international relations scholar Barry Posen on &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the-american-interest.com/ai2/article.cfm?Id=331&amp;amp;MId=16&#34;&gt;the case for restraint&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in U.S. foreign policy.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t read this yet, but I generally like what Posen has to say.  Responses from Francis Fukuyama, Stephen Krasner, G. John Ikenberry, and others are also online.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Max Muller, historian of religion</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-max-muller-historian-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 22:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-max-muller-historian-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not many years ago great offence was given by an eminent writer who remarked that the time had come when the history of Christianity should be treated in a truly historical spirit, in the same spirit in which we treat the history of other religions, such as Brahmanism, Buddhism, or Mohammedanism. And yet what can be truer? He must be a man of little faith, who would fear to subject his own religion to the same critical tests to which the historian subjects all other religions. We need not surely crave a tender or merciful treatment for that faith which we hold to be the only true one. We should rather challenge for it the severest tests and trials, as the sailor would for the good ship to which he entrusts his own life, and the lives of those who are most dear to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The difficulties which trouble us, have troubled the hearts and minds of men as far back as we can trace the beginnings of religious life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(We) must aim at truth, trusting that even unpalatable truths, like unpalatable medicine, will reinvigorate the system which they enter. To those, no doubt, who value the tenets of their religion as the miser values his pearls and precious stones, thinking their value lessened if pearls and stones of the same kind are found in other parts of the world, the Science of Religion will bring many a rude shock; but to the true believer, truth, wherever it appears, is welcome, nor will any doctrine seem the less true or the less precious, because it was seen, not only by Moses or Christ, but likewise by Buddha or Laotse.  &amp;hellip;Some of the most vital articles of faith are the common property of the whole of mankind&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are philosophers, no doubt, to whom both Christianity and all other religions are exploded errors, things belonging to the past, and to be replaced by more positive knowledge. To them the study of the religions of the world could only have a pathological interest, and their hearts could never warm at the sparks of truth that light up, like stars, the dark yet glorious night of the ancient world.  They tell us that the world has passed through the phases of religious and metaphysical errors, in order to arrive at the safe haven of positive knowledge of facts.  But if they would but study positive facts, if they would but read, patiently and thoughtfully, the history of the world, as it is, not as it might have been: they would see that, as in geology, so in the history of human thought, theoretic uniformity does not exist, and that the past is never altogether lost. The oldest formations of thought crop out everywhere, and if we dig but deep enough, we shall find that even the sandy desert in which we are asked to live, rests everywhere on the firm foundation of that primeval, yet indestructible granite of the human soul, &amp;ndash; religious faith.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Friedrich Max Muller, &lt;em&gt;Chips from a German Woodshop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Perhaps there are few people here present who have watched a sunrise more than once or twice in their lives; few people who have ever known the true meaning of a morning prayer, or a morning sacrifice.  But think of man at the dawn of time&amp;hellip; with his mind yet lying fallow, though full of germs - germs of which I hold as strongly as ever no trace has ever, no trace will ever, be discovered anywhere but in man; think of the Sun awakening the eyes of man from sleep, and his mind from slumber!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is a mere story, it might be said, and why should there be any meaning in it?  My answer is, because people do not tell such stories of their gods and heroes, unless there is some sense in them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Friedrich Max Muller, &amp;ldquo;On the Philosophy of Mythology&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both selections from Strenski, ed., &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Thinking-about-Religion-Ivan-Strenski/dp/140512167X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2/104-9600508-5525554?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1187838214&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;Thinking About Religion: A Reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Pascal&#39;s &#39;Thoughts&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-pascals-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2007 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-pascals-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never does one do evil so fully and so gaily as when one does it as a matter of conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;895&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What a man&amp;rsquo;s virtue is capable of is not to be measured by his exceptional efforts, but by his daily life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 352&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He must have movements of humiliation, not as a consequence of his nature, but of penitence; not as a constant attitude, but to permit him to rise to elevation.  He must have movements of elevation, not because of his merit, but through grace, and after passing through humiliation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 525&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, what advantage is there for us in hearing a man say that he has shaken off the yoke, that he does not believe there is a God watching over his actions, that he considers himself as sole master of his own conduct, and that he intends to be accountable to no one but himself?  Does he think he has inclined us in this way to have henceforth much confidence in him, and to expect from him consolation, counsel, and assistance in all the emergencies of life?  Do such people claim to have caused us to rejoice by telling us that they consider that our soul is only a little wind and smoke, and even by telling us so in a proud and smug tone of voice?  Is that really something to be said gaily?  Is it not on the contrary something to be said sadly, as the saddest thing in the world?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 194&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Faith declares indeed what the senses do not say but never the contrary of what they perceive.  Faith is above, and not against.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 265&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is being superstitious to put one&amp;rsquo;s hope in rites; but one is guilty of overweening pride in refusing to submit to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 294&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just examine whether a given pleasure is stable or fleeting; if it passes, it is a river of Babylon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 459&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is not from space that I must seek my dignity, but it is from the ordering of my thought.  The possession of lands would give me nothing more.  By space, the universe envelops me.  By thought, I envelop it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 348&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They imagine that, if they had obtained that post, they would rest afterwards with pleasure; but they do not recognize the insatiable nature of their desire.  They believe that they are sincerely seeking repose, and in reality they seek only agitation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Pensee 139&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
