<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Criticism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/criticism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Criticism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 20:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/criticism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A vacation and a reading list: a personal update</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-vacation-and-a-reading-list-a-personal-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-vacation-and-a-reading-list-a-personal-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe how quickly things happen.  My summer term - roughly six hours a day, five days a week of education classes - is drawing to a close, and as of Friday afternoon I&amp;rsquo;ll be free for an entire month (the life of a student is good - certainly beats two or three weeks of vacation over the course of a year).  I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Colorado (Boulder, Telluride, Denver) for almost two weeks, in Chicago for one, and in Muskegon for one - as well as a few days of camping in Northern Michigan with friends.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Whenever I prepare to travel, my thoughts quickly turn to the question of what books I will bring along and read.  I always make absurdly ambitious reading lists and pack way, way more than I could ever hope to finish, and this time is no exception.  I am bringing four:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Secular-Age-Charles-Taylor/dp/0674026764&#34;&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  About the rise of secularism in Western society.  Considered one of the most important books in the field of religious studies in recent decades.  Weighs in at a hefty 776 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/John-Cheever-Collected-Stories-Writings/dp/1598530348/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1248827741&amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;Collected Stories and Other Writings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Cheever is one of the best short fiction writers of the 20th century.  969 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Auerbach, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mimesis-Representation-Reality-Western-Literature/dp/069111336X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1248826434&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Mimesis: The Representation of Reality in Western Literature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Publishers Weekly&lt;/em&gt; says: &amp;ldquo;The author, beginning with Homer and the Bible, traces the imitation of life in literature through the ages &amp;hellip;touching upon every major literary figure in western culture on the way.&amp;rdquo;  A key work in 20th-century literary criticism.  574 pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dennis Lord Lloyd of Hampstead, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.librarything.com/work/3078393/details&#34;&gt;Introduction to Jurisprudence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  A vast, out-of-print, fantastically rich collection of writings on the philosophy of law and political philosophy - a mangled old book I believe I picked up for free in the box outside of the Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books in Hyde Park, Chicago.  981 pages (but I&amp;rsquo;ll skip writings that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to read for whatever reason).  From the &lt;em&gt;Independent&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/obituary-lord-lloyd-of-hampstead-1477249.html&#34;&gt;obituary&lt;/a&gt; of Lloyd: &amp;ldquo;As important to generations of students has been his encyclopaedic Introduction to Jurisprudence (1959). Lloyd was working on the sixth edition when he died. It was through this book that law students in much of the English- speaking world came to read Kelsen, Olivecrona, Savigny, Geny, Pashukanis, giants of continental juristic thought otherwise largely inaccessible. The recipe of wise text and suitably chosen extract remains a model guide to the study of legal thought. To the text he brought his own philosophical training, his culture and his erudition. The Introduction has its detractors but it remains the standard student text on the subject.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Will I succeed in finishing all of these, or any of them?  Most likely not.  If history is any guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll buy some other book or books during vacation and distract myself with those, or I&amp;rsquo;ll get heavily involved with my writing, almost as a way of avoiding my reading with a good conscience.  But if I restrict my book-reading to these four tomes and read around 118 pages a day for 27 days, I could do it - so that&amp;rsquo;s the bar I&amp;rsquo;m setting for myself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait.  Two more days of finishing my summer projects, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be free to travel, read, and write without restrictions for an entire month.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal update: spring quarter</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is turning out to be one of the busiest times of my life, so I won’t be posting very much over the next nine weeks.  For one thing, my coursework is forcing me to put most of my personal reading list on the back-burner, so I’ll have fewer excerpts to share.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the academic stress, however, things are better than ever.  My classes are awesome – a Ph.D.-level seminar in Japanese literature of the 1920s and 30s taught from a Marxist perspective (the first time I’ve really had to grapple with critical theory), the third quarter of elementary Norwegian (which I’m taking in the hope of traveling to Norway and studying Knut Hamsun and other Norwegian writers in the original language), the third quarter of fourth-year modern Japanese (which amounts to taking a course with a top-notch private tutor, as there are only three of us in the class), and Jean-Bethke Elshtain’s course on the Just War tradition – a Divinity School course offering a perspective on war and peace that is completely different from the realist perspective of the political science department that I’m used to hearing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than that, I am finishing my M.A. (on the consequences of China’s rise for East Asian security), meeting new people, exploring the city, and spending as much time as possible with my friends.  Spring is here, the quads are full of students, and my last quarter at the U of C is shaping up to be one of the best.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
