<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>East Asia on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/east-asia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in East Asia on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/east-asia/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nuclear Peace and its Consequences for China&#39;s Rise</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just put the finishing touches on my M.A. thesis, bringing one of the most stressful months of my life to a satisfying close.  10,181 words, 45 pages, three entirely different drafts, and an ungodly amount of writing and revision.  I am happy with the finished product and will turn it in tomorrow morning, then post a link to it online.  My faculty advisor was &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Mearsheimer&#34;&gt;John Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt;, the best professor I&amp;rsquo;ve had at the U of C and one of the most influential international relations scholars in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thesis:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I argue that security conflict between the U.S. and China can be managed short of war, regardless of how strong China becomes. This is the case because of the phenomenon known as the “nuclear peace”; because every great power in the contemporary international system possesses a secure, second-strike nuclear capability, the best prediction we can make is that every possible conflict between the U.S. and China - or any pair of contemporary great powers - will be stopped short of war because of nuclear deterrence, which raises the costs of war to unacceptably high levels, outweighing all potential political gains to be had by conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this behind me, I&amp;rsquo;m turning my mind away from school and on to other things, with the exception of my Japanese and Norwegian coursework.  I still need to finish Thomas Mann&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading several books on education: Alfie Kohn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;What Does It Mean to Be Well Educated?, &lt;/em&gt;Nel Nodding&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Education&lt;/em&gt;, and Myron Lieberman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Educational Morass, &lt;/em&gt;among others.  I am extremely excited for this weekend, as I am going home to Muskegon, MI to hang out with my wonderful family for the first time since March.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel as though an enormous burden has been lifted from me.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from the week&#39;s reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weeks-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weeks-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For whom, he thought, that splendor?  For me alone?&lt;br /&gt;Yet it will be here long after I perish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Czeslaw Milosz, from &amp;ldquo;Study of Loneliness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do not neglect to show hospitality to strangers, for thereby some have entertained angels unawares.  Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them; and those who are ill-treated, since you are also in the body.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Hebrews 13:1-3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The behavior of individual consumers and producers in the rational pursuit of their objectives is governed by the principle of marginal utility, or marginality.  On the demand side of the economy, according to marginal-utility analysis, as consumers consume more and more of a good they experience diminishing utility; that is, while the first ice cream sundae consumed may be devoured with great pleasure, each additional sundae provides less pleasure (decreasing utility) and the demand of the individual for more sundaes decreases.  &amp;hellip; The one possible exception to the principle of marginal utility, at least for most individuals, is the desire for wealth itself, a desire that appears insatiable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Robert Gilpin, &lt;em&gt;Global Political Economy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sense of belonging that bound the villagers to their village community was reinforced by social and economic factors.  Population movements among the rural population were slight.  Most families had lived in their villages as far back as memory could stretch, and membership in the village was a kind of birthright.  This population stability over generations created a sense of local roots that is now unimaginable in highly mobile American society, where people change jobs and houses at the drop of a hat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Peter Duus, &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Modern Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now faith is the assurance of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Hebrews 11:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;day draws near&lt;br /&gt;another one&lt;br /&gt;do what you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Czeslaw Milosz, from &amp;ldquo;On Angels&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just because people were diligent did not mean they had to be abstemious.  Enjoyment was not to be repressed, a notion associated with traditional American attitudes toward work and achievement, but rather to be put in its proper place.  The pursuit of pleasure, sexual and otherwise, was regarded as natural and inevitable, to be condemned only when it threatened to put diligence and frugality behind it.  Thus it was possible, as one recent observer has noted, for the Japanese to be Protestant by day and Mediterranean by night, an enviable cultural compromise.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Peter Duus, &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Modern Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems from the Far East</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems-from-the-far-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems-from-the-far-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My recent fascination with Korean poetry continues, and tonight I spent an hour or two reading Japanese poetry as well.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a small sample of what I found:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sad creature, neck stretched out;&lt;br /&gt;Dignified always, you say nothing at all.&lt;br /&gt;With your crown so fragrant,&lt;br /&gt;Yours was too noble a clan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you stare into the depths&lt;br /&gt;And think of lost legends,&lt;br /&gt;In overwhelming sadness, you turn your neck&lt;br /&gt;And look toward mountains far away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Ch’onmyong&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent, but…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I may be silent, but&lt;br /&gt;I’m thinking.&lt;br /&gt;I may not talk, but&lt;br /&gt;Don’t mistake me for a wall.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tsuboi Shigeji&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Through the train window,&lt;br /&gt;Far away to the north,&lt;br /&gt;The hills above my home&lt;br /&gt;Come slowly into sight,&lt;br /&gt;And I straighten my collar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ishikawa Takuboku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, my friends&lt;br /&gt;All seemed to be&lt;br /&gt;More a success than I.&lt;br /&gt;So I brought flowers&lt;br /&gt;And took them to&lt;br /&gt;My wife, to make her happy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ishikawa Takuboku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How far far away&lt;br /&gt;one star looks, when I’m lying on my back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At the same time how near, as if linked&lt;br /&gt;by a golden thread to the corner of my squinting eye,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and in the night, when I gently wake,&lt;br /&gt;how tightly I press against the window-pane, peeping out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Abruptly, as if sprouting,&lt;br /&gt;as if waiting to be called, as if welcoming,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;suddenly, a lonely flame flares within my soul&lt;br /&gt;in regrets that gust like the wind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I rise in my white night-clothes&lt;br /&gt;and clasp my hands to my heart.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chong Chi-yong&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorrow of Parting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the ear of an anchor, a gull croaks.&lt;br /&gt;Suddenly, without a word, the anchor glides down.&lt;br /&gt;Startled, the seagull takes off.&lt;br /&gt;In a moment, the anchor turns pale in the water, sinking.&lt;br /&gt;And what the seagull feels becomes a wild, sad scream&lt;br /&gt;Lost in the wind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maruyama Kaoru&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night song of a traveler&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cold rain swirls savagely,&lt;br /&gt;The lantern in my head hardly&lt;br /&gt;Pierces the gloom at my feet,&lt;br /&gt;Walking through endless night.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should I be walking?&lt;br /&gt;I have put them aside – engulfing&lt;br /&gt;Bed, warm talk, light.  But&lt;br /&gt;Why should I be walking?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When dawn comes, before I sleep,&lt;br /&gt;Where should I get to?  And, once there,&lt;br /&gt;What should I do?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wet through to the skin –&lt;br /&gt;But, wet, I recall&lt;br /&gt;Only good memories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shall I go home?&lt;br /&gt;Or shall I go down&lt;br /&gt;That street of red lights?&lt;br /&gt;No.  Into the darkness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tachihara Michizo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Cumings&#39; &#39;Korea&#39;s Place in the Sun&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/bruce-cumings-koreas-place-in-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/bruce-cumings-koreas-place-in-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally finished University of Chicago professor Bruce Cumings&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Koreas-Place-Sun-History-Updated/dp/0393327027/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/103-2504500-4922224?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1176836960&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Korea&amp;rsquo;s Place in the Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; yesterday, and I give it the highest recommendation to anyone remotely interested in history. Even if you are not specifically interested in Korea or East Asia, this is one of those books that can transform your ideas about warfare, America&amp;rsquo;s role in the world, international relations, and history itself. It certainly had an enormous impact on my way of thinking about these things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Korea&amp;rsquo;s Place in the Sun&lt;/em&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;modern history&amp;rdquo; of Korea, and it spends most of its 500 pp. discussing Korea&amp;rsquo;s 20th century history from the Japanese occupation (1905-1945) to the present day. Cumings persuasively argues that everything you have been taught about Korea and the Korean War (1950-51) is either wrong, lopsided, or inadequate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Did you know, for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Many Koreans, especially in the South and in the police force, collaborated with the Japanese occupation and fought against their countrymen for the Japanese. These Koreans later became the core of the U.S.-supported South Korean (Republic of Korea, or ROK) government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The Japanese empire forced many Korean laborers to relocate to Japan in the years before 1945 to build an underground imperial palace (in case of an American invasion) and to work in war factories. At least 10,000 of these Koreans were killed by the atomic bombs dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Those who survived the blasts were ostracized in Korea and not welcomed into Korean or Japanese society.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-On August 10, 1945, U.S. colonels Dean Rusk and Charles Bonesteel spent 30 minutes or less looking at a map of Korea before deciding to divide it in two at the 38th parallel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-There was no clear aggressor in the Korean War, and neither the North nor the South acknowledged the legitimacy of the 38th parallel as an international border. Both sides wanted war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The U.S. occupied Korea between 1945-1948, during which time it chose to side with the elite minority of landowners in South Korea in the belief that the demand for land reform - universal among the peasantry - smacked of communism. &amp;ldquo;Within one week Americans in Seoul, who had never met a Korean, decided they knew which Korean political leaders they liked,&amp;rdquo; Cumings writes. Unfortunately, most of the elite minority with which the U.S. sided was tainted by collaboration with the Japanese colonizers. A State Department official wrote to Washington: &amp;ldquo;Korea is completely ripe for agitators&amp;hellip;. The most encouraging single factor in the political situation is the presence in Seoul of several hundred conservatives among the older and better educated Koreans. Although many of them have served the Japanese, that stigma ought eventually to disappear.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-To summarize the most important point in the book: The U.S. intervened on the side of the elite of Korean society, &amp;ldquo;nearly all of whom were widely perceived to have fattened under colonial rule while everybody else suffered.&amp;rdquo; This elite was &amp;ldquo;the smallest group in Korea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The U.S. considered using atomic weapons against the North from the very first days of the Korean War and during several crises that arose after the armistice that ended the war. &amp;ldquo;All sides of the war were guilty of atrocities,&amp;rdquo; but the U.S. bombings from the air - directed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curtis_Lemay&#34;&gt;Curtis LeMay&lt;/a&gt;, the mass-murderer responsible for the firebombings of Japan in WWII - were the most devastating aspect of the Korean War. &amp;ldquo;By 1952 just about everything in northern and central Korea was completely leveled. What was left of the population survived in caves, the North Koreans creating an entire life underground, in complexes of dwellings, schools, hospitals, and factories.&amp;rdquo; Most horrible of all was the decision to bomb the North&amp;rsquo;s irrigation dams, which &amp;ldquo;provided water for 75 percent of the North&amp;rsquo;s food production.&amp;rdquo; The destruction of the dams led to the mass starvation of peasants completely unconnected with the war or the politics behind it, people who knew nothing of &amp;ldquo;containment&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;communism.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Following the Korean War, North Korea became a left-wing dictatorship under Kim il Sung and his son Kim Jong Il, and it remains so today. South Korea became a right-wing dictatorship under Syngman Rhee and his successors, and it did not become a democracy until 1997. The democratization process in South Korea was significantly slowed by U.S. policies that coddled the South Korean dictators; several pro-democracy demonstrations and uprisings were put down by the ROK regime using American-supplied tear gas and other weaponry, sometimes resulting in death tolls that rivaled the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre in China.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I could go on, but that&amp;rsquo;s enough for now. Everyone who studies history and has opinions about politics and warfare should go out of their way to study Korea&amp;rsquo;s experience in the past century. This history is a sad tale of &lt;em&gt;avoidable&lt;/em&gt; tragedies.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
