<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Free Trade on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/free-trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Free Trade on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 13:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/free-trade/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Gilpin on the case for free trade</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-gilpin-on-the-case-for-free-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-gilpin-on-the-case-for-free-trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economists of every persuasion are convinced that free trade is superior to trade protection. In fact, they consider free trade to be the best policy for a country even if all other countries should practice trade protection, arguing that if other countries resort to trade protection, the economy that remained open would still gain more from cheaper imports than it would lose in denied export markets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Underlying this liberal commitment to free trade is the belief that the purpose of economic activity is to benefit the consumer and maximize global wealth. Free trade also maximizes consumer choice, reduces prices, and facilitates efficient use of the world&amp;rsquo;s scarce resources.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Economists have strongly disputed the alleged benefits of trade protection. Trade protection, they point out, reduces both national and international economic efficiency by preventing countries from exporting those goods and services in which they have a comparative advantage and from importing those goods and services in which they lack comparative advantage. Protection also decreases the incentive of firms to innovate and thus climb the technological ladder; it also discourages shifting natural resources to their most profitable use.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Most American economists have&amp;hellip; attributed almost all of the relative decline in the wages of low-skilled American workers to technological changes within the American economy itself. Technological changes such as the computer and information economy, they have argued, significantly decreased the demand for low-skilled workers and greatly increased the demand for skilled, especially college-educated, workers. Furthermore, these economists have noted that the relatively small trade flows between the United States and low-wage economies cannot possibly explain the roughly 30 percent difference in wages between skilled/college-educated and unskilled workers in America. Instead, this decline in the wages of low-skilled workers has been due to such technological changes as automation, lean production techniques, and computerization.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is certain that trade protection is not a wise solution to the problems of stagnant wages, income inequality, and job insecurity. The solution lies in job-training programs and other programs to aid adjustment to rapidly changing economic and technological developments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Trade, however, does create losers as well as winners in the areas of both wages and employment. Economic sectors in which a nation possesses or wins a comparative advantage gain from trade, while sectors in which a nation loses comparative advantage suffer. As losers frequently feel the pain more acutely than winners feel the gain, both ethical and political reasons make it necessary that national policy assist or compensate workers and others harmed by trade liberalization. In any case, the worst response a nation can make to inevitable shifts in comparative advantage is to close itself off from the stimulus of trade competition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Gilpin, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Global-Political-Economy-Understanding-International/dp/8125023062/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-9384903-0615323?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1187804857&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Global Political Economy: Understanding the International Economic Order&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, ch. 8.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from the weekend&#39;s reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The (National Assessment of Educational Progress economics exam), taken by a representative sample of twelfth graders at public and private high schools, tested students on micro- and macroeconomic principles and international trade. What, for example, is the effect of breaking down trade barriers between countries? A majority correctly said that goods would become less expensive. They chose this over &amp;ldquo;the quality of goods available would decrease.&amp;rdquo; Maybe John Edwards should hire more teenagers for his Presidential campaign.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/The%20exam,%20taken%20by%20a%20representative%20sample%20of%20twelfth%20graders%20at%20public%20and%20private%20high%20schools,%20tested%20students%20on%20micro-%20and%20macroeconomic%20principles%20and%20international%20trade.%20What,%20for%20example,%20is%20the%20effect%20of%20breaking%20down%20trade%20barriers%20between%20countries?&#34;&gt;The Kids Are All Right&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 10-10-07&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ms. Rodham skates earnestly on the surface of life, raising more questions than answers. “Last week I decided that even if life is absurd why couldn’t I spend it absurdly happy?” she wrote in November of her junior year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times, &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/29/us/politics/29letter.html?ex=1187150400&amp;en=a261bdf200dc7c3e&amp;amp;ei=5070&#34;&gt;In the &amp;lsquo;60s, a Future Candidate Poured Her Heart Out in Letters&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 7-29-07 (must-read - the best article I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in this entire campaign cycle, and it made me a lot more enthusiastic about the Clinton campaign. I continue, however, to support Obama.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, Eleseus was sent to town after all; Inger managed that. &amp;hellip;Now and again he asked for money, something towards his expenses. A watch and chain, for instance, he must have, so as not to oversleep himself in the morning and be late at the office; money for a pipe and tobacco also, such as the other young clerks in the town always had. And for something he called pocket-money, and something he called evening classes, where he learned drawing and gymnastics and other matters proper to his rank and position. Altogether, it was no light matter to keep Eleseus going in a berth in town.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pocket money?&amp;rdquo; said Isak. &amp;ldquo;Is that money to keep in your pocket, maybe?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There was trouble in his mind, like enough, but he bore it silently, and made no scene. Oh, there was something great about Isak; as it might be Israel, promised and ever deceived, but still believing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later in the year Inger was sent for down to the village, to do dressmaking for some of the great folks there.  Inger could not go; she had a household to look after, and animals besides, all the work of a home, and she had no servant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Had no what?  Servant!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She spoke to Isak one day.  &amp;ldquo;If only I had someone to help me, I could put in more time sewing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak did not understand.  &amp;ldquo;Help?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, help in the house - a servant-girl.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak must have been taken aback at this; he laughed a little in his iron beard, and took it as a jest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
