<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University of Chicago on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/university-of-chicago/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University of Chicago on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 07:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/university-of-chicago/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling the dice in Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Rolling the dice in Libya,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. If you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or emailing it to a friend. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rolling the dice in Libya&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Barack Obama won the Democratic nomination in 2008 partly by reminding the party’s base of his early, prescient criticisms of the ill-fated decision to invade Iraq. “What I am opposed to is a dumb war … a rash war,” then-Senator Obama explained in 2002.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama was right to call the Iraq War “dumb” and “rash”: the Bush administration’s decision to invade Iraq was based not just on an “intelligence failure,” but on flagrant hubris, ignorance of geography and history, and unawareness of the limits of American power in the 21st century. And yet the Obama administration demonstrated each of these failings  in deciding to involve the U.S. in Libya’s civil war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Much ado was made about the U.S. “handing over” the Libya mission to NATO after dominating the first stage of the operation. But NATO is best understood as a multilateral cloak for American power; the U.S. has a military far larger and more advanced than any of its NATO allies, and it is by far the largest contributor to NATO’s budget.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The U.S.-NATO mission in Libya, we are told again and again, is nothing more than a temporary “humanitarian” operation to protect civilians. Since we are still bombing away at Col. Moammar Gadhafi’s military, one would think that Gadhafi’s forces are still on the verge of massacring defenseless civilians in rebel-held cities. But then we learn of “progress” in the war: under the cover of U.S./NATO-provided air power, rebels have taken cities from Gadhafi’s forces and advanced closer to Tripoli.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apparently, “protecting civilians” means attempting to crush the Libyan government forces and turn the tide of the civil war in the rebels’ favor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Defenders of the intervention appeal to our sense of decency by warning of the “genocide” that might have occurred had events in Libya been permitted to run their course, but this is nothing more than conjecture. It is possible to defend any course of action by asserting that a worst-case scenario would have occurred had the action not been taken. However, our worst fears usually do not turn out to be accurate predictors of the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the Obama administration’s protests to the contrary, what was sold as an effort to protect Libyan civilians has quickly developed into an unstated commitment to regime-change in Libya, with all the long-term challenges, obligations, and uncertainties that entails. It has also morphed into a full embrace of the Libyan rebels, though no one is sure exactly what the rebels stand for, or whether they have a workable plan to restore stability and govern the country democratically in a post-Gadhafi era.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like Bush’s decision to invade Iraq, Obama’s decision to intervene in Libya relied upon wishful thinking about the post-intervention course of events. Bush assured us that the conflict in Iraq would be swift, decisive, and relatively painless for the U.S.; Obama assured us that the mission in Libya would not require ground troops or a sustained American commitment and that it would be over in “days, not weeks.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But as political scientist Robert Pape has shown, air power alone is rarely, if ever, sufficient to achieve a state’s aims in war. And the “days” of U.S. involvement have already become “weeks” and will soon become “months,” as they tend to do in wars—which are, after all, unpredictable and uncontrollable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Obama has joined the long line of presidents who have been blinded by U.S. power and failed to perceive the limits of that power. He is likely to fail in Libya—or pay a high price for a very limited and temporary success—because he chose to ignore the advice of the great strategist Carl von Clausewitz, who wrote: “War is the realm of chance. … Chance makes everything more uncertain and interferes with the whole course of events.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The hopes and expectations of war supporters are routinely dashed by the complexity of reality. War plans often rely on best-case scenarios and assume that the planners are gifted with such foresight and judgment that they can realistically project how events will unfold. But the human actors driving these events on the ground often respond quite unpredictably to changes in their situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prudent policymakers and citizens should expect hasty wars of choice based on rose-eyed assumptions to fail and to have unforeseen consequences that last decades. This is not the outcome we hope for in the Libya war, but it is the outcome we can most safely bet on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from the stories of John Cheever</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s1600-h/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5391933763386061634&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s400/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 307px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 400px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was after four then, and I lay in the dark, listening to the rain and to the morning trains coming through.  They come from Buffalo and Chicago and the Far West, through Albany and down along the river in the early morning, and at one time or another I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled on most of them, and I lay in the dark thinking about the polar air in the Pullman cars and the smell of nightclothes and the taste of dining-car water and the way it feels to end a day in Cleveland or Chicago and begin another in New York, particularly after you&amp;rsquo;ve been away for a couple of years, and particularly in the summer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I took the eight-ten train into town in the morning and returned on the six-thirty.  I knew enough to avoid the empty house in the summer dusk, and I drove directly from the station parking lot to a good restaurant called Orpheo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Cure&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.  It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful color.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Chaste Clarissa&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt that he was a captive of financial and sentimental commitments, like every other man I know, and that he was no more free to fall in love with a strange woman he saw on a street corner than he was to take a walking trip through French Guiana or to recommence his life in Chicago under an assumed name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is divorce so dreadful and of all the things that hold a marriage together how many of them are good?&amp;rdquo; She sat down at the table.  &amp;ldquo;In Grenoble,&amp;rdquo; she said, &amp;ldquo;I wrote a long paper on Charles Stuart in French.  A professor at the University of Chicago wrote me a letter.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t read a French newspaper without a dictionary today, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to follow any newspaper, and I am ashamed of my incompetence, ashamed of the way I look.  Oh, I guess I love you, I do love the children, but I love myself, I love my life, it has some value and some promise for me and Trencher&amp;rsquo;s roses make me feel that I&amp;rsquo;m losing this, that I&amp;rsquo;m losing my self-respect.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Walking down Lexington Avenue, we heard the drone bass of a church organ sound from the sky, and we and the others on the sidewalk looked up in piety and bewilderment, like a devout and stupid congregation, and saw a formation of heavy bombers heading for the sea.  As it got late, it got cold and clear and still, and on the stillness the waste from the smokestacks along the East River seemed to articulate, as legibly as the Pepsi-Cola plane, whole words and sentences.  Halcyon.  Disaster.  They were hard to make out.  It seemed the ebb of the year - an evil day for gastritis, sinus, and respiratory disease - and remembering other winters, the markings of the light convinced me that it was the season of divorce.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I think that the seriousness of the day affected the children, and when they returned to the house, they were quiet.  The seriousness of it kept coming to me with the feeling that this change, like a phenomenon of speed, was affecting our watches as well as our hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Now when I come home in the evenings, Ethel is still sitting on the stool by the sink cleaning vegetables.  I go with her into the children&amp;rsquo;s room.  The light there is bright.  The children have built something out an orange crate, something preposterous and ascendant, and their sweetness, their compulsion to build, the brightness of the light are reflected perfectly and increased in Ethel&amp;rsquo;s face.  Then she feeds them, bathes them, and sets the table, and stands for a moment in the middle of the room, trying to make some connection between the evening and the day.  Then it is over.  She lights the four candles, and we sit down to our supper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Season of Divorce&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true of even the best of us that if an observer can catch us boarding a train at a way station; if he will mark our faces, stripped by anxiety of their self-possession; if he will appraise our luggage, our clothing, and look out of the window to see who has driven us to the station; if he will listen to the harsh or tender things we say if we are with our families, or notice the way we put our suitcase onto the rack, check the position of our wallet, our key ring, and wipe the sweat off the back of our necks; if he can judge sensibly the self-importance, diffidence, or sadness with which we settle ourselves, he will be given a broader view of our lives than most of us would intend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Summer Farmer&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with the University of Chicago Magazine</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/interview-with-the-university-of-chicago-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/interview-with-the-university-of-chicago-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UChiBLOGo, the blog of the &lt;em&gt;University of Chicago Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed me about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt; and the idea of self-education today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://uchiblogo.uchicago.edu/archives/2009/08/wide_awake_mind.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and please pass the interview along to others if you enjoy reading it.  Thanks for helping to spread the word about self-education!&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for Facebook and social networking</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Facebook currently has over 200 million active users, many people continue to doubt the value of social networking in general and Facebook in particular.  Critics argue that Facebook and other social networking and Web 2.0 tools - including blogs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - are symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;solipsism&amp;rdquo; (meaning, in this context, the self-absorption of users) of the contemporary Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, Facebook can be an enormous time-waster and procrastination tool, as can any medium or Internet resource.  I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected a lot about my own use of the site over the past six years or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself whether it is a worthwhile use of my time and an appropriate way - one among others, obviously - to communicate with my friends, family, colleagues, and acquaintances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate was largely settled for me a few months ago when I heard a remarkable lecture by Clara Shih, social networking expert and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefacebookera.com/&#34;&gt;The Facebook Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shih spoke in April at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Booth School of Business, and I was in attendance to sell copies of her book.  (I was working as a manager at a bookstore at the time).  I went in with low expectations, as I generally take a dim view of the overcrowded genre of popular business books in general and books on making money through technology in particular.  But Shih&amp;rsquo;s presentation blew me away; she made me see Facebook and social networking in an entirely different light, and she helped me understand the many complex issues involved with social networking, and the utility social networking tools can have for those willing to critically evaluate and monitor their use of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The core reason for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s popularity, according to Shih, is that it lowers the cost of keeping in touch.  Keeping in touch with people you&amp;rsquo;ve met is a difficult and time-consuming process.  Facebook makes it much, much easier.  And it can help us keep in touch in a more meaningful way: there is less need to small talk with distant friends about where they are working, what they are studying, where they are living, and so forth - it&amp;rsquo;s all out there on their Facebook page, and so we can keep track of people we&amp;rsquo;ve met as they move through their lives.  When we think of them, we can think of who they are and what they are doing &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; rather than who they were when we met them years before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This powerful idea was brought home to me again this month, as the host family I lived with in Italy for ten weeks in my sophomore year of college joined Facebook and &amp;ldquo;Friended&amp;rdquo; me.  It takes a lot of effort to write a letter in Italian, put it in an envelope, wait in line at the post office to buy international postage, and finally send it - but it takes ten seconds to write on their &amp;ldquo;walls.&amp;rdquo;  And so I am much more likely to do the latter than the former, and our relationship need not be weakened by our falling out of touch.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy Doniger&#39;s &#39;The Hindus: An Alternative History&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s1600-h/doniger.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s400/doniger.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5330565091969721250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently picked up Wendy Doniger&amp;rsquo;s new book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hindus-Alternative-History-Wendy-Doniger/dp/1594202052&#34;&gt;The Hindus: An Alternative History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Doniger, the Mircea Eliade Distinguished Service Professor of Religions at the University of Chicago Divinity School and America&amp;rsquo;s foremost scholar of Hinduism, set out to challenge many prevailing notions of Hinduism and argue for a more inclusive, broad view of the tradition, a view that recognizes the diversity of folk religions in the Hindu world as well as the contributions of women, Muslims, and people of the lower castes to the Hindu tradition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The book was reviewed last weekend in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times Book Review&lt;/em&gt;, and it is slated to be chosen as an Editor&amp;rsquo;s Pick next week.  A comment by Professor Doniger can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://newsweek.washingtonpost.com/onfaith/panelists/wendy_doniger/2009/03/the_battle_over_hindu_history.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the favorable &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; review by Pankaj Mishra can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/26/books/review/Mishra-t.html?_r=1&amp;ref=books&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nuclear Peace and its Consequences for China&#39;s Rise</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just put the finishing touches on my M.A. thesis, bringing one of the most stressful months of my life to a satisfying close.  10,181 words, 45 pages, three entirely different drafts, and an ungodly amount of writing and revision.  I am happy with the finished product and will turn it in tomorrow morning, then post a link to it online.  My faculty advisor was &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Mearsheimer&#34;&gt;John Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt;, the best professor I&amp;rsquo;ve had at the U of C and one of the most influential international relations scholars in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thesis:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I argue that security conflict between the U.S. and China can be managed short of war, regardless of how strong China becomes. This is the case because of the phenomenon known as the “nuclear peace”; because every great power in the contemporary international system possesses a secure, second-strike nuclear capability, the best prediction we can make is that every possible conflict between the U.S. and China - or any pair of contemporary great powers - will be stopped short of war because of nuclear deterrence, which raises the costs of war to unacceptably high levels, outweighing all potential political gains to be had by conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this behind me, I&amp;rsquo;m turning my mind away from school and on to other things, with the exception of my Japanese and Norwegian coursework.  I still need to finish Thomas Mann&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading several books on education: Alfie Kohn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;What Does It Mean to Be Well Educated?, &lt;/em&gt;Nel Nodding&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Education&lt;/em&gt;, and Myron Lieberman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Educational Morass, &lt;/em&gt;among others.  I am extremely excited for this weekend, as I am going home to Muskegon, MI to hang out with my wonderful family for the first time since March.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel as though an enormous burden has been lifted from me.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for a School of Education at the University of Chicago</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-a-school-of-education-at-the-university-of-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2007 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-a-school-of-education-at-the-university-of-chicago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s unsigned &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/11/02/a-failing-grade/&#34;&gt;editorial&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Maroon&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is often referred to as the “Teacher of Teachers.” U of C graduates tend to go into academia at much higher rates than do those at peer schools, and many of the ideas associated with the University—the “Life of the Mind,” “Chicago Math,” and “progressive education,” for example—are directly relevant to the challenges faced by America’s K–12 schools.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having benefited from a great education, many Chicago students would appreciate the opportunity to introduce the next generation of students to the world of ideas. Unfortunately, their desire to do so runs headlong into a system that discourages them from teaching in public schools.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was not always the case. John Dewey, arguably the greatest educational theorist of the 20th century, started the U of C’s School of Education in 1895. The program was allowed to deteriorate until it was finally shut down in 2001. Students in the College now have no way to earn teaching certification or study the discipline of education during their undergraduate years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Each year, many U of C graduates enter Teach for America or other alternative certification programs. Such programs tend to send recent graduates to the toughest, most disadvantaged schools in the country, with minimal training. Although many graduates are able to rise to this challenge, the high turnover rate shows that these programs are not appropriate for everyone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;U of C students who want to teach generally must choose between alternative certification programs and graduate school in education. But the burden of student loans combined with relatively low teacher salaries often precludes the latter option. The current system encourages U of C students with a desire to teach to become investment bankers or consultants instead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a growing consensus in American society that education at the K–12 level needs to be a top priority if American workers are to remain internationally competitive. America’s schools will continue to underperform if the best minds of our generation are turned away from the profession because of financial and practical constraints. As long as the University does not provide a way for students at the College to pursue certification as undergraduates, the University is part of the problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The administration should commission a study to determine the best way to reinvent the School of Education and make it one of the top programs in the country. This would fit comfortably with the University’s traditional focus on research and theory as well as with the administration’s goal of giving back to the community. It’s the least a place that preaches the merits of the “Life of the Mind” can do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Maroon Editorial Board consists of the Editor-in-Chief, Managing Editor, Viewpoints Editors, and an additional Editorial Board member. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Paul Tillich and a poem by Mark Strand</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-paul-tillich-and-a-poem-by-mark-strand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And, certainly, the way to maturity in thinking is a difficult path.  Much must be left behind: early dreams, poetic imaginations, cherished legends, favored doctrines, accustomed laws and ritual traditions.  Some of them must be restored on a deeper level, some must be given up.  Despite this price, maturity can be gained - a manly, self-critical, convincing faith, not produced by reasoning, but reasonable, and at the same time rooted in the message of the divine foolishness, the ultimate source of wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From century to century it has become more and more evident that knowledge without wisdom produces external and internal self-destruction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He who has encountered the mystery of life has reached the source of wisdom.  In encountering it with awe and longing, he experiences the infinite distance of his being from that which is the ground of his being.  He experiences the limits of his being, his finitude in face of the infinite.  He learns that acceptance of one&amp;rsquo;s limits is the decisive step towards wisdom.  The fool rebels against the limits set by his finitude.  He wants to be unlimited in power and knowledge.  He who is wise accepts his finitude.  He knows that he is not God.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;  &amp;ndash;The Eternal Now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man in Black&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was walking downtown&lt;br /&gt;when I noticed a man in black,&lt;br /&gt;black cape and black boots, coming toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His arms out in front of him,&lt;br /&gt;his fingers twinkling with little rings,&lt;br /&gt;he looked like a summer night full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was summer.  The night was full of stars.&lt;br /&gt;the tall buildings formed a hallway down which I walked.&lt;br /&gt;The man in black came toward me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The waxed tips of his mustache shone&lt;br /&gt;like tiny spears and his teeth glistened.&lt;br /&gt;I offered him my hand which he did not take.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt like a fool and stood in his black wake,&lt;br /&gt;shaken and small, and my tears&lt;br /&gt;swung back and forth in the sultry air like chandeliers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mark Strand&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortimer J. Adler on war and peace</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our view of war, then, must be broadened to include both armed conflict and battles of diplomacy, economic aid, and propaganda. War is war, whether it is &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cold.&amp;rdquo; The struggle for power and prestige among the nations goes on all the time. Only the means vary, and whether these be armed force or diplomatic pressure or other nonviolent means depends on the occasion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It follows, then, that peace is not merely a negative thing - the absence of armed conflict. What real, positive peace among the nations would be we may see by considering the state of affairs in local, state, and national communities. In our civil society, peace and order, not war, are the normal state of things. The whole meaning and purpose of civil society is peace and order. Civil government creates civil peace. Individuals who violate the law are disturbers of the peace and are dealt with accordingly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Contrary to a lot of loose talk, it is peace and not war that is proper to human nature. Cicero and many other thinkers rightly point out that fighting and snarling are the way of brute beasts, while talking things over and listening to reason are the proper way for men. Peace is required not only for our material survival but also for a really human existence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mortimer J. Adler, &lt;em&gt;Great Ideas from the Great Books&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Mearsheimer&#39;s &#39;The Tragedy of Great Power Politics&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-mearsheimers-the-tragedy-of-great-power-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-mearsheimers-the-tragedy-of-great-power-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In international politics, God helps those who help themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because Americans dislike realpolitik, public discourse about foreign policy in the United States is usually couched in the language of liberalism.  Hence the pronouncements of the policy elites are heavily flavored with optimism and moralism.  &amp;hellip;Behind closed doors, however, the elites who make national security policy speak mostly the language of power, not that of principle, and the United States acts in the international system according to the dictates of realist logic.  In essence, a discernible gap separates public rhetoric from the actual conduct of American foreign policy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For better or worse, states are rarely willing to expend blood and treasure to protect foreign populations from gross abuses, including genocide.  For instance, despite claims that American foreign policy is filled with moralism, Somalia (1992-93) is the only instance during the past one hundred years in which U.S. soldiers were killed in action on a humanitarian mission.  And in that case, the loss of a mere eighteen soldiers in an infamous firefight in October 1993 so traumatized American policymakers that they immediately pulled all U.S. troops out of Somalia and then refused to intervene in Rwanda in the spring of 1994, when ethnic Hutu went on a genocidal rampage against their Tutsi neighbors.  Stopping that genocide would have been relatively easy and it would have had virtually no effect on the position of the United States in the balance of power.  Yet nothing was done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But sometimes the pursuit of non-security goals conflicts with balance-of-power logic, in which case states usually act according to the dictates of realism.  For example, despite the U.S. commitment to spreading democracy across the globe, it helped overthrow democratically elected governments and embraced a number of authoritarian regimes during the Cold War, when American policymakers felt that these actions would help contain the Soviet Union.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is difficult to imagine a modern political leader openly asking the public to fight and die to improve the balance of power.  No European or American leader did so during their world war or the Cold War.  Most people prefer to think of fights between their own state and rival states as clashes between good and evil, where they are on the side of the angels and their opponents are aligned with the devil.  Thus, leaders tend to portray war as a moral crusade or an ideological contest, rather than as a struggle for power.  Realism is a hard sell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John J. Mearsheimer, &lt;em&gt;The Tragedy of Great Power Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Cumings&#39; &#39;Korea&#39;s Place in the Sun&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/bruce-cumings-koreas-place-in-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/bruce-cumings-koreas-place-in-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally finished University of Chicago professor Bruce Cumings&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Koreas-Place-Sun-History-Updated/dp/0393327027/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/103-2504500-4922224?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1176836960&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Korea&amp;rsquo;s Place in the Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; yesterday, and I give it the highest recommendation to anyone remotely interested in history. Even if you are not specifically interested in Korea or East Asia, this is one of those books that can transform your ideas about warfare, America&amp;rsquo;s role in the world, international relations, and history itself. It certainly had an enormous impact on my way of thinking about these things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Korea&amp;rsquo;s Place in the Sun&lt;/em&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;modern history&amp;rdquo; of Korea, and it spends most of its 500 pp. discussing Korea&amp;rsquo;s 20th century history from the Japanese occupation (1905-1945) to the present day. Cumings persuasively argues that everything you have been taught about Korea and the Korean War (1950-51) is either wrong, lopsided, or inadequate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Did you know, for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Many Koreans, especially in the South and in the police force, collaborated with the Japanese occupation and fought against their countrymen for the Japanese. These Koreans later became the core of the U.S.-supported South Korean (Republic of Korea, or ROK) government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The Japanese empire forced many Korean laborers to relocate to Japan in the years before 1945 to build an underground imperial palace (in case of an American invasion) and to work in war factories. At least 10,000 of these Koreans were killed by the atomic bombs dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Those who survived the blasts were ostracized in Korea and not welcomed into Korean or Japanese society.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-On August 10, 1945, U.S. colonels Dean Rusk and Charles Bonesteel spent 30 minutes or less looking at a map of Korea before deciding to divide it in two at the 38th parallel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-There was no clear aggressor in the Korean War, and neither the North nor the South acknowledged the legitimacy of the 38th parallel as an international border. Both sides wanted war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The U.S. occupied Korea between 1945-1948, during which time it chose to side with the elite minority of landowners in South Korea in the belief that the demand for land reform - universal among the peasantry - smacked of communism. &amp;ldquo;Within one week Americans in Seoul, who had never met a Korean, decided they knew which Korean political leaders they liked,&amp;rdquo; Cumings writes. Unfortunately, most of the elite minority with which the U.S. sided was tainted by collaboration with the Japanese colonizers. A State Department official wrote to Washington: &amp;ldquo;Korea is completely ripe for agitators&amp;hellip;. The most encouraging single factor in the political situation is the presence in Seoul of several hundred conservatives among the older and better educated Koreans. Although many of them have served the Japanese, that stigma ought eventually to disappear.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-To summarize the most important point in the book: The U.S. intervened on the side of the elite of Korean society, &amp;ldquo;nearly all of whom were widely perceived to have fattened under colonial rule while everybody else suffered.&amp;rdquo; This elite was &amp;ldquo;the smallest group in Korea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-The U.S. considered using atomic weapons against the North from the very first days of the Korean War and during several crises that arose after the armistice that ended the war. &amp;ldquo;All sides of the war were guilty of atrocities,&amp;rdquo; but the U.S. bombings from the air - directed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curtis_Lemay&#34;&gt;Curtis LeMay&lt;/a&gt;, the mass-murderer responsible for the firebombings of Japan in WWII - were the most devastating aspect of the Korean War. &amp;ldquo;By 1952 just about everything in northern and central Korea was completely leveled. What was left of the population survived in caves, the North Koreans creating an entire life underground, in complexes of dwellings, schools, hospitals, and factories.&amp;rdquo; Most horrible of all was the decision to bomb the North&amp;rsquo;s irrigation dams, which &amp;ldquo;provided water for 75 percent of the North&amp;rsquo;s food production.&amp;rdquo; The destruction of the dams led to the mass starvation of peasants completely unconnected with the war or the politics behind it, people who knew nothing of &amp;ldquo;containment&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;communism.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Following the Korean War, North Korea became a left-wing dictatorship under Kim il Sung and his son Kim Jong Il, and it remains so today. South Korea became a right-wing dictatorship under Syngman Rhee and his successors, and it did not become a democracy until 1997. The democratization process in South Korea was significantly slowed by U.S. policies that coddled the South Korean dictators; several pro-democracy demonstrations and uprisings were put down by the ROK regime using American-supplied tear gas and other weaponry, sometimes resulting in death tolls that rivaled the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre in China.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I could go on, but that&amp;rsquo;s enough for now. Everyone who studies history and has opinions about politics and warfare should go out of their way to study Korea&amp;rsquo;s experience in the past century. This history is a sad tale of &lt;em&gt;avoidable&lt;/em&gt; tragedies.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. - South Korea ambassadors panel</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.---south-korea-ambassadors-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.---south-korea-ambassadors-panel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the priviledge of listening to the American ambassador to South Korea and the South Korean ambassador to the U.S. give a joint talk on political and economic conditions on the Korean peninsula. Both ambassadors centered their speeches around the issues of the recently agreed-upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ustr.gov/Document_Library/Press_Releases/2007/April/United_States_Korea_Conclude_Historic_Trade_Agreement.html&#34;&gt;KORUS FTA&lt;/a&gt;, or United States - Korea Free Trade Agreement, and the recent breakthrough on the North Korean nuclear issue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The KORUS FTA would be the biggest free trade agreement involving the U.S. since NAFTA; as such, it will run into a lot of opposition in Congress. There are plenty of domestic interest groups that benefit from the tariffs we place on imports from South Korea; the beef lobby will be especially difficult to placate, I was told. But it will be a major boost for most American businesses and consumers. South Korea is a staunch ally and the twelfth largest economy in the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the security side of things, the ambassadors spoke cautiously of a recent breakthrough in which the North Koreans agreed to dismantle their nuclear program and admit IAEA (Int&amp;rsquo;l Atomic Energy Agency) inspectors in exchange for reduced sanctions and normalization talks. As a first step, the U.S. freed $25 million of North Korean funds this week that we had frozen in a bank in Macau. If North Korea follows through, this could be a sign of enormous progress.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
