<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/economics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Great Depression and the New Deal</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in the history of the 1930s, and&amp;nbsp;I just finished Eric Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/IdP1dDU&#34;&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;It has become increasingly clear to me that there are major holes in the dominant historical narrative about the Great Depression, the New Deal, and the Roosevelt administration. &amp;nbsp;The standard, high-school-textbook version of the story goes something like this: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Greedy stock market speculators caused the stock market crash of 1929, which triggered the worst depression in American history; President Herbert Hoover believed in an outdated&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;economic philosophy, so he did nothing; thankfully, President Roosevelt was elected, and his New Deal policies saved capitalism and helped the common man survive the Great Depression; and finally, World War II was an enormous boon to the U.S. economy, and it finally solved the problem once and for all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those of us with a preference for economic liberty and peace should be greatly disturbed by this story. &amp;nbsp;If true, it suggests that&amp;nbsp;the best ways to fix a broken economy are&amp;nbsp;(1) total war, including conscription; and (2) dramatic increases in government taxation, spending, regulation, and redistribution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thankfully, there are convincing reasons to believe that the standard narrative is wrong. &amp;nbsp;There is a lot more I need to read on the topic, but here are some resources and ideas that I look forward to exploring further:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Murray N. Rothbard,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/rothbard/agd/contents.asp&#34;&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(free PDF and ebook)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terry.uga.edu/~selgin/econ4710/Econ4710Syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;The Economics of America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (course syllabus in PDF format with many links to readings). &amp;nbsp;My interest in this topic is largely attributable to a fantastic lecture I heard Selgin deliver in June.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-David Gordon, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/3349&#34;&gt;What you must read about the Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Mises Daily,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;2/22/09&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/article.aspx?record=157&amp;amp;month=5&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of Hall and Ferguson&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Robert P. Murphy,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PWGB3Mb&#34;&gt;The Politically Incorrect Guide to the Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stephen Davies, &amp;ldquo;Top 3 Myths About the Great Depression and the New Deal,&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnliberty.org/&#34;&gt;LearnLiberty.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/7QLoeehMw0w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my next post, I will share excerpts from Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/i&gt;, which - unlike the libertarian works linked to above - is firmly on the side of the standard narrative.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should we finish the books we begin?  It depends.</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/should-we-finish-the-books-we-begin--it-depends./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/should-we-finish-the-books-we-begin--it-depends./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2009/jul/24/edge-closing-the-book-on-a-bad-read/?page=2&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; published in Friday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Washington Times&lt;/em&gt;, economist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marginalrevolution.com/&#34;&gt;Tyler Cowen&lt;/a&gt; makes several interesting and provocative arguments about reading and books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  &amp;ldquo;What should you do when, 20, 50 or 100 pages in, you realize you just don&amp;rsquo;t like a book?&amp;rdquo;  Cowen says: &amp;ldquo;Give up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  &amp;ldquo;We should treat books a little more like we treat TV channels,&amp;rdquo; (Cowen) argues. No one has trouble flipping away from a boring series.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  &amp;ldquo;(Cowen) notes that many up-and-coming writers complain they can&amp;rsquo;t break through in a best-seller-driven marketplace. &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;re also making markets more efficient,&amp;rdquo; Mr. Cowen says. &amp;ldquo;If you can sample more books, you&amp;rsquo;re giving more people a chance.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The article goes on to discuss several other readers who advocate quitting &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo; books: &amp;ldquo;One of her online friends reminded her there&amp;rsquo;s even an abandonment rule: The &amp;lsquo;Deduct Your Age From 100 and Read That Many Pages Before Giving Up on a Book&amp;rsquo; rule&amp;rdquo;; and &amp;ldquo;Having an e-book reader has made Ms. Wendell more ruthless. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m holding 100+ books on one device. If one isn&amp;rsquo;t floating my boat, I can move on to something else by pressing one button,&amp;rdquo; she points out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So should we finish the books we begin?  The short answer: it depends.  On what?  That&amp;rsquo;s more difficult, but it depends on something more than how much we are &lt;em&gt;enjoying&lt;/em&gt; the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why did you pick up the book in the first place?  If you are reading for pure entertainment, it makes sense to put the book down if you aren&amp;rsquo;t feeling entertained after giving the book a fair shot.  But surely most readers read for more than pure entertainment; if &amp;ldquo;entertainment&amp;rdquo; were the ultimate goal, there would be no reason to prefer an entertaining book over an equally or more entertaining movie, television show, or video game.  In fact, I suspect that the widespread idea that books are primarily sources of entertainment is partially responsible for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nea.gov/news/news04/ReadingAtRisk.Html&#34;&gt;decline of book-reading&lt;/a&gt;, especially among young people, in recent decades.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I choose and read books that are rewarding and that will enrich my understanding of the world, of myself, and of the human condition.  If they are entertaining or exciting at the same time, so much the better, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t the primary goal.  In fact, my idea of what is &amp;ldquo;entertaining&amp;rdquo; has shifted.  I have conditioned myself to prefer forms of leisure - i.e., reading good books, practicing banjo and listening to music, engaging in good conversation, watching good movies - that are rewarding and educative.  So even if I am reading a book that I must struggle to get through, that to me is often more entertaining than reading, say, &lt;em&gt;Angels and Demons&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are, in short, problems with considering a book&amp;rsquo;s excitement and ease the most important factors in deciding whether to read it or finish it.  We build our literacy and expand our understanding by reading material that challenges us, just as a musician continually improves his or her proficiency in an instrument not by playing the same basic tunes over and over, but by constantly pushing his or her limits by tackling new, more frustrating and difficult works and techniques.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have as much trouble as anyone with finishing books, but some books are worth finishing regardless of whether I feel like finishing them.  The other week, I completed &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; after a slow, gradual, four-month effort.  &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; would certainly fail the &amp;ldquo;entertainment&amp;rdquo; test for the vast majority of readers, including me.  And yet it is now one of my favorite books, because Melville&amp;rsquo;s incredible use of language and his insights into religion, human nature, and life itself made &lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt; matter to me: I read it in the hope that it might change the way I write, think, and see the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck writes in &lt;em&gt;East of Eden&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;You can start reading if you want and it will raise up your lid a little.&amp;rdquo;  That&amp;rsquo;s as good a statement as any of what good books are for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Hat tip for the link to the Washington Times article: &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/&#34;&gt;Andrew Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent posts on education at Wide Awake Minds</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few of my recent posts at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, in case you missed them:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/few-of-things-you-can-do-in-great.html&#34;&gt;A few of the things you can do in a great university&lt;/a&gt;, in which I argue that if students want to make the most of their school years in general and their college years in particular, they must take ownership of their education and elect to do what is difficult.  I propose a few of the ways in which college students can do so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/thinking-critically-about-critical.html&#34;&gt;Thinking critically about critical pedagogy&lt;/a&gt;, in which I encourage my readers to recognize the reality and complexity of cultural and institutional racism, but also to think critically about the theoretical lenses of critical pedagogy (a framework aimed at correcting racism and other power disparities).  This post sparked a great discussion in the comment section as well as some fruitful email exchanges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/beyond-preparing-our-kids-for-21st.html&#34;&gt;Beyond &amp;ldquo;preparing our kids for 21st-century jobs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - a call to do away with sloganeering about education as job-preparation, and a brief sketch of the case for universal liberal education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/quotes-from-deborah-meiers-in-schools.html&#34;&gt;Ideas about education from Deborah Meier&lt;/a&gt;, one of the greatest progressive educators of our time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/building-collection-of-language_09.html&#34;&gt;On language learning textbooks&lt;/a&gt; - A personal account of my love of language learning textbooks, and what I have learned from them about how and why we should learn world languages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to link to it on your blog or social network or pass it along to someone who might be interested in reading it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Czeslaw Milosz and Herman Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished &amp;ldquo;Moby-Dick&amp;rdquo; yesterday. It was one of the most difficult books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read - but also incredibly beautiful and rewarding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The past is inaccurate, because we cannot determine how it was in fact, no matter how hard we try.  We must rely on people&amp;rsquo;s memory, which is treacherous, because memory is constantly juggling and revising the data of experience.  &amp;hellip;In telling about an event, we ourselves cannot avoid revising it, because our narrative simplifies and composes a whole out of selected components, while omitting others.  It suffices to compare our knowledge of facts with their depiction in chronicles, journalistic accounts, memoirs, to understand the need for fantasizing that is somehow inscribed in the language itself, and which draws us into the forest of fiction.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Los Angeles horrifies me.  In our imagination money is still steel and the production of factories; it is difficult to accustom oneself to the great change, the complete reversal, that has granted a marginal human activity, entertainment, its central position as a source of money or power.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I am moved by the very fact of that woman&amp;rsquo;s existence, of which all that has remained is this verse.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I know my own weakness and am inclined to consider myself&amp;hellip;as a tangle of reflexes, a drunken child in the fog.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The essential characteristic of fame is its illusory nature, for what does a famous name mean if those who mention it are not well-informed about why it is famous?  That, after all, is the fate of the majority of monuments in every large city; they turn into signs from which the content has evaporated.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Everything that enlarges man fortifies us; everything that depicts him as a multidimensional being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABCs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A whole hour now passed; gold-beaten out to ages.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What a lovely day again! were it a new-made world, and made for a summer-house to the angels, and this morning the first of its throwing open to them, a fairer day could not dawn upon that world.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ah! how they still strove through that infinite blueness to seek out the thing that might destroy them!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But Ahab&amp;rsquo;s glance was averted; like a blighted fruit tree he shook, and cast his last, cindered apple to the soil.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Close! stand close to me, Starbuck; let me look into a human eye; it is better than to gaze into sea or sky; better than to gaze upon God.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What! how can you see better of a dark night than anybody else, never mind how foolish?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Old man of oceans! of all this fiery life of thine, what at length will remain but one little heap of ashes!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let faith oust fact; let fancy oust memory; I look deep down and do believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Would to God these blessed calms would last. But the mingled, mingling threads of life are woven by warp and woof: calms crossed by storms, a storm for every calm. There is no steady unretracing progress in this life; we do not advance through fixed gradations, and at the last one pause: - through infancy&amp;rsquo;s unconscious spell, boyhood&amp;rsquo;s thoughtless faith, adolescence&amp;rsquo; doubt (the common doom), then scepticism, then disbelief, resting at last in manhood&amp;rsquo;s pondering repose of If. But once gone through, we trace the round again; and are infants, boys, and men, and Ifs eternally. Where lies the final harbor, whence we unmoor no more? in what rapt ether sails the world, of which the weariest will never weary?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I like a good grip; I like to feel something in this slippery world that can hold, man.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seat thyself sultanically among the moons of Saturn, and take high abstracted man alone; and he seems a wonder, a grandeur, and a woe. But from the same point, take mankind in mass, and for the most part, they seem a mob of unnecessary duplicates, both contemporary and hereditary. But most humble though he was, and far from furnishing an example of the high, humane abstraction; the Pequod&amp;rsquo;s carpenter was no duplicate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For many in Chicago, driving is a necessity, not a luxury</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My most recent op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/cgi-bin/mag/article.pl?articleId=32083&#34;&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (registration required) was published today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;Chicagobusiness.com&lt;/a&gt; and will appear in this week&amp;rsquo;s issue of &lt;em&gt;Crain&amp;rsquo;s Chicago Business&lt;/em&gt;.  You can find the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as reprinted below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is exceedingly difficult for many commuters living on the North Side to find free parking after they return from work. After an often agonizing rush-hour commute, they must circle around their neighborhood until they find a parking space; if they arrive too late, they must choose between parking at a meter and interrupting their lives every two hours to feed it, or parking a mile or more away from their homes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But if the North Side parking situation is a nightmare today, imagine what it will look like when the city installs meters along the entire lakefront, effectively eliminating a major artery of free parking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I commute every workday between my apartment near Belmont Avenue in East Lakeview and Hyde Park. If I drive, I spend around 50 minutes per day, including time spent finding parking, on the road. If I take public transportation, the same round trip can take as long as three hours. That adds an extra two hours to my workday, significantly reducing my time for leisure, exercise, relationships and everything else that is important in life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, for me and for many other commuters, driving is essential to maintaining a high quality of life in Chicago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many users of the free lakefront spots are commuters who do not have access to, cannot afford or choose not to purchase a space in a garage or a residential street parking permit. These commuters, like myself, look for free spots to park in overnight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new lakefront meters, which are scheduled to be in place by the fall, will mean that thousands of drivers will be competing for far fewer free spaces. Many commuters will spend more frustrated and stressful time on the road driving in circles in search of parking. Some will resort to paying an outrageous price to park in a garage. Others will give up driving and double or triple their commuting time by turning to public transit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For many Chicagoans, driving to work — and finding free or affordable parking after work — is a necessity, not a luxury. Contrary to the inclinations of Mayor Richard M. Daley and the city, it is not a vice that ought to be subject to endless taxation and fees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By significantly reducing the availability of free parking in lakefront neighborhoods without creating affordable alternatives for commuters, the new meters will make much of the city more expensive and inconvenient for everyone, including working families. They may boost the city&amp;rsquo;s revenue, but they will do so at the direct expense of the well-being and quality of life of thousands of its residents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Ryan McCarl is a freelance writer.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Kohak&#39;s &#39;The Embers and the Stars&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s1600-h/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 128px; height: 194px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s400/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5302889589404206306&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I recently discovered the work of Erazim Kohak, a Czech philosopher and Professor Emeritus at Boston University who has written extensively on environmental ethics.  I am 30 pages into Kohak&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/span&gt;, and it is incredible so far.  A few excerpts below, with more to come.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Reflection and speculation remain no more than cunningly devised fables if they are not grounded in what, paraphrasing Calvin Schrag, we could call the prephilosophical and prescientific matrix of self-understanding and world-comprehension.  Though philosophy must do much else as well, it must, initially, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;see&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; and, thereafter, ground its speculation ever anew in seeing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;It is, surely, good that there are synthetic medicines to ease the surplus of pain, telephones to break through loneliness, and electric lights to keep the wayfarer from stumbling.  There is, though, something wrong when we use medicine to deaden our sensitivity, when we obliterate solitude with electronics and blind ourselves with the very lights we devised to help us see.  There is nothing wrong with our artifacts; there &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;something wrong with us: we have lost sight of the sense, the purpose of our production and our products.  Artifacts, finally, are good only extrinsically, as tools.  They have no intrinsic sense of their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;My primary tool has been the metaphor, not the argument, and the product of my labors is not a doctrine but an invitation to look and see.  With Husserl, I have sought not to instruct but to point out, to recall what we have forgotten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Contrary to Descartes, long before the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; of reflection there is the goodness and the truth of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;. [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; as in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito ergo sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, &amp;ldquo;I think, therefore I am&amp;rdquo;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= togetherness, &amp;ldquo;we are&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Humans have to dehumanize their world in their imagination in order to be able to exploit it ruthlessly in their actions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Our world of artifacts may be no more than the thinnest of layers covering the rhythm of living nature, but it is that layer that we confront in our daily experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Though the theoretical construct of [nature as] a mechanically ordered matter in motion may bear little resemblance to the living nature of the field and the forest and so may never have appeared convincing before, it is a faithful reflection of a world of artifacts and as such compelling to a humanity whose experience with nature is restricted to contact with artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The technical reason which produces the machine cannot teach us its human use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The logic of&amp;hellip;production and consumption, however, grows ever more elusive.  Through the ages of humanity&amp;rsquo;s precarious survival on this earth, the meeting of basic survival needs provided a ready justification for productive activity.  Were we inclined so to direct our energies, it might still do so: there is more than enough hunger and sheer dismal misery still with us.  For the most part, though, we manage to ignore such need.  The logic of our production is not that of need but of affluence with lacks such automatic justification.  If affluence is to be justified, it cannot be by need but by some greater good, be it meeting the needs of others, caring for the natural world, or creating higher values of culture.  &amp;hellip;Yet individually and collectively we sacrifice precious life and resources to producing and paying for [items such as ever-larger television sets] - and we are constantly assured that we must do so to &amp;ldquo;stimulate the economy.&amp;rdquo;  Production itself has become the justification of ever more absurd consumption: we consume to proudce, produce to consume; all other considerations must stand aside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The heavens may still declare the glory of God, but we look up not at the heavens but at neon reflected on smog; we walk not on the good earth but on asphalt.  Our estrangement from nature is no longer conceptual only: it has acquired an experiential grounding.  Figuratively, we are all in the position of the child who has never seen, never mind milked, a cow, and whose lived experience constantly provides an experiential confirmation for the assumption that milk comes from a supermarket cooler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;If the products of human &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;techne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; become philosophically and experientially problematic, it is, I would submit, because we come to think of them as autonomous of the purpose which led to their production and gives them meaning.  We become, in effect, victims of a self-forgetting, losing sight of the moral sense which is the justification of technology.  Quite concretely, the purpose of electric light is to help humans see.  When it comes to blind them to the world around them, it becomes counterproductive.  The task thus is not to abolish technology but to see through it to the human meaning which justifies it and directs its use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Erazim Kohak  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic; &#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GvI0xlwoMesC&amp;amp;dq=the+embers+and+the+stars&amp;amp;source=gbs_summary_s&amp;amp;cad=0&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Laxness&#39; &#39;Independent People&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-laxness-independent-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-laxness-independent-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Brad Leithauser&amp;rsquo;s introduction to Halldor Laxness&amp;rsquo; novel &lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;There are good books and there are great books and there may be a book that is something still more: it is the book of your life. &amp;hellip;One looks differently on the book of genius that, even in a long bookworm&amp;rsquo;s life, one might not have stumbled upon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;But higher than all dealers and societies stand the dreams of the heart, especially in the autumn when dusk is falling and the clouds of the world are full of marvellous pictures&amp;hellip;.Oh, that it may never end; that it might live on to eternity in the restless splendour of its color. And thus night after night she sat watching the silent music of the clouds.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This was the first time that her soul was charmed by the power of poetry, which shows us the lot of man so truthfully and so sympathetically and with so much love for that which is good that we ourselves become better persons and understand life more fully than before, and hope and trust that good may always prevail in the life of man.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The varied life implicit in all this noise affected the bewildered child with a sad sense of her own isolation, her own insignificance; she stood outside the boundaries of life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His being had rested full of adoration for the glory which unifies all distances in such beauty and sorrow that one no longer wishes for anything - in inconquerable adversity, in unquenchable longing, he felt that life had nevertheless been worth living.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When life is a weariness and escape impossible, it is wonderful to have a friend who can bring us peace with the touch of a hand.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Presently the smell of coffee began to fill the room. This was morning&amp;rsquo;s hallowed moment. In such a fragrance the perversity of the world is forgotten and the soul is inspired with faith in the future; when all was said and done, it was probably true that there really were far-off places, even foreign countries.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Few things are so inconstant, so unstable, as a loving heart, and yet it is the only place in the world where one can find sympathy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;No one will ever be able to say that Bjartur of Summerhouses ever got the worst of it in his world war with the country&amp;rsquo;s spectres, no matter how often he might tumble over a precipice or roll head over heels down a gully - &amp;ldquo;while there&amp;rsquo;s a breath left in my nostrils, it will never keep me down, however hard it blows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;She lay like this for a long time, still quivering and still with a pain in her heart; no memories could comfort her any longer, terror is stronger than the total sum of anyone&amp;rsquo;s happiness. She tried to think with hope of the far-off dawn, for human beings always seek some source of consolation; it is this search for consolation, even when every retreat is obviously cut off, that proves that one is still alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But the high heath had also a value for this man other than the practical and the economic. It was his spiritual mother, his church, his better world, as the ocean must inevitably be to the seafarer. When he walked along over the moors on the clear, frosty days of late autumn, when he ran his eyes over the desert&amp;rsquo;s pathless range and felt the cold clean breeze of the mountains on his face, then he too would prove the substance of patriotic song.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He gazed out the window for a while, without accounting for the trend of his thought, staring in silence towards the mountain.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For you are all of the same high birth: God&amp;rsquo;s children all of you.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Take my word for it, freedom is of more account than the height of a roof beam.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, whatever a man seeks he will find - in his dog.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Harrison&#39;s &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to finally know that the spirit was everywhere rather than a separate thing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clare fed our leftover sandwiches to a stray mutt, who didn&amp;rsquo;t chew the proper thirty-two times.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All of my jobs had kept me grounded in actual life whereas simply sitting in my room with my studies tended to make me unstable.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In New York City the endless blocks of huge buildings say to us, I&amp;rsquo;m serious and within me serious people are doing serious things even though five thousand people in a building might only be playing with the market edge.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a local euphemism in the U.P. that you&amp;rsquo;re not lost, you just can&amp;rsquo;t find your vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A local politician rejecting foreign languages in a school budget had said, &amp;lsquo;If English was good enough for Jesus Christ it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for our kids.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I agreed with K on the addition of what is called a &amp;lsquo;space blanket&amp;rsquo; to the survival kits I put together and distribute for Mexicans intending to migrate north.  Space blankets are sheets of material used by campers to protect them from cold and dampness but I thought they could also defend against the summer heat of the ground, which reaches over one hundred and fifty degrees.  ..The packet was in a Velcro latched bag and could be attached to a waiste belt and weighed a little less than five pounds.  I distributed these free of charge to workers&amp;rsquo; groups and through left-leaning Catholic priests.  I was opposed by many on both sides of the border for political reasons, which didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except for the legal expenses I incurred avoiding prosecution by the United States.  My raison d&amp;rsquo;etre was simple on the surface.  Estimates of crossing deaths along the entire nineteen-hundred-mile border with Mexico went as high as two thousand a year.  I had learned to be goofy rather than logically argumentative with my opponents.  I&amp;rsquo;d ask, If you could prevent twenty major airline disasters each year, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;By common consent we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything more serious than the food and music, which in themselves have become more serious as I get older.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He needed Montana but he also needed Chicago for her museums, libraries, theaters, bookstores, and most of all classical music, which he preferred to hear live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;After a passing glance I averted my eyes from a photo of Carla and me at the cabin and then I fixed on it.  Was I ever that young?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There are no damaged goods when everyone is damaged goods.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The best thing about travel, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be consumed by the past against the backdrop of a fresh landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;I was sorry to hear about Donald.  There was a man who could put in a day&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rsquo; I shook his hand as he offered this ultimate compliment of the north.  His hand felt like a semipetrified baseball mitt.  &amp;lsquo;You might not remember me.  Donny and me played football way back when, then worked together.  The name&amp;rsquo;s Teddy.&amp;rsquo;  He bowed, his face reddening, and walked away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;You were the left tackle,&amp;rsquo; I called out and he turned and grinned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On all levels the main reason to live is because you&amp;rsquo;re already alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While we were out on the park bench a small bank of clouds came across the sun turning our mood somber.  He said, &amp;lsquo;After all, the fact of death is the most brutal thing we humans are forced to accept,&amp;rsquo; but then the sun came out again and I told him that the day after the burial Herald had said, &amp;lsquo;Mother, it can&amp;rsquo;t be awful if it happens to every living thing.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buy Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True North&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/Returning-to-Earth/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802143310/?itm=3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/True-North/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802142061/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of happiness</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from Richard Layard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The extra happiness provided by extra income is greatest when you are poor, and declines steadily as you get richer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Required income&amp;rdquo; varies strongly with the actual income that an individual currently experiences.  A dollar rise in experienced income causes a rise of at least a forty cents in &amp;ldquo;required income.&amp;rdquo;  So when I earn an extra dollar this year, it makes me happier, but next year I shall measure my income from a benchmark that is forty cents higher.  In this sense at least 40% of this year&amp;rsquo;s gain is &amp;ldquo;wiped out&amp;rdquo; next year.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Differences in family situation cause a huge difference in happiness.  If someone is divorced, that person&amp;rsquo;s happiness falls by 5 (percentage) points.  This is more than double the effect of losing a third of one&amp;rsquo;s income.  &amp;hellip;The year of divorce is the worst.  After that year men return on average to their baseline level of happiness, but women continue to suffer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If our goals are too low, we get bored.  But if they are too high, we get frustrated.  The secret is to have goals that are stretching enough, but not too stretching.  Unattainable goals are a well-known cause of depression.  But so too is boredom.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The typical Briton watches television for three and a half hours a day - roughly twenty-five hours a week.  Over a lifetime a typical Briton spends more time watching television than doing paid work.  The figures are much the same in the United States.  &amp;hellip; This viewing time has to come from somewhere, and it mainly comes from social life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;So how does the content of television affect our feelings about life, and our behavior?  If television simply mirrored life as it is, it would be unlikely to have much effect.  However, it does not simply mirror life - that would be boring.  Television focuses far more on the extremes.  It contains far more violence, sex, and chaotic relationships than ordinary life does, and it contains far more wealth and beauty.  &amp;hellip;Chaos on the screen tends to desensitize - to make people more willing to engage in violence themselves and in illicit sex.  At the same time wealth and beauty create discontent with what people have - an itch to earn or steal more wealth, or to find a more beautiful partner.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On one estimate an extra hour a week watching television causes you to spend an extra $4 a week - on &amp;ldquo;keeping up with the Joneses.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;It reduces our happiness with our possessions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Viewing may also reduce our happiness with our bodies, and with our spouses.  The psychologist Douglas Kenrick showed women a series of female models.  He evaluated their mood before and after they looked at the pictures.  After seeing the models, the women&amp;rsquo;s mood fell.  So how must women&amp;rsquo;s moods be affected by television?  In three hours of viewing television each day you cannot fail to see a parade of beautiful women.  What about the effect on men?  As part of the same series of experiments, pictures of models were shown to a sample of men.  Kenrick evaluated their feelings about their wives before and after each presentation.  After seeing the models, most men felt less good about their wives.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Trustworthiness is crucial in any venture, and no long-term contract can flourish except on the basis of commitment to the common goal.  This applies in business, in friendship or in marriage.  Unfortunately, the growth of individualism has encouraged a short-term version of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;contractarian&lt;/span&gt; thinking, where more and more decisions are conducted on the basis of a short-term quid pro quo. &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this environment of continuous reoptimization, it is not surprising that, as we have seen, people are less satisfied with their marriages.  There is also clear evidence that when spouses arrange their lives on the basis of quid pro quo, they are less satisfied with the marriage than when it is based on the concept of giving.  &amp;hellip;The evidence also shows that when one spouse does something and the other spouse reciprocates, the first gets less satisfaction than when no direct reciprocation occurs.  This is because giving confers satisfaction, and can confer more satisfaction than taking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Above all, we need to know that our partner has sufficient emotional commitment to the enterprise.  If so, we know the partner will stick to the relationship, even when short-term advantage would say &amp;ldquo;Out.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;If both parties know that the other is really committed, each will invest more and the probability of success will rise.  In all walks of life, good behavior by one person elicits good behavior by others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Layard&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Milosz, Balthasar, and Stevens</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many definitions of Communism, perhaps one would be the most apt: enemy of orchards. For the disappearance of villages and the remodeling of the terrain necessitated cutting down the orchards once surrounding every house and hut. The idea of collective farming - grain factories instead of little peasant lots - was rational, but with a vengeance, and a similar vengeance lurking in practically every project of the planned economy brought about the downfall of the Soviet system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Orchards under Communism had no chance, but in all fairness let us concede that they are antique by their very nature. Only the passion of a gardener can delight in growing a great variety of trees, each producing a small crop of fruit whose tastes pleases the gardener himself and a few connoisseurs. Market laws favor a few species that are easy to preserve and correspond to basic standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Much was going on inside me, and I was stunned by the strength of that current for which no name seemed adequate. It was like waking up from a long dream and becoming again the person whom I have never ceased to be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Happiness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One would like to astound the world, to save the world, but one can do neither. We are summoned to deeds that are of moment only to our village.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Who Was I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I am not wise, then why must I pretend to be? If I am lost, why must I pretend to have ready counsel for my contemporaries? But perhaps the value of communication depends on the acknowledgment of one&amp;rsquo;s own limits, which, mysteriously, are also limits common to many others; and aren&amp;rsquo;t these the same limits of a hundred or a thousand years ago? And when the air is filled with the clamor of analysis and conclusion, would it be entirely useless to admit you do not understand?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have read many books, but to place all those volumes on top of one another and stand on them would not add a cubit to my stature. Their learned terms are of little use when I try to seize naked experience, which eludes all accepted ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;My Intention&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The man who stakes his all on this one thing wins all, but he must of course reckon with the loss of everything else excluded by this one thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hans Urs von Balthasar&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Moment of Christian Witness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;Divinity must live within herself:&lt;br /&gt;Passions of rain, or moods in falling snow;&lt;br /&gt;Grievings in loneliness, or unsubdued&lt;br /&gt;Elations when the forest blooms; gusty&lt;br /&gt;Emotions on wet roads on autumn nights;&lt;br /&gt;All pleasures and all pains, remembering&lt;br /&gt;The bough of summer and the winter branch.&lt;br /&gt;These are the measures destined for her soul.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shall our blood fail? Or shall it come to be&lt;br /&gt;The blood of paradise? And shall the earth&lt;br /&gt;Seem all of paradise that we shall know?&lt;br /&gt;The sky will be much friendlier then than now,&lt;br /&gt;A part of labor and a part of pain,&lt;br /&gt;And next in glory to enduring love,&lt;br /&gt;Not this dividing and indifferent blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Frank on inequality in America</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-frank-on-inequality-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-frank-on-inequality-in-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started exploring the ideas of liberal economists - those economists who advise and formulate policy for Democratic candidates.  I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded a few fantastic lectures by &lt;a href=&#34;http://robertreich.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Robert Reich&lt;/a&gt;, Secretary of Labor under President Clinton.  And I recently read a book on inequality by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.robert-h-frank.com/&#34;&gt;Robert Frank&lt;/a&gt;, professor of economics at Cornell.  The book - &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200970979&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - is one of the most interesting policy essays I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time.  I highly recommend it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His basic argument is this: since 1979, the trend in America has been for an enormous increase in the incomes of those in the top 1%-5% of earners and a much, much smaller increase in the incomes of everyone else.  Flush with cash, the top earners have been spending wildly on &amp;ldquo;positional goods&amp;rdquo; - goods that display status and wealth, that demonstrate that one is a &amp;ldquo;player,&amp;rdquo; someone to be reckoned with.  Meanwhile, the near-rich emulate the spending patterns of the rich, and so on down the income ladder.  This is the &amp;ldquo;expenditure cascade.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The problem is that the farther down the income ladder one goes, the less capable individuals are of affording to participate in these &amp;ldquo;positional arms races,&amp;rdquo; as Frank calls them.  Individuals in the middle are forced to keep up by spending large portions of their income on positional goods - which include things like housing and education - while increasingly neglecting unseen, nonpositional goods like saving money and buying insurance. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The primary motive for status-spending isn&amp;rsquo;t envy, he argues; rather, middle-class families feel forced to spend heavily on positional goods in order to feel accepted and be recognized as successful.  People take out jumbo mortgages to buy oversized houses they can&amp;rsquo;t afford not because they necessarily believe that more house leads to more happiness, but because they want to send their children to the best schools and have them grow up in &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; neighborhoods - the sort of neighborhoods where housing prices are often beyond their ability to comfortably pay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frank cites research showing that higher income inequality is associated with lower societal happiness, more health problems, and higher rates of crime, homicide, suicide, and depression.  He lambasts the Bush tax cuts, which disproportionately rewarded individuals at the top of the income scale, and argues for making income taxes more progressive or switching to a progressive consumption tax.  This would involve making savings tax-exempt: taxable income in a given year would equal a family&amp;rsquo;s earnings minus its savings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do we want to spend our money on better teachers, better roads, and enhanced national security?  Or do we want to spend it on more expensive watches, more elaborate gas grills, and bigger mansions?  Tired slogans about government waste won&amp;rsquo;t help us make this decision more intelligently.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200970979&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to check out the book on Amazon.com.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from the week&#39;s reading, part 2</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we would expect, during most wars consumer spending is deliberately held back by heavy taxes to make room for swelling military expenditure.  During World War II, for example, consumption was squeezed back by heavy taxes to barely more than half of GDP.  …During the Vietnam War military expenses for that conflict were not compensated by taxes to roll back consumption and the excess demand for goods and services ignited a subsequent inflation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Question: Could this happen today, given that the U.S. government is spending over $2 billion each week in Iraq?]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Heilbroner and Lester Thurow, Economics Explained&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six Years Later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So long had life together been that now&lt;br /&gt;The second of January fell again&lt;br /&gt;On Tuesday, making her astonished brow&lt;br /&gt;Lift like a windshield-wiper in the rain,&lt;br /&gt;So that her misty sadness cleared, and showed&lt;br /&gt;A cloudless distance waiting up the road.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joseph Brodsky&lt;/em&gt;, tr. Richard Wilbur&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Can we still believe at all?  Or rather - for the question must be posed in a more radical fashion - is it still permissible to believe?  Have we not a duty to break with the dream and face reality?  The Christian of today must ask himself this question: he is not at liberty to remain satisfied with finding out that by all kinds of twists and turns an interpretation of Christianity can still be found that no longer offends anybody.  When some theologian explains that &amp;ldquo;the resurrection of the dead&amp;rdquo; simply means that one must cheerfully set about the work of the future afresh every day, offense is certainly avoided.  But are we then really still being honest?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Joseph Cardinal Ratzinger (Pope Benedict XVI), &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Christianity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those societies that adapt themselves to the requirements of economic growth and technological innovation in a particular epoch become the economic leaders of that epoch, and societies that do not or cannot adjust to such requirements fall behind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Gilpin, &lt;em&gt;Global Political Economy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Can the mathematician who looks at the world mathematically find anything else but mathematics in the universe?  Should not one rather ask him whether he has not himself at some time or other looked at the world in a way that is other than mathematical?  Whether, for example, he has never seen an apple tree in blossom and wondered why the process of fertilization by the interplay between bees and trees is not affected otherwise than through the roundabout way of the blossom, thus including the completely superfluous wonder of beauty&amp;hellip;?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Yet the man who seeks a view of the whole will have to say: In the world we find present, without doubt, objective mathematics; but we also find equally present in the world unparalleled and unexplained wonders of beauty, or, to be more accurate, there are events that appear to the apprehending mind of man in the form of beauty, so that he is bound to say that the mathematician responsible for these events has displayed an unparalleled degree of creative imagination.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Joseph Cardinal Ratzinger (Pope Benedict XVI), &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Christianity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from the week&#39;s reading, part 1</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2007 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-the-weeks-reading-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;How It Should Be in Heaven&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How it should be in Heaven I know, for I was there.&lt;br /&gt;By its river.  Listening to its birds.&lt;br /&gt;In its season: in summer, shortly after sunrise.&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;Peace eternal&lt;br /&gt;Could have no mornings and no evenings,&lt;br /&gt;Such a deficiency speaks against it.&lt;br /&gt;And that’s too hard a nut for a theologian to crack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A business that makes nothing but money is a poor kind of business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Joel Kurtzman, &lt;em&gt;MBA in a Box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is every reason to help the poor man who happens to be a farmer, not because he is a farmer but because he is poor.  The program, that is, should be designed to help people as people, not as members of particular occupational groups, age groups, wage-rate groups, labor organizations, or industries.  … The arrangement that recommends itself on purely mechanical grounds is a negative income tax…. The advantages of this arrangement are clear.  It is directed specifically at  the problem of poverty.  It gives help in the form most useful to the individual, namely, cash.  It is general and could be substituted for the host of special measures now in effect.  It makes explicit the cost borne by society.  Like any other measures to alleviate poverty, it reduces the incentives of those helped to help themselves, but it does not eliminate that incentive entirely, as a system of supplementing incomes up to some fixed minimum would.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Milton Friedman, &lt;em&gt;Capitalism and Freedom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Yet The Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And yet the books will be there on the shelves, separate beings,&lt;br /&gt;That appeared once, still wet&lt;br /&gt;As shining chestnuts under a tree in autumn,&lt;br /&gt;And, touched, coddled, began to live&lt;br /&gt;In spite of fires on the horizon, castles blown up,&lt;br /&gt;Tribes on the march, planets in motion.&lt;br /&gt;“We are,” they said, even as their pages&lt;br /&gt;Were being torn out, or a buzzing flame&lt;br /&gt;Licked away their letters.  So much more durable&lt;br /&gt;Than we are, whose frail warmth&lt;br /&gt;Cools down with memory, disperses, perishes.&lt;br /&gt;I imagine the earth when I am no more:&lt;br /&gt;Nothing happens, no loss, it’s still a strange pageant,&lt;br /&gt;Women’s dresses, dewy lilacs, a song in the valley.&lt;br /&gt;Yet the books will be there on the shelves, well born,&lt;br /&gt;Derived from people, but also from radiance, heights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Relics of the Past&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dust raised by the royal cavalry has long since settled.&lt;br /&gt;One by one, poets and historians, the standard-bearers of culture,&lt;br /&gt;have gone silently to their graves.  Of what use is the purple&lt;br /&gt;and fine linen now, the baubles that women love?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Akhtarul Iman, tr. R. Parthsarathy&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
