<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frugality on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/frugality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frugality on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 12:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/frugality/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Du Bois, and Salomon</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-du-bois-and-salomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-du-bois-and-salomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Happy &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/watch?v=PbUtL_0vAJk&#34;&gt;Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/a&gt; Day!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Honest and earnest criticism from those whose interests are most nearly touched - criticism of writers by readers, of government by those governed, of leaders by those led - this is the soul of democracy and the safeguard of modern society.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In fact the burden belongs to the nation, and the hands of none of us are clean if we bend not our energies to righting these wrongs.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The opposition to Negro education in the South was at first bitter, and showed itself in ashes, insult, and blood; for the South believed an educated Negro to be a dangerous Negro.  And the South was not wholly wrong; for education among all kinds of men always has had, and always will have, an element of danger and revolution, of dissatisfaction and discontent.  Nevertheless, men strive to know.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To be a poor man is hard, but to be a poor race in a land of dollars is the very bottom of hardships.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;W.E.B. Du Bois&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200937222&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;The Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His emotion had made him a boy again, a child sitting quietly with folded arms.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s spring, I&amp;rsquo;m walking into the new season,&amp;rsquo; Rolandsen answered over his shoulder as he went by.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, he was not God, he could not contain his heart if it insisted on flying away in the spring.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The nights too were bright and sunny.  It was weather for dreamers, for young people to flit about in restless excitement.  They wandered the roads at night, singing and beating the air with sallow-twigs.  And from all the isles and skerries came the sound of birds: guillemots and oyster-catchers and gulls and eiderducks.  The seal thrust his dripping head up out of the water and looked around, then dived back down again to his own world.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He went to the sexton&amp;rsquo;s house to look for Olga.  Now that it was spring Rolandsen had to have a sweetheart; it was no easy matter to hold his own great heart in check.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Alas, Rolandsen was ever hopeful; it took very little to rouse his expectations.  But it had to be admitted that he was also good at bearing disappointments; he was proud and resilient and his spirit was never broken.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some people are always getting a bigger boat, but rarely sail.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All these books boil down to the same message: &amp;lsquo;Resist the urge to buy.&amp;rsquo;  Once you learn how to do it, it becomes second nature.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Most people find that stuff does indeed expand to fill the space provided.  Do you want to encourage this tendency with the stuff in your house?  Extra space will cost you in several ways: money and times to decorate, clean, and maintain; energy to heat and cool all that space; and outdoor space (the more you put under roof, the less you&amp;rsquo;ll have outside).  There&amp;rsquo;s also the house law of diminishing returns: the difference between having one bathroom or none is enormous, but between two or three may be negligible.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Living smaller frees up&amp;hellip;time and money to pursue fun.  Having good friends is a proven mood elevator.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Polls show that most Americans believe we must earn about twice the median income to be solidly middle class - that is, we believe that what we earn, on average, is just not enough.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shay Salomon and Nigel Valdez&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200937031&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update, and last quotes from Growth of the Soil</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-last-quotes-from-growth-of-the-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 15:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-last-quotes-from-growth-of-the-soil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internship is over and I am home in Muskegon, happy to use the weather as an excuse to spend entire days reading in coffeeshops.  I am leaving for Japan on September 5th and my Japanese is very rusty, and there is plenty of IR and political theory I would like to cover before school starts in late September. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This should be a wonderful week: home, family, friends, books, bowling, Muskegon, running on the lake.  August continues to be the best month yet this year for me - every side of life is good and I am excited about the future.  I love my apartment and roommates in Chicago, am in great shape for the cross-country season that starts next week, have read three new favorite novels over the past month (Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley &lt;/em&gt;along with Knut Hamsun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Pan&lt;/em&gt;), am satisfied with my now-completed internship, and will be in Tokyo in two and a half weeks.  Things are very, very good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The summer was difficult, not least because it was my first experience of working 50 hours a week in an office - that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big leap from academic life.  But I learned an incredible amount; it often felt like I was being paid to go to school.  Every day, I read &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; practically cover to cover as well as pages upon pages of other news sources, academic papers, and economic forecasts.  My discussions about economics with my supervisors - emerging market bond portfolio managers - felt like private office hours with a great professor.  I observed the way Wall Street functions and the way investment decisions are made by institutional investors.  I learned how bonds work and how political risk affects investment decisions, and developed a spreadsheet to quantify the effect of political risk on developing countries&amp;rsquo; creditworthiness.  I created economic forecasts for Brazil, Russia, India and China.  I learned about currency fluctuations, liquidity, the subprime mortgage meltdown, current accounts, economic indicators - and much more.  Every day, I was bombarded with information. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I enjoyed some aspects of the job more than others, and found that my background had left me better prepared for the political risk analysis side of the work than for the economic forecasting and modeling side of the work.  But I also gained a new respect for the power and complexity of financial markets, and I realized that if one&amp;rsquo;s goal is to understand the world in order to improve it, it is crucial to study markets as well as politics.  Political decisions create the space and the incentive structure in which markets function, but it is useful to think of politics and markets as intertwined and inseparable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have a long way to go and a lot to study on all fronts, which is a major reason why I am grateful for this week of peace at home in West Michigan. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final quotes from Hamsun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;/em&gt;Growth of the Soil - &lt;em&gt;right up there with &lt;/em&gt;The Brothers Karamazov, Anna Karenina, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; War and Peace &lt;em&gt;as one of the absolute best novels I have ever gotten my hands on.  This book, like the others just mentioned, has reshaped the way I think and will hopefully reshape the way I live - it has inspired me to look away from the temptation of great wealth and great expectations, avoid being another rootless young person floating around the world&amp;rsquo;s cities, investigate rather than avoid the issue of abortion and find ways to reduce it, and be content with making and spending less and leaving a lighter footprint on earth.  Check the book out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Soil-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0143105108/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-3421197-6377666?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1187556118&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why could not folk go on living as well or as poorly now as before there had been any mine at all?  Well, they could not, and that was all about it.  They had grown accustomed to better food, finer bread, store-bought clothes and higher wages, general extravagance - aye, folk had learned to reckon with money more, that was the matter.  And now the money was gone again, had slipped away like a shoal of herring out to sea - &amp;lsquo;twas dire distress for them all, and what was to be done?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inger has made her stormy voyage, &amp;lsquo;tis true, has lived in a city a while, but now she is home; the world is wide, swarming with tiny specks - Inger has been one of them.  All but nothing in all humanity, only one speck.  Then comes the evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nothing growing there?  All things growing there; men and beasts and fruit of the soil.  Isak sowing his grain.  The evening sunlight falls on the grain that flashes out in an arc from his hand, and falls like a dropping of gold to the ground.  &amp;hellip; Forest and field look on.  All is majesty and power - a sequence and purpose of things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A man of the wild was not put out by the thought of great things he could not get; art, newspapers, luxuries, politics and such-like were worth just what folk were willing to pay for them, no more.  Growth of the soil was something different, a thing to be procured at any cost; the only source, the origin of all.  A dull and desolate existence?  Nay, least of all.  A man had everything; his powers above, his dreams, his loves, his wealth of superstition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There you are, living in touch with heaven and earth, one with them, one with all these wide, deep-rooted things.  No need of a sword in your hands, you go through life bareheaded, barehanded, in the midst of a great kindliness.  Look, Nature&amp;rsquo;s there, for you and yours to have and enjoy.  Man and Nature don&amp;rsquo;t bombard each other, but agree; they don&amp;rsquo;t compete, race one against the other, but go together.  &amp;hellip; Fjeld and forest, moors and meadow, and sky and stars - oh, &amp;lsquo;tis not poor and sparingly counted out, but without measure.  Listen to me, Sivert: you be content!  You&amp;rsquo;ve everything to live on, everything to live for, everything to believe in; being born and bringing forth, you are the needful on earth.  &amp;lsquo;Tis not all that are so, but you are so; needful on earth.  &amp;lsquo;Tis you that maintain life.  Generation to generation, breeding ever anew; and when you die, the new stock goes on.  That&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of eternal life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from the weekend&#39;s reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-the-weekends-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The (National Assessment of Educational Progress economics exam), taken by a representative sample of twelfth graders at public and private high schools, tested students on micro- and macroeconomic principles and international trade. What, for example, is the effect of breaking down trade barriers between countries? A majority correctly said that goods would become less expensive. They chose this over &amp;ldquo;the quality of goods available would decrease.&amp;rdquo; Maybe John Edwards should hire more teenagers for his Presidential campaign.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/The%20exam,%20taken%20by%20a%20representative%20sample%20of%20twelfth%20graders%20at%20public%20and%20private%20high%20schools,%20tested%20students%20on%20micro-%20and%20macroeconomic%20principles%20and%20international%20trade.%20What,%20for%20example,%20is%20the%20effect%20of%20breaking%20down%20trade%20barriers%20between%20countries?&#34;&gt;The Kids Are All Right&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 10-10-07&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ms. Rodham skates earnestly on the surface of life, raising more questions than answers. “Last week I decided that even if life is absurd why couldn’t I spend it absurdly happy?” she wrote in November of her junior year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times, &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/29/us/politics/29letter.html?ex=1187150400&amp;en=a261bdf200dc7c3e&amp;amp;ei=5070&#34;&gt;In the &amp;lsquo;60s, a Future Candidate Poured Her Heart Out in Letters&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; 7-29-07 (must-read - the best article I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in this entire campaign cycle, and it made me a lot more enthusiastic about the Clinton campaign. I continue, however, to support Obama.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, Eleseus was sent to town after all; Inger managed that. &amp;hellip;Now and again he asked for money, something towards his expenses. A watch and chain, for instance, he must have, so as not to oversleep himself in the morning and be late at the office; money for a pipe and tobacco also, such as the other young clerks in the town always had. And for something he called pocket-money, and something he called evening classes, where he learned drawing and gymnastics and other matters proper to his rank and position. Altogether, it was no light matter to keep Eleseus going in a berth in town.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pocket money?&amp;rdquo; said Isak. &amp;ldquo;Is that money to keep in your pocket, maybe?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There was trouble in his mind, like enough, but he bore it silently, and made no scene. Oh, there was something great about Isak; as it might be Israel, promised and ever deceived, but still believing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later in the year Inger was sent for down to the village, to do dressmaking for some of the great folks there.  Inger could not go; she had a household to look after, and animals besides, all the work of a home, and she had no servant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Had no what?  Servant!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She spoke to Isak one day.  &amp;ldquo;If only I had someone to help me, I could put in more time sewing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak did not understand.  &amp;ldquo;Help?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, help in the house - a servant-girl.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Isak must have been taken aback at this; he laughed a little in his iron beard, and took it as a jest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
