<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/chicago/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicago on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/chicago/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitions: A personal update</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/transitions-a-personal-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/transitions-a-personal-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No more than three weeks after making my final decision to move to Ann Arbor to pursue an M.A. in Education at the University of Michigan and become a high school history teacher, it is happening: my furniture is being sold or moved, my possessions are being sorted into boxes.  Yesterday was my last day at the bookstore I&amp;rsquo;ve worked at as a manager since August.  On Friday I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the road to Muskegon with a stuffed car and another empty apartment behind me, and on Sunday I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Ann Arbor to begin the next stage of my life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel alive with the movement of it all: &amp;ldquo;A man gets up, a few strokes of a brush and then already it&amp;rsquo;s evening.&amp;rdquo; (Milosz)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For many in Chicago, driving is a necessity, not a luxury</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/for-many-in-chicago-driving-is-a-necessity-not-a-luxury/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My most recent op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/cgi-bin/mag/article.pl?articleId=32083&#34;&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (registration required) was published today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;Chicagobusiness.com&lt;/a&gt; and will appear in this week&amp;rsquo;s issue of &lt;em&gt;Crain&amp;rsquo;s Chicago Business&lt;/em&gt;.  You can find the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chicagobusiness.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as reprinted below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For us, Mr. Daley, driving to work is a necessity, not a vice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is exceedingly difficult for many commuters living on the North Side to find free parking after they return from work. After an often agonizing rush-hour commute, they must circle around their neighborhood until they find a parking space; if they arrive too late, they must choose between parking at a meter and interrupting their lives every two hours to feed it, or parking a mile or more away from their homes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But if the North Side parking situation is a nightmare today, imagine what it will look like when the city installs meters along the entire lakefront, effectively eliminating a major artery of free parking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I commute every workday between my apartment near Belmont Avenue in East Lakeview and Hyde Park. If I drive, I spend around 50 minutes per day, including time spent finding parking, on the road. If I take public transportation, the same round trip can take as long as three hours. That adds an extra two hours to my workday, significantly reducing my time for leisure, exercise, relationships and everything else that is important in life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, for me and for many other commuters, driving is essential to maintaining a high quality of life in Chicago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many users of the free lakefront spots are commuters who do not have access to, cannot afford or choose not to purchase a space in a garage or a residential street parking permit. These commuters, like myself, look for free spots to park in overnight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new lakefront meters, which are scheduled to be in place by the fall, will mean that thousands of drivers will be competing for far fewer free spaces. Many commuters will spend more frustrated and stressful time on the road driving in circles in search of parking. Some will resort to paying an outrageous price to park in a garage. Others will give up driving and double or triple their commuting time by turning to public transit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For many Chicagoans, driving to work — and finding free or affordable parking after work — is a necessity, not a luxury. Contrary to the inclinations of Mayor Richard M. Daley and the city, it is not a vice that ought to be subject to endless taxation and fees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By significantly reducing the availability of free parking in lakefront neighborhoods without creating affordable alternatives for commuters, the new meters will make much of the city more expensive and inconvenient for everyone, including working families. They may boost the city&amp;rsquo;s revenue, but they will do so at the direct expense of the well-being and quality of life of thousands of its residents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Ryan McCarl is a freelance writer.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a teacher and a Michigan Wolverine</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to report that I have decided to enter the University of Michigan School of Education&amp;rsquo;s Secondary MAC (MA in Education with Secondary Certification) program in mid-June.  The program is 12 months long and includes over 1,000 hours of classroom experience as a student teacher and substitute teacher, resulting in full certification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I look forward to finding unique ways to show my students the importance of learning and reading as well as the value of informed engagement with current events and politics.  I also want to grow into a caring and effective mentor.  And, finally, I hope to learn from my classroom experience in order to become a more informed and articulate advocate for education reform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am very, very sad to be moving from Chicago after living here for five years.  I will miss my tiny apartment in East Lakeview and having easy access to my favorite places - the lakefront, Mickey&amp;rsquo;s Grille, Avenue Tavern, and Stella&amp;rsquo;s Diner in East Lakeview, the Noble Tree Cafe in Lincoln Park, the Grind and the Old Town School of Folk Music in Lincoln Square, the Pub and Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books in Hyde Park, Myopic Books in Wicker Park, Lao Beijing in Chinatown, and the Borders on Michigan Ave., among others.  But I will be visiting at least once a month over the next year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next three weeks will be incredibly busy.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be packing, moving, finding a subletter in Chicago and a temporary place to stay in Ann Arbor, working for a few more weeks, and spending as much time as possible with my friends in Chicago.  But I am thrilled to be entering the program and stepping into the next stage of my life and career.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Harrison&#39;s &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to finally know that the spirit was everywhere rather than a separate thing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clare fed our leftover sandwiches to a stray mutt, who didn&amp;rsquo;t chew the proper thirty-two times.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All of my jobs had kept me grounded in actual life whereas simply sitting in my room with my studies tended to make me unstable.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In New York City the endless blocks of huge buildings say to us, I&amp;rsquo;m serious and within me serious people are doing serious things even though five thousand people in a building might only be playing with the market edge.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a local euphemism in the U.P. that you&amp;rsquo;re not lost, you just can&amp;rsquo;t find your vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A local politician rejecting foreign languages in a school budget had said, &amp;lsquo;If English was good enough for Jesus Christ it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for our kids.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I agreed with K on the addition of what is called a &amp;lsquo;space blanket&amp;rsquo; to the survival kits I put together and distribute for Mexicans intending to migrate north.  Space blankets are sheets of material used by campers to protect them from cold and dampness but I thought they could also defend against the summer heat of the ground, which reaches over one hundred and fifty degrees.  ..The packet was in a Velcro latched bag and could be attached to a waiste belt and weighed a little less than five pounds.  I distributed these free of charge to workers&amp;rsquo; groups and through left-leaning Catholic priests.  I was opposed by many on both sides of the border for political reasons, which didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except for the legal expenses I incurred avoiding prosecution by the United States.  My raison d&amp;rsquo;etre was simple on the surface.  Estimates of crossing deaths along the entire nineteen-hundred-mile border with Mexico went as high as two thousand a year.  I had learned to be goofy rather than logically argumentative with my opponents.  I&amp;rsquo;d ask, If you could prevent twenty major airline disasters each year, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;By common consent we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything more serious than the food and music, which in themselves have become more serious as I get older.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He needed Montana but he also needed Chicago for her museums, libraries, theaters, bookstores, and most of all classical music, which he preferred to hear live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;After a passing glance I averted my eyes from a photo of Carla and me at the cabin and then I fixed on it.  Was I ever that young?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There are no damaged goods when everyone is damaged goods.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The best thing about travel, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be consumed by the past against the backdrop of a fresh landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;I was sorry to hear about Donald.  There was a man who could put in a day&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rsquo; I shook his hand as he offered this ultimate compliment of the north.  His hand felt like a semipetrified baseball mitt.  &amp;lsquo;You might not remember me.  Donny and me played football way back when, then worked together.  The name&amp;rsquo;s Teddy.&amp;rsquo;  He bowed, his face reddening, and walked away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;You were the left tackle,&amp;rsquo; I called out and he turned and grinned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On all levels the main reason to live is because you&amp;rsquo;re already alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While we were out on the park bench a small bank of clouds came across the sun turning our mood somber.  He said, &amp;lsquo;After all, the fact of death is the most brutal thing we humans are forced to accept,&amp;rsquo; but then the sun came out again and I told him that the day after the burial Herald had said, &amp;lsquo;Mother, it can&amp;rsquo;t be awful if it happens to every living thing.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buy Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True North&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/Returning-to-Earth/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802143310/?itm=3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/True-North/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802142061/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highly recommended movie: &#39;The Pool&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/highly-recommended-movie-the-pool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 21:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/highly-recommended-movie-the-pool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SNWlRxabNsI/AAAAAAAAAfE/cl6Oc4db9HQ/s1600-h/thepool.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5248282665510713026&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SNWlRxabNsI/AAAAAAAAAfE/cl6Oc4db9HQ/s400/thepool.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the first Baliwood movie I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, and I loved it. For my Chicago readers, it&amp;rsquo;s currently playing at my favorite cinema, the Landmark Cinema Century Theater.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Reviews &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/the_pool/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update, and last quotes from Growth of the Soil</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-last-quotes-from-growth-of-the-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 15:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-last-quotes-from-growth-of-the-soil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internship is over and I am home in Muskegon, happy to use the weather as an excuse to spend entire days reading in coffeeshops.  I am leaving for Japan on September 5th and my Japanese is very rusty, and there is plenty of IR and political theory I would like to cover before school starts in late September. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This should be a wonderful week: home, family, friends, books, bowling, Muskegon, running on the lake.  August continues to be the best month yet this year for me - every side of life is good and I am excited about the future.  I love my apartment and roommates in Chicago, am in great shape for the cross-country season that starts next week, have read three new favorite novels over the past month (Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley &lt;/em&gt;along with Knut Hamsun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Pan&lt;/em&gt;), am satisfied with my now-completed internship, and will be in Tokyo in two and a half weeks.  Things are very, very good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The summer was difficult, not least because it was my first experience of working 50 hours a week in an office - that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big leap from academic life.  But I learned an incredible amount; it often felt like I was being paid to go to school.  Every day, I read &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; practically cover to cover as well as pages upon pages of other news sources, academic papers, and economic forecasts.  My discussions about economics with my supervisors - emerging market bond portfolio managers - felt like private office hours with a great professor.  I observed the way Wall Street functions and the way investment decisions are made by institutional investors.  I learned how bonds work and how political risk affects investment decisions, and developed a spreadsheet to quantify the effect of political risk on developing countries&amp;rsquo; creditworthiness.  I created economic forecasts for Brazil, Russia, India and China.  I learned about currency fluctuations, liquidity, the subprime mortgage meltdown, current accounts, economic indicators - and much more.  Every day, I was bombarded with information. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I enjoyed some aspects of the job more than others, and found that my background had left me better prepared for the political risk analysis side of the work than for the economic forecasting and modeling side of the work.  But I also gained a new respect for the power and complexity of financial markets, and I realized that if one&amp;rsquo;s goal is to understand the world in order to improve it, it is crucial to study markets as well as politics.  Political decisions create the space and the incentive structure in which markets function, but it is useful to think of politics and markets as intertwined and inseparable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have a long way to go and a lot to study on all fronts, which is a major reason why I am grateful for this week of peace at home in West Michigan. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final quotes from Hamsun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;/em&gt;Growth of the Soil - &lt;em&gt;right up there with &lt;/em&gt;The Brothers Karamazov, Anna Karenina, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; War and Peace &lt;em&gt;as one of the absolute best novels I have ever gotten my hands on.  This book, like the others just mentioned, has reshaped the way I think and will hopefully reshape the way I live - it has inspired me to look away from the temptation of great wealth and great expectations, avoid being another rootless young person floating around the world&amp;rsquo;s cities, investigate rather than avoid the issue of abortion and find ways to reduce it, and be content with making and spending less and leaving a lighter footprint on earth.  Check the book out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Soil-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0143105108/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-3421197-6377666?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1187556118&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why could not folk go on living as well or as poorly now as before there had been any mine at all?  Well, they could not, and that was all about it.  They had grown accustomed to better food, finer bread, store-bought clothes and higher wages, general extravagance - aye, folk had learned to reckon with money more, that was the matter.  And now the money was gone again, had slipped away like a shoal of herring out to sea - &amp;lsquo;twas dire distress for them all, and what was to be done?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Inger has made her stormy voyage, &amp;lsquo;tis true, has lived in a city a while, but now she is home; the world is wide, swarming with tiny specks - Inger has been one of them.  All but nothing in all humanity, only one speck.  Then comes the evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nothing growing there?  All things growing there; men and beasts and fruit of the soil.  Isak sowing his grain.  The evening sunlight falls on the grain that flashes out in an arc from his hand, and falls like a dropping of gold to the ground.  &amp;hellip; Forest and field look on.  All is majesty and power - a sequence and purpose of things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A man of the wild was not put out by the thought of great things he could not get; art, newspapers, luxuries, politics and such-like were worth just what folk were willing to pay for them, no more.  Growth of the soil was something different, a thing to be procured at any cost; the only source, the origin of all.  A dull and desolate existence?  Nay, least of all.  A man had everything; his powers above, his dreams, his loves, his wealth of superstition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There you are, living in touch with heaven and earth, one with them, one with all these wide, deep-rooted things.  No need of a sword in your hands, you go through life bareheaded, barehanded, in the midst of a great kindliness.  Look, Nature&amp;rsquo;s there, for you and yours to have and enjoy.  Man and Nature don&amp;rsquo;t bombard each other, but agree; they don&amp;rsquo;t compete, race one against the other, but go together.  &amp;hellip; Fjeld and forest, moors and meadow, and sky and stars - oh, &amp;lsquo;tis not poor and sparingly counted out, but without measure.  Listen to me, Sivert: you be content!  You&amp;rsquo;ve everything to live on, everything to live for, everything to believe in; being born and bringing forth, you are the needful on earth.  &amp;lsquo;Tis not all that are so, but you are so; needful on earth.  &amp;lsquo;Tis you that maintain life.  Generation to generation, breeding ever anew; and when you die, the new stock goes on.  That&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of eternal life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update and four quotes</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited about the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking straight from work to Union Station tomorrow afternoon, and then the usual, happy routine of a quick trip home: the #370 &lt;em&gt;Pere Marquette &lt;/em&gt;accompanied by caffeine and books (and, since it&amp;rsquo;s summer, a wonderful sunset over the harbor in St. Joseph, MI), a late-night outing to Pints &amp;amp; Quarts and Pablo&amp;rsquo;s Tacos with Muskegon friends, a Saturday morning trip to eat breakfast and shop for used books in Grand Haven, a few intense games of ping-pong with Tyler, and a run on the beach. Early Sunday morning, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the return train to Chicago and it will all seem surreal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two unique and wonderful things about this trip. First: my family got a new dog, a black retriever named Maggie, whom I will have the pleasure of meeting for the first time tomorrow night. And second: on Saturday night, two friends and I are going to a Counting Crows and Collective Soul concert in Grand Rapids.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Quotes from tonight&amp;rsquo;s reading: &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I am saying is this: the score is not what matters. Life does not have to be regarded as a game in which scores are kept and somebody wins. If you are too intent on winning, you will never enjoy playing. If you are too obsessed with success, you will forget to live. If you have learned only how to be a success, your life has probably been wasted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Love and Living&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When that time was over and the good-bys said, I had to go through the same lost loneliness all over again, and it was no less painful than at first. There seemed to be no cure for loneliness save only being alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blackberries for Amelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the far stars, of which we now are told&lt;br /&gt;That ever faster they do bolt away,&lt;br /&gt;And that a night may come in which, some say,&lt;br /&gt;We shall have only blackness to behold.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have no time for any change so great,&lt;br /&gt;But I shall see the August weather spur&lt;br /&gt;Berries to ripen where the flowers were -&lt;br /&gt;Dark berries, savage-sweet and worth the wait -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And there will come the moment to be quick&lt;br /&gt;And save some from the birds, and I shall need&lt;br /&gt;Two pails, old clothes in which to stain and bleed,&lt;br /&gt;And a grandchild to talk with while we pick.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can only imagine that the lonely man peoples his driving dreams with friends, that the loveless man surrounds himself with lovely loving women, and that children climb through the dreaming of the childless driver. And how about the areas of regrets? If only I had done so-and-so, or had not said such-and-such - my God, the damn thing might not have happened. Finding this potential in my own mind, I can suspect it in others, but I will never know, for no one ever tells. And this is why, on my journey which was designed for observation, I stayed as much as possible on secondary roads where there was much to see and hear and smell, and avoided the great wide traffic slashes which promote the self by fostering daydreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos of a beautiful Chicago day</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/photos-of-a-beautiful-chicago-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/photos-of-a-beautiful-chicago-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUo8t630lI/AAAAAAAAABk/qiXZptt0qJE/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070029.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058994780004405842&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUo8t630lI/AAAAAAAAABk/qiXZptt0qJE/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070029.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUoFd630jI/AAAAAAAAABU/y82ZlQzw4fM/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070019.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058993830816633394&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUoFd630jI/AAAAAAAAABU/y82ZlQzw4fM/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070019.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Some mornings I wake up and feel an urgent need to go somewhere, to break up my routine - but in a pinch, the traveling urge can be satisfied simply by eating in a different local restaurant, sitting at a different window in a favorite coffeeshop, and exploring different streets downtown. I woke up at 8:15 this morning, took the #6 bus downtown, walked to Lou Mitchell&#39;s (the best breakfast restaurant in America), and then spent the day exploring the West Loop, reading at Border&#39;s, and buying some summer clothes. It was 80 degrees and sunny.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUpGd630mI/AAAAAAAAABs/Dlhd0t1pRhE/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070033.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058994947508130402&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUpGd630mI/AAAAAAAAABs/Dlhd0t1pRhE/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070033.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUnkt630hI/AAAAAAAAABE/aEH8DKCe6l0/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070034.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058993268175917586&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUnkt630hI/AAAAAAAAABE/aEH8DKCe6l0/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070034.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUnDd630fI/AAAAAAAAAA0/QjoqLU8JgVQ/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070007.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058992696945267186&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUnDd630fI/AAAAAAAAAA0/QjoqLU8JgVQ/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070007.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmU9630cI/AAAAAAAAAAc/6f-GyYbbNl0/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070006.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058991898081350082&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmU9630cI/AAAAAAAAAAc/6f-GyYbbNl0/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070006.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmbN630dI/AAAAAAAAAAk/T3QLRpAJaVM/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070013.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058992005455532498&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmbN630dI/AAAAAAAAAAk/T3QLRpAJaVM/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070013.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmrd630eI/AAAAAAAAAAs/Fox9dEgbdlg/s1600-h/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070028.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5058992284628406754&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RjUmrd630eI/AAAAAAAAAAs/Fox9dEgbdlg/s320/2007_0429downtowntrip4-29-070028.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;---
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: http://ryanmccarl.com
Wide Awake Minds: http://www.wideawakeminds.com
Blog: http://blog.ryanmccarl.com
Twitter: http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl
Facebook: http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
