<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/history/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Great Depression and the New Deal</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in the history of the 1930s, and&amp;nbsp;I just finished Eric Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/IdP1dDU&#34;&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;It has become increasingly clear to me that there are major holes in the dominant historical narrative about the Great Depression, the New Deal, and the Roosevelt administration. &amp;nbsp;The standard, high-school-textbook version of the story goes something like this: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Greedy stock market speculators caused the stock market crash of 1929, which triggered the worst depression in American history; President Herbert Hoover believed in an outdated&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;economic philosophy, so he did nothing; thankfully, President Roosevelt was elected, and his New Deal policies saved capitalism and helped the common man survive the Great Depression; and finally, World War II was an enormous boon to the U.S. economy, and it finally solved the problem once and for all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those of us with a preference for economic liberty and peace should be greatly disturbed by this story. &amp;nbsp;If true, it suggests that&amp;nbsp;the best ways to fix a broken economy are&amp;nbsp;(1) total war, including conscription; and (2) dramatic increases in government taxation, spending, regulation, and redistribution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thankfully, there are convincing reasons to believe that the standard narrative is wrong. &amp;nbsp;There is a lot more I need to read on the topic, but here are some resources and ideas that I look forward to exploring further:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Murray N. Rothbard,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/rothbard/agd/contents.asp&#34;&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(free PDF and ebook)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terry.uga.edu/~selgin/econ4710/Econ4710Syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;The Economics of America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (course syllabus in PDF format with many links to readings). &amp;nbsp;My interest in this topic is largely attributable to a fantastic lecture I heard Selgin deliver in June.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-David Gordon, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/3349&#34;&gt;What you must read about the Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Mises Daily,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;2/22/09&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/article.aspx?record=157&amp;amp;month=5&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of Hall and Ferguson&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Robert P. Murphy,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PWGB3Mb&#34;&gt;The Politically Incorrect Guide to the Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stephen Davies, &amp;ldquo;Top 3 Myths About the Great Depression and the New Deal,&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnliberty.org/&#34;&gt;LearnLiberty.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/7QLoeehMw0w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my next post, I will share excerpts from Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/i&gt;, which - unlike the libertarian works linked to above - is firmly on the side of the standard narrative.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jacques Barzun, &#39;From Dawn to Decadence&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jacques-barzun-from-dawn-to-decadence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jacques-barzun-from-dawn-to-decadence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Note: The excerpts below are related to issues outside of education; I will post education-related excerpts from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060928832?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0060928832&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;From Dawn to Decadence&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widawamin-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0060928832&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, my education blog. You can find these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2011/03/education-related-excerpts-from-jacques.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PNtVFwECE4s/TXGx_OfcLYI/AAAAAAAABBM/48lZ9HY2N4Q/s1600/dawntodecadence.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;172&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PNtVFwECE4s/TXGx_OfcLYI/AAAAAAAABBM/48lZ9HY2N4Q/s320/dawntodecadence.jpg&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are a few excerpts from what I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In any art a new technical power leads to uses and ideas not suspected at first.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Another singularity in Petrarch&amp;rsquo;s life was that he climbed a high hill in southern France in order to admire the view. If it was done before him, it was not recorded. Nature had been endlessly discussed, but as a generality, not as &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y47FlKE0hMI/TXGzHSrRQ-I/AAAAAAAABBk/JQRq9kBlJo8/s1600/barzun-time%2Bmontage-56-97.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y47FlKE0hMI/TXGzHSrRQ-I/AAAAAAAABBk/JQRq9kBlJo8/s320/barzun-time%2Bmontage-56-97.jpg&#34; width=&#34;243&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inquisition as such, that is, apart from methods and severity of results, has remained a live institution. The many dictatorships of the 20th century have relied on it and in free countries it thrives ad hoc - hunting down German sympathizers during the First World War, interning Japanese-Americans during the second, and pursuing Communist fellow-travelers during the Cold War.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Heretics are given us so that we might not remain in infancy. They question, there is discussion, and definitions are arrived at to make an organized faith.&amp;rdquo; -St. Augustine&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It takes hundreds of the gifted to make half a dozen of the great.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Why is fame so capricious a goddess? In any country its favor depends on attention by one group of critics rather than another, or again by the fanatical devotion that goes to the right man at the right time. Some element of the work must chime in with some concern of the moment.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;rdquo;(Smoking) is a custom loathful to the eye, hateful to the nose, harmful to the brain, dangerous to the lungs; and the black, stinking fumes thereof nearest resembling the horrible stygian smoke of the pit that is bottomless.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;James I of England (1604)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Desire must be dammed up to be self-renewing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mankind does nothing save through initiatives on the part of inventors, great or small, and imitation by the rest of us. Individuals show the way, set the patterns, The rivalry of the patterns is the history of the world.&amp;rdquo; -William James (1908)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Where in the scheme of things do I belong? Who am I, anyway? Such questions made up the &amp;lsquo;identity crisis&amp;rsquo; studied by psychiatrists whose patients had not &amp;lsquo;found themselves.&amp;rsquo; &amp;hellip;Finding oneself was a misnomer; a self is not found but made; and the anti-hero, anti-history bias was an obstacle to making it, because a starting point from the past was missing; it had to be made from scratch.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In Geneva under Calvin people had to go to church twice daily. &amp;hellip;If stubborn and persistent in sin, the dear soul must be turned over to the civil authorities. Adultery might mean death, quite as if Jesus had not dealt rather differently with the woman taken in adultery. Blasphemy, that curious crime of &amp;lsquo;damaging God by bringing Him into ill-repute,&amp;rsquo; was even more unforgivable. &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Calvinism, it has been said, makes every man the enemy of every other, as well as his own. Certainly its rigor accounts for the agonizing fear of sin that has been recorded in many lives&amp;hellip;. The number of plain people, especially adolescents, whose minds were tortured by Calvinist sermons in England in America may be imagined.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Luther wrote that &amp;lsquo;the Christian man is dead to the world,&amp;rsquo; yet, as we saw, he relished life. The ailing Calvin was not a relisher; his advice is contradictory and leaves nature a rather narrow crack through which to manifest God&amp;rsquo;s goodness.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bliss was it in that dawn to be alive,&lt;br /&gt;But to be young was very heaven.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Wordsworth remembering the French Revolution&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Montaigne lived in an age full of people who knew that they, and they alone, had the truth, direct from God - and these truth-bearers all disagreed. Reflecting on a far wider set of facts and with greater self-knowledge, Montaigne was at pains to make the point that Cromwell later phrased so superbly: &amp;lsquo;By the bowels of Christ, bethink ye that ye may be mistaken.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Erasmus loved travel and the good things of life, including the rapid, flashing conversation of learned friends in Paris, Oxford, and&amp;hellip;Basel.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The welfare ideal did not merely see to it that the poor should be able to survive, but that everybody should be safe and at ease in a hundred ways. Besides providing health care, pensions (&amp;ldquo;social security&amp;rdquo;), and workmen&amp;rsquo;s compensation for accidents, it undertook to protect every employee by workplace regulations and every consumer by laws against harm from foods, drugs, and the multiform dangers that industry creates. All appliances were subject to design control and inspection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;At the same time, it was also held that the state had the duty of supporting art and science, medical research, and the integrity of the environment, while it must also make sure that all children were not simply literate but educated up to and through college - rules, rules, definitions, classifications, and exceptions = indignation - and litigation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;The cost of welfare in money was huge and in mental effort exorbitant. &amp;hellip;The task of distributing benefits was alone overwhelming. High taxes were unavoidable, and so was waste. Add to it corruption, also inevitable when inspectors are afoot, and it should have been no surprise to the contemporaries that the program fell short of its aim. There was still poverty, derelicts on the street, unattended illness, and complaints of &amp;lsquo;not enough&amp;rsquo; from every welfared group in turn - workers, farmers, businessmen, doctors, artists, scientists, teachers, prisoners, and the homeless.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jacques Barzun &lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060928832?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=widawamin-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0060928832&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;From Dawn to Decadence: 500 Years of Western Cultural Life, 1500 to the Present&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widawamin-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0060928832&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Frankl&#39;s &#39;Man&#39;s Search for Meaning&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading Viktor Frankl&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=pd_lpo_k2_dp_sr_1/189-8560150-0000706?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=lpo-top-stripe-1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0A2K5K4WK03NGZMZ523G&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=486539851&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0671023373&#34;&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankl, a psychiatrist, was imprisoned in the Nazi concentration camps, including Auschwitz, for several years.  He survived the experience and went on to develop the theory of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy&#34;&gt;logotherapy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a branch of psychoanalysis that focuses on human beings&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;will to meaning.&amp;rdquo;  The part of the book that discusses Frankl&amp;rsquo;s memories of his camp experience is, like any Holocaust memoir worth its salt, extremely disturbing and difficult to read, but it ought to be read in spite of that.  Here are a few (non-graphic) excerpts from the book, which I highly recommend:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Soon we had resumed the previous day&amp;rsquo;s positions in the ditch.  The frozen ground cracked under the point of the pickaxes, and sparks flew.  The men were silent, their brains numb.  My mind still clung to the image of my wife.  A thought crossed my mind: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know if she were still alive.  I knew only one thing - which I have learned well by now: Love goes very far beyond the physical person of the beloved.  It finds its deepest meaning in his spiritual being, his inner self.  Whether or not he is actually present, whether or not he is still alive at all, ceases somehow to be of importance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If there is a meaning of life at all, then there must be a meaning in suffering.  Suffering is an ineradicable part of life, even as fate and death.  Without suffering and death human life cannot be complete.  The way in which a man accepts his fate and all the suffering it entails, the way in which he takes up his cross, gives him ample opportunity - even under the most difficult circumstances - to add a deeper meaning to his life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What was really needed was a fundamental change in our attitude toward life.  We had to learn ourselves and, furthermore, we had to teach the despairing men, that &lt;em&gt;it did not really matter what we expected from life, but rather what life expected from us.&lt;/em&gt;  We needed to stop asking about the meaning of life, and instead to think of ourselves as those who were being questioned by life - daily and hourly.  Our answer must consist, not in talk and meditation, but in right action and right conduct.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I remember two cases of would-be suicide, which bore a striking similarity to each other.  Both men had talked of their intentions to commit suicide.  Both used the typical argument - they had nothing more to expect from life.  In both cases it was a question of getting them to realize that life was still expecting something from them; something in the future was expected of them.  We found, in fact, that for the one it was his child whom he adored and who was waiting for him in a foreign country.  For the other it was a thing, not a person.  This man was a scientist and had written a series of books which still needed to be finished.  His work could not be done by anyone else, any more than another person could ever take the place of the father in his child&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Not only our experiences, but all we have done, whatever great thoughts we may have had, and all we have suffered, all this is not lost, though it is past; we have brought it into being.  Having been is also a kind of being, and perhaps the surest kind.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I asked the poor creatures who listened to me attentively in the darkness of the hut to face up to the seriousness of our position.  They must not lose hope but should keep their courage in the certainty that the hopelessness of our struggle did not detract from its dignity and its meaning.  I said that someone looks down on us in different hours - a friend, a wife, somebody alive or dead, or a God - and he would not expect us to disappoint him.  He would hope to find us suffering proudly - not miserably - knowing how to die.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When we spoke about attempts to give a man in camp mental courage, we said that he had to be shown something to look forward to in the future.  He had to be reminded that life still waited for him, that a human being waited for his return.  But after liberation?  There were some men who found that no one awaited them.  Woe to him who found that the person whose memory alone had given him courage in camp did not exist any more!  Woe to him who, when the day of his dreams finally came, found it so different from all he had longed for!  Perhaps he boarded a trolley, traveled out to the home which he had seen for years in his mind, and only in his mind, and pressed the bell, just as he has longed to do in thousands of dreams, only to find that the person who should open the door was not there, and would never be there again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Viktor E. Frankl&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the letters of Justice William O. Douglas</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discovering-the-letters-of-justice-william-o.-douglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discovering-the-letters-of-justice-william-o.-douglas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was sorting through some books in my closet yesterday, and I discovered a fantastic book which drew me away from my regular reading: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Douglas-Letters-Selections-Private-Justice/dp/0917561465&#34;&gt;The Douglas Letters: Selections from the Private Papers of William O. Douglas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Melvin I. Urkofsky.  William O. Douglas was a brilliant, contrarian Associate Justice on the Supreme Court as well as a transformative environmentalist and New Dealer who crusaded against rampant speculation and corruption in the financial industry.  His writing is insightful and often hilarious.  Here are a few samples:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramsey_Clark&#34;&gt;Ramsey Clark&lt;/a&gt;, 4/28/70:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On my visit to Baghdad, I went to the University with my interpreter to see what books, if any, they had on our Constitution or Bill of Rights or Jefferson, Madison, democracy, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That library was bare on those subjects.  So when I returned, I prepared what I called the Douglas Eight Foot Shelf which I thought should be in every underdeveloped nation.  I thought then - and still think - that those ideas are more important than military missions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To Max Radin (professor at Berkeley Law School), 5/27/46:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;If you are willing, I will ask you to find me a law clerk each year&amp;hellip;.I need not only a bright chap, but also a hard-working fellow with a smell for facts as well as for law.  I do not want a hide-bound, conservative fellow.  What I want is a Max Radin - a fellow who can hold his own in these sophisticated circles and who is not going to end up as a stodgy, hide-bound lawyer.  I want the kind of fellow for whom this work would be an exhilaration, who will be going into teaching or into practice of the law for the purpose of promoting the public good.  I do not want to fill the big law offices of the country with my law clerks&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the&lt;/em&gt; Wall Street Journal, 10/16/78&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To the Editors:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Notice of my demise has been emanating from several sources recently, not least of which is your Journal.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please be advised that I am today joining the ranks of citizens known as octogenarians and I assure you that I was never in a position to be resurrected in order to achieve such standing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;To Edward L.R. Elson, 12/7/77:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Concerning my funeral arrangements&amp;hellip;From my hobo days, I knew the famous songwriter Woody Guthrie who wrote a song called &amp;ldquo;This Land is Your Land, This Land is My Land.&amp;rdquo;  It reflects not a socialist dream of mine, but many of the freedoms that are explicit or implicit in the Constitution, such as the right to move from place to place to look for a job or establish a new home, and the right to move interstate without payment of a fee, as some states within the last thirty years have tried to impose.  In other words, it expresses the vagrancy issue as I have expressed it and as it has become in-grained in the law. (See my opinion in &lt;em&gt;Papachristou et al v. City of Jacksonville&lt;/em&gt;, 405 U.S. 156 [1972].)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.law.umich.edu/historyandtraditions/faculty/Faculty_Lists/Alpha_Faculty/Pages/PeterKWesten.aspx&#34;&gt;Peter K. Westen&lt;/a&gt; (Douglas&amp;rsquo; law clerk, now a highly-respected professor at the University of Michigan Law School), 10/1/68:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(After chewing him out for various mistakes)&lt;/em&gt;: You might think these things over, because the first case we have to dispose of when I get back is the case of P.K. Westen.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Charles Taylor and Erich Auerbach</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One way to put the question I want to answer here is this: why was it virtually impossible not to believe in God in, say, 1500 in our Western society, while in 2000 many of us find this not only easy, but even inescapable?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Important as science is to our present outlook, we mustn&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate its causal role here, and make it the main motor of the transformation.  Our encasing in secular time is also something we have brought about in the way we live and order our lives.  It has been brought about by the same social and ideological changes which have wrought disenchantment.  In particular, the disciplines of our modern civilized order have led us to measure and organize time as never before in human history.  Time has become a precious resource, not to be &amp;ldquo;wasted&amp;rdquo;.  The result has been the creation of a tight, ordered time environment.  This has enveloped us, until it comes to seem like nature.  We have constructed an environment in which we live a uniform, univocal secular time, which we try to measure and control in order to get things done.  This &amp;ldquo;time frame&amp;rdquo; deserves, perhaps more than any other facet of modernity, Weber&amp;rsquo;s famous description of a &amp;ldquo;stahlhartes Gehäuse&amp;rdquo; (iron cage).  It occludes all higher times, makes them even hard to conceive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Augustine sees ordinary time as dispersal, distensio, losing the unity, being cut off from our past and out of touch with our future.  We get lost in our little parcel of time.  But we have an irrepressible craving for eternity, and so we strive to go beyond this.  Unfortunately, this all too often takes the form of our trying to invest our little parcel with eternal significance, and therefore divinising things, and therefore falling deeper into sin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If it is true that man is capable of everything horrible, it is also true that the horrible always engenders counterforces and that in most epochs of atrocious occurrences the great vital forces of the human soul reveal themselves: love and sacrifice, heroism in the service of conviction, and the ceaseless search for possibilities of a purer existence.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To write history is so difficult that most historians are forced to make concessions to the technique of legend.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Old Testament, in so far as it is concerned with human events, ranges through all three domains: legend, historical reporting, and interpretative historical theology.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Homeric poems, then, though their intellectual, linguistic, and above all syntactical culture appears to be so&amp;hellip;highly developed, are yet comparatively simple in their picture of human beings; and no less so in relation to the real life which they describe in general.  Delight in physical existence is everything to them, and their highest aim is to make that delight perceptible to us.  &amp;hellip;(The Homeric heroes) wake every morning as if it were the first day of their lives: their emotions, though strong, are simple and find expression instantly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Far from seeking, like Homer, merely to make us forget our own reality for a few hours, (the Bible) seeks to overcome our reality: we are to fit our own life into its world, feel ourselves to be elements in its structure of universal history.  This becomes increasingly difficult the further our historical environment is removed from that of the Biblical books; and if these nevertheless maintain their claim to absolute authority, it is inevitable that they themselves be adapted through interpretative transformation.  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy to separate the historical from the legendary in general.  Their structure is different.  Even where the legendary does not immediately betray itself by elements of the miraculous, by the repetition of well-known standard motives, typical patterns and themes, through neglect of clear details of time and place, and the like, it is generally recognizable by its composition.  It runs far too smoothly.  All cross-currents, all friction, all that is casual, secondary to the main events and themes, everything unresolved, truncated, and uncertain, which confuses the clear progress of the action and the simple orientation of the actors, has disappeared.  The historical event which we witness, or learn from the testimony of those who witnessed it, runs much more variously, contradictorily, and confusedly&amp;hellip;.  Legend arranges its material in a simple and straightforward way; it detaches it from its contemporary historical context, so that the latter will not confuse it; it knows only clearly outlined men who act from few and simple motives and the continuity of whose feelings and actions remains uninterrupted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Auerbach&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Mimesis: The Representation of Reality in Western Literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Czeslaw Milosz and Herman Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished &amp;ldquo;Moby-Dick&amp;rdquo; yesterday. It was one of the most difficult books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read - but also incredibly beautiful and rewarding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The past is inaccurate, because we cannot determine how it was in fact, no matter how hard we try.  We must rely on people&amp;rsquo;s memory, which is treacherous, because memory is constantly juggling and revising the data of experience.  &amp;hellip;In telling about an event, we ourselves cannot avoid revising it, because our narrative simplifies and composes a whole out of selected components, while omitting others.  It suffices to compare our knowledge of facts with their depiction in chronicles, journalistic accounts, memoirs, to understand the need for fantasizing that is somehow inscribed in the language itself, and which draws us into the forest of fiction.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Los Angeles horrifies me.  In our imagination money is still steel and the production of factories; it is difficult to accustom oneself to the great change, the complete reversal, that has granted a marginal human activity, entertainment, its central position as a source of money or power.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I am moved by the very fact of that woman&amp;rsquo;s existence, of which all that has remained is this verse.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I know my own weakness and am inclined to consider myself&amp;hellip;as a tangle of reflexes, a drunken child in the fog.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The essential characteristic of fame is its illusory nature, for what does a famous name mean if those who mention it are not well-informed about why it is famous?  That, after all, is the fate of the majority of monuments in every large city; they turn into signs from which the content has evaporated.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Everything that enlarges man fortifies us; everything that depicts him as a multidimensional being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABCs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A whole hour now passed; gold-beaten out to ages.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What a lovely day again! were it a new-made world, and made for a summer-house to the angels, and this morning the first of its throwing open to them, a fairer day could not dawn upon that world.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ah! how they still strove through that infinite blueness to seek out the thing that might destroy them!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But Ahab&amp;rsquo;s glance was averted; like a blighted fruit tree he shook, and cast his last, cindered apple to the soil.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Close! stand close to me, Starbuck; let me look into a human eye; it is better than to gaze into sea or sky; better than to gaze upon God.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What! how can you see better of a dark night than anybody else, never mind how foolish?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Old man of oceans! of all this fiery life of thine, what at length will remain but one little heap of ashes!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let faith oust fact; let fancy oust memory; I look deep down and do believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Would to God these blessed calms would last. But the mingled, mingling threads of life are woven by warp and woof: calms crossed by storms, a storm for every calm. There is no steady unretracing progress in this life; we do not advance through fixed gradations, and at the last one pause: - through infancy&amp;rsquo;s unconscious spell, boyhood&amp;rsquo;s thoughtless faith, adolescence&amp;rsquo; doubt (the common doom), then scepticism, then disbelief, resting at last in manhood&amp;rsquo;s pondering repose of If. But once gone through, we trace the round again; and are infants, boys, and men, and Ifs eternally. Where lies the final harbor, whence we unmoor no more? in what rapt ether sails the world, of which the weariest will never weary?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I like a good grip; I like to feel something in this slippery world that can hold, man.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seat thyself sultanically among the moons of Saturn, and take high abstracted man alone; and he seems a wonder, a grandeur, and a woe. But from the same point, take mankind in mass, and for the most part, they seem a mob of unnecessary duplicates, both contemporary and hereditary. But most humble though he was, and far from furnishing an example of the high, humane abstraction; the Pequod&amp;rsquo;s carpenter was no duplicate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy Doniger&#39;s &#39;The Hindus: An Alternative History&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s1600-h/doniger.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s400/doniger.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5330565091969721250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently picked up Wendy Doniger&amp;rsquo;s new book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hindus-Alternative-History-Wendy-Doniger/dp/1594202052&#34;&gt;The Hindus: An Alternative History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Doniger, the Mircea Eliade Distinguished Service Professor of Religions at the University of Chicago Divinity School and America&amp;rsquo;s foremost scholar of Hinduism, set out to challenge many prevailing notions of Hinduism and argue for a more inclusive, broad view of the tradition, a view that recognizes the diversity of folk religions in the Hindu world as well as the contributions of women, Muslims, and people of the lower castes to the Hindu tradition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The book was reviewed last weekend in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times Book Review&lt;/em&gt;, and it is slated to be chosen as an Editor&amp;rsquo;s Pick next week.  A comment by Professor Doniger can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://newsweek.washingtonpost.com/onfaith/panelists/wendy_doniger/2009/03/the_battle_over_hindu_history.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the favorable &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; review by Pankaj Mishra can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/26/books/review/Mishra-t.html?_r=1&amp;ref=books&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we must remember Iraq</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;The Next Forgotten War&lt;/a&gt;,” an op-ed of mine, was published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In it, I argue that we must keep the memory of the Iraq War, and the individuals caught up in its maelstroms, alive:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Iraq recedes from the headlines and slips from the public’s mind to make room for the next &amp;lsquo;crisis,&amp;rsquo; we have a responsibility to give some thought to the two million Iraqi refugees displaced by the war and the tens of thousands of Americans and Iraqis killed or maimed as a consequence of the war. And what we should remember is not statistics or grand narratives, but individual stories and the weight they lend to the principles of prudence, humanism, and nonviolence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the article, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/As%20Iraq%20recedes%20from%20the%20headlines%20and%20slips%20from%20the%20public%E2%80%99s%20mind%20to%20make%20room%20for%20the%20next%20%22crisis,%22%20we%20have%20a%20responsibility%20to%20give%20some%20thought%20to%20the%20two%20million%20Iraqi%20refugees%20displaced%20by%20the%20war%20and%20the%20tens%20of%20thousands%20of%20Americans%20and%20Iraqis%20killed%20or%20maimed%20as%20a%20consequence%20of%20the%20war.%20And%20what%20we%20should%20remember%20is%20not%20statistics%20or%20grand%20narratives,%20but%20individual%20stories%20and%20the%20weight%20they%20lend%20to%20the%20principles%20of%20prudence,%20humanism,%20and%20nonviolence.&#34;&gt;linking to it&lt;/a&gt; or sharing it with others you think may be interested.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard Zinn on World War II</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve intended to read Howard Zinn&amp;rsquo;s revisionist history of the United States - &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; - for years, and I finally buckled down and started it this week. It is an excellent and eye-opening book, to say the least, and I found myself becoming absorbed in and largely agreeing with the narrative of the first few chapters - his interpretation of the &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; and colonization of America. Although I&amp;rsquo;m usually not willing to follow Zinn to his ultimate conclusions, I find his eagerness to tear down the myths and falsehoods surrounding the idea of &amp;ldquo;American exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; refreshing - especially after the nationalist fervor of a Presidential election season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zinn reminds us that Americans are fallible human beings like any others, capable of acts of greatness as well as acts of shame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I skipped ahead to find out what Zinn had to say about World War II - the war most often held up in America as an example of America&amp;rsquo;s unique greatness, of America-as-savior-and-beacon-of-hope. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from what I found:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, if the entrance of the United States into World War II was (as so many Americans believed at the time, observing the Nazi invasions) to defend the principle of nonintervention in the affairs of other countries, the nation&amp;rsquo;s record cast doubt on its ability to uphold that principle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;As Bruce Russett says: &amp;ldquo;Throughout the 1930s the United States government had done little to resist the Japanese advance on the Asian continent.&amp;rdquo; But: &amp;ldquo;The Southwest Pacific area was of undeniable economic importance to the United States - at the time most of America&amp;rsquo;s tin and rubber came from there, as did substantial qualities of other raw materials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A State Department memorandum on Japanese expansion, a year before Pearl Harbor, did not talk of the independence of China or the principle of self-determination. It said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;our general diplomatic and strategic position would be considerably weakened - by our loss of Chinese, Indian, and South Seas markets (and by our loss of much of the Japanese market for our goods, as Japan would become more and more self-sufficient) as well as by insurmountable restrictions upon our access to the rubber, tin, jute, and other vital materials of the Asian and Oceanic regions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The plight of Jews in German-occupied Europe, which many people thought was at the heart of the war against the Axis, was not a chief concern of Roosevelt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Was the war being fought to establish that Hitler was wrong in his ideas of white Nordic supremacy over &amp;ldquo;inferior&amp;rdquo; races? The United States&amp;rsquo; armed forces were segregated by race.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In one of its policies, the United States came close to direct duplication of Fascism. This was in its treatment of the Japanese-Americans living on the West Coast. After the Pearl Harbor attack, anti-Japanese hysteria spread in the government. One Congressman said: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m for catching every Japanese in America, Alaska, and Hawaii now and putting them in concentration camps&amp;hellip;. Damn them! Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of them!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt did not share this frenzy, but he calmly signed Executive Order 9066, in February 1942, giving the army the power, without warrants or indictments or hearings, to arrest every Japanese-American on the West Coast - 110,000 men, women, and children - to take them from their homes, transport them to camps far into the interior, and keep them there under prison conditions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hatred against the enemy, against the Japanese particularly, became widespread. Racism was clearly at work. &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; magazine, reporting the battle of Iwo Jima, said: &amp;ldquo;The ordinary unreasoning Jap is ignorant. Perhaps he is human. Nothing&amp;hellip;indicates it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, there was a mass base of support for what became the heaviest bombardment of civilians ever undertaken in any war: the aerial attacks on German and Japanese cities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Italy had bombed cities in the Ethiopian war; Italy and germany had bombed civilians in the Spanish Civil War; at the start of World War II German planes dropped bombs on Rotterdam in Holland, Convetry in England, and elsewhere. Roosevelt had described these as &amp;ldquo;inhuman barbarism that has profoundly shocked the conscience of humanity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These German bombings were very small compared with the British and American bombings of German cities. &amp;hellip;The English flew at night with no pretense of aiming at &amp;ldquo;military&amp;rdquo; targets; the Americans flew in the daytime and pretended precision, but bombing from high altitudes made that impossible. The climax of this terror bormbing was the bombing of Dresden in early 1945, in which the tremendous heat generated by the bombs created a vacuum into which fire leaped swiftly in a great firestorm through the city. More than 100,000 died in Dresden. [See Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slaughterhouse Five&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out Zinn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/A-Peoples-History-of-the-United-States/Howard-Zinn/e/9780060838652/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on psychology, religion, and politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in mundane situations, the individual must &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; in order to discover what he is and he must act in order to continue experiencing aspects of himself which he values and enjoys.  If he thinks of himself as a businessman, a parent, an athlete, an intellectual, he must engage in behavior appropriate to this self-image.  If he does not, he must redefine himself, or he will be left feeling anxious and needful.  (Here is the reason for the psychological shock of retirement; the man who has retired may find that suddenly he can no longer &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;that which he most valued himself for being.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Past actions through which he sought to know and to accept the self are not capable of satisfying this need in the present.  Recalling the past can only remind the individual of what he used to be.  The erstwhile football hero who is still reliving the big game fifteen years later, or the ex-campus queen who tries to give meaning to her life by clinging to her reign over the prom of a decade ago, are pathetic figures.  As the existentialists have pointed out, man must act in order to be, and what he becomes is largely the summation of his actions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Paradoxical though it may seem, it is when the individual is with others that he is best able to enjoy and expand many aspects of himself, to refine and verify his self-image.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Men hate in others those things - and only those things - which they despise in themselves.  It is possible to disapprove of other people in a rational and dispassionate manner, but to hate them is an irrational and impassioned act.  The passion betrays the underlying self-contempt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Distance enables the lover to see his beloved purely in terms of the projections he hangs on her.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The general rule is that people who enjoy life enjoy marriage. Some people would be unhappy with any spouse, for they do not allow themselves happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snell Putney and Gail J. Putney&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Adjusted American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That hatred springs more from self-contempt than from a legitimate grievance is seen in the intimate connection between hatred and a guilty conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Eric Hoffer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Insanity in individuals is something rare - but in groups, parties, nations, and epochs, it is the rule.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If our faith is real, it must encroach upon our life. The Christian Confession in its original Church form will always be exposed to the misunderstanding that the Christian regards the Creed as a matter of heart and conscience, but that here on earth and in the world other truths hold good. The world lives in this misunderstanding; it regards the whole of Christianity as a friendly &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo;, connected with the &amp;lsquo;realm of religion&amp;rsquo;, which is respected and which ought to be left untampered with; and so we get rid of the matter! But this misunderstanding might even have come from within; a Christian might quite well wish to have this realm for himself and to guard faith like a sensitive plant. The relationship between the Church and the world has been widely understood as a question of a fixing of frontiers, whereby each secured itself behind its own frontier, although from time to time it came to a skirmish. From the Church&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, however, such a fixing of frontiers can never exhaust its task. By the very nature of the Christian Church there is only one task, to make the Confession heard in the sphere of the world as well.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us beware of remaining stuck where we are and refusing to advance to meet worldly attitudes. For instance, in Germany in 1933 there was plenty of serious, profound and living Christianity and confession&amp;hellip;. But unfortunately this faith and confession of the German Church remained embedded in the language of the Church, and did not translate what was being excellently said in the language of the Church into the political attitude demanded at the time; in which it would have become clear that the Evangelical Church had to say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to National Socialism, &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; from its very roots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Barth&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Dogmatics in Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Joyce&#39;s &#39;Ulysses&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-joyces-ulysses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-joyces-ulysses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had Pyrrhus not fallen by a beldham&amp;rsquo;s hand in Argos or Julius Caesar not been knifed to death? They are not to be thought away. Time has branded them and fettered they are lodged in the room of the infinite possibilities they have ousted. But can those have been possible seeing that they never were? Or was that only possible which came to pass? Weave, weaver of the wind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-History, Stephen said, is a nightmare from which I am trying to awake.&lt;br /&gt;From the playfield the boys raised a shout. A whirring whistle: goal. What if that nightmare gave you a back kick?&lt;br /&gt;-The ways of the Creator are not our ways, Mr Deasy said. All history moves towards one great goal, the manifestation of God.&lt;br /&gt;Stephen jerked his thumb towards the window, saying:&lt;br /&gt;-That is God.&lt;br /&gt;Hooray! Ay! Whirrwhee!&lt;br /&gt;-What? Mr Deasy asked.&lt;br /&gt;-A shout in the street, Stephen answered, shrugging his shoulders.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For that are you pining, the bark of their applause?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Across the sands of all the world, followed by the sun&amp;rsquo;s flaming sword, to the west, trekking to evening lands.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our souls, shame-wounded by our sins, cling to us yet more, a woman to her lover clinging, the more the more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Somewhere in the east: early morning: set off at dawn, travel round in front of the sun, steal a day&amp;rsquo;s march on him. Keep it up for ever never grow a day old technically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thank you, sir. Another time.&lt;br /&gt;A speck of eager fire from foxeyes thanked him. He withdrew his gaze after an instant. No: better not: another time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To smell the gentle smoke of tea, fume of the pan, sizzling butter. Be near her ample bedwarmed flesh. Yes, yes.&lt;br /&gt;Quick warm sunlight came running from Berkeley Road, swiftly, in slim sandals, along the brightening footpath. Runs, she runs to meet me, a girl with gold hair on the wind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James Joyce&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Ulysses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from recent reading: Robert Jackson, Nate Shaw</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-recent-reading-robert-jackson-nate-shaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-recent-reading-robert-jackson-nate-shaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Struggles to coerce uniformity of sentiment in support of some end thought essentially to their time and country have been waged by many good, as well as by evil, men.  &amp;hellip;Those who begin coercive elimination of dissent soon find themselves exterminating dissenters.  Compulsory unification of opinion achieves only the unanimity of the graveyard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Robert Jackson, writing for the U.S. Supreme Court&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Virginia_State_Board_of_Education_v._Barnette&#34;&gt;West Virginia State Board of Education v. Barnette&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(1943)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Court found that the underlying issue was not any claimed conflict between liberty of conscience and the state&amp;rsquo;s ability to survive in time of crisis.  The issue was not weak versus strong government, but, rather, seeing the strength of America in &amp;ldquo;individual freedom of mind&amp;rdquo; rather than in &amp;ldquo;officially disciplined uniformity for which history indicates a disappointing and disastrous end.&amp;rdquo;  Enforced conformity, far from teaching the value of liberty, would &amp;ldquo;strangle the free mind at its source and teach youth to discount important principles of our government as mere platitudes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jordan Lorence and Harvey A. Silverglate&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefire.org/&#34;&gt;FIRE&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Guide to First-Year Orientation and Thought Reform on Campus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a whole, if children got book learnin enough they&amp;rsquo;d jump off of this country; they don&amp;rsquo;t want to plow, don&amp;rsquo;t want no part of no sort of field work.  That&amp;rsquo;s the way it runs here.  The biggest majority runs off to some place where they can get a public job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And I never did forget none of his treatments toward me.  You forever remember the wrongs done to you as long as you live.  But it&amp;rsquo;s just like forgivin if you just go on in this world and don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;So my daddy married Maggie Reed and him and her was the father and mother of thirteen children - my old daddy was a rooster, he was a humdinger.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;My grandmother and other people that I knowed grew up in slavery time, they wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with their feredom.  They felt like motherless children - they wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied but they had to live under the impression that they were.  Had to act in a way just as though everything was all right.  But they would open up every once in a while and talk about slavery time - they didn&amp;rsquo;t know nothin about no freedom then, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what it was but they wanted it.  And when they got it they knew that what they got wasn&amp;rsquo;t what they wanted, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t freedom, really.  Had to do whatever the white man directed em to do, couldn&amp;rsquo;t voice their heart&amp;rsquo;s desire.  That was the way of life that I was born and raised into.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, years ago I heard that President Lincoln freed the colored people; but it didn&amp;rsquo;t amount to a hill of beans.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He was imprisoned in slavery for fifteen years - slavery were equal or worser than prison, but both of em bad and the poor colored man knows more about them two subjects than anybody.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And when I got to be a little old boy, when I got big enough to catch on to what people said, and even to the words of the old people, and the Bible, it was instilled in me many a time: the bottom rail will come to the top someday.  I taken that to mean a change in the later years, durin of my lifetime maybe.  I believe, if that day come, the poor generation on earth will banish away their toils and snares.  But won&amp;rsquo;t nobody do it for them but themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I was big enough and old enough to abominate what I seed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t a slave but he lived like one.  Because he had to take what the white people gived to get along.  That much of slavery ways was still hangin on.  According to slave days you wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed the privilege to seek knowledge without the white man, master man, allowin you.  And that was the rule durin of my daddy&amp;rsquo;s lifetime and through my life, to be sure.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;They claimed they had a note against him and they took all he had.  In those days, it was out of the knowledge of the colored man to understand that if you gived a man a note on everything you had, exactly how you was subject to the laws.  Because the colored man wasn&amp;rsquo;t educated in the laws for his use; they was a great, dark secret to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nate Shaw&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Theodore Rosengarten (ed), &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/All-Gods-Dangers-Life-Nate/dp/0226727742/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1201377890&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;All God&amp;rsquo;s Dangers: The Life of Nate Shaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dewey, Hoyt, and Freud</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the past provide the only means at command for understanding the present.  &amp;hellip;The institutions and customs that exist in the present and that give rise to present social ills and dislocations did not arise overnight.  They have a long history behind them.  Attempt to deal with them simply on the basis of what is obvious in the present is bound to result in adoption of superficial measures which in the end will only render existing problems more acute and more difficult to solve.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Growth depends upon the presence of difficulty to be overcome by the exercise of intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Dewey&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Experience and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts from a history of the Great Depression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching had investigated college athletics earlier in the year (1929) and found them to be the same across the country - &amp;ldquo;sodden with commercialism.&amp;rdquo;  Of 112 schools investigated, only 28 did not offer improper subsidies to athletes.  But instead of hanging their heads in shame, many colleges defended their athletic activities.  A Brown University professor attacked the foundation for meddling.  &amp;hellip;The Big Ten&amp;rsquo;s commissioner of athletics defended the practice of buying college players.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One telephone operator in one of the city&amp;rsquo;s largest hotels wore a new sealskin coat.  Her spending was typical.  She was playing the stock market on a broker&amp;rsquo;s margin account, and boasted neither a bank savings account, insurance, nor a penny in the world except what she earned from week to week.  But would she take her profits and convert them to bonds, as President Hoover wanted her and all Americans to do?  She would not even consider it, for the gambling fever had her, as it had a million other Americans.  The fever had her and them in red-cheeked, bright-eyed frenzy. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For billions of dollars were lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thursday&#34;&gt;that day&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the young telephone operator in the New York hotel who had invested everything she owned in her sealskin coat and in a margin account on the stock exchange.  A hotel resident, unable to complete a telephone call that night, had gone to the switchboard himself, to overhear her talking to her broker, her voice breaking and eyes bathed in tears.  All the telephone operator had left at the end of this Black Thursday was her sealskin coat and her job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;That night the relatives of Abraham Germansky, a wealthy real estate man who lived in Mount Vernon, New York, put in a frantic call to police to help them find Germansky.  He had last been seen late Thursday on Wall Street, tearing up ticker tape and scattering it along the sidewalk.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hunger was not debatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin P. Hoyt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Tempering Years &lt;/span&gt;(a history of America between 1929 and 1939)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is clear that in their play children repeat everything that has made a great impression on them in real life, and that in doing so they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/abreact&#34;&gt;abreact&lt;/a&gt; the strength of the impression and, as one might put it, make themselves master of the situation.  But on the other hand, it is obvious that all their play is influenced by a wish that dominates them the whole time - the wish to be grown-up and to be able to do what grown-up people do.  It can also be observed that the unpleasurable nature of an experience does not always unsuit it for play.  If the doctor looks down a child&amp;rsquo;s throat or carries out some small operation on him, we may be quite sure that these frightening experiences will be the subject of the next game; but we must not in that connection overlook the fact that their is a yield of pleasure from another source.  As the child passes over from the passivity of the experience to the activity of the game, he hands on the disagreeable experience to one of his playmates and in this way revenges himself on a substitute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beyond the Pleasure Principle&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
