<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Death on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/death/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Death on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/death/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Frankl&#39;s &#39;Man&#39;s Search for Meaning&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading Viktor Frankl&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=pd_lpo_k2_dp_sr_1/189-8560150-0000706?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=lpo-top-stripe-1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0A2K5K4WK03NGZMZ523G&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=486539851&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0671023373&#34;&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankl, a psychiatrist, was imprisoned in the Nazi concentration camps, including Auschwitz, for several years.  He survived the experience and went on to develop the theory of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy&#34;&gt;logotherapy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a branch of psychoanalysis that focuses on human beings&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;will to meaning.&amp;rdquo;  The part of the book that discusses Frankl&amp;rsquo;s memories of his camp experience is, like any Holocaust memoir worth its salt, extremely disturbing and difficult to read, but it ought to be read in spite of that.  Here are a few (non-graphic) excerpts from the book, which I highly recommend:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Soon we had resumed the previous day&amp;rsquo;s positions in the ditch.  The frozen ground cracked under the point of the pickaxes, and sparks flew.  The men were silent, their brains numb.  My mind still clung to the image of my wife.  A thought crossed my mind: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know if she were still alive.  I knew only one thing - which I have learned well by now: Love goes very far beyond the physical person of the beloved.  It finds its deepest meaning in his spiritual being, his inner self.  Whether or not he is actually present, whether or not he is still alive at all, ceases somehow to be of importance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If there is a meaning of life at all, then there must be a meaning in suffering.  Suffering is an ineradicable part of life, even as fate and death.  Without suffering and death human life cannot be complete.  The way in which a man accepts his fate and all the suffering it entails, the way in which he takes up his cross, gives him ample opportunity - even under the most difficult circumstances - to add a deeper meaning to his life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What was really needed was a fundamental change in our attitude toward life.  We had to learn ourselves and, furthermore, we had to teach the despairing men, that &lt;em&gt;it did not really matter what we expected from life, but rather what life expected from us.&lt;/em&gt;  We needed to stop asking about the meaning of life, and instead to think of ourselves as those who were being questioned by life - daily and hourly.  Our answer must consist, not in talk and meditation, but in right action and right conduct.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I remember two cases of would-be suicide, which bore a striking similarity to each other.  Both men had talked of their intentions to commit suicide.  Both used the typical argument - they had nothing more to expect from life.  In both cases it was a question of getting them to realize that life was still expecting something from them; something in the future was expected of them.  We found, in fact, that for the one it was his child whom he adored and who was waiting for him in a foreign country.  For the other it was a thing, not a person.  This man was a scientist and had written a series of books which still needed to be finished.  His work could not be done by anyone else, any more than another person could ever take the place of the father in his child&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Not only our experiences, but all we have done, whatever great thoughts we may have had, and all we have suffered, all this is not lost, though it is past; we have brought it into being.  Having been is also a kind of being, and perhaps the surest kind.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I asked the poor creatures who listened to me attentively in the darkness of the hut to face up to the seriousness of our position.  They must not lose hope but should keep their courage in the certainty that the hopelessness of our struggle did not detract from its dignity and its meaning.  I said that someone looks down on us in different hours - a friend, a wife, somebody alive or dead, or a God - and he would not expect us to disappoint him.  He would hope to find us suffering proudly - not miserably - knowing how to die.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When we spoke about attempts to give a man in camp mental courage, we said that he had to be shown something to look forward to in the future.  He had to be reminded that life still waited for him, that a human being waited for his return.  But after liberation?  There were some men who found that no one awaited them.  Woe to him who found that the person whose memory alone had given him courage in camp did not exist any more!  Woe to him who, when the day of his dreams finally came, found it so different from all he had longed for!  Perhaps he boarded a trolley, traveled out to the home which he had seen for years in his mind, and only in his mind, and pressed the bell, just as he has longed to do in thousands of dreams, only to find that the person who should open the door was not there, and would never be there again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Viktor E. Frankl&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Bishop, Hayden, Olson, and Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Man-Moth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He thinks the moon is a small hole at the top of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;proving the sky quite useless for protection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Mourning Poem for the Queen of Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh who and oh who will sing Jesus down&lt;br /&gt;to help with struggling and doing without and being colored&lt;br /&gt;all through blue Monday?&lt;br /&gt;Till way next Sunday?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Hayden&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Questions of Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Should we have stayed at home,&lt;br /&gt;wherever that may be?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Maximus, to Himself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is undone business&lt;br /&gt;I speak of, this morning,&lt;br /&gt;with the sea&lt;br /&gt;stretching out&lt;br /&gt;from my feet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Charles Olson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Again: as the profound calm which only apparently precedes and prophesies of the storm, is perhaps more awful than the storm itself; for, indeed, the calm is but the wrapper and envelope of the storm; and contains it in itself, as the seemingly harmless rifle holds the fatal powder, and the ball, and the explosion; so the graceful repose of the line, as it silently serpentines about the oarsmen before being brought into actual play - this is a thing which carries more of true terror than any other aspect of this dangerous affair. But why say more? All men live enveloped in whale-lines. All are born with halters round their necks; but it is only when caught in the swift, sudden turn of death, that mortals realize the silent, subtle, ever-present perils of life. And if you be a philosopher, though seated in the whale-boat, you would not at heart feel one whit more of terror, than though seated before your evening fire with a poker, and not a harpoon, by your side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Poems excerpted from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Norton-Anthology-Modern-Contemporary-Poetry/dp/039332429X&#34;&gt;The Norton Anthology of Modern and Contemporary Poetry&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But how? Genius in the Sperm Whale? Has the Sperm Whale ever written a book, spoken a speech? No, his great genius is declared in his doing nothing particular to prove it. It is moreover declared in his pyramidical silence. &amp;hellip;If hereafter any highly cultured, poetical nation shall lure back to their birth-right, the merry May-day gods of old; and livingly enthrone them again in the now egotistical sky; in the now unhaunted hill; then be sure, exalted to Jove&amp;rsquo;s high seat, the great Sperm Whale shall lord it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It was a terrific, most pitiable, and maddening sight. The whale was now going head out, and sending his spout before him in a continual tormented jet; while his one poor fin beat his side in an agony of fright. Now to this hand, now to that, he yawed in his faltering flight, and still at every billow that he broke, he spasmodically sank in the sea, or sideways rolled towards the sky his one beating fin. So have I seen a bird with clipped wing, making affrighted broken circles in the air, vainly striving to escape the piratical hawks. But the bird has a voice, and with plaintive cries will make known her fear; but the fear of this vast dumb brute of the sea, was chained up and enchanted in him; he had no voice, save that choking respiration through his spiracle, and this made the sight of him unspeakably pitiable; while still, in his amazing bulk, portcullis jaw, and omnipotent tail, there was enough to appal the stoutest man who so pitied.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seems it credible that by three such thin threads the great Leviathan was suspended like the big weight to an eight day clock.  Suspended? and to what?  To three bits of board.  Is this the creature of whom it was once so triumphantly said - &amp;lsquo;Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish-spears? The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold, the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon: he esteemeth iron as straw; the arrow cannot make him flee; darts are counted as stubble; he laugheth at the shaking of a spear!&amp;rsquo;  This the creature? this he?  Oh! that unfulfillments should follow the prophets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As strange misgrown masses gather in the knot-holes of the noblest oaks when prostrate, so from the points which the whale&amp;rsquo;s eyes had once occupied, now protruded blind bulbs, horribly pitiable to see.  But pity there was none.  For all his old age, and his one arm, and his blind eyes, he must die the death and be murdered, in order to light the gay bridals and other merry-makings of men, and also to illuminate the solemn churches that preach unconditional inoffensiveness by all to all.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For young whales, in the highest health, and swelling with noble aspirations, prematurely cut off in the warm flush and May of life, with all their panting lard about them; even these brawny, buoyant heroes do sometimes sink.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Amichai, Laxness, Mendelssohn, &amp; Yoder</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch how the cloud sings&lt;br /&gt;All you wanted to say or find.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Let the Coin Decide&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents&lt;br /&gt;Has not subsided in me.  My blood goes on sloshing&lt;br /&gt;Between my ribs, long after the vessel has come to rest.&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents has not subsided in me.&lt;br /&gt;Winds of long time over stones.  Earth&lt;br /&gt;Forgets the steps of those who trod her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;And the Migration of My Parents&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who will love the things that are naught and in vain?&lt;br /&gt;I, who stand in the world like water in the rain,&lt;br /&gt;I love the things that are naught and in vain.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The most wandering thing is a heart that stopped wandering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;At Right Angles: Hebrew Quatrains&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Has the horse been spoken to?&amp;rdquo; asked the old man; and as it had not yet been done, he took an ear in each hand and whispered to it, according to ancient custom, for horses understood these things:  &amp;ldquo;You carry a coffin today.  You carry a coffin today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The coffin was carried straight into the church in compliance with the minister&amp;rsquo;s request and the bells were rung.  Feeble was the sound they made, feeble their intrusion on frozen nature&amp;rsquo;s winter omnipotence, their peal reminiscent of nothing so much as the jingle of a child&amp;rsquo;s toy.  And the folk came trailing out of the drifting snow and into the church, timid in the face of death, which never seems so irrevocable as when bells of such a kind tinkle so helplessly in the cold, white spaces of declining day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Halldor Laxness&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day of our life together&lt;br /&gt;Ecclesiastes erases a verse of his book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Six Poems For Tamar&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do I think he would be &amp;lsquo;saved&amp;rsquo;?  I fancy that whosoever leads men to virtue in this life cannot be damned in the next.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moses Mendelssohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Reply to Johann Kaspar Lavater,&amp;rdquo; 1769.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before the invention of the machine, the only wealth of a people was constituted by the soil and the flocks.  This is what today would be called capital.  Evidently Jesus accepted voluntary poverty for the sake of the kingdom and he ordered his disciples to practice the jubilary redistribution of their capital: &amp;ldquo;all of these things, it is the Gentiles of the world who seek them.  Your Father knows that you need them.  Seek rather the kingdom of God and all these things will be added to you.  Do not fear, little flock, because your Father has chosen to give you the kingdom; sell all that you have and give it as alms&amp;rdquo; (Luke 12:30-33).  No one doubts that he said this.  All that has been debated is whether this redistribution of capital was commanded by Jesus for all Christians at all times and in all places or whether it was just a &amp;ldquo;counsel of perfection&amp;rdquo; directed to the saints.  Traditionally the Church has chosen the second solution, the easy one.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Comparing one day the generosity of the wealthy, who ostentatiously were throwing large offerings in the temple treasury, with that of the poor widow, Jesus exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;This poor widow has put in more than all of them.  They put in from their overflow but she from her poverty has given all that she had to live!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In modern language we can translate: &amp;ldquo;The quantity of money that one gives is of little importance.  What is important is what one gives.   If it only is a part of one&amp;rsquo;s income, then this is not yet righteousness, goodness, and good faith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Howard Yoder&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Politics of Jesus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Harrison&#39;s &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-harrisons-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to finally know that the spirit was everywhere rather than a separate thing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Clare fed our leftover sandwiches to a stray mutt, who didn&amp;rsquo;t chew the proper thirty-two times.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All of my jobs had kept me grounded in actual life whereas simply sitting in my room with my studies tended to make me unstable.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In New York City the endless blocks of huge buildings say to us, I&amp;rsquo;m serious and within me serious people are doing serious things even though five thousand people in a building might only be playing with the market edge.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a local euphemism in the U.P. that you&amp;rsquo;re not lost, you just can&amp;rsquo;t find your vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A local politician rejecting foreign languages in a school budget had said, &amp;lsquo;If English was good enough for Jesus Christ it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for our kids.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I agreed with K on the addition of what is called a &amp;lsquo;space blanket&amp;rsquo; to the survival kits I put together and distribute for Mexicans intending to migrate north.  Space blankets are sheets of material used by campers to protect them from cold and dampness but I thought they could also defend against the summer heat of the ground, which reaches over one hundred and fifty degrees.  ..The packet was in a Velcro latched bag and could be attached to a waiste belt and weighed a little less than five pounds.  I distributed these free of charge to workers&amp;rsquo; groups and through left-leaning Catholic priests.  I was opposed by many on both sides of the border for political reasons, which didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me except for the legal expenses I incurred avoiding prosecution by the United States.  My raison d&amp;rsquo;etre was simple on the surface.  Estimates of crossing deaths along the entire nineteen-hundred-mile border with Mexico went as high as two thousand a year.  I had learned to be goofy rather than logically argumentative with my opponents.  I&amp;rsquo;d ask, If you could prevent twenty major airline disasters each year, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;By common consent we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything more serious than the food and music, which in themselves have become more serious as I get older.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He needed Montana but he also needed Chicago for her museums, libraries, theaters, bookstores, and most of all classical music, which he preferred to hear live.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;After a passing glance I averted my eyes from a photo of Carla and me at the cabin and then I fixed on it.  Was I ever that young?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There are no damaged goods when everyone is damaged goods.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The best thing about travel, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be consumed by the past against the backdrop of a fresh landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;I was sorry to hear about Donald.  There was a man who could put in a day&amp;rsquo;s work.&amp;rsquo; I shook his hand as he offered this ultimate compliment of the north.  His hand felt like a semipetrified baseball mitt.  &amp;lsquo;You might not remember me.  Donny and me played football way back when, then worked together.  The name&amp;rsquo;s Teddy.&amp;rsquo;  He bowed, his face reddening, and walked away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;You were the left tackle,&amp;rsquo; I called out and he turned and grinned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On all levels the main reason to live is because you&amp;rsquo;re already alive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While we were out on the park bench a small bank of clouds came across the sun turning our mood somber.  He said, &amp;lsquo;After all, the fact of death is the most brutal thing we humans are forced to accept,&amp;rsquo; but then the sun came out again and I told him that the day after the burial Herald had said, &amp;lsquo;Mother, it can&amp;rsquo;t be awful if it happens to every living thing.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buy Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;True North&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/Returning-to-Earth/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802143310/?itm=3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/True-North/Jim-Harrison/e/9780802142061/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from David Damrosch, Kahlil Gibran, &amp; Paul Tillich</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 02:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-david-damrosch-kahlil-gibran--paul-tillich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Goethe comments that the Church erred in closing the canon of scripture, as God&amp;rsquo;s creative work still continues, notably in the activity of great spirits like Mozart, Raphael, and Shakespeare, &amp;ldquo;who can draw their lesser contemporaries higher.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For the first time in history, authors of highly successful works can hope to have them translated into twenty or thirty languages within a few years of publication, and foreign countries may even provide the primary readership for writers who have small audiences at home or who are censored by their governments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All&lt;/em&gt; works cease to be the exclusive products of their original culture once they are translated; all become works that only &amp;ldquo;began&amp;rdquo; in their original language.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Society melts away in the vast echo chamber of (literary critic Harold) &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Bloom&#34;&gt;Bloom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s mind, replaced by the warring voices of the few great titans of the literary universe.  The fewer the better: &amp;hellip;Bloom continually narrows his authors&amp;rsquo; already narrow circle.  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1573225142&#34;&gt;The Western Canon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; treats twenty-six writers, but what need twenty-six?  &amp;ldquo;Most simply, the Canon is Plato and Shakespeare&amp;rdquo; (34).  What need even two?  &amp;ldquo;At once no one and everyone, nothing and everything, Shakespeare is the Western Canon&amp;rdquo; (71).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet even Bloom finally relents.  Having spent almost five hundred pages extolling the greatness of the few greatest writers at the heart of his version of the Western canon, he closes with an appendix listing several &lt;em&gt;thousand&lt;/em&gt; works by more than eight hundred and fifty writers whom he considers to be the key figures in the Western canon as a whole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Damrosch&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/What-World-Literature-Translation-Transnation/dp/0691049866/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1204791136&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;What is World Literature&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How shall I go in peace and without sorrow? Nay, not without a wound in the spirit shall I leave this city.  Long were the days of pain I have spent within its walls, and long were the nights of aloneness; and who can depart from his pain and his aloneness without regret?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Too many fragments of the spirit have I scattered in these streets, and too many are the children of my longing that walk naked among these hills, and I cannot withdraw from them without a burden and an ache.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is not a garment I cast off this day, but a skin that I tear with my own hands.  Nor is it a thought I leave behind me, but a heart made sweet with hunger and with thirst.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet I cannot tarry longer.  The sea that calls all things unto her calls me, and I must embark.&lt;br /&gt;For to stay, though the hours burn in the night, is to freeze and crystallize and be bound in a mould. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fain would I take with me all that is here. But how shall I?  A voice cannot carry the tongue and the lips that give it wings. Alone must it seek the ether.  And alone and without his nest shall the eagle fly across the sun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kahlil Gibran&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Prophet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sociological analyses of the present period have pointed to the importance of anxiety as a group phenomenon.  Literature and art have made anxiety a main theme of their creations, in content as well as in style.  The effect of this has been the awakening of at least the educated groups to an awareness of their own anxiety, and a permeation of the public consciousness by ideas and symbols of anxiety.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The first assertion about the nature of anxiety is this: anxiety is the state in which a being is aware of its possible nonbeing.  &amp;hellip;It is not the realization of universal transitoriness, not even the experience of the death of others, but the impression of these events on the always latent awareness of our own having to die that produces anxiety.  Anxiety is finitude, experienced as one&amp;rsquo;s own finitude.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
