<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friendship on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/friendship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Friendship on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/friendship/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for Facebook and social networking</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Facebook currently has over 200 million active users, many people continue to doubt the value of social networking in general and Facebook in particular.  Critics argue that Facebook and other social networking and Web 2.0 tools - including blogs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - are symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;solipsism&amp;rdquo; (meaning, in this context, the self-absorption of users) of the contemporary Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, Facebook can be an enormous time-waster and procrastination tool, as can any medium or Internet resource.  I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected a lot about my own use of the site over the past six years or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself whether it is a worthwhile use of my time and an appropriate way - one among others, obviously - to communicate with my friends, family, colleagues, and acquaintances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate was largely settled for me a few months ago when I heard a remarkable lecture by Clara Shih, social networking expert and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefacebookera.com/&#34;&gt;The Facebook Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shih spoke in April at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Booth School of Business, and I was in attendance to sell copies of her book.  (I was working as a manager at a bookstore at the time).  I went in with low expectations, as I generally take a dim view of the overcrowded genre of popular business books in general and books on making money through technology in particular.  But Shih&amp;rsquo;s presentation blew me away; she made me see Facebook and social networking in an entirely different light, and she helped me understand the many complex issues involved with social networking, and the utility social networking tools can have for those willing to critically evaluate and monitor their use of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The core reason for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s popularity, according to Shih, is that it lowers the cost of keeping in touch.  Keeping in touch with people you&amp;rsquo;ve met is a difficult and time-consuming process.  Facebook makes it much, much easier.  And it can help us keep in touch in a more meaningful way: there is less need to small talk with distant friends about where they are working, what they are studying, where they are living, and so forth - it&amp;rsquo;s all out there on their Facebook page, and so we can keep track of people we&amp;rsquo;ve met as they move through their lives.  When we think of them, we can think of who they are and what they are doing &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; rather than who they were when we met them years before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This powerful idea was brought home to me again this month, as the host family I lived with in Italy for ten weeks in my sophomore year of college joined Facebook and &amp;ldquo;Friended&amp;rdquo; me.  It takes a lot of effort to write a letter in Italian, put it in an envelope, wait in line at the post office to buy international postage, and finally send it - but it takes ten seconds to write on their &amp;ldquo;walls.&amp;rdquo;  And so I am much more likely to do the latter than the former, and our relationship need not be weakened by our falling out of touch.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and poems by Goethe, Coleridge, and A. Daniel</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am more and more convinced that poetry is the universal possession of mankind&amp;hellip;the epoch of world literature is at hand, and everyone must strive to hasten its approach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Goethe (quoted in Damrosch, &lt;em&gt;What is World Literature?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White Towels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been studying the difference&lt;br /&gt;between solitude and loneliness,&lt;br /&gt;telling the story of my life&lt;br /&gt;to the clean white towels taken warm from the dryer.&lt;br /&gt;I carry them through the house&lt;br /&gt;as though they were my children&lt;br /&gt;asleep in my arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Jones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May God, the Chosen, by whom were absolved the sins of the blind Longinus, wish if it please him, that I and my lady lie within one chamber where we shall make a rich covenant, whereon great joy attendeth; where, with laughter and caresses, she shall disclose to me her fair body, with the glamor of the lamplight about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duty Surviving Self-Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unchanged within, to see all changed without,&lt;br /&gt;Is a blank lot and hard to bear, no doubt.&lt;br /&gt;Yet why at others&amp;rsquo; wanings should&amp;rsquo;st thou fret ?&lt;br /&gt;Then only might&amp;rsquo;st thou feel a just regret,&lt;br /&gt;Hadst thou withheld thy love or hid thy light&lt;br /&gt;In selfish forethought of neglect and slight.&lt;br /&gt;O wiselier then, from feeble yearnings freed,&lt;br /&gt;While, and on whom, thou may&amp;rsquo;st&amp;ndash;shine on! nor heed&lt;br /&gt;Whether the object by reflected light&lt;br /&gt;Return thy radiance or absorb it quite :&lt;br /&gt;And tho&amp;rsquo; thou notest from thy safe recess&lt;br /&gt;Old Friends burn dim, like lamps in noisome air,&lt;br /&gt;Love them for what they are ; nor love them less,&lt;br /&gt;Because to thee they are not what they were.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But when I consider how she is the summit of worth, much do I love myself the more for having ever dared to desire her, for now do I know that my heart and my wit will make me to make to their whim a rich conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And since she is of such worth, do not think that my firm will can disperse itself or flow away or divide, for by that God who manifested himself in the dove, I am neither mine nor hers if I leave her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update and four quotes</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited about the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking straight from work to Union Station tomorrow afternoon, and then the usual, happy routine of a quick trip home: the #370 &lt;em&gt;Pere Marquette &lt;/em&gt;accompanied by caffeine and books (and, since it&amp;rsquo;s summer, a wonderful sunset over the harbor in St. Joseph, MI), a late-night outing to Pints &amp;amp; Quarts and Pablo&amp;rsquo;s Tacos with Muskegon friends, a Saturday morning trip to eat breakfast and shop for used books in Grand Haven, a few intense games of ping-pong with Tyler, and a run on the beach. Early Sunday morning, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the return train to Chicago and it will all seem surreal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two unique and wonderful things about this trip. First: my family got a new dog, a black retriever named Maggie, whom I will have the pleasure of meeting for the first time tomorrow night. And second: on Saturday night, two friends and I are going to a Counting Crows and Collective Soul concert in Grand Rapids.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Quotes from tonight&amp;rsquo;s reading: &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I am saying is this: the score is not what matters. Life does not have to be regarded as a game in which scores are kept and somebody wins. If you are too intent on winning, you will never enjoy playing. If you are too obsessed with success, you will forget to live. If you have learned only how to be a success, your life has probably been wasted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Love and Living&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When that time was over and the good-bys said, I had to go through the same lost loneliness all over again, and it was no less painful than at first. There seemed to be no cure for loneliness save only being alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blackberries for Amelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the far stars, of which we now are told&lt;br /&gt;That ever faster they do bolt away,&lt;br /&gt;And that a night may come in which, some say,&lt;br /&gt;We shall have only blackness to behold.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have no time for any change so great,&lt;br /&gt;But I shall see the August weather spur&lt;br /&gt;Berries to ripen where the flowers were -&lt;br /&gt;Dark berries, savage-sweet and worth the wait -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And there will come the moment to be quick&lt;br /&gt;And save some from the birds, and I shall need&lt;br /&gt;Two pails, old clothes in which to stain and bleed,&lt;br /&gt;And a grandchild to talk with while we pick.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can only imagine that the lonely man peoples his driving dreams with friends, that the loveless man surrounds himself with lovely loving women, and that children climb through the dreaming of the childless driver. And how about the areas of regrets? If only I had done so-and-so, or had not said such-and-such - my God, the damn thing might not have happened. Finding this potential in my own mind, I can suspect it in others, but I will never know, for no one ever tells. And this is why, on my journey which was designed for observation, I stayed as much as possible on secondary roads where there was much to see and hear and smell, and avoided the great wide traffic slashes which promote the self by fostering daydreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
