<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Football on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 12:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/football/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal update: the final weeks of summer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-the-final-weeks-of-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-the-final-weeks-of-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMDRSjEbTI/AAAAAAAAAEs/qLrbqMGuDT8/s1600-h/ebay_014.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5103426398312492338&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMDRSjEbTI/AAAAAAAAAEs/qLrbqMGuDT8/s400/ebay_014.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMDDCjEbSI/AAAAAAAAAEk/_2FUpGWCzUs/s1600-h/ebay_016.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5103426153499356450&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMDDCjEbSI/AAAAAAAAAEk/_2FUpGWCzUs/s400/ebay_016.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After a quiet and happy week in Michigan, I am now back in Chicago for a week of training and racing with the U of C cross-country team. This will be my fourth and final year as a member of the squad, and I am more excited about the sport and ready to race than I&amp;rsquo;ve been in years. We begin to miss things and feel the pain of losing them before they go, and being a member of an XC team has been a big part of my life for almost eight years. I will miss it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I spent most of the past week reading social science and other nonfiction stuff at Barnes &amp;amp; Noble and Good Grains in Muskegon: &lt;em&gt;Economics Explained&lt;/em&gt; by Robert Heilbroner and Lester Thurow, &lt;em&gt;Global Political Economy &lt;/em&gt;by Robert Gilpin, a sociology textbook, a book on expressing emotions in Japanese, and an introductory religious studies textbook. I focused on literature all summer because I was dealing with numbers and facts all day at my job and because I was searching for direction. Now I must get into the groove of reading duller and tougher materials in order to prepare for the academic year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The weekend was also nice: Mona Shores beat Muskegon Catholic Central for the second straight year in football on a beautiful Friday night. On Saturday, I won the Roosevelt Park Days 5k in 15:54, hung out all morning with my family and watched my 8 year-old sister in the parade, and then drove to my grandparents&amp;rsquo; cottage in Baldwin for a weekend of kayaking, looking at the stars with Grandpa on the dock, eating at backwoods diners, writing, and watching &lt;em&gt;Stranger Than Fiction&lt;/em&gt;. Driving home through the hills and farmland of west-central Michigan, I felt outrageously happy to be alive. I get that feeling a lot these days. Fall is my favorite season: indoor warmth, Saturday morning meets, football, excitement about school, and hope for new beginnings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This week, training and preparing for the school year in Chicago; Friday, the first race of the 2007 cross-country season (in Elmhurst); Saturday, an overnight stay in Ann Arbor to watch the Michigan vs. Appalachian State football game; another three days in Muskegon; and then, next Wednesday afternoon, I&amp;rsquo;ll step off a plane and be in Tokyo for a two-week stay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMCmSjEbQI/AAAAAAAAAEU/q2Kt65gQ85E/s1600-h/2007_0824August-20070033.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5103425659578117378&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RtMCmSjEbQI/AAAAAAAAAEU/q2Kt65gQ85E/s400/2007_0824August-20070033.JPG&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;What might have been is just thin air,&lt;br /&gt;A loss we long ago outgrew.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz, &amp;ldquo;In Salem&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After Paradise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t run anymore. Quiet. How softly it rains&lt;br /&gt;On the roofs of the city. How perfect&lt;br /&gt;All things are. Now, for the two of you&lt;br /&gt;Waking up in a royal bed by a garret window.&lt;br /&gt;For a man and a woman. For one plant divided&lt;br /&gt;Into masculine and feminine which longed for each other.&lt;br /&gt;Yes, this is my gift to you. Above ashes&lt;br /&gt;On a bitter, bitter earth. Above the subterranean&lt;br /&gt;Echo of clamorings and vows. So that now at dawn&lt;br /&gt;You must be attentive: the tilt of a head,&lt;br /&gt;A hand with a comb, two faces in a mirror&lt;br /&gt;Are only forever once, even if unremembered,&lt;br /&gt;So that you watch what is, though it fades away,&lt;br /&gt;And are grateful every moment for your being.&lt;br /&gt;Let that little park with greenish marble busts&lt;br /&gt;In the pearl-gray light, under a summer drizzle,&lt;br /&gt;Remain as it was when you opened the gate.&lt;br /&gt;And the street of tall peeling porticoes&lt;br /&gt;Which this love of yours suddenly transformed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
