<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loneliness on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/loneliness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loneliness on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/loneliness/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Czeslaw Milosz&#39;s &#39;Milosz&#39;s ABC&#39;s&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s1600-h/Milosz.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s400/Milosz.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5349520508899521426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made it, but I have always tried to remember that I owe it to my lucky star, not to myself, and that right next door are entire neighborhoods of unfortunates.  I will say even more: the thought of their grueling labor and unfulfilled hope, of the gigantic prison system in which the unneeded are kept, taught me to look skeptically at (America&amp;rsquo;s) decorations - those well-kept houses amidst the suburbs&amp;rsquo; greenery.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In our deepest convictions, reaching into the very depths of our being, we deserve to live forever.  We experience our transitoriness and mortality as an act of violence perpetrated against us.  Only Paradise is authentic; the world is inauthentic, and only temporary.  That is why the story of the Fall speaks to us so emotionally, as if summoning an old truth from our slumbering memory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;People go to church because they are divided beings.  They wish, for a moment at least, to find themselves in a reality other than the one that surrounds them and claims to be the only true reality.  This daily reality is unyielding, brutal, cruel, and hard to bear.  The human &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; is soft in the center and feels every moment that its adaptation to the world is doubtful.  &amp;hellip;Participating in the Mass we once again deny a world without meaning and without mercy; we enter into a dimension where what matters are goodness, love, and forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If to participate in the Mass it were necessary to have a strong faith and a consciousness that we act in life as our religion requires us to, all the churchgoing faithful would deserve to be called hypocrites and Pharisees.  In truth, however, strong faith is a rare gift, and as for acts, the liturgy reminds us that we are all sinners.  Attending church is not, therefore, for the elect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The needs of the individual determine church attendance, and knowledge of the catechism or even familiarity with the so-called truths of the faith are not the most important matters, although they are advisable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Miloszs-ABCs-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374527954&#34;&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;The English Major&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s1600-h/EnglishMajor&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s400/EnglishMajor&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5311272264829533522&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s latest novel, &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/English-Major-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802118631&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Harrison, a native of my home state of Michigan, is my favorite contemporary author, and &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major &lt;/span&gt;is the best &amp;rdquo;fun read&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a long time.  In trademark Harrison style, it is both hilarious and poignant, and it contains some great passages.  Excerpts below.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I tried to dismiss a pinprick of homesickness beneath my breastbone but then thought that homesickness like marital love was mostly a habit.  What I missed was no longer there or on the verge of disappearing.  I mean Lola was in dog heaven and the farm which had been sold to a stockbroker and his family from Chicago was to become a horse operation.  The barn and my cozy workshop would likely be remodeled into stables, the orchard uprooted for pasture, and our old home razed in favor of what Viv said would be &amp;ldquo;French provincial&amp;rdquo; whatever that was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad once warned me about this when I was mourning the loss of a girlfriend to a quarterback.  I was a lonely lineman.  I moped and moped, and then when we were cutting wood on an icy October morning he told me that self-pity was a ruinous emotion.  &amp;rdquo;Look at the world, not up your ass,&amp;rdquo; he said.  It took me awhile to figure this out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;She also liked to say that my dead father would wish me to be a &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; when my dad never spoke about such things except to say that successful people never had much time for important things like hunting, fishing, drinking, and wandering around in the woods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t own a cell phone which only made the wandering man a target with the number providing a guaranteed bull&amp;rsquo;s-eye.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Up to this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t questioned the rightness of my trip but suddenly I wondered if I were truly suited for travel.  Reality seemed to be crumbling and I was wise enough to understand that reality stayed the same so it was my mind that was crumbling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;To my dad who was a young man during the Great Depression the only truly hopeless greivance was not to have a job, or not to have &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; as he called it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sort of neutral in terms of religion but ever since I was a kid I&amp;rsquo;ve thought moving water to be the best thing God made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Everyone pretty much pans out in the middle ground or less.  In college I thought I was destined to go overseas but I didn&amp;rsquo;t.  We don&amp;rsquo;t quite get started except on our livelihood which is probably the story of mankind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and poems by Goethe, Coleridge, and A. Daniel</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am more and more convinced that poetry is the universal possession of mankind&amp;hellip;the epoch of world literature is at hand, and everyone must strive to hasten its approach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Goethe (quoted in Damrosch, &lt;em&gt;What is World Literature?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White Towels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been studying the difference&lt;br /&gt;between solitude and loneliness,&lt;br /&gt;telling the story of my life&lt;br /&gt;to the clean white towels taken warm from the dryer.&lt;br /&gt;I carry them through the house&lt;br /&gt;as though they were my children&lt;br /&gt;asleep in my arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Jones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May God, the Chosen, by whom were absolved the sins of the blind Longinus, wish if it please him, that I and my lady lie within one chamber where we shall make a rich covenant, whereon great joy attendeth; where, with laughter and caresses, she shall disclose to me her fair body, with the glamor of the lamplight about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duty Surviving Self-Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unchanged within, to see all changed without,&lt;br /&gt;Is a blank lot and hard to bear, no doubt.&lt;br /&gt;Yet why at others&amp;rsquo; wanings should&amp;rsquo;st thou fret ?&lt;br /&gt;Then only might&amp;rsquo;st thou feel a just regret,&lt;br /&gt;Hadst thou withheld thy love or hid thy light&lt;br /&gt;In selfish forethought of neglect and slight.&lt;br /&gt;O wiselier then, from feeble yearnings freed,&lt;br /&gt;While, and on whom, thou may&amp;rsquo;st&amp;ndash;shine on! nor heed&lt;br /&gt;Whether the object by reflected light&lt;br /&gt;Return thy radiance or absorb it quite :&lt;br /&gt;And tho&amp;rsquo; thou notest from thy safe recess&lt;br /&gt;Old Friends burn dim, like lamps in noisome air,&lt;br /&gt;Love them for what they are ; nor love them less,&lt;br /&gt;Because to thee they are not what they were.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But when I consider how she is the summit of worth, much do I love myself the more for having ever dared to desire her, for now do I know that my heart and my wit will make me to make to their whim a rich conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And since she is of such worth, do not think that my firm will can disperse itself or flow away or divide, for by that God who manifested himself in the dove, I am neither mine nor hers if I leave her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Frost, Tillich, O&#39;Hara, and Pound</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 01:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Desert Places&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They cannot scare me with their empty spaces&lt;br /&gt;Between stars - on stars where no human race is.&lt;br /&gt;I have it in me so much nearer home&lt;br /&gt;To scare myself with my own desert places.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One cannot remove anxiety by arguing it away.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The affirmation of one&amp;rsquo;s essential being in spite of desires and anxieties creates joy.  Lucillus is exhorted by Seneca to make it his business &amp;ldquo;to learn how to feel joy.&amp;rdquo;  It is not the joy of fulfilled desires to which he refers, for real joy is a &amp;ldquo;severe matter&amp;rdquo;; it is the happiness of a soul which is &amp;ldquo;lifted above every circumstance.&amp;rdquo;  Joy accompanies the self-affirmation of our essential being in spite of the inhibitions coming from the accidental elements in us.  Joy is the emotional expression of the courageous Yes to one&amp;rsquo;s own true being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the Harbormaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I wanted to be sure to reach you&lt;br /&gt;though my ship was on the way it got caught&lt;br /&gt;in some moorings. I am always tying up&lt;br /&gt;and then deciding to depart. In storms and&lt;br /&gt;at sunset, with the metallic coils of the tide&lt;br /&gt;around my fathomless arms, I am unable&lt;br /&gt;to understand the forms of my vanity&lt;br /&gt;or I am hard alee with my Polish rudder&lt;br /&gt;in my hand and the sun sinking. To&lt;br /&gt;you I offer my hull and the tattered cordage&lt;br /&gt;of my will. The terrible channels where&lt;br /&gt;the wind drives me against the brown lips&lt;br /&gt;of the reeds are not all behind me. Yet&lt;br /&gt;I trust the sanity of my vessel; and&lt;br /&gt;if it sinks it may well be in answer&lt;br /&gt;to the reasoning of the eternal voices,&lt;br /&gt;the waves which have kept me from reaching you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Frank O&amp;rsquo;Hara&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sceptical age hungers after the definite, after something it can pretend to believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;You read, as a child who has listened to ghost stories goes into a dark room; it is no accurate information about historical things that you seek, it is the thrill which mere reality would never satisfy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of literary criticism is largely the history of a vain struggle to find a terminology which will define something.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is dawn at Jerusalem while midnight hovers above the Pillars of Hercules.  All ages are contemporaneous.  The Middle Ages are in Russia.  The future stirs already in the minds of the few.  This is especially true of literature, where the real time is independent of the apparent, and where many dead men are our grandchildren&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries, while many of our contemporaries have been already gathered into Abraham&amp;rsquo;s bosom, or some more fitting receptacle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of an art is the history of masterwork, not of failures, or mediocrity.  The ominscient historian would display the masterpieces, their causes and their inter-relation.  The study of literature is hero-worship.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Good art never bores one.  By that I mean that it is the business of the artist to prevent ennui; in the literary art, to relieve, refresh, revive the mind of the reader - at reasonable intervals - with some form of ecstasy, by some splendor of thought, some presentation of sheer beauty, some lightning turn of phrase - laughter is no mean ecstasy.  Good art begins with an escape from dullness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ezra Pound&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Spirit of Romance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Petterson, &#39;Out Stealing Horses&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t switch on the ceiling light at once but leave the room in twilight so the yellow flames in the stove flicker brightly over the floor and walls. The sight of them slows my breathing down and makes me calm as it must have done for men through thousands of years: let the wolves howl, here by the fire it’s safe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But each time he came home he had changed a little, and I had to concentrate hard to hold on to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My father looked almost happy then, and I could see by the way he looked at me that I did, too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And she waves briefly and slams the car door and it starts to roll down the slope. I go up the steps and turn off the yard light and walk through the hall to the kitchen. Lyra is at my heels, but even when she is behind me the room feels a bit empty. I look out at the yard, but there is nothing but my own reflection in the dark glass.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He is watching the news. I don’t know when I last watched the news. I did not bring a television set out here with me, and I regret it sometimes when the evenings get long, but my idea was that living alone you can soon get stuck to those flickering images and to the chair you will sit on far into the night, and then time merely passes as you let others do the moving. I do not want that. I will keep myself company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;‘Would you rather I hadn’t come?’ she says again, insistently.&lt;br /&gt;‘I don’t know,’ I say, and that is also true; I don’t know what to think of her coming out here, it was not part of my plan, and then it strikes me: now she will go away and never come back. That thought fills me with such sudden terror that I quickly say:&lt;br /&gt;‘No, that’s not true. Don’t go.’&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I get up. Six fifteen. Lyra leaves her place beside the stove and goes to the kitchen door to wait. She turns her head and looks at me, and there is a trustfulness in that look I probably do not deserve. But maybe that is not the point, to deserve it or not, perhaps it just exists, that trust, disconnected from who you are and what you have done, and is not to be measured in any way. That’s a nice thought. Good dog, Lyra, I think, good dog.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Per Petterson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Out Stealing Horses &lt;/em&gt;(highly recommended; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1197353675&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon.com)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quotes from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We keep the wall between us as we go.&lt;br /&gt;To each the boulders that have fallen to each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mending Wall&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World peace cannot be safeguarded without the making of creative efforts proportionate to the dangers which threaten it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Schumann&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Schumann Declaration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I asked her, urgently, if she could see my face, and she said: &amp;ldquo;See it?&amp;rdquo; And, smiling: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s reflected in my eyes, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(じゃ、私の顔が見えるかいと一心に聞くと、見えるかいって、そら、そこに、写ってるじゃありませんかと、にこりと笑ってみせた。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Natsume Soseki&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;The First Night&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And home, where passion lived and died,&lt;br /&gt;Becomes a place where she can hide,&lt;br /&gt;While all the town and harbor side&lt;br /&gt;Vibrate with her seclusion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin Arlington Robinson&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Eros Turannos&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite all of these examples of colloquialism and apparent simplicity in Frost&amp;rsquo;s poetry, we should not be deceived into thinking of Frost as a rustic or a primitive.  On the contrary, Frost was a sophisticated writer who was well versed in Latin poetry and who knew as well as any poet of his time how to make effective use of formal and rhetorical strategies.  From his early career on, Frost prided himself on being &amp;ldquo;one of the most notable craftsmen of my time,&amp;rdquo; as he wrote in his 1913 letter to John Bartlett.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Christopher Beach&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Twentieth-Century American Poetry&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;In Those Days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In those days - they were long ago -&lt;br /&gt;The snow was cold, the night was black.&lt;br /&gt;I licked from my cracked lips&lt;br /&gt;A snowflake, as I looked back&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Through branches, the last uneasy snow.&lt;br /&gt;Your shadow, there in the light, was still.&lt;br /&gt;In a little the light went out.&lt;br /&gt;I went on, stumbling - till at last the hill&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hid the house.  And, yawning,&lt;br /&gt;In bed in my room, alone,&lt;br /&gt;I would look out: over the quilted&lt;br /&gt;Rooftops, the clear stars shone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How poor and miserable we were,&lt;br /&gt;How seldom together!&lt;br /&gt;And yet after so long one thinks:&lt;br /&gt;In those days everything was better.&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems &amp; fragments by William Meredith</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems--fragments-by-william-meredith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems--fragments-by-william-meredith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Ten-Day Leave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh, identity is a traveling-piece with some,&lt;br /&gt;But here is what calls me, here what I call home.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Major Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Poems are hard to read&lt;br /&gt;Pictures are hard to see&lt;br /&gt;Music is hard to hear&lt;br /&gt;And people are hard to love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But whether from brute need&lt;br /&gt;Or divine energy&lt;br /&gt;At last mind eye and ear&lt;br /&gt;And the great sloth heart will move.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;June: Dutch Harbor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is hard to keep your mind on war, with all that green.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Open Sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We say the sea is lonely; better say&lt;br /&gt;Ourselves are lonesome creatures whom the sea&lt;br /&gt;Gives neither yes or no for company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh, there are people, all right, settled in the sea-&lt;br /&gt;It is as populous as Maine today-&lt;br /&gt;But no one who will give you the time of day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A man who asks there of his family&lt;br /&gt;Or a friend or teacher gets a cold reply&lt;br /&gt;Or finds him dead against that vast majority.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They are speechless. And the famous noise of the sea,&lt;br /&gt;Which a poet has beautifully told us in our day,&lt;br /&gt;Is hardly a sound to speak comfort to the lonely.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although not yet a man given to prayer, I pray&lt;br /&gt;For each creature lost since the start of the sea,&lt;br /&gt;And give thanks that it was not I, nor yet one close to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;From William Meredith, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Effort-Speech-New-Selected-Poems/dp/0810150719/ref=sr_1_3/002-8606436-4954458?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1193894320&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;&gt;Effort at Speech: New and Selected Poems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knut Hamsun&#39;s &#39;Pan&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/knut-hamsuns-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/knut-hamsuns-pan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RrWND9ughiI/AAAAAAAAAEM/_4c5MCTKreE/s1600-h/Knut_Hamsun.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5095133652688340514&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RrWND9ughiI/AAAAAAAAAEM/_4c5MCTKreE/s400/Knut_Hamsun.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I just finished the best novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a very long time. I am stunned at how beautiful &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knut_Hamsun&#34;&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s writing is, and cannot believe that he is not a household name in America. He was a very flawed man - like Martin Heidegger, Carl Schmitt, and too many others, he abused his considerable intellectual gifts in support of Nazism, and it is understandable that this removed his right to a full place in the Great Books pantheon. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All the same, however, he is an incredible writer whose work deserves to be a standard on classics lists. &lt;em&gt;Pan &lt;/em&gt;was a truly special read, and I am going to read as many of his novels as I can get my hands on. Here are some excerpts to give you a taste:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a big, white-washed house down by the sea, I met someone who for a short while filled my thoughts. She is no longer always in my memory, not now - no, I have quite forgotten her. But I do recall the other things, the cries of the sea birds, the hunting in the forest, my nights, and all the warm hours of the summer. It was in any case by sheer chance that I met her; and had it not been for that chance she would never have lain in my thoughts for a single day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For it is within ourselves that the sources of joy and sorrow lie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There was a boulder outside my hut, a big grey boulder. It always seemed by its expression to be well-disposed towards me; it was as if it saw me as I came past and knew me again. I used to like making my way past this boulder when I went out in the mornings, and it was as though I left a good friend there who would be waiting when I got back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For some days a chill atmosphere of unrest hung over the earth; rotten branches snapped and the crows collected in flocks and squawked. But it was not for long, the sun was near; one morning it rose up behind the forest. A sweet pang strikes through me when the sun comes; I throw my gun on my shoulder in silent rejoicing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I followed every bend, taking my time; there was no hurry and nobody was waiting for me at home. Free as a king I went my way in the peace of the forest, as leisurely as I pleased.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everywhere the sky was open and pure. I gazed into the clear sea and it was as if I lay face to face with the depths of the earth, and as if my beating heart went out to those depths and was at home there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;More excerpts to come; all of the above beauties were in the first ten pages of the 192 page book. A &lt;/em&gt;New Yorker&lt;em&gt; article about Hamsun can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/archive/2005/12/26/051226crat_atlarge&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the book can be purchased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pan-Knut-Hamsun/dp/1406937932/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/102-0086905-3665754?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1186303891&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I give it my highest recommendation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Thomas Merton and John Steinbeck</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living is more than submission: it is creation.  To live is to create one&amp;rsquo;s own world as a scene of personal happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Celebration is the beginning of confidence, therefore of power.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next passage in my journey is a love affair.  I am in love with Montana.  For other states I have admiration, respect, recognition, even some affection, but with Montana it is love, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to analyze love when you&amp;rsquo;re in it.  &amp;hellip; It seems to me that Montana is a great splash of grandeur.  The scale is huge but not overpowering.  The land is rich with grass and color, and the mountains are the kind I would create if mountains were ever put on my agenda.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The calm of the mountains and the rolling grasslands had got into the inhabitants.  It was hunting season when I drove through the state.  The men I talked to seemed to me not moved to a riot of seasonal slaughter but simply to be going out to kill edible meat.  Again my attitude may be informed by love, but it seemed to me that the towns were places to live in rather than nervous hives.  People had time to pause in their occupations to undertake the passing art of neighborliness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When we live superficially, when we are always outside ourselves, never quite &amp;ldquo;with&amp;rdquo; ourselves, always divided and pulled in many directions by conflicting plans and projects, we find ourselves doing many things that we do not really want to do, saying things we do not really mean, needing things we do not really need, exhausting ourselves for what we secretly realize to be worthless and without meaning in our lives: &amp;ldquo;Why spend your money on what is not food and your earnings on what never satisfies?&amp;rdquo; (Isaiah 55:2)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having a companion fixes you in time and that the present, but when the quality of aloneness settles down, past, present, and future all flow together.  A memory, a present event, and a forecast all equally present.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the long run, the discipline of creative silence demands a certain kind of faith.  For when we come face to face with ourselves in the lonely ground of our own being, we confront many questions about the value of our existence, the reality of our commitments, the authenticity of our everyday lives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
