<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/religion/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Solomon&#39;s &#39;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s1600-h/judaism.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5394862253055997906&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s400/judaism.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 215px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 200px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin Buber and Emanuel Levinas put their faith in the God of relationships.  &lt;em&gt;Alles Leben ist Begegnung&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;all life is encounter&amp;rsquo;), declared Buber, and the important thing is to get your relationship with God and with people right (I-Thou, rather than I-It); from that relationship, which is the essence of Revelation, ethical action flows; laws and rules are feeble attempts to capture revelation, and doomed to inadequacy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Genesis 1:27 states clearly enough: &amp;lsquo;So God created humankind in his own image; in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&amp;rsquo; This implies that in using our concept of God to model human behavior we should not distinguish between male and female.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Emil Fackenheim grounds his theology in the actual resistance of Shoah [Holocaust] victims to whom no realistic hope remained: &amp;lsquo;A philosophical Tikkun [&amp;lsquo;repair&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restoration&amp;rsquo;] is possible after the Holocaust because a philosophical Tikkun already took place, however fragmentarily, during the Holocaust itself&amp;rsquo;; the rebirth of Israel, and a new constructive dialogue with a self-critical Christianity, are essential to this process.  Fackenheim is also noted for his statement that there should be a 614th commandment, surplus to the 613 of tradition - to survive as Jews, to remember, never to despair of God, lest we hand Hitler a posthumous victory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Is there such a thing as a &amp;lsquo;just war&amp;rsquo;, and if so, what are the conditions of engagement?  Out of this debate emerged the novel concept of &lt;em&gt;tohar ha-nesheq&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;purity of arms&amp;rsquo;), which demands &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt; that the fighting force take special risks to avoid harm to non-combatants and to minimize enemy casualties.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Many Jews, including secular ones, see Israel as the fulfilment of the &amp;lsquo;national&amp;rsquo; aspirations of the Jewish people; after thousands of years of minority status, of being alienated from the host societies, and in many  cases actually prevented from becoming full citizens of the lands in which they lived, they feel that they have at last &amp;lsquo;come home&amp;rsquo; and are able to control their own destiny within the normal limitations of independent statehood.  Israel is perceived as a secure haven for persecuted Jews; had Israel existed during the years of the Holocaust, Jews would have had somewhere to turn to.  Moreover, Israel provides the opportunity to live a fulfilling Jewish life free from the inhibitions and restrictions of minority status.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Large numbers of men and women have abandoned organized religion, some because they have found it intellectually untenable, more because they have found it emotionally unsatisfying, most because they have found that its demands inhibit the personal freedom which they regard as a fundamental human right.  If Western Christianity has been most strongly affected, Western Judaism runs it a close second, for both have their home in the lands which modernity and the Enlightenment were nurtured.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The downside of the emphasis on family values is the danger of marginalizing the stranger, the single, and the unattached.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;. They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/html/staff/hjs/nsolomon.html&#34;&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CAwQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJudaism-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions%2Fdp%2F0192853902&amp;amp;ei=4GXeSo_3FYOk8AaKwvVy&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAV2jscXmj3uoFSGTQwfG8MHXsPA&#34;&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Frankl&#39;s &#39;Man&#39;s Search for Meaning&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading Viktor Frankl&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=pd_lpo_k2_dp_sr_1/189-8560150-0000706?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=lpo-top-stripe-1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0A2K5K4WK03NGZMZ523G&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=486539851&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0671023373&#34;&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankl, a psychiatrist, was imprisoned in the Nazi concentration camps, including Auschwitz, for several years.  He survived the experience and went on to develop the theory of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy&#34;&gt;logotherapy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a branch of psychoanalysis that focuses on human beings&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;will to meaning.&amp;rdquo;  The part of the book that discusses Frankl&amp;rsquo;s memories of his camp experience is, like any Holocaust memoir worth its salt, extremely disturbing and difficult to read, but it ought to be read in spite of that.  Here are a few (non-graphic) excerpts from the book, which I highly recommend:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Soon we had resumed the previous day&amp;rsquo;s positions in the ditch.  The frozen ground cracked under the point of the pickaxes, and sparks flew.  The men were silent, their brains numb.  My mind still clung to the image of my wife.  A thought crossed my mind: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know if she were still alive.  I knew only one thing - which I have learned well by now: Love goes very far beyond the physical person of the beloved.  It finds its deepest meaning in his spiritual being, his inner self.  Whether or not he is actually present, whether or not he is still alive at all, ceases somehow to be of importance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If there is a meaning of life at all, then there must be a meaning in suffering.  Suffering is an ineradicable part of life, even as fate and death.  Without suffering and death human life cannot be complete.  The way in which a man accepts his fate and all the suffering it entails, the way in which he takes up his cross, gives him ample opportunity - even under the most difficult circumstances - to add a deeper meaning to his life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What was really needed was a fundamental change in our attitude toward life.  We had to learn ourselves and, furthermore, we had to teach the despairing men, that &lt;em&gt;it did not really matter what we expected from life, but rather what life expected from us.&lt;/em&gt;  We needed to stop asking about the meaning of life, and instead to think of ourselves as those who were being questioned by life - daily and hourly.  Our answer must consist, not in talk and meditation, but in right action and right conduct.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I remember two cases of would-be suicide, which bore a striking similarity to each other.  Both men had talked of their intentions to commit suicide.  Both used the typical argument - they had nothing more to expect from life.  In both cases it was a question of getting them to realize that life was still expecting something from them; something in the future was expected of them.  We found, in fact, that for the one it was his child whom he adored and who was waiting for him in a foreign country.  For the other it was a thing, not a person.  This man was a scientist and had written a series of books which still needed to be finished.  His work could not be done by anyone else, any more than another person could ever take the place of the father in his child&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Not only our experiences, but all we have done, whatever great thoughts we may have had, and all we have suffered, all this is not lost, though it is past; we have brought it into being.  Having been is also a kind of being, and perhaps the surest kind.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I asked the poor creatures who listened to me attentively in the darkness of the hut to face up to the seriousness of our position.  They must not lose hope but should keep their courage in the certainty that the hopelessness of our struggle did not detract from its dignity and its meaning.  I said that someone looks down on us in different hours - a friend, a wife, somebody alive or dead, or a God - and he would not expect us to disappoint him.  He would hope to find us suffering proudly - not miserably - knowing how to die.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When we spoke about attempts to give a man in camp mental courage, we said that he had to be shown something to look forward to in the future.  He had to be reminded that life still waited for him, that a human being waited for his return.  But after liberation?  There were some men who found that no one awaited them.  Woe to him who found that the person whose memory alone had given him courage in camp did not exist any more!  Woe to him who, when the day of his dreams finally came, found it so different from all he had longed for!  Perhaps he boarded a trolley, traveled out to the home which he had seen for years in his mind, and only in his mind, and pressed the bell, just as he has longed to do in thousands of dreams, only to find that the person who should open the door was not there, and would never be there again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Viktor E. Frankl&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Charles Taylor and Erich Auerbach</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-charles-taylor-and-erich-auerbach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One way to put the question I want to answer here is this: why was it virtually impossible not to believe in God in, say, 1500 in our Western society, while in 2000 many of us find this not only easy, but even inescapable?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Important as science is to our present outlook, we mustn&amp;rsquo;t exaggerate its causal role here, and make it the main motor of the transformation.  Our encasing in secular time is also something we have brought about in the way we live and order our lives.  It has been brought about by the same social and ideological changes which have wrought disenchantment.  In particular, the disciplines of our modern civilized order have led us to measure and organize time as never before in human history.  Time has become a precious resource, not to be &amp;ldquo;wasted&amp;rdquo;.  The result has been the creation of a tight, ordered time environment.  This has enveloped us, until it comes to seem like nature.  We have constructed an environment in which we live a uniform, univocal secular time, which we try to measure and control in order to get things done.  This &amp;ldquo;time frame&amp;rdquo; deserves, perhaps more than any other facet of modernity, Weber&amp;rsquo;s famous description of a &amp;ldquo;stahlhartes Gehäuse&amp;rdquo; (iron cage).  It occludes all higher times, makes them even hard to conceive.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Augustine sees ordinary time as dispersal, distensio, losing the unity, being cut off from our past and out of touch with our future.  We get lost in our little parcel of time.  But we have an irrepressible craving for eternity, and so we strive to go beyond this.  Unfortunately, this all too often takes the form of our trying to invest our little parcel with eternal significance, and therefore divinising things, and therefore falling deeper into sin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If it is true that man is capable of everything horrible, it is also true that the horrible always engenders counterforces and that in most epochs of atrocious occurrences the great vital forces of the human soul reveal themselves: love and sacrifice, heroism in the service of conviction, and the ceaseless search for possibilities of a purer existence.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To write history is so difficult that most historians are forced to make concessions to the technique of legend.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Old Testament, in so far as it is concerned with human events, ranges through all three domains: legend, historical reporting, and interpretative historical theology.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Homeric poems, then, though their intellectual, linguistic, and above all syntactical culture appears to be so&amp;hellip;highly developed, are yet comparatively simple in their picture of human beings; and no less so in relation to the real life which they describe in general.  Delight in physical existence is everything to them, and their highest aim is to make that delight perceptible to us.  &amp;hellip;(The Homeric heroes) wake every morning as if it were the first day of their lives: their emotions, though strong, are simple and find expression instantly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Far from seeking, like Homer, merely to make us forget our own reality for a few hours, (the Bible) seeks to overcome our reality: we are to fit our own life into its world, feel ourselves to be elements in its structure of universal history.  This becomes increasingly difficult the further our historical environment is removed from that of the Biblical books; and if these nevertheless maintain their claim to absolute authority, it is inevitable that they themselves be adapted through interpretative transformation.  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy to separate the historical from the legendary in general.  Their structure is different.  Even where the legendary does not immediately betray itself by elements of the miraculous, by the repetition of well-known standard motives, typical patterns and themes, through neglect of clear details of time and place, and the like, it is generally recognizable by its composition.  It runs far too smoothly.  All cross-currents, all friction, all that is casual, secondary to the main events and themes, everything unresolved, truncated, and uncertain, which confuses the clear progress of the action and the simple orientation of the actors, has disappeared.  The historical event which we witness, or learn from the testimony of those who witnessed it, runs much more variously, contradictorily, and confusedly&amp;hellip;.  Legend arranges its material in a simple and straightforward way; it detaches it from its contemporary historical context, so that the latter will not confuse it; it knows only clearly outlined men who act from few and simple motives and the continuity of whose feelings and actions remains uninterrupted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Erich Auerbach&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Mimesis: The Representation of Reality in Western Literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Czeslaw Milosz and Herman Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-czeslaw-milosz-and-herman-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished &amp;ldquo;Moby-Dick&amp;rdquo; yesterday. It was one of the most difficult books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read - but also incredibly beautiful and rewarding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The past is inaccurate, because we cannot determine how it was in fact, no matter how hard we try.  We must rely on people&amp;rsquo;s memory, which is treacherous, because memory is constantly juggling and revising the data of experience.  &amp;hellip;In telling about an event, we ourselves cannot avoid revising it, because our narrative simplifies and composes a whole out of selected components, while omitting others.  It suffices to compare our knowledge of facts with their depiction in chronicles, journalistic accounts, memoirs, to understand the need for fantasizing that is somehow inscribed in the language itself, and which draws us into the forest of fiction.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Los Angeles horrifies me.  In our imagination money is still steel and the production of factories; it is difficult to accustom oneself to the great change, the complete reversal, that has granted a marginal human activity, entertainment, its central position as a source of money or power.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I am moved by the very fact of that woman&amp;rsquo;s existence, of which all that has remained is this verse.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I know my own weakness and am inclined to consider myself&amp;hellip;as a tangle of reflexes, a drunken child in the fog.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The essential characteristic of fame is its illusory nature, for what does a famous name mean if those who mention it are not well-informed about why it is famous?  That, after all, is the fate of the majority of monuments in every large city; they turn into signs from which the content has evaporated.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Everything that enlarges man fortifies us; everything that depicts him as a multidimensional being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABCs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A whole hour now passed; gold-beaten out to ages.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What a lovely day again! were it a new-made world, and made for a summer-house to the angels, and this morning the first of its throwing open to them, a fairer day could not dawn upon that world.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ah! how they still strove through that infinite blueness to seek out the thing that might destroy them!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But Ahab&amp;rsquo;s glance was averted; like a blighted fruit tree he shook, and cast his last, cindered apple to the soil.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Close! stand close to me, Starbuck; let me look into a human eye; it is better than to gaze into sea or sky; better than to gaze upon God.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What! how can you see better of a dark night than anybody else, never mind how foolish?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Old man of oceans! of all this fiery life of thine, what at length will remain but one little heap of ashes!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let faith oust fact; let fancy oust memory; I look deep down and do believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Would to God these blessed calms would last. But the mingled, mingling threads of life are woven by warp and woof: calms crossed by storms, a storm for every calm. There is no steady unretracing progress in this life; we do not advance through fixed gradations, and at the last one pause: - through infancy&amp;rsquo;s unconscious spell, boyhood&amp;rsquo;s thoughtless faith, adolescence&amp;rsquo; doubt (the common doom), then scepticism, then disbelief, resting at last in manhood&amp;rsquo;s pondering repose of If. But once gone through, we trace the round again; and are infants, boys, and men, and Ifs eternally. Where lies the final harbor, whence we unmoor no more? in what rapt ether sails the world, of which the weariest will never weary?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I like a good grip; I like to feel something in this slippery world that can hold, man.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seat thyself sultanically among the moons of Saturn, and take high abstracted man alone; and he seems a wonder, a grandeur, and a woe. But from the same point, take mankind in mass, and for the most part, they seem a mob of unnecessary duplicates, both contemporary and hereditary. But most humble though he was, and far from furnishing an example of the high, humane abstraction; the Pequod&amp;rsquo;s carpenter was no duplicate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell, Herman Melville, and John D. Caputo</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Next Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wisdom, said William James,&lt;br /&gt;Is learning what to overlook.  And I am wise&lt;br /&gt;If that is wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;Yet somehow, as I buy All from these shelves&lt;br /&gt;And the boy takes it to my station wagon,&lt;br /&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve become&lt;br /&gt;Troubles me even if I shut my eyes.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Imaginings within my imagining,&lt;br /&gt;I too have taken&lt;br /&gt;The chance of life.  Now the boy pats my dog&lt;br /&gt;And we start home.  Now I am good.&lt;br /&gt;The last mistaken,&lt;br /&gt;Ecstatic, accidental bliss, the blind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness that, bursting, leaves upon the palm&lt;br /&gt;Some soap and water -&lt;br /&gt;It was so long ago&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The overt Godlessness of our world is a latent Godliness.  To an eye keen for things theological, religion is most present where it is least visible.  That &amp;ldquo;secularism&amp;rdquo; blinds us to the theological order everywhere implicit in the secular order is the &amp;ldquo;central&amp;rdquo; player in (Mark C.) Taylor&amp;rsquo;s dialectic.  &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; is full of illuminating narratives generated by this hypothesis, the central story being how much &amp;ldquo;modernity&amp;rdquo; goes back to the Reformation: Luther&amp;rsquo;s assertion of subjectivity, his rejection of tradition in favor of personal experience, his media-savvy insistence on the vernacular and use of the printing press&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John D. Caputo&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;Review of Mark C. Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Academy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; 77:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look not too long in the face of the fire, O man! Never dream with thy hand on the helm! Turn not thy back to the compass; accept the first hint of the hitching tiller; believe not the artificial fire, when its redness makes all things look ghastly. To-morrow, in the natural sun, the skies will be bright; those who glared like devils in the forking flames, the morn will show in far other, at least gentler, relief; the glorious, golden, glad sun, the only true lamp - all others but liars!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless the sun hides not Virginia&amp;rsquo;s Dismal Swamp, nor Rome&amp;rsquo;s accursed Campagna, nor wide Sahara, nor all the millions of miles of deserts and of griefs beneath the moon. The sun hides not the ocean, which is the dark side of this earth, and which is two thirds of this earth. So, therefore, that mortal man who hath more of joy than sorrow in him, that mortal man cannot be true - not true, or undeveloped. With books the same. The truest of all men was the Man of Sorrows, and the truest of all books is Solomon&amp;rsquo;s, and Ecclesiastes is the fine hammered steel of woe. &amp;ldquo;All is vanity.&amp;rdquo; ALL.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There is a wisdom that is woe; but there is a woe that is madness. And there is a Catskill eagle in some souls that can alike dive down into the blackest gorges, and soar out of them again and become invisible in the sunny spaces. And even if he for ever flies within the gorge, that gorge is in the mountains; so that even in his lowest swoop the mountain eagle is still higher than other birds upon the plain, even though they soar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Herman Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;90 North&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I see at last that all the knowledge&lt;br /&gt;I wrung from the darkness - that the darkness flung me -&lt;br /&gt;Is worthless as ignorance: nothing comes from nothing,&lt;br /&gt;The darkness from the darkness.  Pain comes from the darkness&lt;br /&gt;And we call it wisdom.  It is pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But how? Genius in the Sperm Whale? Has the Sperm Whale ever written a book, spoken a speech? No, his great genius is declared in his doing nothing particular to prove it. It is moreover declared in his pyramidical silence. &amp;hellip;If hereafter any highly cultured, poetical nation shall lure back to their birth-right, the merry May-day gods of old; and livingly enthrone them again in the now egotistical sky; in the now unhaunted hill; then be sure, exalted to Jove&amp;rsquo;s high seat, the great Sperm Whale shall lord it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It was a terrific, most pitiable, and maddening sight. The whale was now going head out, and sending his spout before him in a continual tormented jet; while his one poor fin beat his side in an agony of fright. Now to this hand, now to that, he yawed in his faltering flight, and still at every billow that he broke, he spasmodically sank in the sea, or sideways rolled towards the sky his one beating fin. So have I seen a bird with clipped wing, making affrighted broken circles in the air, vainly striving to escape the piratical hawks. But the bird has a voice, and with plaintive cries will make known her fear; but the fear of this vast dumb brute of the sea, was chained up and enchanted in him; he had no voice, save that choking respiration through his spiracle, and this made the sight of him unspeakably pitiable; while still, in his amazing bulk, portcullis jaw, and omnipotent tail, there was enough to appal the stoutest man who so pitied.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Seems it credible that by three such thin threads the great Leviathan was suspended like the big weight to an eight day clock.  Suspended? and to what?  To three bits of board.  Is this the creature of whom it was once so triumphantly said - &amp;lsquo;Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish-spears? The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold, the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon: he esteemeth iron as straw; the arrow cannot make him flee; darts are counted as stubble; he laugheth at the shaking of a spear!&amp;rsquo;  This the creature? this he?  Oh! that unfulfillments should follow the prophets.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As strange misgrown masses gather in the knot-holes of the noblest oaks when prostrate, so from the points which the whale&amp;rsquo;s eyes had once occupied, now protruded blind bulbs, horribly pitiable to see.  But pity there was none.  For all his old age, and his one arm, and his blind eyes, he must die the death and be murdered, in order to light the gay bridals and other merry-makings of men, and also to illuminate the solemn churches that preach unconditional inoffensiveness by all to all.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For young whales, in the highest health, and swelling with noble aspirations, prematurely cut off in the warm flush and May of life, with all their panting lard about them; even these brawny, buoyant heroes do sometimes sink.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Czeslaw Milosz&#39;s &#39;Milosz&#39;s ABC&#39;s&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s1600-h/Milosz.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s400/Milosz.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5349520508899521426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made it, but I have always tried to remember that I owe it to my lucky star, not to myself, and that right next door are entire neighborhoods of unfortunates.  I will say even more: the thought of their grueling labor and unfulfilled hope, of the gigantic prison system in which the unneeded are kept, taught me to look skeptically at (America&amp;rsquo;s) decorations - those well-kept houses amidst the suburbs&amp;rsquo; greenery.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In our deepest convictions, reaching into the very depths of our being, we deserve to live forever.  We experience our transitoriness and mortality as an act of violence perpetrated against us.  Only Paradise is authentic; the world is inauthentic, and only temporary.  That is why the story of the Fall speaks to us so emotionally, as if summoning an old truth from our slumbering memory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;People go to church because they are divided beings.  They wish, for a moment at least, to find themselves in a reality other than the one that surrounds them and claims to be the only true reality.  This daily reality is unyielding, brutal, cruel, and hard to bear.  The human &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; is soft in the center and feels every moment that its adaptation to the world is doubtful.  &amp;hellip;Participating in the Mass we once again deny a world without meaning and without mercy; we enter into a dimension where what matters are goodness, love, and forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If to participate in the Mass it were necessary to have a strong faith and a consciousness that we act in life as our religion requires us to, all the churchgoing faithful would deserve to be called hypocrites and Pharisees.  In truth, however, strong faith is a rare gift, and as for acts, the liturgy reminds us that we are all sinners.  Attending church is not, therefore, for the elect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The needs of the individual determine church attendance, and knowledge of the catechism or even familiarity with the so-called truths of the faith are not the most important matters, although they are advisable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Miloszs-ABCs-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374527954&#34;&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Hemingway, O&#39;Connor, and K. Shapiro</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s heart tightened as the trout moved.  He felt all the old feeling.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His muscles ached and the day was hot, but Nick felt happy.  He had left everything behind, the need for thinking, the need to write, other needs.  It was all back of him.  From the time he had gotten down off the train and the baggage man had thrown his pack out of the open car door things had been different.  Seney was burned, the country was burned over and changed, but it did not matter.  It could not all be burned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The road ran on, dipping occasionally, but always climbing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inside the tent the light came through the brown canvas.  It smelled pleasantly of canvas.  Already there was something mysterious and homelike.  Nick was happy as he crawled inside the tent.  He had not been unhappy all day.  This was different though.  Now things were done.  There had been this to do.  Now it was done.  It had been a hard trip.  He was very tired.  That was done.  He had made his camp.  He was settled.  Nothing could touch him.  It was a good place to camp.  He was there, in the good place.  He was in his home where he had made it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nick laughed.  It made a good ending to the story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Big Two-Hearted River: Part I&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;.  They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tide of darkness seemed to sweep him back to her, postponing from moment to moment his entry into the world of guilt and sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery O&amp;rsquo;Connor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Everything That Rises Must Converge&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But no appeal has yet been made to the vast American middle class, the majority class, to detach itself from our competitive industrial insanity.  It is indeed our industrial way of life that lends sanction to militarism and colonialism, Preparedness and suppression of human rights.  Our enemy, strange as it may sound to American ears, is the Standard of Living.  We worship at the altar of the White Rhinoceros, the American kitchen.  Standard of Living is the holy of holies in whose name every other evil is committed.  To lower this standard or to equalize it among the peoples of the world is our greatest need.  And the first step is to disassociate ourselves from the industrial-scientific madness which rules our lives twenty-four hours a day.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To remove ourselves from the world of competition is of paramount importance to the individual and to the nation.  Competition is the most terrible vice of modern society.  Competition is the disease of the West and is the source of our violence.  Non-violence means non-competition.  &amp;hellip;It cannot be employed by governments because governments are by definition committed to violence.  Nonviolence is not a prerogative of governments but of men, even of one man.  One nonviolent man, like Gandhi or Christ, can change history.  Governments can only keep history on the march.  &lt;em&gt;Ahimsa&lt;/em&gt; can stop history.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Vinoba Bhave, the greatest living disciple of Gandhi, who travels throughout India asking for land for the peasantry from the great landlords and receiving it, says: &amp;ldquo;I desire to humiliate neither the rich nor the poor&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  This is the opposite of communist expropriation or of capitalist competition.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Instead of class war and hatred as preached by the communists or industrial-scientific competition as preached by us, to survive we must behave nonviolently and in the spirit of love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Shapiro&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;To Revive Anarchism&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Creative Glut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy Doniger&#39;s &#39;The Hindus: An Alternative History&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/wendy-donigers-the-hindus-an-alternative-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s1600-h/doniger.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sfn4tWbz46I/AAAAAAAAAvg/vYxLqzXT4mU/s400/doniger.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5330565091969721250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently picked up Wendy Doniger&amp;rsquo;s new book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hindus-Alternative-History-Wendy-Doniger/dp/1594202052&#34;&gt;The Hindus: An Alternative History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Doniger, the Mircea Eliade Distinguished Service Professor of Religions at the University of Chicago Divinity School and America&amp;rsquo;s foremost scholar of Hinduism, set out to challenge many prevailing notions of Hinduism and argue for a more inclusive, broad view of the tradition, a view that recognizes the diversity of folk religions in the Hindu world as well as the contributions of women, Muslims, and people of the lower castes to the Hindu tradition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The book was reviewed last weekend in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times Book Review&lt;/em&gt;, and it is slated to be chosen as an Editor&amp;rsquo;s Pick next week.  A comment by Professor Doniger can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://newsweek.washingtonpost.com/onfaith/panelists/wendy_doniger/2009/03/the_battle_over_hindu_history.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the favorable &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; review by Pankaj Mishra can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/26/books/review/Mishra-t.html?_r=1&amp;ref=books&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from C. Taylor, J.T. Johnson, and the US Catholic Bishops</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Faith does not insulate us from the challenges of life; rather, it intensifies our desire to help solve them&amp;hellip;.  From the resources of our faith we wish to provide hope and strength to all who seek a world free of the nuclear threat.  Hope sustains one&amp;rsquo;s capacity to live with danger without being overwhelmed by it; hope is the will to struggle against obstacles even when they appear insuperable.  Ultimately our hope rests in the God who gave us life, sustains the world by his power and has called us to revere the lives of every person and all peoples.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As Americans, citizens of the nation which was first to produce atomic weapons, which has been the only one to use them and which today is one of the handful of nations capable of decisively influencing the course of the nuclear age, we have grave human, moral, and political responsibilities to see that a &amp;ldquo;conscious choice&amp;rdquo; is made to save humanity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;United States Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response - The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The definition of combatancy and noncombatancy follows from direct involvement in prosecuting the war, not from one&amp;rsquo;s citizenship or one&amp;rsquo;s personal preference among the belligerents.  It is action that matters, not attitude.  For this reason, I regard the use of the term &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; in the Protocols to the Geneva Conventions as misleading: it is not civilian status that matters, as irregular soldiers may technically be civilians; what matters is whether people are engaged in combatant activity or not.  The relevant moral term is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;noncombatant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, even though the language of the protocols uses &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, and this usage has seeped into the moral debate at times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James Turner Johnson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The War to Oust Saddam Hussein: Just War and the New Face of Conflict&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;In the following chapters, I will be making a continuing polemic against what I call &amp;ldquo;subtraction stories.&amp;rdquo;  Concisely put, I mean by this stories of modernity in general, and secularity in particular, which explain them by human beings having lost, or sloughed off, or liberated themselves from certain earlier, confining horizons, or illusions, or limitations of knowledge.  What emerges from this process - modernity or secularity - is to be understood in terms of underlying features of human nature which were there all along, but had been impeded by what is now set aside.  Against this kind of story, I will steadily be arguing that Western modernity, including its secularity, is the fruit of new inventions, newly constructed self-understandings and related practices, and can&amp;rsquo;t be explained in terms of perennial features of human life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Melville&#39;s &#39;Moby-Dick&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-melvilles-moby-dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SevlYahAQRI/AAAAAAAAAuo/nBhOE7jOm-A/s1600-h/moby-dick.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 300px; height: 400px;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SevlYahAQRI/AAAAAAAAAuo/nBhOE7jOm-A/s400/moby-dick.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5326603191893115154&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Let the most absent-minded of men be plunged in his deepest reveries - stand that man on his legs, set his feet a-going, and he will infallibly lead you to water, if water there be in all that region.  &amp;hellip;Yes, as every one knows, meditation and water are wedded for ever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;What of it, if some old hunks of a sea-captain orders me to get a broom and sweep down the decks?  What does that indignity amount to, weighed, I mean, in the scales of the New Testament?  Do you think the archangel Gabriel thinks anything the less of me, because I promptly and respectfully obey that old hunks in that particular instance?  Who aint a slave?  Tell me that.  Well, then, however the old sea-captains may order me about - however they may thump and punch me about, I have the satisfaction of knowing that it is all right; that everybody else is one way or other served in much the same way - either in a physical or metaphysical point of view, that is; and so the universal thump is passed around, and all hands should rub each other&amp;rsquo;s shoulder-blades, and be content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;As for me, I am tormented with an everlasting itch for things remote.  I love to sail forbidden seas, and land on barbarous coasts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Each silent worshipper seemed purposely sitting apart from the other, as if each silent grief were insular and incommunicable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;But Faith, like a jackal, feeds among the tombs, and even from those dead doubts she gathers her most vital hope.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I began to be sensible of strange feelings.  I felt a melting in me.  No more my splintered heart and maddened hand were turned against the wolfish world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;One most perilous and long voyage ended, only begins a second; and a second ended, only begins a third, and so on, for ever and for aye.  Such is the endlessness, yea, the intolerableness of all earthly effort.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Now then, thou not only wantest to go a-whaling, to find out by experience what whaling is, buy ye also want to go in order to see the world?  Was not that what ye said?  I thought so.   Well then, just step forward there, and take a peep over the weather-bow, and then back to me and tell me what ye see there.&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Going forward and glancing over the weather bow, I perceived that the ship swinging to her anchor with the flood-tide, was now obliquely pointing towards the open ocean.  The prospect was unlimited, but exceedingly monotonous and forbidding; not the slightest variety that I could see.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Well, what&amp;rsquo;s the report?&amp;rsquo; said Peleg when I came back; &amp;lsquo;what did ye see?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Not much,&amp;rsquo; I replied - &amp;lsquo;nothing but water; considerable horizon though, and there&amp;rsquo;s a squall coming up, I think.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Well, what dost thou think then of seeing the world?  Do ye wish to go round Cape Horn to see any more of it, eh?  Can&amp;rsquo;t ye see the world where you stand?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Herman Melville&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;The English Major&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s1600-h/EnglishMajor&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s400/EnglishMajor&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5311272264829533522&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s latest novel, &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/English-Major-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802118631&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Harrison, a native of my home state of Michigan, is my favorite contemporary author, and &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major &lt;/span&gt;is the best &amp;rdquo;fun read&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a long time.  In trademark Harrison style, it is both hilarious and poignant, and it contains some great passages.  Excerpts below.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I tried to dismiss a pinprick of homesickness beneath my breastbone but then thought that homesickness like marital love was mostly a habit.  What I missed was no longer there or on the verge of disappearing.  I mean Lola was in dog heaven and the farm which had been sold to a stockbroker and his family from Chicago was to become a horse operation.  The barn and my cozy workshop would likely be remodeled into stables, the orchard uprooted for pasture, and our old home razed in favor of what Viv said would be &amp;ldquo;French provincial&amp;rdquo; whatever that was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad once warned me about this when I was mourning the loss of a girlfriend to a quarterback.  I was a lonely lineman.  I moped and moped, and then when we were cutting wood on an icy October morning he told me that self-pity was a ruinous emotion.  &amp;rdquo;Look at the world, not up your ass,&amp;rdquo; he said.  It took me awhile to figure this out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;She also liked to say that my dead father would wish me to be a &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; when my dad never spoke about such things except to say that successful people never had much time for important things like hunting, fishing, drinking, and wandering around in the woods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t own a cell phone which only made the wandering man a target with the number providing a guaranteed bull&amp;rsquo;s-eye.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Up to this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t questioned the rightness of my trip but suddenly I wondered if I were truly suited for travel.  Reality seemed to be crumbling and I was wise enough to understand that reality stayed the same so it was my mind that was crumbling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;To my dad who was a young man during the Great Depression the only truly hopeless greivance was not to have a job, or not to have &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; as he called it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sort of neutral in terms of religion but ever since I was a kid I&amp;rsquo;ve thought moving water to be the best thing God made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Everyone pretty much pans out in the middle ground or less.  In college I thought I was destined to go overseas but I didn&amp;rsquo;t.  We don&amp;rsquo;t quite get started except on our livelihood which is probably the story of mankind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Kohak&#39;s &#39;The Embers and the Stars&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s1600-h/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 128px; height: 194px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s400/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5302889589404206306&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I recently discovered the work of Erazim Kohak, a Czech philosopher and Professor Emeritus at Boston University who has written extensively on environmental ethics.  I am 30 pages into Kohak&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/span&gt;, and it is incredible so far.  A few excerpts below, with more to come.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Reflection and speculation remain no more than cunningly devised fables if they are not grounded in what, paraphrasing Calvin Schrag, we could call the prephilosophical and prescientific matrix of self-understanding and world-comprehension.  Though philosophy must do much else as well, it must, initially, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;see&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; and, thereafter, ground its speculation ever anew in seeing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;It is, surely, good that there are synthetic medicines to ease the surplus of pain, telephones to break through loneliness, and electric lights to keep the wayfarer from stumbling.  There is, though, something wrong when we use medicine to deaden our sensitivity, when we obliterate solitude with electronics and blind ourselves with the very lights we devised to help us see.  There is nothing wrong with our artifacts; there &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;something wrong with us: we have lost sight of the sense, the purpose of our production and our products.  Artifacts, finally, are good only extrinsically, as tools.  They have no intrinsic sense of their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;My primary tool has been the metaphor, not the argument, and the product of my labors is not a doctrine but an invitation to look and see.  With Husserl, I have sought not to instruct but to point out, to recall what we have forgotten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Contrary to Descartes, long before the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; of reflection there is the goodness and the truth of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;. [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; as in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito ergo sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, &amp;ldquo;I think, therefore I am&amp;rdquo;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= togetherness, &amp;ldquo;we are&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Humans have to dehumanize their world in their imagination in order to be able to exploit it ruthlessly in their actions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Our world of artifacts may be no more than the thinnest of layers covering the rhythm of living nature, but it is that layer that we confront in our daily experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Though the theoretical construct of [nature as] a mechanically ordered matter in motion may bear little resemblance to the living nature of the field and the forest and so may never have appeared convincing before, it is a faithful reflection of a world of artifacts and as such compelling to a humanity whose experience with nature is restricted to contact with artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The technical reason which produces the machine cannot teach us its human use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The logic of&amp;hellip;production and consumption, however, grows ever more elusive.  Through the ages of humanity&amp;rsquo;s precarious survival on this earth, the meeting of basic survival needs provided a ready justification for productive activity.  Were we inclined so to direct our energies, it might still do so: there is more than enough hunger and sheer dismal misery still with us.  For the most part, though, we manage to ignore such need.  The logic of our production is not that of need but of affluence with lacks such automatic justification.  If affluence is to be justified, it cannot be by need but by some greater good, be it meeting the needs of others, caring for the natural world, or creating higher values of culture.  &amp;hellip;Yet individually and collectively we sacrifice precious life and resources to producing and paying for [items such as ever-larger television sets] - and we are constantly assured that we must do so to &amp;ldquo;stimulate the economy.&amp;rdquo;  Production itself has become the justification of ever more absurd consumption: we consume to proudce, produce to consume; all other considerations must stand aside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The heavens may still declare the glory of God, but we look up not at the heavens but at neon reflected on smog; we walk not on the good earth but on asphalt.  Our estrangement from nature is no longer conceptual only: it has acquired an experiential grounding.  Figuratively, we are all in the position of the child who has never seen, never mind milked, a cow, and whose lived experience constantly provides an experiential confirmation for the assumption that milk comes from a supermarket cooler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;If the products of human &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;techne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; become philosophically and experientially problematic, it is, I would submit, because we come to think of them as autonomous of the purpose which led to their production and gives them meaning.  We become, in effect, victims of a self-forgetting, losing sight of the moral sense which is the justification of technology.  Quite concretely, the purpose of electric light is to help humans see.  When it comes to blind them to the world around them, it becomes counterproductive.  The task thus is not to abolish technology but to see through it to the human meaning which justifies it and directs its use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Erazim Kohak  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic; &#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GvI0xlwoMesC&amp;amp;dq=the+embers+and+the+stars&amp;amp;source=gbs_summary_s&amp;amp;cad=0&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
