<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/writing/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying about Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lying about Libya,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; appeared today in &lt;i&gt;Mises Daily&lt;/i&gt;, a publication of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Ludwig von Mises Institute&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;You can read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s1600/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s320/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What was sold to the American public as a humanitarian intervention morphed almost immediately into unreserved support of one side in Libya&amp;rsquo;s civil war and a commitment to overthrowing Libya&amp;rsquo;s existing government.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;To decide whether a military action undertaken in our name is prudent and just, we must adopt a skeptical stance toward politicians&amp;rsquo; stories and rationalizations. We must attempt to see through these to the reality of the situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;Stories can change, and new excuses can be spun, but once a war is launched there is no predicting the course it will take or the consequences it will have. Wars rarely go according to plan; they set in motion a course of events that no one person or group of people can hope to control.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the entire article.  Please consider posting it on Facebook or Twitter, or otherwise passing it along to others if you enjoy it.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Libya War on &#39;Russia Today&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rt.com/news/sanctions-showdown-syria-libya/&#34;&gt;Russia Today&lt;/a&gt; (RT) yesterday to discuss the U.S./NATO intervention in Libya as well as the situation in Syria - feel free to check it out if you are interested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/by444eRvSSI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My related article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Rolling the Dice in Libya&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another, unrelated op-ed of mine appeared yesterday as well in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;Michigan Education Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;National standards will stifle innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  In it, I argue that &amp;ldquo;strict standards risk forcing students and teachers alike into a curricular straitjacket, alienating creative teachers and sapping the motivation of students.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find links to all of my online publications at my homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;www.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling the dice in Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Rolling the dice in Libya,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. If you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or emailing it to a friend. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rolling the dice in Libya&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Barack Obama won the Democratic nomination in 2008 partly by reminding the party’s base of his early, prescient criticisms of the ill-fated decision to invade Iraq. “What I am opposed to is a dumb war … a rash war,” then-Senator Obama explained in 2002.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obama was right to call the Iraq War “dumb” and “rash”: the Bush administration’s decision to invade Iraq was based not just on an “intelligence failure,” but on flagrant hubris, ignorance of geography and history, and unawareness of the limits of American power in the 21st century. And yet the Obama administration demonstrated each of these failings  in deciding to involve the U.S. in Libya’s civil war.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Much ado was made about the U.S. “handing over” the Libya mission to NATO after dominating the first stage of the operation. But NATO is best understood as a multilateral cloak for American power; the U.S. has a military far larger and more advanced than any of its NATO allies, and it is by far the largest contributor to NATO’s budget.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The U.S.-NATO mission in Libya, we are told again and again, is nothing more than a temporary “humanitarian” operation to protect civilians. Since we are still bombing away at Col. Moammar Gadhafi’s military, one would think that Gadhafi’s forces are still on the verge of massacring defenseless civilians in rebel-held cities. But then we learn of “progress” in the war: under the cover of U.S./NATO-provided air power, rebels have taken cities from Gadhafi’s forces and advanced closer to Tripoli.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apparently, “protecting civilians” means attempting to crush the Libyan government forces and turn the tide of the civil war in the rebels’ favor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Defenders of the intervention appeal to our sense of decency by warning of the “genocide” that might have occurred had events in Libya been permitted to run their course, but this is nothing more than conjecture. It is possible to defend any course of action by asserting that a worst-case scenario would have occurred had the action not been taken. However, our worst fears usually do not turn out to be accurate predictors of the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the Obama administration’s protests to the contrary, what was sold as an effort to protect Libyan civilians has quickly developed into an unstated commitment to regime-change in Libya, with all the long-term challenges, obligations, and uncertainties that entails. It has also morphed into a full embrace of the Libyan rebels, though no one is sure exactly what the rebels stand for, or whether they have a workable plan to restore stability and govern the country democratically in a post-Gadhafi era.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like Bush’s decision to invade Iraq, Obama’s decision to intervene in Libya relied upon wishful thinking about the post-intervention course of events. Bush assured us that the conflict in Iraq would be swift, decisive, and relatively painless for the U.S.; Obama assured us that the mission in Libya would not require ground troops or a sustained American commitment and that it would be over in “days, not weeks.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But as political scientist Robert Pape has shown, air power alone is rarely, if ever, sufficient to achieve a state’s aims in war. And the “days” of U.S. involvement have already become “weeks” and will soon become “months,” as they tend to do in wars—which are, after all, unpredictable and uncontrollable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;President Obama has joined the long line of presidents who have been blinded by U.S. power and failed to perceive the limits of that power. He is likely to fail in Libya—or pay a high price for a very limited and temporary success—because he chose to ignore the advice of the great strategist Carl von Clausewitz, who wrote: “War is the realm of chance. … Chance makes everything more uncertain and interferes with the whole course of events.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The hopes and expectations of war supporters are routinely dashed by the complexity of reality. War plans often rely on best-case scenarios and assume that the planners are gifted with such foresight and judgment that they can realistically project how events will unfold. But the human actors driving these events on the ground often respond quite unpredictably to changes in their situation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prudent policymakers and citizens should expect hasty wars of choice based on rose-eyed assumptions to fail and to have unforeseen consequences that last decades. This is not the outcome we hope for in the Libya war, but it is the outcome we can most safely bet on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two cents about COIN</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Two cents about COIN,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. It discusses the the growing faith of U.S. political and military leaders in the military doctrine of COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below; if you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or linking to it on your blog. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Cents About COIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The war in Afghanistan, according to Gen. Stanley McChrystal’s recent assessment, is &amp;ldquo;a situation that defies simple solutions or quick fixes.  Success demands a comprehensive counterinsurgency (COIN) campaign.&amp;rdquo;  McChrystal and other American leaders calling for a &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; of additional U.S. troops into Afghanistan to mirror the alleged success of the &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; in Iraq are voicing their belief that the doctrinal framework for the original surge – COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare – is a widely-applicable tool in asymmetric warfare that the U.S. ought to employ in Afghanistan. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Top decisionmakers in the U.S. military, including Gen. McChrystal and Gen. David Petraeus, continue to express their faith in the doctrine, which they played major roles in creating.  Prominent Republicans in Congress, who almost unanimously support sending more troops to Afghanistan, have endorsed a nation-building strategy that relies heavily on COIN over a counterterrorism strategy that focuses on targeting al-Qaeda and other militants from a distance.  Several key figures in the Obama administration also appear to favor that approach. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It may be true that, as military expert Stephen Biddle said in recent Congressional testimony, &amp;ldquo;the U.S. is an unusually experienced counterinsurgent force today,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the new Army/Marine counterinsurgency doctrine…is the product of a nearly unprecedented degree of internal debate, external vetting, historical analysis, and direct recent combat experience.&amp;rdquo;   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But these very factors that have encouraged so many highly capable U.S. leaders to sign on to &amp;ldquo;COIN&amp;rdquo; should cause observers to be wary of the doctrine and the currency it increasingly enjoys in the American political debate.  After all, the more enthusiastic we are about the potential of COIN warfare, the more blind we will be to its costs, which are enormous. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We can and must think about contemporary problems – such as what strategy the U.S. should pursue in Afghanistan – through the lenses of relevant theories and historical analogies.  But it is foolish to think within the box of a single analogy, such as the Iraq &amp;ldquo;surge,&amp;rdquo; or a single theory, such as the idea that we can succeed at counterinsurgency and nation-building by deploying generous numbers of ground troops and focusing on winning the &amp;ldquo;hearts and minds&amp;rdquo; of local communities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our need to make quick decisions and cope with a complex world creates a powerful incentive for us to create &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; default beliefs, habits, choices, or courses of action that we adopt almost without thinking.  And yet when those in the halls of power make major decisions on the basis of such &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; the results can sometimes be disastrous.  It behooves political observers to be aware of new decision-making habits, and the spread of some new piece of &amp;ldquo;conventional wisdom,&amp;rdquo; in their leaders. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to remember that military leaders have a major incentive to endorse a COIN approach in Afghanistan.  According to General Petraeus and other experts, most successful COIN operations require very high numbers of U.S. troops on the ground – numbers that may be politically and logistically impossible for the Obama administration to accept. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because the number of troops that can be reasonably demanded for a COIN operation is essentially limitless, mission failure can be blamed on the executive branch for not sending enough troops rather than on military leaders, the combat environment, or the COIN playbook itself.  As Gen. McChrystal wrote in his assessment: &amp;ldquo;Success is not ensured by additional forces alone, but continued underresourcing will likely cause failure.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Organizational psychology and the logic of bureaucracies provide more clues into the wave of COIN-fever that appears to have struck so many of our political and military leaders.  Simply put, it was neither easy nor cheap for the military to develop COIN doctrine as we attempted to salvage the war in Iraq in recent years, and now COIN feels like hard-won wisdom that we should put to the test in another theater of war.  It’s a classic case of sunk costs: it is felt that we paid too much for COIN to abandon it now. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Policymakers’ belief in the power of COIN may encourage them to see military solutions where none exist.  If the U.S. opts to send tens of thousands of additional ground troops to Afghanistan in order to pursue a comprehensive COIN strategy, it will be taking on a great deal of risk and incurring substantial additional costs in pursuit of a highly uncertain outcome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/www.ryanmccarl.com&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator. He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New short fiction: &#39;The Day-Trader&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/new-short-fiction-the-day-trader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Day-Trader,&amp;rdquo; my most recent short story, is being featured in the July issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/06/the-day-trader/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a lot of great stuff in this issue - fiction, poetry, a short film, visual art, a music album, and an essay - so be sure to check out the other pieces as well.  If you like what you see, you can support &lt;em&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/em&gt; by linking to it, passing it along to others, and making a &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/donations/&#34;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Milosz, Balthasar, and Stevens</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many definitions of Communism, perhaps one would be the most apt: enemy of orchards. For the disappearance of villages and the remodeling of the terrain necessitated cutting down the orchards once surrounding every house and hut. The idea of collective farming - grain factories instead of little peasant lots - was rational, but with a vengeance, and a similar vengeance lurking in practically every project of the planned economy brought about the downfall of the Soviet system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Orchards under Communism had no chance, but in all fairness let us concede that they are antique by their very nature. Only the passion of a gardener can delight in growing a great variety of trees, each producing a small crop of fruit whose tastes pleases the gardener himself and a few connoisseurs. Market laws favor a few species that are easy to preserve and correspond to basic standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Much was going on inside me, and I was stunned by the strength of that current for which no name seemed adequate. It was like waking up from a long dream and becoming again the person whom I have never ceased to be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Happiness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One would like to astound the world, to save the world, but one can do neither. We are summoned to deeds that are of moment only to our village.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Who Was I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I am not wise, then why must I pretend to be? If I am lost, why must I pretend to have ready counsel for my contemporaries? But perhaps the value of communication depends on the acknowledgment of one&amp;rsquo;s own limits, which, mysteriously, are also limits common to many others; and aren&amp;rsquo;t these the same limits of a hundred or a thousand years ago? And when the air is filled with the clamor of analysis and conclusion, would it be entirely useless to admit you do not understand?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have read many books, but to place all those volumes on top of one another and stand on them would not add a cubit to my stature. Their learned terms are of little use when I try to seize naked experience, which eludes all accepted ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;My Intention&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The man who stakes his all on this one thing wins all, but he must of course reckon with the loss of everything else excluded by this one thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hans Urs von Balthasar&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Moment of Christian Witness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;Divinity must live within herself:&lt;br /&gt;Passions of rain, or moods in falling snow;&lt;br /&gt;Grievings in loneliness, or unsubdued&lt;br /&gt;Elations when the forest blooms; gusty&lt;br /&gt;Emotions on wet roads on autumn nights;&lt;br /&gt;All pleasures and all pains, remembering&lt;br /&gt;The bough of summer and the winter branch.&lt;br /&gt;These are the measures destined for her soul.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shall our blood fail? Or shall it come to be&lt;br /&gt;The blood of paradise? And shall the earth&lt;br /&gt;Seem all of paradise that we shall know?&lt;br /&gt;The sky will be much friendlier then than now,&lt;br /&gt;A part of labor and a part of pain,&lt;br /&gt;And next in glory to enduring love,&lt;br /&gt;Not this dividing and indifferent blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great lines from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to think - seriously - with words like Classicism, Romanticism, Humanism, Realism. &amp;hellip;One does not get drunk nor does one quench one&amp;rsquo;s thirst with bottle labels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Paul Valery, quoted in C. Milosz, &lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beauty is momentary in the mind -&lt;br /&gt;The fitful tracing of a portal;&lt;br /&gt;But in the flesh it is immortal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Peter Quince at the Clavier&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At no moment during my work did I feel boredom; indeed, I was playing more than toiling, and several passages preserve, I hope, a trace of my smile.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright, green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, in the isolation of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;At evening, casual flocks of pigeons make&lt;br /&gt;Ambiguous undulations as they sink,&lt;br /&gt;Downward to darkness, on extended wings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I got away with half my heart - no more.&lt;br /&gt;Barely a trace of my old gaiety.&lt;br /&gt;The crowd like market cattle bore&lt;br /&gt;Me along. The world was loathsome to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyprian Norwid&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Nerves&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With nothing can one approach a work of art so little as with critical words: they always come down to more or less happy misunderstandings.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This above all - ask yourself in the stillest hour of the night: &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; I write? Delve into yourself for a deep answer. And if this should be affirmative, if you may meet this question with a strong and simple &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I must&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; then build your life according to this necessity; your life even into its most indifferent and slightest hour must be a sign of this urge and a testimony to it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Therefore save yourself from these general themes and seek those which your own everyday life offers you; describe your sorrows and desires, passing thoughts and the belief in some sort of beauty - describe all these with loving, quiet, humble sincerity, and use, to express yourself, the things in your environment, the images from your dreams, and the objects of your memory. If your daily life seems poor, do not blame it; blame yourself, tell yourself that you are not poet enough to call forth its riches; for to the creator there is no poverty and no poor indifferent place. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A work of art is good if it has sprung from necessity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Live a while in these books, learn from them what seems to you worth learning, but above all love them. This love will be repaid you a thousand and a thousand times, and however your life may turn, - it will, I am certain of it, run through the fabric of your growth as one of the most important threads among all the threads of your experiences, disappointments and joys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Letters to a Young Poet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
