<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poetry on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poetry on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/poetry/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Klein, Warren, Chirelstein, and Gluck</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-klein-warren-chirelstein-and-gluck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-klein-warren-chirelstein-and-gluck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Customs grow out of social processes whose details are highly individuated in regards to the type of activity, the individuals involved, their reputational pedigree, the knowledge they have about each other, and so on. &amp;nbsp;Viewing cultural evolution as deeply and densely rooted process may make one doubt the wisdom of government attempts to fine tune, guide, or supplant it. &amp;nbsp;It is highly unlikely that the blunt instruments of government will be well suited to cultivating the growth of delicate, teeming, unique interactions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Daniel B. Klein&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Assurance and Trust in a Great Society.&amp;rdquo; &amp;nbsp;FEE Occasional Paper Two.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I kneeled to the crickets trilling&lt;br /&gt;underfoot as if about&lt;br /&gt;to burst from their crusty shells;&lt;br /&gt;and like a child again&lt;br /&gt;marveled to hear so clear&lt;br /&gt;and brave a music pour&lt;br /&gt;from such a small machine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Penn Warren&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;Touch Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some assert that strict enforcement of contracts is really a way of showing respect for the dignity and freedom of other individuals by taking them at their word.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Marvin A. Chirelstein&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;Concepts and Case Analysis in the Law of Contracts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look at her, touching his cheek&lt;br /&gt;to make a truce, her fingers&lt;br /&gt;cool with spring rain;&lt;br /&gt;in thin grass, bursts of purple crocus -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;even here, even at the beginning of love,&lt;br /&gt;her hand leaving his face makes&lt;br /&gt;an image of departure&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and they think&lt;br /&gt;they are free to overlook&lt;br /&gt;this sadness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Louise Gluck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;The Garden&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Michael Walzer and Harold Bloom</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-michael-walzer-and-harold-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-michael-walzer-and-harold-bloom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the very center of conservative thought lies this idea: that the present division of wealth and power corresponds to some deeper reality of human life.  &amp;hellip;They want to say that whatever the division of wealth and power is, it naturally is, and that all efforts to change it, temporarily successful in proportion to their bloodiness, must be futile in the end.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Michael Walzer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;In Defense of Equality&amp;rdquo; in Howe, ed., &lt;em&gt;25 Years of Dissent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For why do men write poems?  To rally everything that remains.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shelly speculated that poets of all ages contributed to one Great Poem perpetually in progress.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the contemporary poems that most move me&amp;hellip;I can recognize a strength that battles against the death of poetry, yet also the exhaustions of being a latecomer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Freud recognized sublimation as the highest human achievement, a recognition that allies him to both Plato and to the entire moral traditions of both Judaism and Christianity.  Freudian sublimation involves the yielding-up of more primordial for more refined modes of pleasure, which is to exalt the second chance above the first.  &amp;hellip;To equate emotional maturation with the discovery of acceptable substitutes may be pragmatic wisdom, especially in the realm of Eros, but this is not the wisdom of the strong poets.  The surrendered dream is not merely a phantasmagoria of endless gratification, but is the greatest of all human illusions, the vision of immortality.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Poetic history, in this book&amp;rsquo;s argument, is held to be indistinguishable from poetic influence, since strong poets make that history by misreading one another, so as to clear imaginative space for themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;More than any other purely secular author, Shakespeare makes history more than history makes Shakespeare.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A good biography of Shakespeare, like Russell Fraser&amp;rsquo;s, is preferable to any historicism, because at least we are alone with Shakespeare and Fraser, rather than being propagandized by an academic sect or coven.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s energies so fuse rhetoric, psychology, and cosmology that we cannot distinguish them from one another in his greatest plays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harold Bloom&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Anxiety of Influence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell, Herman Melville, and John D. Caputo</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Next Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wisdom, said William James,&lt;br /&gt;Is learning what to overlook.  And I am wise&lt;br /&gt;If that is wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;Yet somehow, as I buy All from these shelves&lt;br /&gt;And the boy takes it to my station wagon,&lt;br /&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve become&lt;br /&gt;Troubles me even if I shut my eyes.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Imaginings within my imagining,&lt;br /&gt;I too have taken&lt;br /&gt;The chance of life.  Now the boy pats my dog&lt;br /&gt;And we start home.  Now I am good.&lt;br /&gt;The last mistaken,&lt;br /&gt;Ecstatic, accidental bliss, the blind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness that, bursting, leaves upon the palm&lt;br /&gt;Some soap and water -&lt;br /&gt;It was so long ago&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The overt Godlessness of our world is a latent Godliness.  To an eye keen for things theological, religion is most present where it is least visible.  That &amp;ldquo;secularism&amp;rdquo; blinds us to the theological order everywhere implicit in the secular order is the &amp;ldquo;central&amp;rdquo; player in (Mark C.) Taylor&amp;rsquo;s dialectic.  &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; is full of illuminating narratives generated by this hypothesis, the central story being how much &amp;ldquo;modernity&amp;rdquo; goes back to the Reformation: Luther&amp;rsquo;s assertion of subjectivity, his rejection of tradition in favor of personal experience, his media-savvy insistence on the vernacular and use of the printing press&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John D. Caputo&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;Review of Mark C. Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Academy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; 77:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look not too long in the face of the fire, O man! Never dream with thy hand on the helm! Turn not thy back to the compass; accept the first hint of the hitching tiller; believe not the artificial fire, when its redness makes all things look ghastly. To-morrow, in the natural sun, the skies will be bright; those who glared like devils in the forking flames, the morn will show in far other, at least gentler, relief; the glorious, golden, glad sun, the only true lamp - all others but liars!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless the sun hides not Virginia&amp;rsquo;s Dismal Swamp, nor Rome&amp;rsquo;s accursed Campagna, nor wide Sahara, nor all the millions of miles of deserts and of griefs beneath the moon. The sun hides not the ocean, which is the dark side of this earth, and which is two thirds of this earth. So, therefore, that mortal man who hath more of joy than sorrow in him, that mortal man cannot be true - not true, or undeveloped. With books the same. The truest of all men was the Man of Sorrows, and the truest of all books is Solomon&amp;rsquo;s, and Ecclesiastes is the fine hammered steel of woe. &amp;ldquo;All is vanity.&amp;rdquo; ALL.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There is a wisdom that is woe; but there is a woe that is madness. And there is a Catskill eagle in some souls that can alike dive down into the blackest gorges, and soar out of them again and become invisible in the sunny spaces. And even if he for ever flies within the gorge, that gorge is in the mountains; so that even in his lowest swoop the mountain eagle is still higher than other birds upon the plain, even though they soar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Herman Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;90 North&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I see at last that all the knowledge&lt;br /&gt;I wrung from the darkness - that the darkness flung me -&lt;br /&gt;Is worthless as ignorance: nothing comes from nothing,&lt;br /&gt;The darkness from the darkness.  Pain comes from the darkness&lt;br /&gt;And we call it wisdom.  It is pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Bishop, Hayden, Olson, and Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Man-Moth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He thinks the moon is a small hole at the top of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;proving the sky quite useless for protection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Mourning Poem for the Queen of Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh who and oh who will sing Jesus down&lt;br /&gt;to help with struggling and doing without and being colored&lt;br /&gt;all through blue Monday?&lt;br /&gt;Till way next Sunday?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Hayden&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Questions of Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Should we have stayed at home,&lt;br /&gt;wherever that may be?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Maximus, to Himself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is undone business&lt;br /&gt;I speak of, this morning,&lt;br /&gt;with the sea&lt;br /&gt;stretching out&lt;br /&gt;from my feet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Charles Olson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Again: as the profound calm which only apparently precedes and prophesies of the storm, is perhaps more awful than the storm itself; for, indeed, the calm is but the wrapper and envelope of the storm; and contains it in itself, as the seemingly harmless rifle holds the fatal powder, and the ball, and the explosion; so the graceful repose of the line, as it silently serpentines about the oarsmen before being brought into actual play - this is a thing which carries more of true terror than any other aspect of this dangerous affair. But why say more? All men live enveloped in whale-lines. All are born with halters round their necks; but it is only when caught in the swift, sudden turn of death, that mortals realize the silent, subtle, ever-present perils of life. And if you be a philosopher, though seated in the whale-boat, you would not at heart feel one whit more of terror, than though seated before your evening fire with a poker, and not a harpoon, by your side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Poems excerpted from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Norton-Anthology-Modern-Contemporary-Poetry/dp/039332429X&#34;&gt;The Norton Anthology of Modern and Contemporary Poetry&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edna St. Vincent Millay&#39;s &#39;Conscientious Objector&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/edna-st.-vincent-millays-conscientious-objector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/edna-st.-vincent-millays-conscientious-objector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I discovered one of the best poems on war I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read the other day while reading David P. Barash&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Approaches-Peace-Reader-Studies/dp/0195123867&#34;&gt;Approaches to Peace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, an excellent edited volume on peace and conflict studies:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;Conscientious Objector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;Edna St. Vincent Millay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I shall die, but&lt;br /&gt;that is all that I shall do for Death.&lt;br /&gt;I hear him leading his horse out of the stall;&lt;br /&gt;I hear the clatter on the barn-floor.&lt;br /&gt;He is in haste; he has business in Cuba,&lt;br /&gt;business in the Balkans,&lt;br /&gt;many calls to make this morning.&lt;br /&gt;But I will not hold the bridle&lt;br /&gt;while he cinches the girth.&lt;br /&gt;And he may mount by himself:&lt;br /&gt;I will not give him a leg up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Though he flick my shoulders with his whip,&lt;br /&gt;I will not tell him which way the fox ran.&lt;br /&gt;With his hoof on my breast, I will not tell him where&lt;br /&gt;the black boy hides in the swamp.&lt;br /&gt;I shall die, but that is all that I shall do for Death;&lt;br /&gt;I am not on his pay-roll.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I will not tell him the whereabouts of my friends&lt;br /&gt;nor of my enemies either.&lt;br /&gt;Though he promise me much,&lt;br /&gt;I will not map him the route to any man&amp;rsquo;s door.&lt;br /&gt;Am I a spy in the land of the living,&lt;br /&gt;that I should deliver men to Death?&lt;br /&gt;Brother, the password and the plans of our city&lt;br /&gt;are safe with me; never through me&lt;br /&gt;Shall you be overcome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Milosz, Balthasar, and Stevens</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-milosz-balthasar-and-stevens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many definitions of Communism, perhaps one would be the most apt: enemy of orchards. For the disappearance of villages and the remodeling of the terrain necessitated cutting down the orchards once surrounding every house and hut. The idea of collective farming - grain factories instead of little peasant lots - was rational, but with a vengeance, and a similar vengeance lurking in practically every project of the planned economy brought about the downfall of the Soviet system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Orchards under Communism had no chance, but in all fairness let us concede that they are antique by their very nature. Only the passion of a gardener can delight in growing a great variety of trees, each producing a small crop of fruit whose tastes pleases the gardener himself and a few connoisseurs. Market laws favor a few species that are easy to preserve and correspond to basic standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Much was going on inside me, and I was stunned by the strength of that current for which no name seemed adequate. It was like waking up from a long dream and becoming again the person whom I have never ceased to be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Happiness&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One would like to astound the world, to save the world, but one can do neither. We are summoned to deeds that are of moment only to our village.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Who Was I?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If I am not wise, then why must I pretend to be? If I am lost, why must I pretend to have ready counsel for my contemporaries? But perhaps the value of communication depends on the acknowledgment of one&amp;rsquo;s own limits, which, mysteriously, are also limits common to many others; and aren&amp;rsquo;t these the same limits of a hundred or a thousand years ago? And when the air is filled with the clamor of analysis and conclusion, would it be entirely useless to admit you do not understand?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have read many books, but to place all those volumes on top of one another and stand on them would not add a cubit to my stature. Their learned terms are of little use when I try to seize naked experience, which eludes all accepted ideas.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;My Intention&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The man who stakes his all on this one thing wins all, but he must of course reckon with the loss of everything else excluded by this one thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hans Urs von Balthasar&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Moment of Christian Witness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;Divinity must live within herself:&lt;br /&gt;Passions of rain, or moods in falling snow;&lt;br /&gt;Grievings in loneliness, or unsubdued&lt;br /&gt;Elations when the forest blooms; gusty&lt;br /&gt;Emotions on wet roads on autumn nights;&lt;br /&gt;All pleasures and all pains, remembering&lt;br /&gt;The bough of summer and the winter branch.&lt;br /&gt;These are the measures destined for her soul.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Shall our blood fail? Or shall it come to be&lt;br /&gt;The blood of paradise? And shall the earth&lt;br /&gt;Seem all of paradise that we shall know?&lt;br /&gt;The sky will be much friendlier then than now,&lt;br /&gt;A part of labor and a part of pain,&lt;br /&gt;And next in glory to enduring love,&lt;br /&gt;Not this dividing and indifferent blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Mann, Golley, and Eliot</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Must-read: the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt; on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/24/us/24land.html?hp&#34;&gt;severe case of protracted bullying&lt;/a&gt;.  This is real, and it&amp;rsquo;s an enormous problem.  There is a spectrum of school violence ranging from verbal harassment and bullying all the way to school shootings, and it needs to be taken more seriously and addressed more quickly at every stage.  An atmosphere of security and mutual respect in classrooms is essential to students&amp;rsquo; well-being and ability to learn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A human being lives out not only his personal life as an individual, but also, consciously or subconsciously, the lives of his epoch and contemporaries.  &amp;hellip;All sorts of personal goals, purposes, hopes, prospects may float before the eyes of a given individual, from which he may then glean the impulse for exerting himself for great deeds; if the impersonal world around him, however, if the times themselves, despite all their hustle and bustle, provide him with neither hopes nor prospects, if they secretly supply him with evidence that things are in fact hopeless, without prospect or remedy, if the times respond with hollow silence to every conscious or subconscious question, however it may be posed, about the ultimate, unequivocal meaning of all exertions and deeds that are more than exclusively personal - then it is almost inevitable&amp;hellip;that the situation will have a crippling effect, which, following moral and spiritual paths, may even spread to that person&amp;rsquo;s physical and organic life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Two days of travel separate this young man (and young he is, with few firm roots in life) from his everyday world, especially from what might be called his duties, interests, worries, and prospects - separate him far more than he had dreamed possible as he rode to the station in a hansom cab.  Space, as it rolls and tumbles away between him and his native soil, proves to have powers normally ascribed only to time; from hour to hour, space brings about changes very like those time produces, yet surpassing them in certain ways.  Space, like time, gives birth to forgetfulness, but does so by removing an individual from all relationships and placing him in a free and pristine state - indeed, in but a moment it can turn a pedant and a philistine into something like a vagabond.  Time, they say, is water from the river Lethe, but alien air is a similar drink; and if its effects are less profound, it works all the more quickly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;All divine attributes have been taken over by human hands,&amp;rdquo; (Hirato Renkichi) wrote.  &amp;ldquo;Today, the engine of God is the engine of the city, and partakes in the activities of humanity&amp;rsquo;s millions.&amp;rdquo;  Almost every sentence of this document seems to anticipate Paul Virilio&amp;rsquo;s 1997 equation of &amp;ldquo;new technologies&amp;rdquo; with the &amp;ldquo;three traditional characteristics of the Divine: ubiquity, instantaneity, and immediacy.&amp;rdquo;  Although Virilio refers here to a much later technological revolution, the logic of his thinking echoes the poetics of Hirato Renkichi.  &amp;hellip;For Hirato, the powers of the divine had come to reside in &amp;ldquo;the impulsive candor of the machine, in its light, its heat, its ceaseless rhythms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gregory Golley&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See: Realism, Science, and Ecology in Japanese Literary Modernism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When a poet&amp;rsquo;s mind is perfectly equipped for its work, it is constantly amalgamating disparate experience; the ordinary man&amp;rsquo;s experience is chaotic, irregular, fragmentary.  The latter falls in love, or reads Spinoza, and these two experiences have nothing to do with each other, or with the noise of the typewriter or the smell of cooking; in the mind of the poet these experiences are always forming new wholes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;T.S. Eliot&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Metaphysical Poets,&amp;rdquo; quoted in Golley, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and poems by Goethe, Coleridge, and A. Daniel</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-and-poems-by-goethe-coleridge-and-a.-daniel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am more and more convinced that poetry is the universal possession of mankind&amp;hellip;the epoch of world literature is at hand, and everyone must strive to hasten its approach.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Goethe (quoted in Damrosch, &lt;em&gt;What is World Literature?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White Towels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been studying the difference&lt;br /&gt;between solitude and loneliness,&lt;br /&gt;telling the story of my life&lt;br /&gt;to the clean white towels taken warm from the dryer.&lt;br /&gt;I carry them through the house&lt;br /&gt;as though they were my children&lt;br /&gt;asleep in my arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Jones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone XII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May God, the Chosen, by whom were absolved the sins of the blind Longinus, wish if it please him, that I and my lady lie within one chamber where we shall make a rich covenant, whereon great joy attendeth; where, with laughter and caresses, she shall disclose to me her fair body, with the glamor of the lamplight about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duty Surviving Self-Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unchanged within, to see all changed without,&lt;br /&gt;Is a blank lot and hard to bear, no doubt.&lt;br /&gt;Yet why at others&amp;rsquo; wanings should&amp;rsquo;st thou fret ?&lt;br /&gt;Then only might&amp;rsquo;st thou feel a just regret,&lt;br /&gt;Hadst thou withheld thy love or hid thy light&lt;br /&gt;In selfish forethought of neglect and slight.&lt;br /&gt;O wiselier then, from feeble yearnings freed,&lt;br /&gt;While, and on whom, thou may&amp;rsquo;st&amp;ndash;shine on! nor heed&lt;br /&gt;Whether the object by reflected light&lt;br /&gt;Return thy radiance or absorb it quite :&lt;br /&gt;And tho&amp;rsquo; thou notest from thy safe recess&lt;br /&gt;Old Friends burn dim, like lamps in noisome air,&lt;br /&gt;Love them for what they are ; nor love them less,&lt;br /&gt;Because to thee they are not what they were.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Canzone III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But when I consider how she is the summit of worth, much do I love myself the more for having ever dared to desire her, for now do I know that my heart and my wit will make me to make to their whim a rich conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And since she is of such worth, do not think that my firm will can disperse itself or flow away or divide, for by that God who manifested himself in the dove, I am neither mine nor hers if I leave her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Arnaut Daniel (tr. Ezra Pound)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Frost, Tillich, O&#39;Hara, and Pound</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 01:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-frost-tillich-ohara-and-pound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Desert Places&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They cannot scare me with their empty spaces&lt;br /&gt;Between stars - on stars where no human race is.&lt;br /&gt;I have it in me so much nearer home&lt;br /&gt;To scare myself with my own desert places.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One cannot remove anxiety by arguing it away.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The affirmation of one&amp;rsquo;s essential being in spite of desires and anxieties creates joy.  Lucillus is exhorted by Seneca to make it his business &amp;ldquo;to learn how to feel joy.&amp;rdquo;  It is not the joy of fulfilled desires to which he refers, for real joy is a &amp;ldquo;severe matter&amp;rdquo;; it is the happiness of a soul which is &amp;ldquo;lifted above every circumstance.&amp;rdquo;  Joy accompanies the self-affirmation of our essential being in spite of the inhibitions coming from the accidental elements in us.  Joy is the emotional expression of the courageous Yes to one&amp;rsquo;s own true being.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Paul Tillich&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Courage to Be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the Harbormaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I wanted to be sure to reach you&lt;br /&gt;though my ship was on the way it got caught&lt;br /&gt;in some moorings. I am always tying up&lt;br /&gt;and then deciding to depart. In storms and&lt;br /&gt;at sunset, with the metallic coils of the tide&lt;br /&gt;around my fathomless arms, I am unable&lt;br /&gt;to understand the forms of my vanity&lt;br /&gt;or I am hard alee with my Polish rudder&lt;br /&gt;in my hand and the sun sinking. To&lt;br /&gt;you I offer my hull and the tattered cordage&lt;br /&gt;of my will. The terrible channels where&lt;br /&gt;the wind drives me against the brown lips&lt;br /&gt;of the reeds are not all behind me. Yet&lt;br /&gt;I trust the sanity of my vessel; and&lt;br /&gt;if it sinks it may well be in answer&lt;br /&gt;to the reasoning of the eternal voices,&lt;br /&gt;the waves which have kept me from reaching you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Frank O&amp;rsquo;Hara&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sceptical age hungers after the definite, after something it can pretend to believe.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;You read, as a child who has listened to ghost stories goes into a dark room; it is no accurate information about historical things that you seek, it is the thrill which mere reality would never satisfy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of literary criticism is largely the history of a vain struggle to find a terminology which will define something.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is dawn at Jerusalem while midnight hovers above the Pillars of Hercules.  All ages are contemporaneous.  The Middle Ages are in Russia.  The future stirs already in the minds of the few.  This is especially true of literature, where the real time is independent of the apparent, and where many dead men are our grandchildren&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries, while many of our contemporaries have been already gathered into Abraham&amp;rsquo;s bosom, or some more fitting receptacle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The history of an art is the history of masterwork, not of failures, or mediocrity.  The ominscient historian would display the masterpieces, their causes and their inter-relation.  The study of literature is hero-worship.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Good art never bores one.  By that I mean that it is the business of the artist to prevent ennui; in the literary art, to relieve, refresh, revive the mind of the reader - at reasonable intervals - with some form of ecstasy, by some splendor of thought, some presentation of sheer beauty, some lightning turn of phrase - laughter is no mean ecstasy.  Good art begins with an escape from dullness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ezra Pound&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Spirit of Romance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great lines from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-lines-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to think - seriously - with words like Classicism, Romanticism, Humanism, Realism. &amp;hellip;One does not get drunk nor does one quench one&amp;rsquo;s thirst with bottle labels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Paul Valery, quoted in C. Milosz, &lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beauty is momentary in the mind -&lt;br /&gt;The fitful tracing of a portal;&lt;br /&gt;But in the flesh it is immortal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Peter Quince at the Clavier&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At no moment during my work did I feel boredom; indeed, I was playing more than toiling, and several passages preserve, I hope, a trace of my smile.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The History of Polish Poetry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why should she give her bounty to the dead?&lt;br /&gt;What is divinity if it can come&lt;br /&gt;Only in silent shadows and in dreams?&lt;br /&gt;Shall she not find in comforts of the sun,&lt;br /&gt;In pungent fruit and bright, green wings, or else&lt;br /&gt;In any balm or beauty of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;Things to be cherished like the thought of heaven?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, in the isolation of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;At evening, casual flocks of pigeons make&lt;br /&gt;Ambiguous undulations as they sink,&lt;br /&gt;Downward to darkness, on extended wings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Sunday Morning&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I got away with half my heart - no more.&lt;br /&gt;Barely a trace of my old gaiety.&lt;br /&gt;The crowd like market cattle bore&lt;br /&gt;Me along. The world was loathsome to me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyprian Norwid&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Nerves&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With nothing can one approach a work of art so little as with critical words: they always come down to more or less happy misunderstandings.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This above all - ask yourself in the stillest hour of the night: &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; I write? Delve into yourself for a deep answer. And if this should be affirmative, if you may meet this question with a strong and simple &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I must&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;rdquo; then build your life according to this necessity; your life even into its most indifferent and slightest hour must be a sign of this urge and a testimony to it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Therefore save yourself from these general themes and seek those which your own everyday life offers you; describe your sorrows and desires, passing thoughts and the belief in some sort of beauty - describe all these with loving, quiet, humble sincerity, and use, to express yourself, the things in your environment, the images from your dreams, and the objects of your memory. If your daily life seems poor, do not blame it; blame yourself, tell yourself that you are not poet enough to call forth its riches; for to the creator there is no poverty and no poor indifferent place. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A work of art is good if it has sprung from necessity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Live a while in these books, learn from them what seems to you worth learning, but above all love them. This love will be repaid you a thousand and a thousand times, and however your life may turn, - it will, I am certain of it, run through the fabric of your growth as one of the most important threads among all the threads of your experiences, disappointments and joys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Letters to a Young Poet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2007 book recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2007-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following list includes the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year that I enjoyed the most and that had the biggest effect on me.  I give the highest recommendation to all of them, and I&amp;rsquo;ve bolded the top five.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Akhmatova, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Anna-Akhmatova/dp/0939010615/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804019&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Bonhoeffer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Letter-Papers-Prison-Dietrich-Bonhoeffer/dp/0684838273/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Letters and Papers From Prison&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Cumings, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Koreas-Place-Sun-History-Updated/dp/0393327027/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198804099&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Korea’s Place in the Sun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;de Bary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0231121393/ref=pd_cp_b_1?pf_rd_p=317711001&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=center-41&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0231086040&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=1FDVCJHA9ZCSZ7N3WY39&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Sources of Japanese Tradition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frye, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Imagination-Cbc-Massey-Lectures/dp/0887845983/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805497&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Educated Imagination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gilpin, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Change-World-Politics-Robert-Gilpin/dp/0521273765/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805537&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;War and Change in World Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pan-Knut-Hamsun/dp/1426422571/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Pan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Hamsun, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Soil-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0394717813/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198805602&amp;amp;sr=1-7&#34;&gt;Growth of the Soil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Victoria-Penguin-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0143039377/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198806948&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hardy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Selected-Poems-Penguin-Classics-Thomas/dp/0140436995/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807069&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Selected Poems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ienaga, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pacific-War-1931-1945-Saburo-Ienaga/dp/0394734963/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807106&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pacific War 1931-1945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Into-Wild-Jon-Krakauer/dp/0307387178/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807224&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;McCann, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Columbia-Anthology-Modern-Korean-Poetry/dp/0231111290/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198810919&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Columbia Anthology of Modern Korean Poetry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Petterson, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807402&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Out Stealing Horses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pieper, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;H&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hope-History-Josef-Pieper/dp/0898704650/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807583&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;ope and History&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rilke, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Duino-Elegies-Sonnets-Orpheus-Rainer/dp/0395250587/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807628&amp;amp;sr=1-8&#34;&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rowling, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Harry-Potter-Deathly-Hallows-Book/dp/0545010225/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807697&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/East-Eden-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142004235/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807783&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;East of Eden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pearl-Centennial-John-Steinbeck/dp/0142000698/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807841&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Pearl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinbeck, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Travels-Charley-Search-America-Steinbeck/dp/0140053204/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807914&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Walker, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prompt-Utter-Destruction-Truman-Against/dp/080785607X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1198807943&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Prompt and Utter Destruction: Truman and the Use of Atomic Bombs&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;If you are interested in checking out last year&amp;rsquo;s list of recommended books, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts: Jung, Rilke, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fact that an intellectual formula never has been and never will be devised which could embrace and express the manifest possibilities of life must lead to the inhibition or exclusion of other activities and ways of living that are just as important. &amp;hellip;Doubtless there are exceptional people who are able to sacrifice their entire life to a particular formula, but for most of us such exclusiveness is impossible in the long run. Sooner or later&amp;hellip;the potentialities repressed by the intellectual attitude will make themselves indirectly felt by disturbing the conscious conduct of life. &amp;hellip; The first function to be affected by the conscious inhibition is feeling, since it is the most opposed to the rigid intellectual formula and is therefore repressed the most intensely. No function can be entirely eliminated - it can only be greatly distorted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jung, &amp;ldquo;General Descriptions of the Types&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke, tr. Leishman &amp;amp; Spender:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;And before&lt;br /&gt;A single pain has got within range of your ever-&lt;br /&gt;galloping heart, comes the tingling&lt;br /&gt;in the soles of your feet, ahead of the spring that it wells from,&lt;br /&gt;chasing into your eyes a few physical tears.&lt;br /&gt;And, in spite of all, blindly,&lt;br /&gt;your smile&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Angel: suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a place we know nothing about, and there,&lt;br /&gt;on some indescribable carpet, lovers showed all that here&lt;br /&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re for ever unable to manage - their daring&lt;br /&gt;lofty figures of heart-flight,&lt;br /&gt;their towers of pleasure, their ladders,&lt;br /&gt;long since, where ground never was, just quiveringly&lt;br /&gt;propped by each other&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pillars, pylons, the Sphinx, all the striving thrust,&lt;br /&gt;grey, from fading or foreign town, of the spire!&lt;br /&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t all this a miracle? Angel, gaze, for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;-&lt;br /&gt;O mightiness, tell them that &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;were capable of it - my breath&amp;rsquo;s&lt;br /&gt;too short for this celebration. So, after all, we have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;failed to make use of the spaces, these generous spaces, these,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;our &lt;/em&gt;spaces. (How terribly big they must be,&lt;br /&gt;when, with thousands of years of our feeling, they&amp;rsquo;re not over-crowded.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Seventh Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The multitude of men and women choose the less adventurous way of the comparatively unconscious civic and tribal routines. But these seekers, too, are saved - by virtue of the inherited symbolic aids of society, the rites of passage, the grace-yielding sacraments, given to manking of old by the redeemers and handed down through milleniums. It is only those who know neither an inner call nor an outer doctrine whose plight truly is desperate: that is to say, most of us today, in this labyrinth without and within the heart.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Jung and Rilke</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man is not a machine that can be remodelled for quite other purposes as occasion demands, in the hope that it will go on functioning as regularly as before but in a quite different way. He carries his whole history with him; in his very structure is written the history of mankind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the extravert&amp;rsquo;s danger: he gets sucked into objects and completely loses himself in them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;C.G. Jung&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s not sat tense before his own heart&amp;rsquo;s curtain?&lt;br /&gt;Up it would go: the scenery was parting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Fourth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do you really suppose your gentle approach could have so&lt;br /&gt;convulsed him, you, that wander like morning-breezes?&lt;br /&gt;You terrified his heart, indeed; but more ancient terrors&lt;br /&gt;rushed into him in that instant of shattering contact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Third Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know why you so blissfully touch: because the caress persists,&lt;br /&gt;because it does not vanish, the place that you&lt;br /&gt;so tenderly cover; because you perceive thereupon&lt;br /&gt;pure duration.  Until your embraces almost&lt;br /&gt;promise eternity.  Yet, when you&amp;rsquo;ve once withstood&lt;br /&gt;the startled first encounter, the window-longing,&lt;br /&gt;and that first walk, just once, through the garden together:&lt;br /&gt;Lovers, are you the same?  When you lift yourselves&lt;br /&gt;up to each other&amp;rsquo;s lips - drink unto drink:&lt;br /&gt;oh, how strangely the drinker eludes his part!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Were not love and farewell&lt;br /&gt;so lightly laid upon shoulders, they seemed to be made&lt;br /&gt;of other stuff than with us?  Remember the hands,&lt;br /&gt;how they rest without pressure, though power is there in the torsos.&lt;br /&gt;The wisdom of those self-masters was this: we have got so far;&lt;br /&gt;ours is to touch one another like this; the gods&lt;br /&gt;may press more strongly upon us.  But that is the gods&amp;rsquo; affair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Second Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Meredith, Apollinaire, and Delors</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-meredith-apollinaire-and-delors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-meredith-apollinaire-and-delors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Fables about Error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is as wrong as the uninstructed heart?&lt;br /&gt;Left to its ends, it clutches things and creatures&lt;br /&gt;That can&amp;rsquo;t be held, or held, will slip their natures;&lt;br /&gt;It lives to hoard or to protect a hoard.&lt;br /&gt;To school, to school! Teach the poor organ skill&lt;br /&gt;That all its ignorant, nervous will&lt;br /&gt;Does not unpage us like old calendars.&lt;br /&gt;A life should be all gathering and art.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let there be academies of everything,&lt;br /&gt;That the trap in the warm kitchen yield to guile,&lt;br /&gt;That grackles leave a fire single file&lt;br /&gt;And swallows find their true halves the first spring.&lt;br /&gt;The mind should be, like art, a gathering&lt;br /&gt;Where the red heart that fumes in the chest&lt;br /&gt;Saying &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;kill, kill, kill&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;love, love, love,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Gentled of the need to be possessed,&lt;br /&gt;Can study a little the things that it dreams of.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;William Meredith&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a need for urgency, for history does not wait.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jacques Delors, &amp;ldquo;A Necessary Union&amp;rdquo; (in Nelsen &amp;amp; Stubb, eds., &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The European Union: Readings on the Theory and Practice of European Integration&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Rhenish Night&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My glass is filled with a wine that trembles like flame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Guillaume Apollinaire (tr. William Meredith)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More poems &amp; lines by William Meredith</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-poems--lines-by-william-meredith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 02:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-poems--lines-by-william-meredith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Aversions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In all respects unready for a fall&lt;br /&gt;They fell, our first progenitors, and these&lt;br /&gt;Two traumas still disturb us most of all:&lt;br /&gt;High places and our own unreadiness.&lt;br /&gt;Towers or wells unfoot us in our dreams&lt;br /&gt;Repeatedly. Old-fashioned people still&lt;br /&gt;Believe that nothing saves them but their screams&lt;br /&gt;And that an unawakened fall would kill.&lt;br /&gt;Anticipation cannot really ease&lt;br /&gt;The other trouble; waiting for the day&lt;br /&gt;When such and such will happen or will pass,&lt;br /&gt;It is not hard to wish your life away.&lt;br /&gt;Apart from angels, winged and prevised,&lt;br /&gt;Nobody likes to fall or be surprised.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Starlight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going abruptly into a starry night&lt;br /&gt;It is ignorance we blink from, dark, unhoused;&lt;br /&gt;There is a gaze of animal delight&lt;br /&gt;Before the human vision. Then, aroused&lt;br /&gt;To nebulous danger, we may look for east stars,&lt;br /&gt;Orion and the Dipper; but they are not ours,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These learned fields. Dark and ignorant,&lt;br /&gt;Unable to see what our forebears saw,&lt;br /&gt;We keep some fear of random firmament&lt;br /&gt;Vestigal in us. And we think, Ah,&lt;br /&gt;If I had lived then, when these stories were made up, I&lt;br /&gt;Could have found more likely pictures in haphazard sky.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sonnet on Rare Animals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have alarmed on your behalf and others&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;Sauntering things galore.&lt;br /&gt;It is this way with verse and animals&lt;br /&gt;And love, that when you point you lose them all.&lt;br /&gt;Startled or on a signal, what is rare&lt;br /&gt;Is off before you have it anywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Orpheus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The mind turns from causes in such cases -&lt;br /&gt;All a man can say is, it happened.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
