<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vouchers on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/vouchers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vouchers on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/vouchers/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael McConnell on multiculturalism and educational choice</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/michael-mcconnell-on-multiculturalism-and-educational-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/michael-mcconnell-on-multiculturalism-and-educational-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite insistent demands by minority groups, principally Catholics, but including Jews, Presbyterians, Baptists, and Methodists, for equal funding for their free schools, the common school movement soon achieved a monopoly of public funding.  Many states even adopted constitutional provisions barring state funding of religious schools, and a federal constitutional amendment to that effect was narrowly defeated in Congress.  The opposition to particularistic private schools grew to the extent that, in the early twentieth century, some states passed laws forbidding the education of children in languages other than English and banning private schools altogether.  These efforts were promptly overturned by the Supreme Court, on the ground that &amp;ldquo;[t]he fundamental theory of liberty upon which all governments in this union repose excludes any general power of the state to standardize its children by forcing them to accept instruction from public teachers only.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;Pierce v. Society of Sisters&lt;/em&gt;, 1925)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The leading elementary and secondary school textbooks virtually neglect any mention of religious influences or ideas in history, ethics, or social studies.  Thus, the &amp;ldquo;public values&amp;rdquo; inculcated by the public schools are not, in fact, the values held by the large majority of the American public, but the values held by a secular minority.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is not possible, practically or theoretically, for public schools to be &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; with respect to contentious questions of morality, politics, and religion.  The more the school attempts to be evenhanded, the more it will appear to endorse a position of relativism, or worse, cynicism.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;No shifts in constitutional doctrine governing the conduct of the public schools can solve this problem, because it inheres in the nature of things.  The Supreme Court can alter the character of public education, making it more religious or more secular, but it cannot make public education genuinely more pluralistic.  A common school is a common school.  That is its blessing and its curse.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While fears of church-state constitutional problems are often cited by opponents of educational choice, those fears are groundless.  Whatever may be the flaws in the educational choice idea, it should be debated on its merits and not rejected on spurious constitutional grounds.  In fact, far from offending the First Amendment, an educational choice plan is much more consistent with the pluralistic vision of the First Amendment than is granting secular schools a monopoly of public funds.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The common school movement now teaches our children, unintentionally, to be value-less, culture-less, root-less, and religion-less.  It can no longer achieve its crowning purpose of providing a unifying moral culture in the face of our many differences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_W._McConnell&#34;&gt;Michael W. McConnell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Multiculturalism, Majoritarianism, and Educational Choice: What Does Our Constitutional Tradition Have to Say?,&amp;rdquo; University of Chicago Legal Forum 1991.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Alfie Kohn and Virginia Woolf</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons policymakers seek to impose detailed curriculum mandates.  They may fundamentally distrust educators: Much of the current standards movement is just the latest episdoe in a long, sorry history of trying to create a teacher-proof curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;These days almost anything can be done to students and to schools, no matter how ill-considered, as long as it is done in the name of raising standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s convenient for us to assume that kids who cut corners are just being lazy, because then it&amp;rsquo;s the kids who have to be fixed.  But perhaps they&amp;rsquo;re just being rational.  They have adapted to an environment where results, not intellectual exploration, are what count.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Assessment is used less to support learning than to evaluate and compare people.  &amp;hellip;(Standardized testing) screens and sorts students for the convenience of industry (and higher education).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What happens to schools when they are plunged into the marketplace?  To begin with, they must shift much of their time and resources to, well, marketing.  (It is those who sell themselves skillfully, not those who are especially good at what they do, who tend to succeed in a competitive market.)  Moreover, the pressure to make themselves look better presents a temptation to screen out less desirable students, those whose education takes more effort or expense.  &amp;ldquo;The problem with public schools,&amp;rdquo; remarked author John Chubb, &amp;ldquo;is that they must take whoever walks in the door.&amp;rdquo;  The philosophical core of the privatization movement for which Chubb speaks is neatly revealed in the use of the word &lt;em&gt;problem &lt;/em&gt;in that sentence.  &lt;em&gt;[Note: I disagree with this statement, but it is the among the best anti-voucher arguments I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alfie Kohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Essays-Standards-Grading-Follies/dp/0807032670&#34;&gt;What Does it Mean to Be Well Educated?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Highly recommended.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And, thanking Mr. Ramsay for it and Mrs. Ramsay for it and the hour and the place, crediting the world with a power which she had not suspected - that one could walk away down that long gallery not alone any more but arm in arm with somebody - the strangest feeling in the world, and the most exhilarating&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Here she saddened, darkened, and came back to her chair, there could be no disputing this: an unmarried woman (she lightly took her hand for a moment), an unmarried woman has missed the best of life.  The house seemed full of children sleeping and Mrs. Ramsay listening; shaded lights and regular breathing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;How strangely he was venerable and laughable at one and the same time.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;She bore about with her, she could not help knowing it, the torch of her beauty; she carried it erect into any room that she entered; and after all, veil it as she might, and shrink from the monotony of bearing that it imposed on her, her beauty was apparent.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The very stone one kicks with one&amp;rsquo;s boot will outlast Shakespeare.  His own little light would shine, not very brightly, for a year or two, and would then be merged in some bigger light, and that in a bigger still.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All at once he realised that it was this: it was this: - she was the most beautiful person he had ever seen.  &amp;hellip;For the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; a man digging in a drain stopped digging and looked at her, let his arm fall down and looked at her; for the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; felt the wind and the cyclamen and the violets for he was walking with a beautiful woman.  He had hold of her bag.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Virginia Woolf&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;To the Lighthouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four quotes from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/four-quotes-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 23:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/four-quotes-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tell me one last thing,&amp;rdquo; said Harry. &amp;ldquo;Is this real? Or has this been happening inside my head?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Of course it is happening inside your head, Harry, but why on earth should that mean that it is not real?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-J.K. Rowling, &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Secular nationalism of the sort Fatah stood for is coming to look like the weak force and radical Islam like the strong force. This poses a huge danger to a region already beset by violent conflicts. What is worse, Western policy is in danger of strengthening the wrong side by making the Islamists look like martyrs and the secularists like traitors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;ldquo;Martyrs or Traitors,&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;The Economist&lt;/em&gt;, June 21st 2007&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This competition for students would force public schools to become better.  The system of higher education in the U.S. is the world&amp;rsquo;s best mainly because competition between private colleges and tuition-charging public colleges has improved the performance of both.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Gary Becker, &amp;ldquo;School-Finance Reform: Don&amp;rsquo;t Give Up on Vouchers,&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;The Economics of Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But if you will just change your ways immediately, then everyone will have peace.  Although this has been going on since time immemorial, today we could make a special effort to be good, and say this is not to be done!  I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can say so, brother.  The other day when the tenant wanted the rent reduced, you said it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Lu Hsun, &amp;ldquo;A Madman&amp;rsquo;s Diary&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
