<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>America on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/america/</link>
    <description>Recent content in America on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 23:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/america/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from the stories of John Cheever</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s1600-h/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5391933763386061634&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s400/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 307px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 400px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was after four then, and I lay in the dark, listening to the rain and to the morning trains coming through.  They come from Buffalo and Chicago and the Far West, through Albany and down along the river in the early morning, and at one time or another I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled on most of them, and I lay in the dark thinking about the polar air in the Pullman cars and the smell of nightclothes and the taste of dining-car water and the way it feels to end a day in Cleveland or Chicago and begin another in New York, particularly after you&amp;rsquo;ve been away for a couple of years, and particularly in the summer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I took the eight-ten train into town in the morning and returned on the six-thirty.  I knew enough to avoid the empty house in the summer dusk, and I drove directly from the station parking lot to a good restaurant called Orpheo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Cure&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.  It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful color.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Chaste Clarissa&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt that he was a captive of financial and sentimental commitments, like every other man I know, and that he was no more free to fall in love with a strange woman he saw on a street corner than he was to take a walking trip through French Guiana or to recommence his life in Chicago under an assumed name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is divorce so dreadful and of all the things that hold a marriage together how many of them are good?&amp;rdquo; She sat down at the table.  &amp;ldquo;In Grenoble,&amp;rdquo; she said, &amp;ldquo;I wrote a long paper on Charles Stuart in French.  A professor at the University of Chicago wrote me a letter.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t read a French newspaper without a dictionary today, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to follow any newspaper, and I am ashamed of my incompetence, ashamed of the way I look.  Oh, I guess I love you, I do love the children, but I love myself, I love my life, it has some value and some promise for me and Trencher&amp;rsquo;s roses make me feel that I&amp;rsquo;m losing this, that I&amp;rsquo;m losing my self-respect.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Walking down Lexington Avenue, we heard the drone bass of a church organ sound from the sky, and we and the others on the sidewalk looked up in piety and bewilderment, like a devout and stupid congregation, and saw a formation of heavy bombers heading for the sea.  As it got late, it got cold and clear and still, and on the stillness the waste from the smokestacks along the East River seemed to articulate, as legibly as the Pepsi-Cola plane, whole words and sentences.  Halcyon.  Disaster.  They were hard to make out.  It seemed the ebb of the year - an evil day for gastritis, sinus, and respiratory disease - and remembering other winters, the markings of the light convinced me that it was the season of divorce.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I think that the seriousness of the day affected the children, and when they returned to the house, they were quiet.  The seriousness of it kept coming to me with the feeling that this change, like a phenomenon of speed, was affecting our watches as well as our hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Now when I come home in the evenings, Ethel is still sitting on the stool by the sink cleaning vegetables.  I go with her into the children&amp;rsquo;s room.  The light there is bright.  The children have built something out an orange crate, something preposterous and ascendant, and their sweetness, their compulsion to build, the brightness of the light are reflected perfectly and increased in Ethel&amp;rsquo;s face.  Then she feeds them, bathes them, and sets the table, and stands for a moment in the middle of the room, trying to make some connection between the evening and the day.  Then it is over.  She lights the four candles, and we sit down to our supper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Season of Divorce&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true of even the best of us that if an observer can catch us boarding a train at a way station; if he will mark our faces, stripped by anxiety of their self-possession; if he will appraise our luggage, our clothing, and look out of the window to see who has driven us to the station; if he will listen to the harsh or tender things we say if we are with our families, or notice the way we put our suitcase onto the rack, check the position of our wallet, our key ring, and wipe the sweat off the back of our necks; if he can judge sensibly the self-importance, diffidence, or sadness with which we settle ourselves, he will be given a broader view of our lives than most of us would intend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Summer Farmer&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Bishop, Hayden, Olson, and Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-bishop-hayden-olson-and-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Man-Moth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He thinks the moon is a small hole at the top of the sky,&lt;br /&gt;proving the sky quite useless for protection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Mourning Poem for the Queen of Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh who and oh who will sing Jesus down&lt;br /&gt;to help with struggling and doing without and being colored&lt;br /&gt;all through blue Monday?&lt;br /&gt;Till way next Sunday?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Hayden&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Questions of Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Should we have stayed at home,&lt;br /&gt;wherever that may be?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Elizabeth Bishop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Maximus, to Himself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is undone business&lt;br /&gt;I speak of, this morning,&lt;br /&gt;with the sea&lt;br /&gt;stretching out&lt;br /&gt;from my feet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Charles Olson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Again: as the profound calm which only apparently precedes and prophesies of the storm, is perhaps more awful than the storm itself; for, indeed, the calm is but the wrapper and envelope of the storm; and contains it in itself, as the seemingly harmless rifle holds the fatal powder, and the ball, and the explosion; so the graceful repose of the line, as it silently serpentines about the oarsmen before being brought into actual play - this is a thing which carries more of true terror than any other aspect of this dangerous affair. But why say more? All men live enveloped in whale-lines. All are born with halters round their necks; but it is only when caught in the swift, sudden turn of death, that mortals realize the silent, subtle, ever-present perils of life. And if you be a philosopher, though seated in the whale-boat, you would not at heart feel one whit more of terror, than though seated before your evening fire with a poker, and not a harpoon, by your side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Melville&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Poems excerpted from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Norton-Anthology-Modern-Contemporary-Poetry/dp/039332429X&#34;&gt;The Norton Anthology of Modern and Contemporary Poetry&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Czeslaw Milosz&#39;s &#39;Milosz&#39;s ABC&#39;s&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-czeslaw-miloszs-miloszs-abcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s1600-h/Milosz.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Sj1Qj1Ofc5I/AAAAAAAAAw4/_2DIpjTUnhY/s400/Milosz.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5349520508899521426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made it, but I have always tried to remember that I owe it to my lucky star, not to myself, and that right next door are entire neighborhoods of unfortunates.  I will say even more: the thought of their grueling labor and unfulfilled hope, of the gigantic prison system in which the unneeded are kept, taught me to look skeptically at (America&amp;rsquo;s) decorations - those well-kept houses amidst the suburbs&amp;rsquo; greenery.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In our deepest convictions, reaching into the very depths of our being, we deserve to live forever.  We experience our transitoriness and mortality as an act of violence perpetrated against us.  Only Paradise is authentic; the world is inauthentic, and only temporary.  That is why the story of the Fall speaks to us so emotionally, as if summoning an old truth from our slumbering memory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;People go to church because they are divided beings.  They wish, for a moment at least, to find themselves in a reality other than the one that surrounds them and claims to be the only true reality.  This daily reality is unyielding, brutal, cruel, and hard to bear.  The human &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; is soft in the center and feels every moment that its adaptation to the world is doubtful.  &amp;hellip;Participating in the Mass we once again deny a world without meaning and without mercy; we enter into a dimension where what matters are goodness, love, and forgiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If to participate in the Mass it were necessary to have a strong faith and a consciousness that we act in life as our religion requires us to, all the churchgoing faithful would deserve to be called hypocrites and Pharisees.  In truth, however, strong faith is a rare gift, and as for acts, the liturgy reminds us that we are all sinners.  Attending church is not, therefore, for the elect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The needs of the individual determine church attendance, and knowledge of the catechism or even familiarity with the so-called truths of the faith are not the most important matters, although they are advisable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Czeslaw Milosz&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Miloszs-ABCs-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374527954&#34;&gt;Milosz&amp;rsquo;s ABC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from C. Taylor, J.T. Johnson, and the US Catholic Bishops</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Faith does not insulate us from the challenges of life; rather, it intensifies our desire to help solve them&amp;hellip;.  From the resources of our faith we wish to provide hope and strength to all who seek a world free of the nuclear threat.  Hope sustains one&amp;rsquo;s capacity to live with danger without being overwhelmed by it; hope is the will to struggle against obstacles even when they appear insuperable.  Ultimately our hope rests in the God who gave us life, sustains the world by his power and has called us to revere the lives of every person and all peoples.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As Americans, citizens of the nation which was first to produce atomic weapons, which has been the only one to use them and which today is one of the handful of nations capable of decisively influencing the course of the nuclear age, we have grave human, moral, and political responsibilities to see that a &amp;ldquo;conscious choice&amp;rdquo; is made to save humanity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;United States Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response - The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The definition of combatancy and noncombatancy follows from direct involvement in prosecuting the war, not from one&amp;rsquo;s citizenship or one&amp;rsquo;s personal preference among the belligerents.  It is action that matters, not attitude.  For this reason, I regard the use of the term &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; in the Protocols to the Geneva Conventions as misleading: it is not civilian status that matters, as irregular soldiers may technically be civilians; what matters is whether people are engaged in combatant activity or not.  The relevant moral term is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;noncombatant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, even though the language of the protocols uses &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, and this usage has seeped into the moral debate at times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James Turner Johnson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The War to Oust Saddam Hussein: Just War and the New Face of Conflict&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;In the following chapters, I will be making a continuing polemic against what I call &amp;ldquo;subtraction stories.&amp;rdquo;  Concisely put, I mean by this stories of modernity in general, and secularity in particular, which explain them by human beings having lost, or sloughed off, or liberated themselves from certain earlier, confining horizons, or illusions, or limitations of knowledge.  What emerges from this process - modernity or secularity - is to be understood in terms of underlying features of human nature which were there all along, but had been impeded by what is now set aside.  Against this kind of story, I will steadily be arguing that Western modernity, including its secularity, is the fruit of new inventions, newly constructed self-understandings and related practices, and can&amp;rsquo;t be explained in terms of perennial features of human life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;True North&#39; and &#39;Returning to Earth&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/jim-harrisons-true-north-and-returning-to-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/jim-harrisons-true-north-and-returning-to-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made plenty of discoveries this year - a love for banjo and bluegrass, a greater appreciation for the outdoors and concern for the environment, a new appreciation for the upper Midwest, the desire (if not yet the discipline) to live more simply and learn to cook - but one of the best recent discoveries I&amp;rsquo;ve made is the fiction of Jim Harrison.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished his &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=wW5CXWQNt6IC&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - a novel about a very physically-oriented man who comes down with Lou Gehrig&amp;rsquo;s disease in his early 40s - and I cannot recommend it enough.  It is a sequel of sorts to Harrison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=pAVWwx2g9CAC&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and these two books are the first I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year to make my list of fiction favorites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVs4Z9CtTI/AAAAAAAAAgU/UxfZ_-ewCW8/s1600-h/returning+to+earth.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVs4Z9CtTI/AAAAAAAAAgU/UxfZ_-ewCW8/s200/returning+to+earth.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227856320312626&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsxC9H-lI/AAAAAAAAAgM/JxugjoVWP-A/s1600-h/truenorth.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsxC9H-lI/AAAAAAAAAgM/JxugjoVWP-A/s200/truenorth.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227729887558226&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsqCXCI3I/AAAAAAAAAgE/15eFmT9sDZk/s1600-h/jimharrison.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SPVsqCXCI3I/AAAAAAAAAgE/15eFmT9sDZk/s320/jimharrison.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34;id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5257227609468707698&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following links are also worth checking out:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/01/25/books/25harr.html&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Jim Harrison: &amp;ldquo;Pleasures of the Hard-Worn Life&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Harrison&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article &lt;/a&gt;on Jim Harrison&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/11/books/review/Blythe.t.html?_r=1&amp;pagewanted=2&amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/em&gt; (warning: gives a lot away).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on certainty, racism, and foreign policy</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-certainty-racism-and-foreign-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Today&amp;rsquo;s Maroon &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;column&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Certainty is a luxury none of us has.&amp;rdquo;  Religious fundamentalists and secular fundamentalists are all-too-alike in their belief that they, and only they, have answers to the biggest questions in the human dialogue.  What unites us all is doubt and searching.  Read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://maroon.uchicago.edu/online_edition/viewpoints/2007/10/16/certainty-is-a-luxury-none-of-us-has/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Must-read: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/10/16/principal-of-citys-arabic-school-says-she-was-forced-out/index.html?ex=1350273600&amp;amp;en=5fc98d5704a026df&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;Principal of Arabic School Says She was Forced Out&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  This is what racist, nativist hysteria looks like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-From an Economist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/displayStory.cfm?story_id=9973918&amp;amp;fsrc=RSS&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the new Fox Business Channel: &lt;em&gt;Mr Murdoch apparently wants his channel to be more “pro-capitalism” than CNBC—which is hardly a pinko outfit—and, sure enough, there was soon a discussion about the pharmaceutical industry entitled &amp;ldquo;Capitalism cures cancer&amp;rdquo;, which—let’s be “fair and balanced”, as the Fox News slogan puts it—it does&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-MIT international relations scholar Barry Posen on &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the-american-interest.com/ai2/article.cfm?Id=331&amp;amp;MId=16&#34;&gt;the case for restraint&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in U.S. foreign policy.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t read this yet, but I generally like what Posen has to say.  Responses from Francis Fukuyama, Stephen Krasner, G. John Ikenberry, and others are also online.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Thomas Merton and John Steinbeck</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living is more than submission: it is creation.  To live is to create one&amp;rsquo;s own world as a scene of personal happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Celebration is the beginning of confidence, therefore of power.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next passage in my journey is a love affair.  I am in love with Montana.  For other states I have admiration, respect, recognition, even some affection, but with Montana it is love, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to analyze love when you&amp;rsquo;re in it.  &amp;hellip; It seems to me that Montana is a great splash of grandeur.  The scale is huge but not overpowering.  The land is rich with grass and color, and the mountains are the kind I would create if mountains were ever put on my agenda.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The calm of the mountains and the rolling grasslands had got into the inhabitants.  It was hunting season when I drove through the state.  The men I talked to seemed to me not moved to a riot of seasonal slaughter but simply to be going out to kill edible meat.  Again my attitude may be informed by love, but it seemed to me that the towns were places to live in rather than nervous hives.  People had time to pause in their occupations to undertake the passing art of neighborliness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When we live superficially, when we are always outside ourselves, never quite &amp;ldquo;with&amp;rdquo; ourselves, always divided and pulled in many directions by conflicting plans and projects, we find ourselves doing many things that we do not really want to do, saying things we do not really mean, needing things we do not really need, exhausting ourselves for what we secretly realize to be worthless and without meaning in our lives: &amp;ldquo;Why spend your money on what is not food and your earnings on what never satisfies?&amp;rdquo; (Isaiah 55:2)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having a companion fixes you in time and that the present, but when the quality of aloneness settles down, past, present, and future all flow together.  A memory, a present event, and a forecast all equally present.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the long run, the discipline of creative silence demands a certain kind of faith.  For when we come face to face with ourselves in the lonely ground of our own being, we confront many questions about the value of our existence, the reality of our commitments, the authenticity of our everyday lives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
