<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C.g. Jung on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/c.g.-jung/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C.g. Jung on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/c.g.-jung/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts: Jung, Rilke, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fact that an intellectual formula never has been and never will be devised which could embrace and express the manifest possibilities of life must lead to the inhibition or exclusion of other activities and ways of living that are just as important. &amp;hellip;Doubtless there are exceptional people who are able to sacrifice their entire life to a particular formula, but for most of us such exclusiveness is impossible in the long run. Sooner or later&amp;hellip;the potentialities repressed by the intellectual attitude will make themselves indirectly felt by disturbing the conscious conduct of life. &amp;hellip; The first function to be affected by the conscious inhibition is feeling, since it is the most opposed to the rigid intellectual formula and is therefore repressed the most intensely. No function can be entirely eliminated - it can only be greatly distorted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jung, &amp;ldquo;General Descriptions of the Types&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke, tr. Leishman &amp;amp; Spender:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;And before&lt;br /&gt;A single pain has got within range of your ever-&lt;br /&gt;galloping heart, comes the tingling&lt;br /&gt;in the soles of your feet, ahead of the spring that it wells from,&lt;br /&gt;chasing into your eyes a few physical tears.&lt;br /&gt;And, in spite of all, blindly,&lt;br /&gt;your smile&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Angel: suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a place we know nothing about, and there,&lt;br /&gt;on some indescribable carpet, lovers showed all that here&lt;br /&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re for ever unable to manage - their daring&lt;br /&gt;lofty figures of heart-flight,&lt;br /&gt;their towers of pleasure, their ladders,&lt;br /&gt;long since, where ground never was, just quiveringly&lt;br /&gt;propped by each other&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pillars, pylons, the Sphinx, all the striving thrust,&lt;br /&gt;grey, from fading or foreign town, of the spire!&lt;br /&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t all this a miracle? Angel, gaze, for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;-&lt;br /&gt;O mightiness, tell them that &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;were capable of it - my breath&amp;rsquo;s&lt;br /&gt;too short for this celebration. So, after all, we have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;failed to make use of the spaces, these generous spaces, these,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;our &lt;/em&gt;spaces. (How terribly big they must be,&lt;br /&gt;when, with thousands of years of our feeling, they&amp;rsquo;re not over-crowded.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Seventh Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The multitude of men and women choose the less adventurous way of the comparatively unconscious civic and tribal routines. But these seekers, too, are saved - by virtue of the inherited symbolic aids of society, the rites of passage, the grace-yielding sacraments, given to manking of old by the redeemers and handed down through milleniums. It is only those who know neither an inner call nor an outer doctrine whose plight truly is desperate: that is to say, most of us today, in this labyrinth without and within the heart.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Jung and Rilke</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man is not a machine that can be remodelled for quite other purposes as occasion demands, in the hope that it will go on functioning as regularly as before but in a quite different way. He carries his whole history with him; in his very structure is written the history of mankind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the extravert&amp;rsquo;s danger: he gets sucked into objects and completely loses himself in them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;C.G. Jung&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s not sat tense before his own heart&amp;rsquo;s curtain?&lt;br /&gt;Up it would go: the scenery was parting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Fourth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do you really suppose your gentle approach could have so&lt;br /&gt;convulsed him, you, that wander like morning-breezes?&lt;br /&gt;You terrified his heart, indeed; but more ancient terrors&lt;br /&gt;rushed into him in that instant of shattering contact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Third Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know why you so blissfully touch: because the caress persists,&lt;br /&gt;because it does not vanish, the place that you&lt;br /&gt;so tenderly cover; because you perceive thereupon&lt;br /&gt;pure duration.  Until your embraces almost&lt;br /&gt;promise eternity.  Yet, when you&amp;rsquo;ve once withstood&lt;br /&gt;the startled first encounter, the window-longing,&lt;br /&gt;and that first walk, just once, through the garden together:&lt;br /&gt;Lovers, are you the same?  When you lift yourselves&lt;br /&gt;up to each other&amp;rsquo;s lips - drink unto drink:&lt;br /&gt;oh, how strangely the drinker eludes his part!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Were not love and farewell&lt;br /&gt;so lightly laid upon shoulders, they seemed to be made&lt;br /&gt;of other stuff than with us?  Remember the hands,&lt;br /&gt;how they rest without pressure, though power is there in the torsos.&lt;br /&gt;The wisdom of those self-masters was this: we have got so far;&lt;br /&gt;ours is to touch one another like this; the gods&lt;br /&gt;may press more strongly upon us.  But that is the gods&amp;rsquo; affair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Second Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
