<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>William Meredith on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/william-meredith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in William Meredith on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 01:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/william-meredith/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from James, Meredith, Campbell, and Jung</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-james-meredith-campbell-and-jung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-james-meredith-campbell-and-jung/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;His lack of all thought by which to weigh the danger against the attractiveness of the bait, and of all volition to remain hungry a little while longer, is the direct measure of his lowness in the mental scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But whether small or great, and no matter what the stage or grade of life, the call (to adventure) rings up the curtain, always, on a mystery of transfiguration - a rite, or moment, of spiritual passage, which, when complete, amounts to a dying and a birth.  The familiar life horizon has been outgrown; the old concepts, ideals, and emotional patterns no longer fit; the time for the passing of a threshold is at hand.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Refusal of the summons converts the adventure into its negative.  Walled in boredom, hard work, or &amp;ldquo;culture,&amp;rdquo; the subject loses the power of significant affirmative action and becomes a victim to be saved.  His flowering world becomes a wasteland of dry stones and his life feels meaningless&amp;hellip;.  Whatever house he builds, it will be a house of death: a labyrinth of cyclopean walls to hide from him his Minotaur.  &amp;hellip;The myths and folk tales of the whole world make clear that the refusal is essentially a refusal to give up what one takes to be one&amp;rsquo;s own interest.  The future is regarded not in terms of an unremitting series of deaths and births, but as though one&amp;rsquo;s present system of ideals, virtues, goals, and advantages were to be fixed and made secure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romeo wants Juliet as the filings want the magnet; and if no obstacles intervene he moves toward her by as straight a line as they.  But Romeo and Juliet, if a wall be built between them, do not remain idiotically pressing their faces against its opposite sides like the magnet and the filings with the card.  Romeo soon finds a circuitous way, by scaling the wall or otherwise, of touching Juliet&amp;rsquo;s lips directly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(The introvert&amp;rsquo;s) ideal is a lonely island where nothing moves except what he permits to move.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Carl Jung&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In all ages the man whose determinations are swayed by reference to the most distant ends has been held to possess the highest intelligence.  The tramp who lives from hour to hour; the bohemian whose engagements are from day to day; the bachelor who builds but for a single life; the father who acts for another generation; the patriot who thinks of a whole community and many generations; and finally, the philosopher and saint whose cares are for humanity and for eternity, - these range themselves in an unbroken hierarchy&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I read, I love&lt;br /&gt;I eat, I drink&lt;br /&gt;I watch the world tilt&lt;br /&gt;I watch the children think:&lt;br /&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s so much to it&lt;br /&gt;and most of it good&lt;br /&gt;that while I&amp;rsquo;ve tendons&lt;br /&gt;to lift my head,&lt;br /&gt;like a rooster drinking&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll nod to God&lt;br /&gt;and save despair&lt;br /&gt;for when I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William Meredith&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Preponderance&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More poems &amp; lines by William Meredith</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-poems--lines-by-william-meredith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 02:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/more-poems--lines-by-william-meredith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Aversions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In all respects unready for a fall&lt;br /&gt;They fell, our first progenitors, and these&lt;br /&gt;Two traumas still disturb us most of all:&lt;br /&gt;High places and our own unreadiness.&lt;br /&gt;Towers or wells unfoot us in our dreams&lt;br /&gt;Repeatedly. Old-fashioned people still&lt;br /&gt;Believe that nothing saves them but their screams&lt;br /&gt;And that an unawakened fall would kill.&lt;br /&gt;Anticipation cannot really ease&lt;br /&gt;The other trouble; waiting for the day&lt;br /&gt;When such and such will happen or will pass,&lt;br /&gt;It is not hard to wish your life away.&lt;br /&gt;Apart from angels, winged and prevised,&lt;br /&gt;Nobody likes to fall or be surprised.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Starlight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going abruptly into a starry night&lt;br /&gt;It is ignorance we blink from, dark, unhoused;&lt;br /&gt;There is a gaze of animal delight&lt;br /&gt;Before the human vision. Then, aroused&lt;br /&gt;To nebulous danger, we may look for east stars,&lt;br /&gt;Orion and the Dipper; but they are not ours,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These learned fields. Dark and ignorant,&lt;br /&gt;Unable to see what our forebears saw,&lt;br /&gt;We keep some fear of random firmament&lt;br /&gt;Vestigal in us. And we think, Ah,&lt;br /&gt;If I had lived then, when these stories were made up, I&lt;br /&gt;Could have found more likely pictures in haphazard sky.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sonnet on Rare Animals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have alarmed on your behalf and others&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;Sauntering things galore.&lt;br /&gt;It is this way with verse and animals&lt;br /&gt;And love, that when you point you lose them all.&lt;br /&gt;Startled or on a signal, what is rare&lt;br /&gt;Is off before you have it anywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Orpheus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The mind turns from causes in such cases -&lt;br /&gt;All a man can say is, it happened.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
