<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Judaism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/judaism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Judaism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/judaism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Solomon&#39;s &#39;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s1600-h/judaism.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5394862253055997906&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s400/judaism.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 215px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 200px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin Buber and Emanuel Levinas put their faith in the God of relationships.  &lt;em&gt;Alles Leben ist Begegnung&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;all life is encounter&amp;rsquo;), declared Buber, and the important thing is to get your relationship with God and with people right (I-Thou, rather than I-It); from that relationship, which is the essence of Revelation, ethical action flows; laws and rules are feeble attempts to capture revelation, and doomed to inadequacy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Genesis 1:27 states clearly enough: &amp;lsquo;So God created humankind in his own image; in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&amp;rsquo; This implies that in using our concept of God to model human behavior we should not distinguish between male and female.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Emil Fackenheim grounds his theology in the actual resistance of Shoah [Holocaust] victims to whom no realistic hope remained: &amp;lsquo;A philosophical Tikkun [&amp;lsquo;repair&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restoration&amp;rsquo;] is possible after the Holocaust because a philosophical Tikkun already took place, however fragmentarily, during the Holocaust itself&amp;rsquo;; the rebirth of Israel, and a new constructive dialogue with a self-critical Christianity, are essential to this process.  Fackenheim is also noted for his statement that there should be a 614th commandment, surplus to the 613 of tradition - to survive as Jews, to remember, never to despair of God, lest we hand Hitler a posthumous victory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Is there such a thing as a &amp;lsquo;just war&amp;rsquo;, and if so, what are the conditions of engagement?  Out of this debate emerged the novel concept of &lt;em&gt;tohar ha-nesheq&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;purity of arms&amp;rsquo;), which demands &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt; that the fighting force take special risks to avoid harm to non-combatants and to minimize enemy casualties.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Many Jews, including secular ones, see Israel as the fulfilment of the &amp;lsquo;national&amp;rsquo; aspirations of the Jewish people; after thousands of years of minority status, of being alienated from the host societies, and in many  cases actually prevented from becoming full citizens of the lands in which they lived, they feel that they have at last &amp;lsquo;come home&amp;rsquo; and are able to control their own destiny within the normal limitations of independent statehood.  Israel is perceived as a secure haven for persecuted Jews; had Israel existed during the years of the Holocaust, Jews would have had somewhere to turn to.  Moreover, Israel provides the opportunity to live a fulfilling Jewish life free from the inhibitions and restrictions of minority status.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Large numbers of men and women have abandoned organized religion, some because they have found it intellectually untenable, more because they have found it emotionally unsatisfying, most because they have found that its demands inhibit the personal freedom which they regard as a fundamental human right.  If Western Christianity has been most strongly affected, Western Judaism runs it a close second, for both have their home in the lands which modernity and the Enlightenment were nurtured.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The downside of the emphasis on family values is the danger of marginalizing the stranger, the single, and the unattached.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;. They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/html/staff/hjs/nsolomon.html&#34;&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CAwQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJudaism-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions%2Fdp%2F0192853902&amp;amp;ei=4GXeSo_3FYOk8AaKwvVy&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAV2jscXmj3uoFSGTQwfG8MHXsPA&#34;&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Hemingway, O&#39;Connor, and K. Shapiro</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s heart tightened as the trout moved.  He felt all the old feeling.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His muscles ached and the day was hot, but Nick felt happy.  He had left everything behind, the need for thinking, the need to write, other needs.  It was all back of him.  From the time he had gotten down off the train and the baggage man had thrown his pack out of the open car door things had been different.  Seney was burned, the country was burned over and changed, but it did not matter.  It could not all be burned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The road ran on, dipping occasionally, but always climbing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inside the tent the light came through the brown canvas.  It smelled pleasantly of canvas.  Already there was something mysterious and homelike.  Nick was happy as he crawled inside the tent.  He had not been unhappy all day.  This was different though.  Now things were done.  There had been this to do.  Now it was done.  It had been a hard trip.  He was very tired.  That was done.  He had made his camp.  He was settled.  Nothing could touch him.  It was a good place to camp.  He was there, in the good place.  He was in his home where he had made it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nick laughed.  It made a good ending to the story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Big Two-Hearted River: Part I&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;.  They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tide of darkness seemed to sweep him back to her, postponing from moment to moment his entry into the world of guilt and sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery O&amp;rsquo;Connor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Everything That Rises Must Converge&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But no appeal has yet been made to the vast American middle class, the majority class, to detach itself from our competitive industrial insanity.  It is indeed our industrial way of life that lends sanction to militarism and colonialism, Preparedness and suppression of human rights.  Our enemy, strange as it may sound to American ears, is the Standard of Living.  We worship at the altar of the White Rhinoceros, the American kitchen.  Standard of Living is the holy of holies in whose name every other evil is committed.  To lower this standard or to equalize it among the peoples of the world is our greatest need.  And the first step is to disassociate ourselves from the industrial-scientific madness which rules our lives twenty-four hours a day.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To remove ourselves from the world of competition is of paramount importance to the individual and to the nation.  Competition is the most terrible vice of modern society.  Competition is the disease of the West and is the source of our violence.  Non-violence means non-competition.  &amp;hellip;It cannot be employed by governments because governments are by definition committed to violence.  Nonviolence is not a prerogative of governments but of men, even of one man.  One nonviolent man, like Gandhi or Christ, can change history.  Governments can only keep history on the march.  &lt;em&gt;Ahimsa&lt;/em&gt; can stop history.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Vinoba Bhave, the greatest living disciple of Gandhi, who travels throughout India asking for land for the peasantry from the great landlords and receiving it, says: &amp;ldquo;I desire to humiliate neither the rich nor the poor&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  This is the opposite of communist expropriation or of capitalist competition.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Instead of class war and hatred as preached by the communists or industrial-scientific competition as preached by us, to survive we must behave nonviolently and in the spirit of love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Shapiro&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;To Revive Anarchism&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Creative Glut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Amichai, Laxness, Mendelssohn, &amp; Yoder</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-amichai-laxness-mendelssohn--yoder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watch how the cloud sings&lt;br /&gt;All you wanted to say or find.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Let the Coin Decide&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents&lt;br /&gt;Has not subsided in me.  My blood goes on sloshing&lt;br /&gt;Between my ribs, long after the vessel has come to rest.&lt;br /&gt;And the migration of my parents has not subsided in me.&lt;br /&gt;Winds of long time over stones.  Earth&lt;br /&gt;Forgets the steps of those who trod her.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;And the Migration of My Parents&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who will love the things that are naught and in vain?&lt;br /&gt;I, who stand in the world like water in the rain,&lt;br /&gt;I love the things that are naught and in vain.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The most wandering thing is a heart that stopped wandering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;At Right Angles: Hebrew Quatrains&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Has the horse been spoken to?&amp;rdquo; asked the old man; and as it had not yet been done, he took an ear in each hand and whispered to it, according to ancient custom, for horses understood these things:  &amp;ldquo;You carry a coffin today.  You carry a coffin today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The coffin was carried straight into the church in compliance with the minister&amp;rsquo;s request and the bells were rung.  Feeble was the sound they made, feeble their intrusion on frozen nature&amp;rsquo;s winter omnipotence, their peal reminiscent of nothing so much as the jingle of a child&amp;rsquo;s toy.  And the folk came trailing out of the drifting snow and into the church, timid in the face of death, which never seems so irrevocable as when bells of such a kind tinkle so helplessly in the cold, white spaces of declining day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Halldor Laxness&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Independent People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day of our life together&lt;br /&gt;Ecclesiastes erases a verse of his book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yehuda Amichai&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Six Poems For Tamar&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do I think he would be &amp;lsquo;saved&amp;rsquo;?  I fancy that whosoever leads men to virtue in this life cannot be damned in the next.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moses Mendelssohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Reply to Johann Kaspar Lavater,&amp;rdquo; 1769.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before the invention of the machine, the only wealth of a people was constituted by the soil and the flocks.  This is what today would be called capital.  Evidently Jesus accepted voluntary poverty for the sake of the kingdom and he ordered his disciples to practice the jubilary redistribution of their capital: &amp;ldquo;all of these things, it is the Gentiles of the world who seek them.  Your Father knows that you need them.  Seek rather the kingdom of God and all these things will be added to you.  Do not fear, little flock, because your Father has chosen to give you the kingdom; sell all that you have and give it as alms&amp;rdquo; (Luke 12:30-33).  No one doubts that he said this.  All that has been debated is whether this redistribution of capital was commanded by Jesus for all Christians at all times and in all places or whether it was just a &amp;ldquo;counsel of perfection&amp;rdquo; directed to the saints.  Traditionally the Church has chosen the second solution, the easy one.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Comparing one day the generosity of the wealthy, who ostentatiously were throwing large offerings in the temple treasury, with that of the poor widow, Jesus exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;This poor widow has put in more than all of them.  They put in from their overflow but she from her poverty has given all that she had to live!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In modern language we can translate: &amp;ldquo;The quantity of money that one gives is of little importance.  What is important is what one gives.   If it only is a part of one&amp;rsquo;s income, then this is not yet righteousness, goodness, and good faith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Howard Yoder&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Politics of Jesus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
