<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/technology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2016-17 Final NHL power rankings and playoff predictions</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2017-nhl-final-power-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2017-nhl-final-power-rankings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve created somewhat elaborate spreadsheets to rank NHL, NCAA Men&amp;rsquo;s Basketball and Football, and NFL teams by averaging a number of basic and advanced statistics as well as power rankings produced by various experts. The NHL playoffs start tonight. Here is (1) how my spreadsheet ranks all of the teams in the lead, and (2) my predictions for what will happen in the playoffs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;nhl-power-rankings-2016-17-end-of-regular-season&#34;&gt;NHL Power Rankings, 2016-17 (end of regular season)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Washington&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Montreal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Columbus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pittsburgh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minnesota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Jose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edmonton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anaheim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boston&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nashville&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NY Rangers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;St. Louis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calgary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tampa Bay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ottawa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NY Islanders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winnipeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carolina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dallas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Florida&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detroit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buffalo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Jersey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vancouver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colorado&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2017-nhl-playoff-predictions&#34;&gt;2017 NHL Playoff Predictions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eastern-conference-quarterfinals&#34;&gt;Eastern Conference Quarterfinals:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;montreal-canadiens-1st-in-atlantic-2-in-power-ranking-vs-n-y-rangers-1st-eastern-conf-wild-card-12-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Montreal Canadiens (1st in Atlantic, #2 in power ranking) vs. N.Y. Rangers (1st Eastern Conf. Wild Card, #12 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Montreal in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ottawa-senators-2nd-in-atlantic-18-in-power-ranking-vs-boston-bruins-3rd-in-atlantic-10-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Ottawa Senators (2nd in Atlantic, #18 in power ranking) vs. Boston Bruins (3rd in Atlantic, #10 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Boston in 6 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;washington-capitals-1st-in-metro-1st-in-eastern-conf-1st-in-nhl-1-in-power-ranking-vs-toronto-maple-leafs-2nd-eastern-conf-wild-card-14-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Washington Capitals (1st in Metro, 1st in Eastern Conf., 1st in NHL, #1 in power ranking) vs. Toronto Maple Leafs (2nd Eastern Conf. Wild Card, #14 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Washington in 5 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pittsburgh-penguins-2nd-in-metro-5-in-power-rankings-defending-stanley-cup-champions-vs-columbus-blue-jackets-3rd-in-metro-4-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Pittsburgh Penguins (2nd in Metro, #5 in power rankings, defending Stanley Cup Champions) vs. Columbus Blue Jackets (3rd in Metro, #4 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Pittsburgh in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;western-conference-quarterfinals&#34;&gt;Western Conference Quarterfinals:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;chicago-blackhawks-1st-in-central-1st-in-western-conf-3-in-power-ranking-vs-nashville-predators-2nd-western-conf-wild-card-11-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Chicago Blackhawks (1st in Central, 1st in Western Conf., #3 in power ranking) vs. Nashville Predators (2nd Western Conf. Wild Card, #11 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Chicago in 6 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;minnesota-wild-2nd-in-central-5-in-power-rankings-vs-st-louis-blues-3rd-in-central-13-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Minnesota Wild (2nd in Central, #5 in power rankings) vs. St. Louis Blues (3rd in Central, #13 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Minnesota in 6 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;anaheim-ducks-1st-in-pacific-9-in-power-rankings-vs-calgary-flames-1st-western-conf-wild-card-15-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Anaheim Ducks (1st in Pacific, #9 in power rankings) vs. Calgary Flames (1st Western Conf. Wild Card, #15 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Anaheim in 5 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;edmonton-oilers-2nd-in-pacific-8-in-power-rankings-vs-san-jose-sharks-3rd-in-pacific-7-in-power-rankings&#34;&gt;Edmonton Oilers (2nd in Pacific, #8 in power rankings) vs. San Jose Sharks (3rd in Pacific, #7 in power rankings)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Edmonton in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;western-conference-semifinals&#34;&gt;Western Conference Semifinals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicago Blackhawks vs. Minnesota Wild&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicago in 6 games&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;anaheim-ducks-vs-edmonton-oilers&#34;&gt;Anaheim Ducks vs. Edmonton Oilers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edmonton in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eastern-conference-semifinals&#34;&gt;Eastern Conference Semifinals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;montreal-canadians-vs-boston-bruins&#34;&gt;Montreal Canadians vs. Boston Bruins&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Montreal in 5 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;washington-capitals-vs-pittsburgh-penguins&#34;&gt;Washington Capitals vs. Pittsburgh Penguins&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;western-conference-finals&#34;&gt;Western Conference Finals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;chicago-blackhawks-vs-edmonton-oilers&#34;&gt;Chicago Blackhawks vs. Edmonton Oilers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction: Chicago in 5 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eastern-conference-finals&#34;&gt;Eastern Conference Finals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;washington-capitals-vs-montreal-canadiens&#34;&gt;Washington Capitals vs. Montreal Canadiens&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington in 6 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stanley-cup-finals&#34;&gt;Stanley Cup Finals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;chicago-blackhawks-vs-washington-capitals&#34;&gt;Chicago Blackhawks vs. Washington Capitals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington in 7 games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a language-learning program (high-frequency sentence identifier)</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/2015/10/09/developing-a-language-learning-program-high-frequency-sentence-identifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 05:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/2015/10/09/developing-a-language-learning-program-high-frequency-sentence-identifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I devoted most of my nights and weekends this year to building the program described below with the help of Kostyantyn Grinchenko, an excellent Ukrainian freelance developer. Then, after realizing that we had stumbled upon a breakthrough idea that could revolutionize language learning and help many people become fluent readers of their target language, I assembled a remote team of freelance and volunteer developers, designers, native-speaker audio recorders, and translators to help me develop it into a webapp (and future mobile app): &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordBrewery.com&lt;/a&gt;. Please help WordBrewery grow by &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;trying it out&lt;/a&gt;, joining our &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordbrewery.us12.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=de5def825a669f96078a614d4&amp;amp;id=ccf98da72c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email list&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://feeds.feedburner.com/LanguageUntapped&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;subscribing&lt;/a&gt; to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordbrewery.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, following us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/WordBrewery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WordBrewery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or taking a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1VLYcHdI5-FLlr5hMRJ1DzhLKDUzfkPvyI8Bx3bvvk3w/viewform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;beta tester survey&lt;/a&gt;. Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:admin@wordbrewery.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in supporting the WordBrewery project as a donor, investor, advocate, or volunteer. Thank you for your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past two months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with outsourcing small personal digital projects to overseas freelancers on Upwork. The experience has been very positive so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to devote a post to each of the tasks I outsource to give readers a sense of how freelancers and virtual assistants can both make one&amp;rsquo;s life easier in various ways and enable one to pursue projects and ideas despite lacking the time, expertise, or patience to implement them without outside help and delegation. I find Upwork and similar programs to be fascinating&amp;ndash;a fantastic, unambiguously positive example of open markets and the division of labor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very interested in finding efficient ways to learn things, especially languages. Language vocabulary is an example of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pareto Principle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (also known as the &amp;ldquo;80-20 rule&amp;rdquo;), according to which, &amp;ldquo;for many events, roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes.&amp;rdquo; In the context of language learning, the rule fits the fact that the most common 1,000 words or so in a language account for about 90% of spoken speech in that language. Thus, the best way to quickly develop one&amp;rsquo;s practical vocabulary in a second language is to focus on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://fluent-forever.com/the-method/vocabulary/#.VhdQRBNViko&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;core vocabulary list&lt;/a&gt; of high-frequency words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This insight, however, most be paired with another well-established principle of literacy and language learning: it is far better to learn vocabulary by studying it in context rather than in the form of isolated words in a list or on flash cards. Accordingly, language learners should study sentences, not words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thus came up with the idea for a language learning tool that identifies sentences with numerous high-frequency words: such sentences are especially valuable for language learners. But I could not find any program or tool that does this seemingly straightforward task. I know some basic computer programming, but for the near future I will lack the time and expertise to create such a tool from scratch myself. So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to partially &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.upwork.com/jobs/~0160ccc97b753712cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;outsource it&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found several overseas programmers who appear to be very capable of creating the program as I envision it. Here is the job as posted on Upwork:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_Language learning tool: High-frequency sentence identifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose: allow language learners to identify and collect sentences that are particularly valuable to study and memorize because they use several high-frequency words and do not include any obscure words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested mode of operation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-For each language, the program would draw upon data from at least two sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) a spreadsheet (CSV) or other easily manipulable data storage mechanism in which the 10,000 or 20,000 most column words of a language are pasted. In column one, assign the word a frequency score: the higher the frequency, the higher the score. So, for example, if the list has 500 words, the least common (most obscure) word in that list could be assigned a score of &amp;ldquo;1,&amp;rdquo; and the most common word in the list could be assigned a score of 500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) a list or corpus of example sentences, whether scraped in real-time from Wikipedia or other websites (e.g. Project Gutenberg, Tatoeba), or manually created and made available in a text file. For example, an Anki deck of example sentences (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1715094364&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1715094364&lt;/a&gt;) can be exported into a text file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-El ministro ha informado a la nación sobre la guerra. (The prime minister has informed the nation about the war.)
-Él tragaba sus bebidas rápidamente. (He used to gulp his drinks too quickly.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would iterate over the target-language example sentences, scoring each sentence for its potential value to the language-learner. Sentences that use several high-frequency words would receive a higher score&amp;ndash;and thus be more likely to be presented to the user. Sentences that include an uncommon or obscure word that does not appear on the frequency list at all (e.g., a word that is not among the 20,000 most common words of a language) would be penalized and less likely to be presented to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would have some mechanism for avoiding or reducing repetitiveness so that it brings in diverse sentences that do not repeat the same high-frequency words over and over. Ideally, this would be flexible so it does not completely disqualify a sentence just because one of its words was already used: this would disqualify too many sentences. But the program could somehow penalize sentences that use words that have already appeared in sentences the program has selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program would produce a CSV or text file of the sentences it has selected. The user should be able to instruct the program to return a certain number of sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-To avoid repetitive results in repeat uses, the program should include an element of randomness in selecting sentences for presentation to the user. Ideally, the user should be able to set the randomness level. A randomness level of 0, for example, could remove all randomness and simply return the highest-scoring sentences, while a randomness level of 100 could return a completely random set of sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical necessities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program needs to be able to handle non-English characters and words such as French/Spanish/Portuguese accented characters as well as Japanese, Chinese, Korean, and Thai. For the Asian languages, the program will also need to be able to cope with sentences that do not separate words with spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The program must be able to handle sentence data formatted in varying ways from diverse sources. For example, it should use regular expressions or other tools to automatically identify the delimiters that signal where each sentence begins and ends. Whether the program is iterating over a text file exported from Anki or a messy webpage, the program should return only sentences&amp;ndash;not single words, multiple sentences, translations, HTML tags, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I would like the scoring mechanism to be flexible so I can experiment with different ways of scoring the sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-It would be a bonus if the program could somehow be used to identify sentences that use a particular grammatical pattern or construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-It would further be helpful if the search mechanism accepted close matches to words on the frequency list to account for different verb conjugations, spelling variations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-I would like it if the program could, at the user&amp;rsquo;s option, show its work by: (1) showing or hiding each sentence&amp;rsquo;s frequency score in its results, and (2) returning not only sentences, but also&amp;ndash;for each sentence&amp;ndash;the high-frequency words the program found in that sentence, and those words&amp;rsquo; frequency score._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryan.mccarl@gmail.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; if you have suggestions or would like to help out with creating the program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for Facebook and social networking</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-case-for-facebook-and-social-networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Facebook currently has over 200 million active users, many people continue to doubt the value of social networking in general and Facebook in particular.  Critics argue that Facebook and other social networking and Web 2.0 tools - including blogs and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - are symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;solipsism&amp;rdquo; (meaning, in this context, the self-absorption of users) of the contemporary Internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, Facebook can be an enormous time-waster and procrastination tool, as can any medium or Internet resource.  I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected a lot about my own use of the site over the past six years or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve asked myself whether it is a worthwhile use of my time and an appropriate way - one among others, obviously - to communicate with my friends, family, colleagues, and acquaintances.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate was largely settled for me a few months ago when I heard a remarkable lecture by Clara Shih, social networking expert and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefacebookera.com/&#34;&gt;The Facebook Era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shih spoke in April at the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Booth School of Business, and I was in attendance to sell copies of her book.  (I was working as a manager at a bookstore at the time).  I went in with low expectations, as I generally take a dim view of the overcrowded genre of popular business books in general and books on making money through technology in particular.  But Shih&amp;rsquo;s presentation blew me away; she made me see Facebook and social networking in an entirely different light, and she helped me understand the many complex issues involved with social networking, and the utility social networking tools can have for those willing to critically evaluate and monitor their use of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The core reason for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s popularity, according to Shih, is that it lowers the cost of keeping in touch.  Keeping in touch with people you&amp;rsquo;ve met is a difficult and time-consuming process.  Facebook makes it much, much easier.  And it can help us keep in touch in a more meaningful way: there is less need to small talk with distant friends about where they are working, what they are studying, where they are living, and so forth - it&amp;rsquo;s all out there on their Facebook page, and so we can keep track of people we&amp;rsquo;ve met as they move through their lives.  When we think of them, we can think of who they are and what they are doing &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; rather than who they were when we met them years before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This powerful idea was brought home to me again this month, as the host family I lived with in Italy for ten weeks in my sophomore year of college joined Facebook and &amp;ldquo;Friended&amp;rdquo; me.  It takes a lot of effort to write a letter in Italian, put it in an envelope, wait in line at the post office to buy international postage, and finally send it - but it takes ten seconds to write on their &amp;ldquo;walls.&amp;rdquo;  And so I am much more likely to do the latter than the former, and our relationship need not be weakened by our falling out of touch.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Camus and Melville</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-camus-and-melville/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-camus-and-melville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;I once said that, after the experiences of the last two years, I could no longer hold to any truth which might oblige me, directly or indirectly, to demand a man&amp;rsquo;s life.  Certain friends whom I respected retorted that I was living in Utopia, that there was no political truth which could not one day reduce us to such an extremity, and that we must therefore either run the risk of this extremity or else simply put up with the world as it is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;They argued the point most forcefully.  But I think they were able to put such force into it only because they were unable to really &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;imagine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt; other people&amp;rsquo;s death.  It is a freak of the times.  We make love by telephone, we work not on matter but on machines, and we kill and are killed by proxy.  We gain in cleanliness, but lose in understanding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Albert Camus&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Neither Victims nor Executioners,&amp;rdquo; in David P. Barash, ed., &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Approaches to Peace&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;I would up heart, were it not like lead.  But my whole clock&amp;rsquo;s run down; my heart the all-controlling weight, I have no key to lift again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;I leave a white and turbid wake; pale waters, paler cheeks, where&amp;rsquo;er I sail.  The envious billows sidelong swell to whelm my track; let them; but first I pass.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;Already we are boldly launched upon the deep; but soon we shall be lost in its unshored, harborless immensities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Herman Melville&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;The English Major&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s1600-h/EnglishMajor&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s400/EnglishMajor&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5311272264829533522&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s latest novel, &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/English-Major-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802118631&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Harrison, a native of my home state of Michigan, is my favorite contemporary author, and &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major &lt;/span&gt;is the best &amp;rdquo;fun read&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a long time.  In trademark Harrison style, it is both hilarious and poignant, and it contains some great passages.  Excerpts below.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I tried to dismiss a pinprick of homesickness beneath my breastbone but then thought that homesickness like marital love was mostly a habit.  What I missed was no longer there or on the verge of disappearing.  I mean Lola was in dog heaven and the farm which had been sold to a stockbroker and his family from Chicago was to become a horse operation.  The barn and my cozy workshop would likely be remodeled into stables, the orchard uprooted for pasture, and our old home razed in favor of what Viv said would be &amp;ldquo;French provincial&amp;rdquo; whatever that was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad once warned me about this when I was mourning the loss of a girlfriend to a quarterback.  I was a lonely lineman.  I moped and moped, and then when we were cutting wood on an icy October morning he told me that self-pity was a ruinous emotion.  &amp;rdquo;Look at the world, not up your ass,&amp;rdquo; he said.  It took me awhile to figure this out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;She also liked to say that my dead father would wish me to be a &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; when my dad never spoke about such things except to say that successful people never had much time for important things like hunting, fishing, drinking, and wandering around in the woods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t own a cell phone which only made the wandering man a target with the number providing a guaranteed bull&amp;rsquo;s-eye.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Up to this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t questioned the rightness of my trip but suddenly I wondered if I were truly suited for travel.  Reality seemed to be crumbling and I was wise enough to understand that reality stayed the same so it was my mind that was crumbling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;To my dad who was a young man during the Great Depression the only truly hopeless greivance was not to have a job, or not to have &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; as he called it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sort of neutral in terms of religion but ever since I was a kid I&amp;rsquo;ve thought moving water to be the best thing God made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Everyone pretty much pans out in the middle ground or less.  In college I thought I was destined to go overseas but I didn&amp;rsquo;t.  We don&amp;rsquo;t quite get started except on our livelihood which is probably the story of mankind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Kohak&#39;s &#39;The Embers and the Stars&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-kohaks-the-embers-and-the-stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s1600-h/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 128px; height: 194px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SZel_FOOBOI/AAAAAAAAAuQ/zZar8WZIWwg/s400/Embers+and+the+Stars&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5302889589404206306&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I recently discovered the work of Erazim Kohak, a Czech philosopher and Professor Emeritus at Boston University who has written extensively on environmental ethics.  I am 30 pages into Kohak&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/span&gt;, and it is incredible so far.  A few excerpts below, with more to come.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Reflection and speculation remain no more than cunningly devised fables if they are not grounded in what, paraphrasing Calvin Schrag, we could call the prephilosophical and prescientific matrix of self-understanding and world-comprehension.  Though philosophy must do much else as well, it must, initially, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;see&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; and, thereafter, ground its speculation ever anew in seeing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;It is, surely, good that there are synthetic medicines to ease the surplus of pain, telephones to break through loneliness, and electric lights to keep the wayfarer from stumbling.  There is, though, something wrong when we use medicine to deaden our sensitivity, when we obliterate solitude with electronics and blind ourselves with the very lights we devised to help us see.  There is nothing wrong with our artifacts; there &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;something wrong with us: we have lost sight of the sense, the purpose of our production and our products.  Artifacts, finally, are good only extrinsically, as tools.  They have no intrinsic sense of their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;My primary tool has been the metaphor, not the argument, and the product of my labors is not a doctrine but an invitation to look and see.  With Husserl, I have sought not to instruct but to point out, to recall what we have forgotten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Contrary to Descartes, long before the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; of reflection there is the goodness and the truth of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;. [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; as in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;cogito ergo sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, &amp;ldquo;I think, therefore I am&amp;rdquo;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;sumus &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;= togetherness, &amp;ldquo;we are&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Humans have to dehumanize their world in their imagination in order to be able to exploit it ruthlessly in their actions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Our world of artifacts may be no more than the thinnest of layers covering the rhythm of living nature, but it is that layer that we confront in our daily experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Though the theoretical construct of [nature as] a mechanically ordered matter in motion may bear little resemblance to the living nature of the field and the forest and so may never have appeared convincing before, it is a faithful reflection of a world of artifacts and as such compelling to a humanity whose experience with nature is restricted to contact with artifacts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The technical reason which produces the machine cannot teach us its human use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The logic of&amp;hellip;production and consumption, however, grows ever more elusive.  Through the ages of humanity&amp;rsquo;s precarious survival on this earth, the meeting of basic survival needs provided a ready justification for productive activity.  Were we inclined so to direct our energies, it might still do so: there is more than enough hunger and sheer dismal misery still with us.  For the most part, though, we manage to ignore such need.  The logic of our production is not that of need but of affluence with lacks such automatic justification.  If affluence is to be justified, it cannot be by need but by some greater good, be it meeting the needs of others, caring for the natural world, or creating higher values of culture.  &amp;hellip;Yet individually and collectively we sacrifice precious life and resources to producing and paying for [items such as ever-larger television sets] - and we are constantly assured that we must do so to &amp;ldquo;stimulate the economy.&amp;rdquo;  Production itself has become the justification of ever more absurd consumption: we consume to proudce, produce to consume; all other considerations must stand aside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The heavens may still declare the glory of God, but we look up not at the heavens but at neon reflected on smog; we walk not on the good earth but on asphalt.  Our estrangement from nature is no longer conceptual only: it has acquired an experiential grounding.  Figuratively, we are all in the position of the child who has never seen, never mind milked, a cow, and whose lived experience constantly provides an experiential confirmation for the assumption that milk comes from a supermarket cooler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;If the products of human &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;techne&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; become philosophically and experientially problematic, it is, I would submit, because we come to think of them as autonomous of the purpose which led to their production and gives them meaning.  We become, in effect, victims of a self-forgetting, losing sight of the moral sense which is the justification of technology.  Quite concretely, the purpose of electric light is to help humans see.  When it comes to blind them to the world around them, it becomes counterproductive.  The task thus is not to abolish technology but to see through it to the human meaning which justifies it and directs its use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Erazim Kohak  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic; &#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=GvI0xlwoMesC&amp;amp;dq=the+embers+and+the+stars&amp;amp;source=gbs_summary_s&amp;amp;cad=0&#34;&gt;The Embers and the Stars: A Philosophical Inquiry into the Moral Sense of Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Mann, Golley, and Eliot</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Must-read: the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt; on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/24/us/24land.html?hp&#34;&gt;severe case of protracted bullying&lt;/a&gt;.  This is real, and it&amp;rsquo;s an enormous problem.  There is a spectrum of school violence ranging from verbal harassment and bullying all the way to school shootings, and it needs to be taken more seriously and addressed more quickly at every stage.  An atmosphere of security and mutual respect in classrooms is essential to students&amp;rsquo; well-being and ability to learn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A human being lives out not only his personal life as an individual, but also, consciously or subconsciously, the lives of his epoch and contemporaries.  &amp;hellip;All sorts of personal goals, purposes, hopes, prospects may float before the eyes of a given individual, from which he may then glean the impulse for exerting himself for great deeds; if the impersonal world around him, however, if the times themselves, despite all their hustle and bustle, provide him with neither hopes nor prospects, if they secretly supply him with evidence that things are in fact hopeless, without prospect or remedy, if the times respond with hollow silence to every conscious or subconscious question, however it may be posed, about the ultimate, unequivocal meaning of all exertions and deeds that are more than exclusively personal - then it is almost inevitable&amp;hellip;that the situation will have a crippling effect, which, following moral and spiritual paths, may even spread to that person&amp;rsquo;s physical and organic life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Two days of travel separate this young man (and young he is, with few firm roots in life) from his everyday world, especially from what might be called his duties, interests, worries, and prospects - separate him far more than he had dreamed possible as he rode to the station in a hansom cab.  Space, as it rolls and tumbles away between him and his native soil, proves to have powers normally ascribed only to time; from hour to hour, space brings about changes very like those time produces, yet surpassing them in certain ways.  Space, like time, gives birth to forgetfulness, but does so by removing an individual from all relationships and placing him in a free and pristine state - indeed, in but a moment it can turn a pedant and a philistine into something like a vagabond.  Time, they say, is water from the river Lethe, but alien air is a similar drink; and if its effects are less profound, it works all the more quickly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;All divine attributes have been taken over by human hands,&amp;rdquo; (Hirato Renkichi) wrote.  &amp;ldquo;Today, the engine of God is the engine of the city, and partakes in the activities of humanity&amp;rsquo;s millions.&amp;rdquo;  Almost every sentence of this document seems to anticipate Paul Virilio&amp;rsquo;s 1997 equation of &amp;ldquo;new technologies&amp;rdquo; with the &amp;ldquo;three traditional characteristics of the Divine: ubiquity, instantaneity, and immediacy.&amp;rdquo;  Although Virilio refers here to a much later technological revolution, the logic of his thinking echoes the poetics of Hirato Renkichi.  &amp;hellip;For Hirato, the powers of the divine had come to reside in &amp;ldquo;the impulsive candor of the machine, in its light, its heat, its ceaseless rhythms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gregory Golley&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See: Realism, Science, and Ecology in Japanese Literary Modernism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When a poet&amp;rsquo;s mind is perfectly equipped for its work, it is constantly amalgamating disparate experience; the ordinary man&amp;rsquo;s experience is chaotic, irregular, fragmentary.  The latter falls in love, or reads Spinoza, and these two experiences have nothing to do with each other, or with the noise of the typewriter or the smell of cooking; in the mind of the poet these experiences are always forming new wholes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;T.S. Eliot&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Metaphysical Poets,&amp;rdquo; quoted in Golley, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
