<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamakura on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/kamakura/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kamakura on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 16:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/kamakura/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the States!</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/back-in-the-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 16:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/back-in-the-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a great time in Tokyo, and now I am home - in Muskegon overnight and driving to Chicago first thing tomorrow morning. I&amp;rsquo;ll post a few of the best pictures from the trip over the weekend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A few of the things I did in Japan:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Reconnected with the Japanese people with whom I am closest - Ai (a former exchange student in Muskegon) and my former host family. Had many memorable outings with friends of Ai and became close with one in particular, a guitar-playing writer/actor named Okada who, at age 23, has already published two books of poetry in Japan.&lt;br /&gt;-Took a scenic train that ran along the seacoast to Kamakura, a beautiful, tree-filled former capital of Japan that is filled with temples and shrines.&lt;br /&gt;-Had dinner at a yakitori restaurant and drinks at an bar with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jdorama.com/artiste_95.htm&#34;&gt;Morimoto Reo&lt;/a&gt; (Leo), an actor famous in Japan. We discussed politics, literature, translation, and all sorts of other things. He said that he had never expected to be able to have a real conversation with an American, so we went out and talked from six at night to 1:30 in the morning.&lt;br /&gt;-Went to a members-only bar in Shinjuku run by another famous actor.&lt;br /&gt;-Went to Tokyo Disneyland with my former host family. Heard the Enchanted Tiki Birds and the Country Bears sing in Japanese.&lt;br /&gt;-Observed my first typhoon, Typhoon No. 10 (of the year), which hit Tokyo a few hours after I arrived.&lt;br /&gt;-Ate at &amp;ldquo;Freshness Burger,&amp;rdquo; a Japanese burger chain. Not good.&lt;br /&gt;-Toured various places in Tokyo: Shibuya, Shinjuku, Asagaya (where I lived), Koenji, Kichijoji, Odaiba, Jinbocho, Nakano, Urayasu.&lt;br /&gt;-Discovered that in the four years since I was last in Tokyo, at least one Starbucks has prominently appeared in every district.&lt;br /&gt;-Saw a Disney-style line formed in front of Tokyo&amp;rsquo;s one Krispy Kreme, near Shinjuku Station. A white-gloved employee guided people into the line and managed a sign that said: 30 minutes.&lt;br /&gt;-Learned that when the first Burger King opened in Tokyo recently, some people waited (and still wait) several hours to eat there.&lt;br /&gt;-Was robbed by the exchange rate and fees to the tune of 8 cents per dollar I exchanged.&lt;br /&gt;-Wrote over 100 pages in a travel journal and took almost 500 photographs.&lt;br /&gt;-Watched a Japanese friend get written up by a policeman in Asagaya after ignoring a command to stop our guitar-playing and singing in a park at 1 a.m.&lt;br /&gt;-Read Tolstoy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Hadji Murad&lt;/em&gt;, Murakami&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Kafka on the Shore&lt;/em&gt;, Northrop Frye&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Educated Imagination &lt;/em&gt;(a book about the importance of literature), Walker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Prompt and Utter Destruction: Truman and the Use of Atomic Bombs Against Japan, &lt;/em&gt;and about half of McCormack&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Emptiness of Japanese Affluence &lt;/em&gt;and Virgil&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Aeneid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Discovered new Japanese music and brought home seven CDs.&lt;br /&gt;-Visited a used English-language bookstore in Jinbocho; the bookstore had some incredibly rare books, including a complete set of the &lt;em&gt;Criterion&lt;/em&gt;, the journal T.S. Eliot edited, and many first-edition books by John Steinbeck, my favorite American author.&lt;br /&gt;-Bought Japanese books: the collected early poems of Tanigawa Shuntaro (some of which I am going to translate this year), a book on homes in Tokyo, and others. Also bought several used books in English.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The trip was a complete success. I was glad to be in Japan, and now I am glad to be back. Everything starts on Monday: classes in the M.A. program at Chicago, cross-country practice, editorial meetings at the &lt;em&gt;Maroon&lt;/em&gt;, and another year of work at D&amp;rsquo;Angelo Law Library.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
