<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cross Country on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/cross-country/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cross Country on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/cross-country/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a teacher and a Michigan Wolverine</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/becoming-a-teacher-and-a-michigan-wolverine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to report that I have decided to enter the University of Michigan School of Education&amp;rsquo;s Secondary MAC (MA in Education with Secondary Certification) program in mid-June.  The program is 12 months long and includes over 1,000 hours of classroom experience as a student teacher and substitute teacher, resulting in full certification.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I look forward to finding unique ways to show my students the importance of learning and reading as well as the value of informed engagement with current events and politics.  I also want to grow into a caring and effective mentor.  And, finally, I hope to learn from my classroom experience in order to become a more informed and articulate advocate for education reform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am very, very sad to be moving from Chicago after living here for five years.  I will miss my tiny apartment in East Lakeview and having easy access to my favorite places - the lakefront, Mickey&amp;rsquo;s Grille, Avenue Tavern, and Stella&amp;rsquo;s Diner in East Lakeview, the Noble Tree Cafe in Lincoln Park, the Grind and the Old Town School of Folk Music in Lincoln Square, the Pub and Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books in Hyde Park, Myopic Books in Wicker Park, Lao Beijing in Chinatown, and the Borders on Michigan Ave., among others.  But I will be visiting at least once a month over the next year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next three weeks will be incredibly busy.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be packing, moving, finding a subletter in Chicago and a temporary place to stay in Ann Arbor, working for a few more weeks, and spending as much time as possible with my friends in Chicago.  But I am thrilled to be entering the program and stepping into the next stage of my life and career.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCXC: Midwest Regional Championships 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-midwest-regional-championships-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2007 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-midwest-regional-championships-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzdz_xLaQjI/AAAAAAAAAFg/h8PFajRs5GY/s1600-h/regionals3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5131697839782117938&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; CURSOR: pointer&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzdz_xLaQjI/AAAAAAAAAFg/h8PFajRs5GY/s400/regionals3.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzd0bBLaQlI/AAAAAAAAAFw/cn72AIkLgpE/s1600-h/regionals5.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5131698307933553234&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; CURSOR: pointer&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzd0bBLaQlI/AAAAAAAAAFw/cn72AIkLgpE/s400/regionals5.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzd0nRLaQmI/AAAAAAAAAF4/eiKdLJgxG1s/s1600-h/regionals16.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5131698518386950754&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; CURSOR: pointer&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rzd0nRLaQmI/AAAAAAAAAF4/eiKdLJgxG1s/s400/regionals16.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was one of the best weekends of my life. It was my last team trip as a member of a collegiate cross-country squad, and memories were made. We traveled to beautiful, spacious Oshkosh, WI for the Midwest Regional meet. Shortly before the starting gun, huddling with the team, doing stride-outs, and giving high-fives, I realized that I was doing all of these things for the last time, and in a moment of clarity I understood how much cross-country has meant to me for the past 8 years.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Conditions were flawless - 45 degrees, hard ground, a flat course, winds under 10 mph - and everyone on the team had a performance they could be proud to end the season with. The men finished 12th and the women finished 14th out of 35 teams. There were several personal bests, and Liz Lawton made All-Region on the women&amp;rsquo;s side.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran 24:33 - 57 seconds faster than my P.R. of two weeks ago - finishing 7th overall, qualifying for the national championships, and setting a new University of Chicago cross-country school record. It was far and away the best race of my life, and I&amp;rsquo;m still feeling high from it. In &lt;span style=&#34;FONT-STYLE: italic&#34;&gt;Anna Karenina&lt;/span&gt;, Leo Tolstoy describes the emotion like this: &lt;p class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;Yet that grief and this joy were alike outside all the ordinary conditions of life; they were loopholes, as it were, in that ordinary life through which there came glimpses of something sublime. And in the contemplation of this sublime something the soul was exalted to inconceivable heights of which it had before had no conception, while reason lagged behind, unable to keep up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;12. University of Chicago&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;7. Ryan McCarl (Sr.) - 24:33&lt;br /&gt;57. Arthur Baptist (Fr.) - 25:36&lt;br /&gt;80. Chris Peverada (Jr.) - 25:59&lt;br /&gt;96. Alex Garbier (So.) - 26:25&lt;br /&gt;98. Nick Nunez (Fr.) - 26:26&lt;br /&gt;102. Andrew Wells-Qu (Fr.) - 26:30&lt;br /&gt;114. Adam Kaye (So.) - 26:47&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCXC: Parkside Invitational 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-parkside-invitational-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 00:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-parkside-invitational-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RxGla9F1m-I/AAAAAAAAAFE/2oaPCpSgdt0/s1600-h/loyolastart.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5121056133791194082&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/RxGla9F1m-I/AAAAAAAAAFE/2oaPCpSgdt0/s400/loyolastart.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a beautiful fall day in Kenosha, Wisconsin, and I was reminded of why I love cross-country. The course at Wisconsin-Parkside is designed specifically for cross-country: it isn&amp;rsquo;t a golf course with a white line drawn through it. It has handmade signs marking each quarter-mile, it has hills and trails through woods, and the start is sounded with a cannon rather than a gun. From the starting line, runners look forward and see an enormous hill surrounded by trees, and above the hill, the cloud-filled Wisconsin sky.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Whenever I am in Wisconsin, I feel at home. In the &lt;em&gt;Aeneid, &lt;/em&gt;Virgil writes of people&amp;rsquo;s desire for a &amp;ldquo;permanent shore.&amp;rdquo; When I think of my own permanent shore, I think of the upper Midwest, and places filled with lakes and trees, where Saturday mornings in the fall are spent at cross-country meets.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are our team results for the day (out of 17 teams, 187 runners):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;6. University of Chicago (154 points)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;11. Ryan McCarl (Sr.) (26:06)&lt;br /&gt;16. Chris Peverada (Jr.) (26:11)&lt;br /&gt;41. Nick Nunez (Fr.) (27:01)&lt;br /&gt;45. Adam Kaye (So.) (27:10)&lt;br /&gt;54. Andrew Wells-Qu (Fr.) (27:10)&lt;br /&gt;56. Brian Taylor (Sr.) (27:23)&lt;br /&gt;61. Alex Garbier (So.) (27:29)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCXC: Loyola Invitational 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-loyola-invitational-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 19:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/ucxc-loyola-invitational-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not the best day for the UCXC men: we were hoping to place around seventh or eighth at the Loyola Invitational, the gold division of which is packed with DI and DII teams, but no one ran particularly well, and we wound up in thirteenth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the final steps of the race, I was hit by the problem of overheating I occasionally get when I race - suddenly, all strength goes out of my limbs, moving a single step becomes a major effort, my body has begun to burn muscle instead of calories/fat, and I feel as though I might black out. After the race, I was barely conscious and could not open my eyes more than a fraction, my feet and legs were racked with cramps, and my head burned with a dehydration headache. It is an extraordinarily unpleasant experience, but things ended up fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;13. University of Chicago (359 points)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;44. Ryan McCarl (Sr.) (26:00)&lt;br /&gt;57. Jon Ascolese (Jr.) (26:12)&lt;br /&gt;92. Arthur Baptist (Fr.) (26:41)&lt;br /&gt;101. Greg Rizzolo (Sr.) (26:56)&lt;br /&gt;107. Alex Garbier (So.) (27:00)&lt;br /&gt;122. Adam Kaye (So.) (27:00)&lt;br /&gt;123. Nick Nunez (Fr.) (27:12)&lt;br /&gt;127. Chris Peverada (Jr.) (27:15)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal update: Elmhurst Invitational 2007</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-elmhurst-invitational-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-elmhurst-invitational-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rtj6FijEbUI/AAAAAAAAAE0/RKs9JejXllc/s1600-h/Pack_of_guys-Elmhurst.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5105105150704643394&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/Rtj6FijEbUI/AAAAAAAAAE0/RKs9JejXllc/s400/Pack_of_guys-Elmhurst.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The cross-country season got off to a great start for the UCXC men and women - the men placed our top 5 in the top 11 spots of the meet. What&amp;rsquo;s more, we did it by starting very conservatively and gradually moving up, a tactic that allowed us to run comfortably in a pack of 7-10 runners for the first 2 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; miles of the 4 mile race. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I enjoyed a race so much. Full results are &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.athletics.elmhurst.edu/documents/07ebmen.htm&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The UCXC women took 2nd, placing 4 in the top 11.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write more later, as I&amp;rsquo;m driving to Ann Arbor in six hours for a Michigan football game. But here are the team results:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Overall place, name, year, time)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2. Ryan McCarl (Sr) - 17:57&lt;br /&gt;5. Jon Ascolese (Jr) - 18:11&lt;br /&gt;8. Chris Peverada (Jr) - 18:14&lt;br /&gt;10. Arthur Baptist (Fr) - 18:19&lt;br /&gt;11. Nick Nunez (Fr) - 18:27&lt;br /&gt;15. David Yu (Jr) - 18:50 - (David ran unattached; he&amp;rsquo;s spending the year in Great Britain)&lt;br /&gt;18. Harry Backlund (Fr) - 18:57&lt;br /&gt;22. Greg Rizzolo (Sr) - 19:06&lt;br /&gt;24. Dan Gardner (Jr) - 19:07&lt;br /&gt;30. Adam Kaye (So) - 19:16&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
