<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Just War Theory on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/just-war-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Just War Theory on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/just-war-theory/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Solomon&#39;s &#39;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s1600-h/judaism.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5394862253055997906&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s400/judaism.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 215px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 200px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin Buber and Emanuel Levinas put their faith in the God of relationships.  &lt;em&gt;Alles Leben ist Begegnung&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;all life is encounter&amp;rsquo;), declared Buber, and the important thing is to get your relationship with God and with people right (I-Thou, rather than I-It); from that relationship, which is the essence of Revelation, ethical action flows; laws and rules are feeble attempts to capture revelation, and doomed to inadequacy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Genesis 1:27 states clearly enough: &amp;lsquo;So God created humankind in his own image; in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&amp;rsquo; This implies that in using our concept of God to model human behavior we should not distinguish between male and female.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Emil Fackenheim grounds his theology in the actual resistance of Shoah [Holocaust] victims to whom no realistic hope remained: &amp;lsquo;A philosophical Tikkun [&amp;lsquo;repair&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restoration&amp;rsquo;] is possible after the Holocaust because a philosophical Tikkun already took place, however fragmentarily, during the Holocaust itself&amp;rsquo;; the rebirth of Israel, and a new constructive dialogue with a self-critical Christianity, are essential to this process.  Fackenheim is also noted for his statement that there should be a 614th commandment, surplus to the 613 of tradition - to survive as Jews, to remember, never to despair of God, lest we hand Hitler a posthumous victory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Is there such a thing as a &amp;lsquo;just war&amp;rsquo;, and if so, what are the conditions of engagement?  Out of this debate emerged the novel concept of &lt;em&gt;tohar ha-nesheq&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;purity of arms&amp;rsquo;), which demands &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt; that the fighting force take special risks to avoid harm to non-combatants and to minimize enemy casualties.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Many Jews, including secular ones, see Israel as the fulfilment of the &amp;lsquo;national&amp;rsquo; aspirations of the Jewish people; after thousands of years of minority status, of being alienated from the host societies, and in many  cases actually prevented from becoming full citizens of the lands in which they lived, they feel that they have at last &amp;lsquo;come home&amp;rsquo; and are able to control their own destiny within the normal limitations of independent statehood.  Israel is perceived as a secure haven for persecuted Jews; had Israel existed during the years of the Holocaust, Jews would have had somewhere to turn to.  Moreover, Israel provides the opportunity to live a fulfilling Jewish life free from the inhibitions and restrictions of minority status.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Large numbers of men and women have abandoned organized religion, some because they have found it intellectually untenable, more because they have found it emotionally unsatisfying, most because they have found that its demands inhibit the personal freedom which they regard as a fundamental human right.  If Western Christianity has been most strongly affected, Western Judaism runs it a close second, for both have their home in the lands which modernity and the Enlightenment were nurtured.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The downside of the emphasis on family values is the danger of marginalizing the stranger, the single, and the unattached.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;. They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/html/staff/hjs/nsolomon.html&#34;&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CAwQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJudaism-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions%2Fdp%2F0192853902&amp;amp;ei=4GXeSo_3FYOk8AaKwvVy&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAV2jscXmj3uoFSGTQwfG8MHXsPA&#34;&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from C. Taylor, J.T. Johnson, and the US Catholic Bishops</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-c.-taylor-j.t.-johnson-and-the-us-catholic-bishops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Faith does not insulate us from the challenges of life; rather, it intensifies our desire to help solve them&amp;hellip;.  From the resources of our faith we wish to provide hope and strength to all who seek a world free of the nuclear threat.  Hope sustains one&amp;rsquo;s capacity to live with danger without being overwhelmed by it; hope is the will to struggle against obstacles even when they appear insuperable.  Ultimately our hope rests in the God who gave us life, sustains the world by his power and has called us to revere the lives of every person and all peoples.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As Americans, citizens of the nation which was first to produce atomic weapons, which has been the only one to use them and which today is one of the handful of nations capable of decisively influencing the course of the nuclear age, we have grave human, moral, and political responsibilities to see that a &amp;ldquo;conscious choice&amp;rdquo; is made to save humanity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;United States Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response - The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;The definition of combatancy and noncombatancy follows from direct involvement in prosecuting the war, not from one&amp;rsquo;s citizenship or one&amp;rsquo;s personal preference among the belligerents.  It is action that matters, not attitude.  For this reason, I regard the use of the term &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt; in the Protocols to the Geneva Conventions as misleading: it is not civilian status that matters, as irregular soldiers may technically be civilians; what matters is whether people are engaged in combatant activity or not.  The relevant moral term is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;noncombatant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, even though the language of the protocols uses &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;civilian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;, and this usage has seeped into the moral debate at times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;James Turner Johnson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The War to Oust Saddam Hussein: Just War and the New Face of Conflict&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;In the following chapters, I will be making a continuing polemic against what I call &amp;ldquo;subtraction stories.&amp;rdquo;  Concisely put, I mean by this stories of modernity in general, and secularity in particular, which explain them by human beings having lost, or sloughed off, or liberated themselves from certain earlier, confining horizons, or illusions, or limitations of knowledge.  What emerges from this process - modernity or secularity - is to be understood in terms of underlying features of human nature which were there all along, but had been impeded by what is now set aside.  Against this kind of story, I will steadily be arguing that Western modernity, including its secularity, is the fruit of new inventions, newly constructed self-understandings and related practices, and can&amp;rsquo;t be explained in terms of perennial features of human life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Taylor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;A Secular Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we must remember Iraq</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/why-we-must-remember-iraq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;The Next Forgotten War&lt;/a&gt;,” an op-ed of mine, was published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/the-next-forgotten-war/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In it, I argue that we must keep the memory of the Iraq War, and the individuals caught up in its maelstroms, alive:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Iraq recedes from the headlines and slips from the public’s mind to make room for the next &amp;lsquo;crisis,&amp;rsquo; we have a responsibility to give some thought to the two million Iraqi refugees displaced by the war and the tens of thousands of Americans and Iraqis killed or maimed as a consequence of the war. And what we should remember is not statistics or grand narratives, but individual stories and the weight they lend to the principles of prudence, humanism, and nonviolence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the article, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/As%20Iraq%20recedes%20from%20the%20headlines%20and%20slips%20from%20the%20public%E2%80%99s%20mind%20to%20make%20room%20for%20the%20next%20%22crisis,%22%20we%20have%20a%20responsibility%20to%20give%20some%20thought%20to%20the%20two%20million%20Iraqi%20refugees%20displaced%20by%20the%20war%20and%20the%20tens%20of%20thousands%20of%20Americans%20and%20Iraqis%20killed%20or%20maimed%20as%20a%20consequence%20of%20the%20war.%20And%20what%20we%20should%20remember%20is%20not%20statistics%20or%20grand%20narratives,%20but%20individual%20stories%20and%20the%20weight%20they%20lend%20to%20the%20principles%20of%20prudence,%20humanism,%20and%20nonviolence.&#34;&gt;linking to it&lt;/a&gt; or sharing it with others you think may be interested.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal update: spring quarter</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/personal-update-spring-quarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is turning out to be one of the busiest times of my life, so I won’t be posting very much over the next nine weeks.  For one thing, my coursework is forcing me to put most of my personal reading list on the back-burner, so I’ll have fewer excerpts to share.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite the academic stress, however, things are better than ever.  My classes are awesome – a Ph.D.-level seminar in Japanese literature of the 1920s and 30s taught from a Marxist perspective (the first time I’ve really had to grapple with critical theory), the third quarter of elementary Norwegian (which I’m taking in the hope of traveling to Norway and studying Knut Hamsun and other Norwegian writers in the original language), the third quarter of fourth-year modern Japanese (which amounts to taking a course with a top-notch private tutor, as there are only three of us in the class), and Jean-Bethke Elshtain’s course on the Just War tradition – a Divinity School course offering a perspective on war and peace that is completely different from the realist perspective of the political science department that I’m used to hearing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than that, I am finishing my M.A. (on the consequences of China’s rise for East Asian security), meeting new people, exploring the city, and spending as much time as possible with my friends.  Spring is here, the quads are full of students, and my last quarter at the U of C is shaping up to be one of the best.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings on Easter, Just War Theory, and Japanese lit</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-on-easter-just-war-theory-and-japanese-lit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The resurrection of Jesus is the sign to the world that God indeed does reign, does give life in death and that the love of God is stronger even than death (Rom. 8:36-39).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;At the center of the church&amp;rsquo;s teaching on peace and at the center of all Catholic social teaching, are the transcendence of God and the dignity of the human person.  The human person is the clearest reflection of God&amp;rsquo;s presence in the world; all of the church&amp;rsquo;s work in pursuit of both justice and peace is designed to protect and promote the dignity of every person.  For each person not only reflects God, but is the expression of God&amp;rsquo;s creative work and the meaning of Christ&amp;rsquo;s redemptive ministry.  Christians approach the problem of war and peace with fear and reverence.  God is the Lord of life, and so each human life is sacred; modern warfare threatens the obliteration of human life on a previously unimaginable scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;U.S. Catholic Bishops&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Challenge of Peace: God&amp;rsquo;s Promise and Our Response (The Pastoral Letter on War and Peace, 1983)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us.  &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28140&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, &lt;span id=&#34;en-NIV-28141&#34; class=&#34;sup&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romans 8:37-39&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The aggressor is always peace-loving; he would prefer to take over our country unopposed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Carl Von Clausewitz, quoted in J.T. Turner, &amp;ldquo;Threats, Values and Defense: Does the Defense of Values by Force Remain a Moral Possibility?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;***&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His desire for a woman was not of a sort to make him want this particular woman - it was something to be taken care of lightly and with no sense of guilt.  This woman was too clean.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The window of the waiting-room was clear for an instant as the train started to move.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s face glowed forth, and as quickly disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;But this love would leave behind it nothing so definite as a piece of Chijimi.  Though cloth to be worn is among the most short-lived of craftworks, a good piece of Chijimi, if it has been taken care of, can be worn quite unfaded a half-century and more after weaving.  As Shimamura thought absently how human intricacies have not even so long a life, the image of Komako as the mother of another man&amp;rsquo;s children suddenly floated into his mind.  He looked around, startled.  Possibly he was tired.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He leaned against the brazier, provided against the coming of the snowy season, and thought how unlikely it was that he would come again once he had left.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Komako had come up to him, he did not know when.  She took his hand.  He looked around at her but said nothing.  She gazed at the fire, the pulse of the fire beating on her intent, slightly flushed face.  Shimamura felt a violent rising in his chest.  Komako&amp;rsquo;s hair was coming undone, and her throat was bare and arched.  His fingers trembled from the urge to touch it.  His hand was warm, but Komako&amp;rsquo;s was still warmer.  He did not know why he should feel that a separation was forcing itself upon them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kawabata Yasunari&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Snow Country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obviously he did not much enjoy reading and discussing a typical month&amp;rsquo;s production of Japanese literature.  In a 1935 essay Kobayashi expressed his annoyance with authors who complained that he had not been sufficiently kind in his reviews, and asked sardonically what kindness contemporary authors have ever shown their critics.  The only kindness a critic really wants from authors is that they will supply him with the basis for writing decent criticism; but present-day authors do precisely the opposite.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donald Keene&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Dawn to the West: A History of Japanese Literature (Vol. 4)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
