<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>College on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/college/</link>
    <description>Recent content in College on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/college/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dewey, Hoyt, and Freud</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the past provide the only means at command for understanding the present.  &amp;hellip;The institutions and customs that exist in the present and that give rise to present social ills and dislocations did not arise overnight.  They have a long history behind them.  Attempt to deal with them simply on the basis of what is obvious in the present is bound to result in adoption of superficial measures which in the end will only render existing problems more acute and more difficult to solve.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Growth depends upon the presence of difficulty to be overcome by the exercise of intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Dewey&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Experience and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts from a history of the Great Depression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching had investigated college athletics earlier in the year (1929) and found them to be the same across the country - &amp;ldquo;sodden with commercialism.&amp;rdquo;  Of 112 schools investigated, only 28 did not offer improper subsidies to athletes.  But instead of hanging their heads in shame, many colleges defended their athletic activities.  A Brown University professor attacked the foundation for meddling.  &amp;hellip;The Big Ten&amp;rsquo;s commissioner of athletics defended the practice of buying college players.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One telephone operator in one of the city&amp;rsquo;s largest hotels wore a new sealskin coat.  Her spending was typical.  She was playing the stock market on a broker&amp;rsquo;s margin account, and boasted neither a bank savings account, insurance, nor a penny in the world except what she earned from week to week.  But would she take her profits and convert them to bonds, as President Hoover wanted her and all Americans to do?  She would not even consider it, for the gambling fever had her, as it had a million other Americans.  The fever had her and them in red-cheeked, bright-eyed frenzy. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For billions of dollars were lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thursday&#34;&gt;that day&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the young telephone operator in the New York hotel who had invested everything she owned in her sealskin coat and in a margin account on the stock exchange.  A hotel resident, unable to complete a telephone call that night, had gone to the switchboard himself, to overhear her talking to her broker, her voice breaking and eyes bathed in tears.  All the telephone operator had left at the end of this Black Thursday was her sealskin coat and her job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;That night the relatives of Abraham Germansky, a wealthy real estate man who lived in Mount Vernon, New York, put in a frantic call to police to help them find Germansky.  He had last been seen late Thursday on Wall Street, tearing up ticker tape and scattering it along the sidewalk.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hunger was not debatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin P. Hoyt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Tempering Years &lt;/span&gt;(a history of America between 1929 and 1939)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is clear that in their play children repeat everything that has made a great impression on them in real life, and that in doing so they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/abreact&#34;&gt;abreact&lt;/a&gt; the strength of the impression and, as one might put it, make themselves master of the situation.  But on the other hand, it is obvious that all their play is influenced by a wish that dominates them the whole time - the wish to be grown-up and to be able to do what grown-up people do.  It can also be observed that the unpleasurable nature of an experience does not always unsuit it for play.  If the doctor looks down a child&amp;rsquo;s throat or carries out some small operation on him, we may be quite sure that these frightening experiences will be the subject of the next game; but we must not in that connection overlook the fact that their is a yield of pleasure from another source.  As the child passes over from the passivity of the experience to the activity of the game, he hands on the disagreeable experience to one of his playmates and in this way revenges himself on a substitute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beyond the Pleasure Principle&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quotes on education and business</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-on-education-and-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 21:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-on-education-and-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After all, I got into teaching for the same reason, I suspect, that many people did: because I thought it was a high-stakes affair, a pursuit in which souls are won and lost.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the ways we&amp;rsquo;ve tried to be attractive is by loosening up.  We grade much more genially than our colleagues in the sciences.  In English and history, we don&amp;rsquo;t give many D&amp;rsquo;s, or C&amp;rsquo;s, either.  (The rigors of Chem 101 may create almost as many humanities majors per year as the splendors of Shakespeare.)  A professor at Stanford explained that grades were getting better because the students were getting smarter every year.  Anything, I suppose, is possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I read the reviews, I thought of a story I&amp;rsquo;d heard about a Columbia University instructor who issued a two-part question at the end of his literature course.  Part one: What book in the course did you most dislike?  Part two: What flaws of intellect or character does that dislike point up in you?  The hand that framed those questions may have been slightly heavy.  But at least they compelled the students to see intellectual work as a confrontation between two people, reader and author, where the stakes mattered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Mark Edmundson, &lt;em&gt;Why Read?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best businessperson in the world can&amp;rsquo;t sell something the world isn&amp;rsquo;t ready to use.  People don&amp;rsquo;t buy inventions.  They don&amp;rsquo;t buy technology.  They buy a solution to a perceived problem.  And if you have the greatest solution in the world and people don&amp;rsquo;t perceive it as the solution to their problem, they are not going to buy it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Dean Kamen, in Kurtzman, ed., &lt;em&gt;MBA in a Box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[Lord] Acton&amp;rsquo;s learning and culture, like his ideas, were neither casually acquired nor casually expended.  The languages he assimilated from his multilingual, multinational family were deliberately refined by years of careful study, and were cultivated as scholarly tools rather than as social graces.  It was this seriousness and dedication of purpose that characterized the whole of his life, that made of his library not the cultured gentleman&amp;rsquo;s lounge but the crowded workshop of the professional historian.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Gertrude Himmelfarb, &lt;em&gt;Lord Acton: A Study in Conscience and Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
