<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/psychology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Frankl&#39;s &#39;Man&#39;s Search for Meaning&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading Viktor Frankl&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=pd_lpo_k2_dp_sr_1/189-8560150-0000706?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=lpo-top-stripe-1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0A2K5K4WK03NGZMZ523G&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=486539851&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0671023373&#34;&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankl, a psychiatrist, was imprisoned in the Nazi concentration camps, including Auschwitz, for several years.  He survived the experience and went on to develop the theory of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy&#34;&gt;logotherapy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a branch of psychoanalysis that focuses on human beings&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;will to meaning.&amp;rdquo;  The part of the book that discusses Frankl&amp;rsquo;s memories of his camp experience is, like any Holocaust memoir worth its salt, extremely disturbing and difficult to read, but it ought to be read in spite of that.  Here are a few (non-graphic) excerpts from the book, which I highly recommend:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Soon we had resumed the previous day&amp;rsquo;s positions in the ditch.  The frozen ground cracked under the point of the pickaxes, and sparks flew.  The men were silent, their brains numb.  My mind still clung to the image of my wife.  A thought crossed my mind: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know if she were still alive.  I knew only one thing - which I have learned well by now: Love goes very far beyond the physical person of the beloved.  It finds its deepest meaning in his spiritual being, his inner self.  Whether or not he is actually present, whether or not he is still alive at all, ceases somehow to be of importance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If there is a meaning of life at all, then there must be a meaning in suffering.  Suffering is an ineradicable part of life, even as fate and death.  Without suffering and death human life cannot be complete.  The way in which a man accepts his fate and all the suffering it entails, the way in which he takes up his cross, gives him ample opportunity - even under the most difficult circumstances - to add a deeper meaning to his life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What was really needed was a fundamental change in our attitude toward life.  We had to learn ourselves and, furthermore, we had to teach the despairing men, that &lt;em&gt;it did not really matter what we expected from life, but rather what life expected from us.&lt;/em&gt;  We needed to stop asking about the meaning of life, and instead to think of ourselves as those who were being questioned by life - daily and hourly.  Our answer must consist, not in talk and meditation, but in right action and right conduct.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I remember two cases of would-be suicide, which bore a striking similarity to each other.  Both men had talked of their intentions to commit suicide.  Both used the typical argument - they had nothing more to expect from life.  In both cases it was a question of getting them to realize that life was still expecting something from them; something in the future was expected of them.  We found, in fact, that for the one it was his child whom he adored and who was waiting for him in a foreign country.  For the other it was a thing, not a person.  This man was a scientist and had written a series of books which still needed to be finished.  His work could not be done by anyone else, any more than another person could ever take the place of the father in his child&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Not only our experiences, but all we have done, whatever great thoughts we may have had, and all we have suffered, all this is not lost, though it is past; we have brought it into being.  Having been is also a kind of being, and perhaps the surest kind.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I asked the poor creatures who listened to me attentively in the darkness of the hut to face up to the seriousness of our position.  They must not lose hope but should keep their courage in the certainty that the hopelessness of our struggle did not detract from its dignity and its meaning.  I said that someone looks down on us in different hours - a friend, a wife, somebody alive or dead, or a God - and he would not expect us to disappoint him.  He would hope to find us suffering proudly - not miserably - knowing how to die.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When we spoke about attempts to give a man in camp mental courage, we said that he had to be shown something to look forward to in the future.  He had to be reminded that life still waited for him, that a human being waited for his return.  But after liberation?  There were some men who found that no one awaited them.  Woe to him who found that the person whose memory alone had given him courage in camp did not exist any more!  Woe to him who, when the day of his dreams finally came, found it so different from all he had longed for!  Perhaps he boarded a trolley, traveled out to the home which he had seen for years in his mind, and only in his mind, and pressed the bell, just as he has longed to do in thousands of dreams, only to find that the person who should open the door was not there, and would never be there again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Viktor E. Frankl&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jim Harrison&#39;s &#39;The English Major&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jim-harrisons-the-english-major/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s1600-h/EnglishMajor&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 240px; height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SbVt_AqMfVI/AAAAAAAAAug/Lg32OK9MQsQ/s400/EnglishMajor&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5311272264829533522&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently finished Jim Harrison&amp;rsquo;s latest novel, &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/English-Major-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802118631&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Harrison, a native of my home state of Michigan, is my favorite contemporary author, and &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major &lt;/span&gt;is the best &amp;rdquo;fun read&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a long time.  In trademark Harrison style, it is both hilarious and poignant, and it contains some great passages.  Excerpts below.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I tried to dismiss a pinprick of homesickness beneath my breastbone but then thought that homesickness like marital love was mostly a habit.  What I missed was no longer there or on the verge of disappearing.  I mean Lola was in dog heaven and the farm which had been sold to a stockbroker and his family from Chicago was to become a horse operation.  The barn and my cozy workshop would likely be remodeled into stables, the orchard uprooted for pasture, and our old home razed in favor of what Viv said would be &amp;ldquo;French provincial&amp;rdquo; whatever that was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad once warned me about this when I was mourning the loss of a girlfriend to a quarterback.  I was a lonely lineman.  I moped and moped, and then when we were cutting wood on an icy October morning he told me that self-pity was a ruinous emotion.  &amp;rdquo;Look at the world, not up your ass,&amp;rdquo; he said.  It took me awhile to figure this out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;She also liked to say that my dead father would wish me to be a &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; when my dad never spoke about such things except to say that successful people never had much time for important things like hunting, fishing, drinking, and wandering around in the woods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Dad certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t own a cell phone which only made the wandering man a target with the number providing a guaranteed bull&amp;rsquo;s-eye.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Up to this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t questioned the rightness of my trip but suddenly I wondered if I were truly suited for travel.  Reality seemed to be crumbling and I was wise enough to understand that reality stayed the same so it was my mind that was crumbling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;To my dad who was a young man during the Great Depression the only truly hopeless greivance was not to have a job, or not to have &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; as he called it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sort of neutral in terms of religion but ever since I was a kid I&amp;rsquo;ve thought moving water to be the best thing God made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34;  style=&#34;font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Everyone pretty much pans out in the middle ground or less.  In college I thought I was destined to go overseas but I didn&amp;rsquo;t.  We don&amp;rsquo;t quite get started except on our livelihood which is probably the story of mankind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jim Harrison&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The English Major&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Reading Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  At the end of each of the past three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post listing the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the course of the year in order to bring these books to the attention of others.  My lists from 2007 and 2006 are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2007/12/2007-book-recommendations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve put the titles of the five books most important to me this year in bold, and I&amp;rsquo;ve linked each book to its Amazon.com page.  Enjoy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Arons, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Compelling-Belief-Culture-American-Schooling/dp/0870235249/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899752&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Compelling Belief: The Future of American Schooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (education/religion/politics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doniger, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Implied-Spider-Wendy-Doniger/dp/0231111711/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899795&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics and Theology in Myth&lt;/a&gt; (religion / mythology)&lt;br /&gt;Du Bois, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899814&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt; (history / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frank, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899838&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt; (economics / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frankel, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Faith-Freedom-Religious-Liberty-Critical/dp/0809015757/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Faith and Freedom: Religious Liberty in America&lt;/a&gt; (religion / politics / law)&lt;div&gt;Gibran, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prophet-Kahlil-Gibran/dp/000100039X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900039&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; philosophy / religion)&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900186&amp;amp;sr=1-3&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Harrison, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Returning-Earth-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802143318/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harrison, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;br /&gt;Hemingway, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; literature)&lt;br /&gt;Kerouac, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dharma-Bums-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/0143039601/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900162&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Laxness, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Independent-People-Halldor-Laxness/dp/0679767924/ref=pd_sim_b_1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Independent People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Mann, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Milosz, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Native-Realm-Self-Definition-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374528306/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900582&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Native Realm: A Search for Self-Definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (memoirs / literature / history)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Putney &amp;amp; Putney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Adjusted-American-Neurosis-Individual-Society/dp/0060900954/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900593&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Adjusted American: Normal Neurosis in the Individual and Society&lt;/a&gt; (psychology)&lt;br /&gt;Salomon &amp;amp; Valdez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900612&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt; (design / environment)&lt;br /&gt;Walzer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Unjust-Wars-Historical-Illustrations/dp/0465037070/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900722&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Just and Unjust Wars&lt;/a&gt; (3rd reading; politics / international relations)    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of happiness</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-science-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from Richard Layard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The extra happiness provided by extra income is greatest when you are poor, and declines steadily as you get richer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Required income&amp;rdquo; varies strongly with the actual income that an individual currently experiences.  A dollar rise in experienced income causes a rise of at least a forty cents in &amp;ldquo;required income.&amp;rdquo;  So when I earn an extra dollar this year, it makes me happier, but next year I shall measure my income from a benchmark that is forty cents higher.  In this sense at least 40% of this year&amp;rsquo;s gain is &amp;ldquo;wiped out&amp;rdquo; next year.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Differences in family situation cause a huge difference in happiness.  If someone is divorced, that person&amp;rsquo;s happiness falls by 5 (percentage) points.  This is more than double the effect of losing a third of one&amp;rsquo;s income.  &amp;hellip;The year of divorce is the worst.  After that year men return on average to their baseline level of happiness, but women continue to suffer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If our goals are too low, we get bored.  But if they are too high, we get frustrated.  The secret is to have goals that are stretching enough, but not too stretching.  Unattainable goals are a well-known cause of depression.  But so too is boredom.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The typical Briton watches television for three and a half hours a day - roughly twenty-five hours a week.  Over a lifetime a typical Briton spends more time watching television than doing paid work.  The figures are much the same in the United States.  &amp;hellip; This viewing time has to come from somewhere, and it mainly comes from social life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;So how does the content of television affect our feelings about life, and our behavior?  If television simply mirrored life as it is, it would be unlikely to have much effect.  However, it does not simply mirror life - that would be boring.  Television focuses far more on the extremes.  It contains far more violence, sex, and chaotic relationships than ordinary life does, and it contains far more wealth and beauty.  &amp;hellip;Chaos on the screen tends to desensitize - to make people more willing to engage in violence themselves and in illicit sex.  At the same time wealth and beauty create discontent with what people have - an itch to earn or steal more wealth, or to find a more beautiful partner.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On one estimate an extra hour a week watching television causes you to spend an extra $4 a week - on &amp;ldquo;keeping up with the Joneses.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;It reduces our happiness with our possessions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Viewing may also reduce our happiness with our bodies, and with our spouses.  The psychologist Douglas Kenrick showed women a series of female models.  He evaluated their mood before and after they looked at the pictures.  After seeing the models, the women&amp;rsquo;s mood fell.  So how must women&amp;rsquo;s moods be affected by television?  In three hours of viewing television each day you cannot fail to see a parade of beautiful women.  What about the effect on men?  As part of the same series of experiments, pictures of models were shown to a sample of men.  Kenrick evaluated their feelings about their wives before and after each presentation.  After seeing the models, most men felt less good about their wives.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Trustworthiness is crucial in any venture, and no long-term contract can flourish except on the basis of commitment to the common goal.  This applies in business, in friendship or in marriage.  Unfortunately, the growth of individualism has encouraged a short-term version of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;contractarian&lt;/span&gt; thinking, where more and more decisions are conducted on the basis of a short-term quid pro quo. &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this environment of continuous reoptimization, it is not surprising that, as we have seen, people are less satisfied with their marriages.  There is also clear evidence that when spouses arrange their lives on the basis of quid pro quo, they are less satisfied with the marriage than when it is based on the concept of giving.  &amp;hellip;The evidence also shows that when one spouse does something and the other spouse reciprocates, the first gets less satisfaction than when no direct reciprocation occurs.  This is because giving confers satisfaction, and can confer more satisfaction than taking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Above all, we need to know that our partner has sufficient emotional commitment to the enterprise.  If so, we know the partner will stick to the relationship, even when short-term advantage would say &amp;ldquo;Out.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;If both parties know that the other is really committed, each will invest more and the probability of success will rise.  In all walks of life, good behavior by one person elicits good behavior by others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Layard&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Two Mules: A Fable for the Nations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-two-mules-a-fable-for-the-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-two-mules-a-fable-for-the-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SAvWAdMfPaI/AAAAAAAAAIE/CP49F6lxN84/s1600-h/cooperation-two-mules.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5191478298799979938&#34; style=&#34;FLOAT: left; MARGIN: 0px 10px 10px 0px; CURSOR: hand&#34; alt=&#39;&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SAvWAdMfPaI/AAAAAAAAAIE/CP49F6lxN84/s400/cooperation-two-mules.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;(Saw this in Richard Layard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a New Science&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on psychology, religion, and politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-psychology-religion-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even in mundane situations, the individual must &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; in order to discover what he is and he must act in order to continue experiencing aspects of himself which he values and enjoys.  If he thinks of himself as a businessman, a parent, an athlete, an intellectual, he must engage in behavior appropriate to this self-image.  If he does not, he must redefine himself, or he will be left feeling anxious and needful.  (Here is the reason for the psychological shock of retirement; the man who has retired may find that suddenly he can no longer &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;that which he most valued himself for being.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Past actions through which he sought to know and to accept the self are not capable of satisfying this need in the present.  Recalling the past can only remind the individual of what he used to be.  The erstwhile football hero who is still reliving the big game fifteen years later, or the ex-campus queen who tries to give meaning to her life by clinging to her reign over the prom of a decade ago, are pathetic figures.  As the existentialists have pointed out, man must act in order to be, and what he becomes is largely the summation of his actions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Paradoxical though it may seem, it is when the individual is with others that he is best able to enjoy and expand many aspects of himself, to refine and verify his self-image.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Men hate in others those things - and only those things - which they despise in themselves.  It is possible to disapprove of other people in a rational and dispassionate manner, but to hate them is an irrational and impassioned act.  The passion betrays the underlying self-contempt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Distance enables the lover to see his beloved purely in terms of the projections he hangs on her.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The general rule is that people who enjoy life enjoy marriage. Some people would be unhappy with any spouse, for they do not allow themselves happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snell Putney and Gail J. Putney&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Adjusted American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That hatred springs more from self-contempt than from a legitimate grievance is seen in the intimate connection between hatred and a guilty conscience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Eric Hoffer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Insanity in individuals is something rare - but in groups, parties, nations, and epochs, it is the rule.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If our faith is real, it must encroach upon our life. The Christian Confession in its original Church form will always be exposed to the misunderstanding that the Christian regards the Creed as a matter of heart and conscience, but that here on earth and in the world other truths hold good. The world lives in this misunderstanding; it regards the whole of Christianity as a friendly &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo;, connected with the &amp;lsquo;realm of religion&amp;rsquo;, which is respected and which ought to be left untampered with; and so we get rid of the matter! But this misunderstanding might even have come from within; a Christian might quite well wish to have this realm for himself and to guard faith like a sensitive plant. The relationship between the Church and the world has been widely understood as a question of a fixing of frontiers, whereby each secured itself behind its own frontier, although from time to time it came to a skirmish. From the Church&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, however, such a fixing of frontiers can never exhaust its task. By the very nature of the Christian Church there is only one task, to make the Confession heard in the sphere of the world as well.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us beware of remaining stuck where we are and refusing to advance to meet worldly attitudes. For instance, in Germany in 1933 there was plenty of serious, profound and living Christianity and confession&amp;hellip;. But unfortunately this faith and confession of the German Church remained embedded in the language of the Church, and did not translate what was being excellently said in the language of the Church into the political attitude demanded at the time; in which it would have become clear that the Evangelical Church had to say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to National Socialism, &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; from its very roots.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Barth&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Dogmatics in Outline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on religion and culture</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-religion-and-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He who refuses to embrace a unique opportunity loses the prize as surely as if he tried and failed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our errors are surely not such awfully solemn things. In a world where we are so certain to incur them in spite of all our caution, a certain lightness of heart seems healthier than this excessive nervousness on their behalf.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Let us give the name &lt;em&gt;hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; to anything that may be proposed to our belief; and just as the electricians speak of live and dead wires, let us speak of any hypothesis as either &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;dead&lt;/em&gt;. A live hypothesis is one which appears as a real possibility to him to whom it is proposed. If I ask you to believe in the Mahdi, the notion makes no electric connection with your nature, - it refuses to scintillate with any credibility at all. As an hypothesis it is completely dead. To an Arab, however (even if he be not one of the Mahdi&amp;rsquo;s followers), the hypothesis is among the mind&amp;rsquo;s possibilities: it is alive. This shows that deadness and liveness in an hypothesis are not intrinsic properties, but relations to the individual thinker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Will to Believe&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The distance, and as it were the space around man, grows with the strength of his intellectual vision and insight: his world becomes profounder; new stars, new enigmas, and notions are ever coming into view. Perhaps everything on which the intellectual eye has exercised its acuteness and profundity has just been an occasion for its exercise, something of a game, something for children and childish minds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Beyond Good and Evil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The perspective of the &amp;lsquo;unbeliever&amp;rsquo; on the traditional forms of belief has seldom been welcomed with any enthusiasm inside the communities of faith, but in spite of that it has provided an invaluable service to them. If one were to write the history of modern reform movements within the several world religions, the critical outsider would have to be accorded a substantial position in such a history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jaroslav Pelikan&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The World Treasury of Modern Religious Thought&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of today’s churches have bought the culture’s lie that religion is not about sex or anything else of much importance. But, as theologian Sarah Coakley has so brilliantly said, ancient Christian reflection on desire shows that Freud is exactly wrong: Talk about God is not repressed talk about sexuality; talk about sex is, in fact, repressed talk about God. To paraphrase C.S. Lewis, porn users are not to be rebuked for desiring too much but for desiring too little.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jason Byassee, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/article.php3?id_article=6105&#34;&gt;Not Your Father&amp;rsquo;s Pornography&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;First Things, &lt;/em&gt;January 2008)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dewey, Hoyt, and Freud</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the past provide the only means at command for understanding the present.  &amp;hellip;The institutions and customs that exist in the present and that give rise to present social ills and dislocations did not arise overnight.  They have a long history behind them.  Attempt to deal with them simply on the basis of what is obvious in the present is bound to result in adoption of superficial measures which in the end will only render existing problems more acute and more difficult to solve.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Growth depends upon the presence of difficulty to be overcome by the exercise of intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Dewey&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Experience and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts from a history of the Great Depression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching had investigated college athletics earlier in the year (1929) and found them to be the same across the country - &amp;ldquo;sodden with commercialism.&amp;rdquo;  Of 112 schools investigated, only 28 did not offer improper subsidies to athletes.  But instead of hanging their heads in shame, many colleges defended their athletic activities.  A Brown University professor attacked the foundation for meddling.  &amp;hellip;The Big Ten&amp;rsquo;s commissioner of athletics defended the practice of buying college players.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One telephone operator in one of the city&amp;rsquo;s largest hotels wore a new sealskin coat.  Her spending was typical.  She was playing the stock market on a broker&amp;rsquo;s margin account, and boasted neither a bank savings account, insurance, nor a penny in the world except what she earned from week to week.  But would she take her profits and convert them to bonds, as President Hoover wanted her and all Americans to do?  She would not even consider it, for the gambling fever had her, as it had a million other Americans.  The fever had her and them in red-cheeked, bright-eyed frenzy. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For billions of dollars were lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thursday&#34;&gt;that day&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the young telephone operator in the New York hotel who had invested everything she owned in her sealskin coat and in a margin account on the stock exchange.  A hotel resident, unable to complete a telephone call that night, had gone to the switchboard himself, to overhear her talking to her broker, her voice breaking and eyes bathed in tears.  All the telephone operator had left at the end of this Black Thursday was her sealskin coat and her job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;That night the relatives of Abraham Germansky, a wealthy real estate man who lived in Mount Vernon, New York, put in a frantic call to police to help them find Germansky.  He had last been seen late Thursday on Wall Street, tearing up ticker tape and scattering it along the sidewalk.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hunger was not debatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin P. Hoyt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Tempering Years &lt;/span&gt;(a history of America between 1929 and 1939)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is clear that in their play children repeat everything that has made a great impression on them in real life, and that in doing so they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/abreact&#34;&gt;abreact&lt;/a&gt; the strength of the impression and, as one might put it, make themselves master of the situation.  But on the other hand, it is obvious that all their play is influenced by a wish that dominates them the whole time - the wish to be grown-up and to be able to do what grown-up people do.  It can also be observed that the unpleasurable nature of an experience does not always unsuit it for play.  If the doctor looks down a child&amp;rsquo;s throat or carries out some small operation on him, we may be quite sure that these frightening experiences will be the subject of the next game; but we must not in that connection overlook the fact that their is a yield of pleasure from another source.  As the child passes over from the passivity of the experience to the activity of the game, he hands on the disagreeable experience to one of his playmates and in this way revenges himself on a substitute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beyond the Pleasure Principle&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Krakauer, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-krakauer-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wanders eastward, toward the sun, he comes to a mountain.  A voice calls: are you near a mountain?  Yes, he answers, I&amp;rsquo;m standing near a mountain.  Then the voice says: That mountain you are standing near is my foot; I am lying bound in the uttermost part of the earth, come set me free!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Later, when he came to think about it, he acknowledged that those hours had had a significance for him that no one could realize, and if it was true - as had just been said - that at times his writing &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;sparkled&lt;/span&gt;, then it was his memories of that time that had kindled the spark; it was a reflection of the happiness his two playmates had bestowed on him in his childhood.  For that reason they could claim a large share in his achievements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But his days varied, the good alternating with the bad, and sometimes he would be working at his best when a thought, a pair of eyes, a word from the past would strike him, quenching his inspiration.  Then he would get up and begin to pace his room from wall to wall; he had done this so often, he had worn a white path across the floor, and the path grew daily whiter&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so it turned out that only a life similar to the life of those around us, merging with it without a ripple, is genuine life, and that an unshared happiness is not happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boris Pasternak&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Doctor Zhivago&lt;/span&gt; (quoted in Krakauer, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because I was alone, however, even the mundane seemed charged with meaning.  The ice looked colder and more mysterious, the sky a cleaner shade of blue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is easy, when you are young, to believe that what you desire is no less than what you deserve, to assume that if you want something badly enough, it is your God-given right to have it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jon Krakauer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The universal triumph of the secular state has thrown all religious organizations into such a definitely secondary, and finally ineffectual, position that religious pantomime is hardly more today than a sanctimonious exercise for Sunday morning, whereas business ethics and patriotism stand for the remainder of the week.  Such a monkey-holiness is not what the functioning world requires&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A single song is being inflected through all the colorations of the human choir.  General propaganda for one or another of the local solutions is superfluous - or much rather, a menace.  The way to become human is to learn to recognize the lineaments of God in all of the wonderful modulations of the face of man.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from James, Meredith, Campbell, and Jung</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-james-meredith-campbell-and-jung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 01:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-james-meredith-campbell-and-jung/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;His lack of all thought by which to weigh the danger against the attractiveness of the bait, and of all volition to remain hungry a little while longer, is the direct measure of his lowness in the mental scale.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But whether small or great, and no matter what the stage or grade of life, the call (to adventure) rings up the curtain, always, on a mystery of transfiguration - a rite, or moment, of spiritual passage, which, when complete, amounts to a dying and a birth.  The familiar life horizon has been outgrown; the old concepts, ideals, and emotional patterns no longer fit; the time for the passing of a threshold is at hand.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Refusal of the summons converts the adventure into its negative.  Walled in boredom, hard work, or &amp;ldquo;culture,&amp;rdquo; the subject loses the power of significant affirmative action and becomes a victim to be saved.  His flowering world becomes a wasteland of dry stones and his life feels meaningless&amp;hellip;.  Whatever house he builds, it will be a house of death: a labyrinth of cyclopean walls to hide from him his Minotaur.  &amp;hellip;The myths and folk tales of the whole world make clear that the refusal is essentially a refusal to give up what one takes to be one&amp;rsquo;s own interest.  The future is regarded not in terms of an unremitting series of deaths and births, but as though one&amp;rsquo;s present system of ideals, virtues, goals, and advantages were to be fixed and made secure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Romeo wants Juliet as the filings want the magnet; and if no obstacles intervene he moves toward her by as straight a line as they.  But Romeo and Juliet, if a wall be built between them, do not remain idiotically pressing their faces against its opposite sides like the magnet and the filings with the card.  Romeo soon finds a circuitous way, by scaling the wall or otherwise, of touching Juliet&amp;rsquo;s lips directly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(The introvert&amp;rsquo;s) ideal is a lonely island where nothing moves except what he permits to move.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Carl Jung&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In all ages the man whose determinations are swayed by reference to the most distant ends has been held to possess the highest intelligence.  The tramp who lives from hour to hour; the bohemian whose engagements are from day to day; the bachelor who builds but for a single life; the father who acts for another generation; the patriot who thinks of a whole community and many generations; and finally, the philosopher and saint whose cares are for humanity and for eternity, - these range themselves in an unbroken hierarchy&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William James&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Principles of Psychology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I read, I love&lt;br /&gt;I eat, I drink&lt;br /&gt;I watch the world tilt&lt;br /&gt;I watch the children think:&lt;br /&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s so much to it&lt;br /&gt;and most of it good&lt;br /&gt;that while I&amp;rsquo;ve tendons&lt;br /&gt;to lift my head,&lt;br /&gt;like a rooster drinking&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll nod to God&lt;br /&gt;and save despair&lt;br /&gt;for when I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;William Meredith&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Preponderance&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts: Jung, Rilke, and Campbell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-jung-rilke-and-campbell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fact that an intellectual formula never has been and never will be devised which could embrace and express the manifest possibilities of life must lead to the inhibition or exclusion of other activities and ways of living that are just as important. &amp;hellip;Doubtless there are exceptional people who are able to sacrifice their entire life to a particular formula, but for most of us such exclusiveness is impossible in the long run. Sooner or later&amp;hellip;the potentialities repressed by the intellectual attitude will make themselves indirectly felt by disturbing the conscious conduct of life. &amp;hellip; The first function to be affected by the conscious inhibition is feeling, since it is the most opposed to the rigid intellectual formula and is therefore repressed the most intensely. No function can be entirely eliminated - it can only be greatly distorted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Jung, &amp;ldquo;General Descriptions of the Types&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke, tr. Leishman &amp;amp; Spender:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;And before&lt;br /&gt;A single pain has got within range of your ever-&lt;br /&gt;galloping heart, comes the tingling&lt;br /&gt;in the soles of your feet, ahead of the spring that it wells from,&lt;br /&gt;chasing into your eyes a few physical tears.&lt;br /&gt;And, in spite of all, blindly,&lt;br /&gt;your smile&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Angel: suppose there&amp;rsquo;s a place we know nothing about, and there,&lt;br /&gt;on some indescribable carpet, lovers showed all that here&lt;br /&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re for ever unable to manage - their daring&lt;br /&gt;lofty figures of heart-flight,&lt;br /&gt;their towers of pleasure, their ladders,&lt;br /&gt;long since, where ground never was, just quiveringly&lt;br /&gt;propped by each other&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Fifth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pillars, pylons, the Sphinx, all the striving thrust,&lt;br /&gt;grey, from fading or foreign town, of the spire!&lt;br /&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t all this a miracle? Angel, gaze, for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;-&lt;br /&gt;O mightiness, tell them that &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;were capable of it - my breath&amp;rsquo;s&lt;br /&gt;too short for this celebration. So, after all, we have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;failed to make use of the spaces, these generous spaces, these,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;our &lt;/em&gt;spaces. (How terribly big they must be,&lt;br /&gt;when, with thousands of years of our feeling, they&amp;rsquo;re not over-crowded.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Seventh Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The multitude of men and women choose the less adventurous way of the comparatively unconscious civic and tribal routines. But these seekers, too, are saved - by virtue of the inherited symbolic aids of society, the rites of passage, the grace-yielding sacraments, given to manking of old by the redeemers and handed down through milleniums. It is only those who know neither an inner call nor an outer doctrine whose plight truly is desperate: that is to say, most of us today, in this labyrinth without and within the heart.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joseph Campbell&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Jung and Rilke</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-jung-and-rilke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man is not a machine that can be remodelled for quite other purposes as occasion demands, in the hope that it will go on functioning as regularly as before but in a quite different way. He carries his whole history with him; in his very structure is written the history of mankind.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the extravert&amp;rsquo;s danger: he gets sucked into objects and completely loses himself in them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;C.G. Jung&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Psychological Types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Duino Elegies&lt;/strong&gt; by Rainer Maria Rilke:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s not sat tense before his own heart&amp;rsquo;s curtain?&lt;br /&gt;Up it would go: the scenery was parting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Fourth Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do you really suppose your gentle approach could have so&lt;br /&gt;convulsed him, you, that wander like morning-breezes?&lt;br /&gt;You terrified his heart, indeed; but more ancient terrors&lt;br /&gt;rushed into him in that instant of shattering contact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Third Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I know why you so blissfully touch: because the caress persists,&lt;br /&gt;because it does not vanish, the place that you&lt;br /&gt;so tenderly cover; because you perceive thereupon&lt;br /&gt;pure duration.  Until your embraces almost&lt;br /&gt;promise eternity.  Yet, when you&amp;rsquo;ve once withstood&lt;br /&gt;the startled first encounter, the window-longing,&lt;br /&gt;and that first walk, just once, through the garden together:&lt;br /&gt;Lovers, are you the same?  When you lift yourselves&lt;br /&gt;up to each other&amp;rsquo;s lips - drink unto drink:&lt;br /&gt;oh, how strangely the drinker eludes his part!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;Were not love and farewell&lt;br /&gt;so lightly laid upon shoulders, they seemed to be made&lt;br /&gt;of other stuff than with us?  Remember the hands,&lt;br /&gt;how they rest without pressure, though power is there in the torsos.&lt;br /&gt;The wisdom of those self-masters was this: we have got so far;&lt;br /&gt;ours is to touch one another like this; the gods&lt;br /&gt;may press more strongly upon us.  But that is the gods&amp;rsquo; affair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;The Second Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
