<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World War Ii on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/world-war-ii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in World War Ii on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/world-war-ii/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Frankl&#39;s &#39;Man&#39;s Search for Meaning&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-frankls-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently reading Viktor Frankl&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807014273/ref=pd_lpo_k2_dp_sr_1/189-8560150-0000706?pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=lpo-top-stripe-1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0A2K5K4WK03NGZMZ523G&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=201&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=486539851&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=0671023373&#34;&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  Frankl, a psychiatrist, was imprisoned in the Nazi concentration camps, including Auschwitz, for several years.  He survived the experience and went on to develop the theory of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy&#34;&gt;logotherapy&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a branch of psychoanalysis that focuses on human beings&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;will to meaning.&amp;rdquo;  The part of the book that discusses Frankl&amp;rsquo;s memories of his camp experience is, like any Holocaust memoir worth its salt, extremely disturbing and difficult to read, but it ought to be read in spite of that.  Here are a few (non-graphic) excerpts from the book, which I highly recommend:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Soon we had resumed the previous day&amp;rsquo;s positions in the ditch.  The frozen ground cracked under the point of the pickaxes, and sparks flew.  The men were silent, their brains numb.  My mind still clung to the image of my wife.  A thought crossed my mind: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know if she were still alive.  I knew only one thing - which I have learned well by now: Love goes very far beyond the physical person of the beloved.  It finds its deepest meaning in his spiritual being, his inner self.  Whether or not he is actually present, whether or not he is still alive at all, ceases somehow to be of importance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If there is a meaning of life at all, then there must be a meaning in suffering.  Suffering is an ineradicable part of life, even as fate and death.  Without suffering and death human life cannot be complete.  The way in which a man accepts his fate and all the suffering it entails, the way in which he takes up his cross, gives him ample opportunity - even under the most difficult circumstances - to add a deeper meaning to his life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What was really needed was a fundamental change in our attitude toward life.  We had to learn ourselves and, furthermore, we had to teach the despairing men, that &lt;em&gt;it did not really matter what we expected from life, but rather what life expected from us.&lt;/em&gt;  We needed to stop asking about the meaning of life, and instead to think of ourselves as those who were being questioned by life - daily and hourly.  Our answer must consist, not in talk and meditation, but in right action and right conduct.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I remember two cases of would-be suicide, which bore a striking similarity to each other.  Both men had talked of their intentions to commit suicide.  Both used the typical argument - they had nothing more to expect from life.  In both cases it was a question of getting them to realize that life was still expecting something from them; something in the future was expected of them.  We found, in fact, that for the one it was his child whom he adored and who was waiting for him in a foreign country.  For the other it was a thing, not a person.  This man was a scientist and had written a series of books which still needed to be finished.  His work could not be done by anyone else, any more than another person could ever take the place of the father in his child&amp;rsquo;s affections.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Not only our experiences, but all we have done, whatever great thoughts we may have had, and all we have suffered, all this is not lost, though it is past; we have brought it into being.  Having been is also a kind of being, and perhaps the surest kind.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I asked the poor creatures who listened to me attentively in the darkness of the hut to face up to the seriousness of our position.  They must not lose hope but should keep their courage in the certainty that the hopelessness of our struggle did not detract from its dignity and its meaning.  I said that someone looks down on us in different hours - a friend, a wife, somebody alive or dead, or a God - and he would not expect us to disappoint him.  He would hope to find us suffering proudly - not miserably - knowing how to die.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;When we spoke about attempts to give a man in camp mental courage, we said that he had to be shown something to look forward to in the future.  He had to be reminded that life still waited for him, that a human being waited for his return.  But after liberation?  There were some men who found that no one awaited them.  Woe to him who found that the person whose memory alone had given him courage in camp did not exist any more!  Woe to him who, when the day of his dreams finally came, found it so different from all he had longed for!  Perhaps he boarded a trolley, traveled out to the home which he had seen for years in his mind, and only in his mind, and pressed the bell, just as he has longed to do in thousands of dreams, only to find that the person who should open the door was not there, and would never be there again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Viktor E. Frankl&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
