<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steinbeck on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/steinbeck/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steinbeck on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/steinbeck/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Merton, Steinbeck, and Leon &amp; Amy Kass</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-merton-steinbeck-and-leon--amy-kass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-merton-steinbeck-and-leon--amy-kass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most important - and most neglected - elements in the beginnings of the interior life is the ability to respond to reality, to see the value and beauty in ordinary things, to come alive to the splendor that is all around us in the creatures of God. We do not see these things because we have withdrawn from them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Thomas Merton, &lt;em&gt;No Man is an Island&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s absolutely nothing to take the place of a good man.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For asceticism is not merely a matter of renouncing television, cigarettes, and gin. Before we can begin to be ascetics, we first have to learn to see life as if it were something more than a hypnotizing telecast. And we must be able to taste something besides tobacco and alcohol: we must perhaps be able to taste these luxuries themselves as if they too were good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Thomas Merton, &lt;em&gt;No Man is an Island&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But Charley doesn&amp;rsquo;t have our problems. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong to a species clever enough to split the atom but not clever enough to live in peace with itself. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t even know about race, nor is he concerned with his sister&amp;rsquo;s marriage. It&amp;rsquo;s quite the opposite. Once Charley fell in love with a daschund, a romance racially unsuitable, physically ridiculous, and mechanically impossible. But all these problems Charley ignored. He loved deeply and tried dogfully.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For in truth, despite their differences, those who treasure marriage in fact stand on common ground: whether religious or secular, they take human life in all its seriousness, affirm its goodness, and commit themselves in hope to its indefinite renewal and perpetuation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Leon and Amy Kass, &lt;em&gt;Wing to Wing, Oar to Oar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief readings on home, travel, and finance</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/brief-readings-on-home-travel-and-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/brief-readings-on-home-travel-and-finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Short History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Corn planted us; tamed cattle made us tame.&lt;br /&gt;Thence hut and citadel and kingdom came.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let us not fool ourselves. What we knew is dead, and maybe the greatest part of what we were is dead. What&amp;rsquo;s out there is perhaps good, but it&amp;rsquo;s nothing we know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The place of my origin had changed, and having gone away I had not changed with it. In my memory it stood as it once did and its outward appearance confused and angered me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;For C.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After the clash of elevator gates&lt;br /&gt;And the long sinking, she emerges where,&lt;br /&gt;A slight thing in the morning&amp;rsquo;s crosstown glare,&lt;br /&gt;She looks up toward the window where he waits,&lt;br /&gt;Then in a fleeting taxi joins the rest&lt;br /&gt;Of the huge traffic bound forever west.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ndash;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, financial analysts in pin-striped suits do not like being compared with bare-assed apes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Burton Malkiel, &lt;em&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When a stranger addresses Charley in baby talk, Charley avoids him. For Charley is not a human; he&amp;rsquo;s a dog, and he likes it that way. He feels that he is a first-rate dog and has no wish to be a second-rate human.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The public, it seemed, would buy anything. &amp;hellip;The prize&amp;hellip;must surely goe to the unknown soul who started &amp;ldquo;A Company for carrying on an undertaking of great advantage, but nobody to know what it is.&amp;rdquo; The prospectus promised unheard-of rewards. At nine o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, when the subscription books opened, crowds of people from all walks of life practically beat down the door in an effort to subscribe. Within five hours 1,000 investors handed over their money for shares in the company. Not being greedy himself, the promoter promptly closed up shop and set off for the Continent. He was never heard from again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Burton Malkiel, &lt;em&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Current events: a hilarious, brilliantly written &lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/08/01/business/media/01carr.html?_r=1&amp;hp&amp;amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on Rupert Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s sadly successful takeover of the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; and its parent, the Dow Jones Company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Thomas Merton and John Steinbeck</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-thomas-merton-and-john-steinbeck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living is more than submission: it is creation.  To live is to create one&amp;rsquo;s own world as a scene of personal happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Celebration is the beginning of confidence, therefore of power.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;The Street is For Celebration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next passage in my journey is a love affair.  I am in love with Montana.  For other states I have admiration, respect, recognition, even some affection, but with Montana it is love, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to analyze love when you&amp;rsquo;re in it.  &amp;hellip; It seems to me that Montana is a great splash of grandeur.  The scale is huge but not overpowering.  The land is rich with grass and color, and the mountains are the kind I would create if mountains were ever put on my agenda.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The calm of the mountains and the rolling grasslands had got into the inhabitants.  It was hunting season when I drove through the state.  The men I talked to seemed to me not moved to a riot of seasonal slaughter but simply to be going out to kill edible meat.  Again my attitude may be informed by love, but it seemed to me that the towns were places to live in rather than nervous hives.  People had time to pause in their occupations to undertake the passing art of neighborliness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When we live superficially, when we are always outside ourselves, never quite &amp;ldquo;with&amp;rdquo; ourselves, always divided and pulled in many directions by conflicting plans and projects, we find ourselves doing many things that we do not really want to do, saying things we do not really mean, needing things we do not really need, exhausting ourselves for what we secretly realize to be worthless and without meaning in our lives: &amp;ldquo;Why spend your money on what is not food and your earnings on what never satisfies?&amp;rdquo; (Isaiah 55:2)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having a companion fixes you in time and that the present, but when the quality of aloneness settles down, past, present, and future all flow together.  A memory, a present event, and a forecast all equally present.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the long run, the discipline of creative silence demands a certain kind of faith.  For when we come face to face with ourselves in the lonely ground of our own being, we confront many questions about the value of our existence, the reality of our commitments, the authenticity of our everyday lives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thomas Merton, &amp;ldquo;Creative Silence&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update and four quotes</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited about the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking straight from work to Union Station tomorrow afternoon, and then the usual, happy routine of a quick trip home: the #370 &lt;em&gt;Pere Marquette &lt;/em&gt;accompanied by caffeine and books (and, since it&amp;rsquo;s summer, a wonderful sunset over the harbor in St. Joseph, MI), a late-night outing to Pints &amp;amp; Quarts and Pablo&amp;rsquo;s Tacos with Muskegon friends, a Saturday morning trip to eat breakfast and shop for used books in Grand Haven, a few intense games of ping-pong with Tyler, and a run on the beach. Early Sunday morning, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the return train to Chicago and it will all seem surreal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two unique and wonderful things about this trip. First: my family got a new dog, a black retriever named Maggie, whom I will have the pleasure of meeting for the first time tomorrow night. And second: on Saturday night, two friends and I are going to a Counting Crows and Collective Soul concert in Grand Rapids.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Quotes from tonight&amp;rsquo;s reading: &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I am saying is this: the score is not what matters. Life does not have to be regarded as a game in which scores are kept and somebody wins. If you are too intent on winning, you will never enjoy playing. If you are too obsessed with success, you will forget to live. If you have learned only how to be a success, your life has probably been wasted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Love and Living&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When that time was over and the good-bys said, I had to go through the same lost loneliness all over again, and it was no less painful than at first. There seemed to be no cure for loneliness save only being alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blackberries for Amelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the far stars, of which we now are told&lt;br /&gt;That ever faster they do bolt away,&lt;br /&gt;And that a night may come in which, some say,&lt;br /&gt;We shall have only blackness to behold.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have no time for any change so great,&lt;br /&gt;But I shall see the August weather spur&lt;br /&gt;Berries to ripen where the flowers were -&lt;br /&gt;Dark berries, savage-sweet and worth the wait -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And there will come the moment to be quick&lt;br /&gt;And save some from the birds, and I shall need&lt;br /&gt;Two pails, old clothes in which to stain and bleed,&lt;br /&gt;And a grandchild to talk with while we pick.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can only imagine that the lonely man peoples his driving dreams with friends, that the loveless man surrounds himself with lovely loving women, and that children climb through the dreaming of the childless driver. And how about the areas of regrets? If only I had done so-and-so, or had not said such-and-such - my God, the damn thing might not have happened. Finding this potential in my own mind, I can suspect it in others, but I will never know, for no one ever tells. And this is why, on my journey which was designed for observation, I stayed as much as possible on secondary roads where there was much to see and hear and smell, and avoided the great wide traffic slashes which promote the self by fostering daydreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from John Steinbeck&#39;s &#39;Travels with Charley&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A dog, particularly an exotic like Charley, is a bond between strangers.  Many conversations en route began with &amp;ldquo;What degree of a dog is that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dairy man had a Ph.D. in mathematics, and he must have had some training in philosophy.  He liked what he was doing and he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be somewhere else - one of the very few contented people I met in my whole journey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then a submarine slipped to the surface half a mile away, and the day lost part of its brightness.  Farther away another dark creature slashed through the water, and another; of course they are based in New London, and this is their home.  And perhaps they are keeping the world&amp;rsquo;s peace with their venom.  I wish I could like submarines, for then I might find them beautiful, but they are designed for destruction, and while they may explore and chart the sea bottom, and draw new trade lines under the Arctic ice, their main purpose is threat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to be a center for concern?  A kind of second childhood falls on so many men.  They trade their violence for the promise of a small increase of life span.  In effect, the head of the house becomes the youngest child.  And I have searched myself for this possibility with a kind of horror.  For I have always lived violently, drunk hugely, eaten too much or not at all, slept around the clock or missed two nights of sleeping, worked too hard and too long in glory, or slobbed for a time in utter laziness.  I&amp;rsquo;ve lifted, pulled, chopped, climbed, made love with joy and taken my hangovers as a consequence, not as a punishment.  I did not want to surrender fierceness for a small gain in yardage.  My wife married a man; I saw no reason why she should inherit a baby. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I saw in their eyes something I was to see over and over in every part of the nation - a burning desire to go, to move, to get under way, anyplace, away from any Here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Ftt&amp;rdquo; usually means he would like to salute a bush or a tree.  I opened the cab door and let him out, and he went about his ceremony.  He doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it to do it well.  It is my experience that in some areas Charley is more intelligent than I am, but in others he is abysmally ignorant.  He can&amp;rsquo;t read, can&amp;rsquo;t drive a car, and has no grasp of mathematics.  But in his own field of endeavor, which was now practicing, the slow, imperial smelling over and anointing of an area, he has no peer.  Of course his horizons are limited, but how wide are mine?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley in Search of America &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Personal note: Steinbeck is my favorite American writer, and &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley &lt;/em&gt;is on track to become one of my absolute favorite books; I&amp;rsquo;m especially excited about it because my family just got a second dog, a black retriever named Maggie.  I&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet Maggie for the first time when I go home to Muskegon on Friday for a Counting Crows concert.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East of Eden quotes - third and last batch</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/east-of-eden-quotes---third-and-last-batch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/east-of-eden-quotes---third-and-last-batch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see, there’s a responsibility in being a person.  It’s more than just taking up space where air would be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He looked up at the sky.  “Lord, how the day passes!  It’s like a life - so quickly when we don’t watch it and so slowly when we do.  No,” he said, “I’m having enjoyment.  And I made a promise to myself that I would not consider enjoyment a sin.  I take a pleasure in inquiring into things.  I’ve never been content to pass a stone without looking under it.  And it is a black disappointment to me that I can never see the far side of the moon.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“But there’s all that fallow land, and here beside me is all that fallow man.  It seems a waste.  And I have a bad feeling about waste because I could never afford it.  Is it a good thing to let life lie fallow?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“What else could I do?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“You could try again.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I can’t tell you how to live your life,” Samuel said, “although I do be telling you how to live it.  I know that it might be better for you to come out from under your might-have-beens, into the winds of the world.  And while I tell you, I am myself sifting my memories, the way men pan the dirt under a barroom floor for the bits of gold dust that fall between the cracks.  It’s small mining - small mining.  You’re too young a man to be panning memories, Adam.  You should be getting yourself some new ones, so that the mining will be richer when you come to age.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I love that dust heap,” Samuel said.  “I love it the way a bitch loves her runty pup.  I love every flint, the plow-breaking outcroppings, the thin and barren topsoil, the waterless heart of her.  Somewhere in my dust heap there’s a richness.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;….&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I’m free, she’s gone,” he chanted aloud.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Virtue and vice were warp and woof of our first consciousness, and they will be the fabric of our last, and this despite any changes we may impose on field and river and mountain, on economy and manners.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It seems to me that if you or I must choose between two courses of thought or action, we should remember our dying and try so to live that our death brings no pleasure to the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The nation and the Salinas Valley changed its songs.  At first we sang of how we would knock the hell out of Helgoland and hang the Kaiser and march over there and clean up the mess them damn foreigners had made.  And then suddenly we sang, “In the war’s red curse stands the Red Cross nurse.  She’s the rose of No Man’s Land,” and we sang, “Hello, central, give me heaven, ‘cause my Daddy’s there”….  I guess we were like a tough but inexperienced little boy who gets punched in the nose in the first flurry and it hurts and we wished it was over.  [&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;As today, in Iraq.&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She went back to work.  “Do you think it’s funny to be so serious when I’m not even out of high school?” she asked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I don’t see how it could be any other way,” said Lee.  “Laughter comes later, like wisdom teeth, and laughter at yourself comes last of all in a mad race with death, and sometimes it isn’t in time.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietrich Bonhoeffer&#39;s &#39;Letters and Papers from Prison&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/dietrich-bonhoeffers-letters-and-papers-from-prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/dietrich-bonhoeffers-letters-and-papers-from-prison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After finishing Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;East of Eden &lt;/span&gt;this week, I turned my attention to Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Letters and Papers from Prison&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dietrich_Bonhoeffer&#34;&gt;Bonhoeffer&lt;/a&gt; was an incredible man with an incredible story.  He was an innovative theologian and an erudite scholar, and he wrote several highly influential books before his thirtieth birthday.  Refusing to escape the fate of his family, friends, and church, Bonhoeffer - a German - turned down an invitation to repatriate to America in 1939.  In Spring 1943, he was imprisoned by the Nazis, and two years later, on April 9, 1945, he was executed.  During his two years in prison, he corresponded with his family and a friend on the Italian front; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Letters-Papers-Prison-Dietrich-Bonhoeffer/dp/0334028361/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/104-4601658-5091105?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1181506557&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;letters&lt;/a&gt; are some of the most inspirational documents I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read, and they display an incredible level of humility, patience, and strength in adversity.  One needn&amp;rsquo;t be a Christian to find peace and reassurance in Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s writings.  Here are a few of the many passages that I found worth remembering:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;And though the world outside be mad,&lt;br /&gt;Christian or unchristian,&lt;br /&gt;Yet the world, the beautiful world&lt;br /&gt;Is utterly indestructible&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All I need to bring that home to me is a few autumn flowers, the view from my cell window, and half an hour&amp;rsquo;s exercise in the courtyard.  But in the last resort, the world, for me at any rate, consists of those few we would like to see, and whose company we long to share.  &amp;hellip;And if I could also hear a good sermon on Sundays - I often here fragments of the chorales carried up here on the breeze - it would be better still.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As we were all lying on the floor [during an air raid] yesterday, someone muttered &amp;ldquo;O God, O God&amp;rdquo; - he is normally a frivolous sort of chap - but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to offer him any Christian encouragement or comfort.  All I did was to glance at my watch and say: &amp;ldquo;It won&amp;rsquo;t last any more than ten minutes now.&amp;rdquo;  There was nothing premeditated about it; it came quite automatically, though perhaps I had a feeling that it was wrong to force religion down his throat just then.  Incidentally, Jesus himself did not try to convert the two thieves on the cross; he waited until one of them turned to him.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;As compared with marriage and the ties of kindred, friendship has no generally recognized rights, and is therefore wholly dependent on its own inherent quality.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The idea that we could have avoided many of life&amp;rsquo;s difficulties if we had taken things more quietly is one that cannot be taken seriously for a moment.  As I look back on your past I am sure that everything has turned out for the best, and so we have every reason to hope that what is happening at the present can only be for the best too.  To renounce a full life and all its joys in order to escape pain is neither Christian nor human&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nothing can make up for the absence of someone whom we love, and it would be wrong to try to find a substitute; we must simply hold out and see it through. That sounds very hard at first, but at the same time it is a great consolation, for the gap, as long as it remains unfilled, preserves the bonds between us. It is nonsense to say that God fills the gap; God does not fill it, but on the contrary, God keeps it empty and so helps us keep alive our former communion with each other, even at the cost of pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dearer and richer our memories, the more difficult the separation. But gratitude changes the pangs of memory into a tranquil joy. The beauties of the past are borne, not as a thorn in the flesh, but as a precious gift in themselves. We must take care not to wallow in our memories or to hand ourselves over to them, just as we do not gaze all the time at a valuable present, but only at special times, and apart from these keep it simply as a hidden treasure that is ours for certain. In this way the past gives us lasting joy and strength.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Another point, I am sure it is best not to talk to strangers about our feelings; that only makes matters worse, though we should always be ready to listen to the troubles of others.  Above all, we must never give way to self-pity.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;We ought to love God in our &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;lives&lt;/span&gt; and in all the blessings he sends us.  We should trust him in our lives, so that when our time comes, but not before, we may go to him in love and trust and joy.  But, speaking frankly, to long for the transcendent when you are in your wife&amp;rsquo;s arms is, to put it mildly, a lack of taste, and it is certainly not what God expects of us.  We ought to find God  and love him in the blessings he sends us.  If he pleases to grant us some overwhelming earthly bliss, we ought not to try and be more religious than God himself.  &amp;hellip;Once a man has found God in his earthly bliss and has thanked him for it, there will be plenty of opportunities for him to remind himself that these earthly pleasures are only transitory, and that it is good for him to accustom himself to the idea of eternity, and there will be many hours in which he can say with all sincerity, &amp;ldquo;I would that I were home.&amp;rdquo;  But everything in its season, and the important thing is to keep step with God, and not get a step or two in front of him&amp;hellip;.  It is arrogance to want to have everything at once - matrimonial bliss, and the cross, and the heavenly Jerusalem.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In a word, live together in the forgiveness of your sins, for without it no human fellowship, least of all a marriage, can survive.  Don&amp;rsquo;t insist on your rights, don&amp;rsquo;t blame each other, don&amp;rsquo;t judge or condemn each other, don&amp;rsquo;t find fault with each other, but take one another as you are, and forgive each other every day from the bottom of your hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I have just read this in Jean Paul: &amp;ldquo;The only joys which can stand the fires of adversity are the joys of home.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;I wish you a happy day from the bottom of my heart, and shall be with you in spirit.  May your thoughts about me be confined to happy memories of the past and hopes for the future.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East of Eden quotes, part II</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/east-of-eden-quotes-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/east-of-eden-quotes-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished John Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;East of Eden&lt;/span&gt; yesterday, and it immediately became one of my favorite novels - joining the good company of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Brothers Karamazov&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Anna Karenina&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;War and Peace&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/span&gt;, among others.  It is a story of the great tragedies that befall two generations of the Trask and Hamilton families in California&amp;rsquo;s Salinas Valley in the years leading up to and including World War I.  As in any great novel, its themes are far larger than any particular time or place: death and rebirth, grief and recovery, family and home, wealth and ethics, racism, love and lust, greatness and mediocrity.  It&amp;rsquo;s a big book, but we should be grateful for that because it makes the story last longer.  It is a hopeful manual for living that makes the world a bit bigger and clearer for those who take the time to read it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here is a second batch of quotes:&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And Samuel could remember hearing of a cousin of his mother&amp;rsquo;s in Ireland, a knight and rich and handsome, and anyway shot himself on a silken couch, sitting beside the most beautiful woman in the world who loved him.  &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a capacity for appetite,&amp;rdquo; Samuel said, &amp;ldquo;that a whole heaven and earth of cake can&amp;rsquo;t satisfy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A kind of light spread out from her.  And everything changed color.  And the world opened out.  And a day was good to awaken to.  And there were no limits to anything.  And the people of the world were good and handsome.  And I was not afraid any more.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;You can start reading if you want and it will raise up your lid a little.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want advice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nobody does.  It&amp;rsquo;s a giver&amp;rsquo;s present.  Go through the motions, Adam.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;What motions?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Act out being alive, like a play.  And after a while, a long while, it will be true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And finally comes culture, which is entertainment, relaxation, transport out of the pain of living.  And culture can be on any level, and is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The church and the whorehouse arrived in the Far West simultaneously.  And each would have been horrified to think it was a different facet of the same thing.  But surely they were both intended to accomplish the same thing: the singing, the devotion, the poetry of churches took a man out of his bleakness for a time, and so did the brothels. &amp;hellip; Indeed, if after hearing the ecstatic shrieks of climactic conversion against the thumping beat of the melodeon you had stood under the window of a whorehouse and listened to low decorous voices, you would have been likely to confuse the identities of the two ministries.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Samuel wrote to Joe, saying, &amp;ldquo;I would have been disappointed if you had not become an atheist, and I read pleasantly that you have, in your age and wisdom, accepted agnosticism the way you&amp;rsquo;d take a cookie on a full stomach.  But I would ask you with all my understanding heart not to try to convert your mother.  Your last letter only made her think you are not well.  Your mother does not believe there are many ills uncurable by good strong soup.  She puts your brave attack on the structure of our civilization down to a stomach ache.  It worries her.  Her faith is a mountain, and you, my son, haven&amp;rsquo;t even got a shovel yet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;No story has power, nor will it last, unless we feel in ourselves that it is true and true of us.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Lee said, &amp;ldquo;Remember, Mr. Hamilton, I told you I was trying to translate some old Chinese poetry into English?  &amp;hellip;Doing it, I found some of the old things as fresh and clear as this morning.  And I wondered why.  And, of course, people are only interested in themselves.  If a story is not about the hearer he will not listen.  And I here make a rule - a great and lasting story is about everyone or it will not last.  The strange and foreign is not interesting - only the deeply personal and familiar.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you want the boys to learn Chinese, Adam?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adam thought for a moment.  &amp;ldquo;It seems a time for honesty,&amp;rdquo; he said at last.  &amp;ldquo;I guess it was plain jealousy.  I gave it another name, but maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t want them to be able so easily to go way from me in a direction I couldn&amp;rsquo;t follow.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s reasonable enough and almost too human,&amp;rdquo; said Samuel.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, it seemed to me that the man who could conceive this great story [Genesis 4] would know exactly what he wanted to say and there would be no confusion in his statement.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;You say &amp;lsquo;the man.&amp;rsquo;  Do you then not think this is a divine book written by the inky finger of God?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think the mind that could think this story was a curiously divine mind.  We have had a few such minds in China too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any writing which has influenced the thinking and the lives of innumerable people is important.  Now, there are many millions in their sects and churches who feel the order, &amp;lsquo;Do thou,&amp;rsquo; and throw their weight into obedience.  And there are millions more who feel predestination in &amp;lsquo;Thou shalt.&amp;rsquo;  Nothing they may do can interfere with what will be.  But &amp;lsquo;Thou mayest&amp;rsquo;!  Why, that makes a man great, that gives him stature with the gods, for in his weakness and his filth and his murder of his brother he still has the great choice.  He can choose his course and fight it through and win.&amp;rdquo;  Lee&amp;rsquo;s voice was a chant of triumph.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adam said, &amp;ldquo;Do you believe that, Lee?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I do.  It is easy out of laziness, out of weakness, to throw oneself into the lap of deity, saying, &amp;lsquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help it; the way was set.&amp;rsquo;  But think of the glory of the choice!  That makes a man a man.  A cat has no choice, a bee must make honey.  There&amp;rsquo;s no godliness there. &amp;hellip; Confucius tells men how they shold live to have good and successful lives.  But this - this is a ladder to climb to the stars.&amp;rdquo;  Lee&amp;rsquo;s eyes shone.  &amp;ldquo;You can never lose that.  It cuts the feet from under weakness and cowardliness and laziness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
