<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 11:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/education/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Libya War on &#39;Russia Today&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/discussing-the-libya-war-on-russia-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rt.com/news/sanctions-showdown-syria-libya/&#34;&gt;Russia Today&lt;/a&gt; (RT) yesterday to discuss the U.S./NATO intervention in Libya as well as the situation in Syria - feel free to check it out if you are interested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/by444eRvSSI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My related article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Rolling the Dice in Libya&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/04/25/rolling-the-dice-in-libya/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another, unrelated op-ed of mine appeared yesterday as well in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;Michigan Education Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.educationreport.org/pubs/mer/article.aspx?id=14967&#34;&gt;National standards will stifle innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;  In it, I argue that &amp;ldquo;strict standards risk forcing students and teachers alike into a curricular straitjacket, alienating creative teachers and sapping the motivation of students.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find links to all of my online publications at my homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;www.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy across neighborhood lines</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/empathy-across-neighborhood-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations,&amp;rdquo; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Weekly&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed and add your comments &lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagoweekly.net/2009/10/28/love-thy-neighbor-in-the-wake-of-an-attack-on-the-mens-cross-country-team-its-time-to-rethink-university-community-relations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Love Thy Neighbor: In the wake of an attack on the Men’s Cross Country team, it’s time to rethink University-community relations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of Chicago is a bastion of resources and privilege in a largely underserved and segregated South Side. The University and many of its students regularly engage in outreach and volunteer programs aimed at bridging the gap between the University community and the broader South Side, and Hyde Park is often hailed as one of the most integrated neighborhoods in the United States. But there is an undeniable separation—an invisible wall—between the University and its surroundings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every day, the wall is breached by students working in local schools through the Neighborhood Schools Program, by local residents seeking treatment at the University of Chicago Hospitals, and by members of the University staff who live in nearby communities. The constant movement of people and capital between the University area and surrounding areas is a movement across the barriers of income, class, and often race, and such movement is critical to reducing tensions between the communities and promoting empathy, awareness, and mutual understanding.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the decision to cross barriers is rarely risk-free. It often requires going outside of one’s comfort zone and making oneself feel vulnerable. Sometimes the experience is rewarding, but that is not always the case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Members of the University of Chicago cross country team often see much more of the South Side than the average University of Chicago student. Their runs of four, eight, or twenty miles carry them all around the city, through neighborhoods where their presence as a large group of often scantily-clad, mostly white runners speeding along down the middle of the street comes as a surprise to the residents they encounter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran with the team for four years as a student. I remember positive experiences of having moments of connection and shared humor and understanding with some of the people we passed on our runs, of having friendly snowball fights in the winter, and of seeing communities that I would never see if not for those runs. The places I saw helped to shape my social, political, and economic awareness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also remember negative experiences: having rocks thrown at us by students, being cursed at and called racist and homophobic epithets, encountering big-and-mean-looking stray dogs, and having two teammates shot with a BB gun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week, the team was running their “Garfield Loop,” a run west on Garfield, past the Dan Ryan interchange and toward Midway Airport, when the team was shot at with paintball guns fired by an eastbound car. One team member was struck between the eyes, and the paintball buried itself in his right eye, where it caused substantial damage. His iris is now partially detached; cells deep in his eye are traumatized; and his vision in that eye is &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt; instead of the &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; it was previously. It is probable that the injury will affect his vision for the rest of his life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is there a moral to this unpleasant story? Let’s hope it isn’t, “Don’t run through unsafe neighborhoods; stick to the treadmills or the lakefront parks.” It is essential that University of Chicago students accept some personal risk in order to spend time in the neighborhoods around their school. Like all great cities, Chicago is flawed, but Chicago’s particularly egregious flaw is its sharply drawn, if invisible, barriers between communities separated by de facto segregation, uneven development, and unequal opportunities for work and education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to break down those barriers is through the continued exchange of people, conversations, and capital: we must visit each other&amp;rsquo;s homes and communities, walk awhile in each other’s shoes, and see the places where each other lives. We must see and hear our neighbors in order to empathize with them and see them in the fullness of their individuality and their common humanity. Knowledge and empathy go hand in hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The joyriders who shot my teammate in the eye with a paintball gun would not have done the same to their own family and friends, those they care most about. May we all work to expand the circle of those we care about to include all our neighbors; let us see these neighbors as neighbors, as our human family, rather than as distant others from whom we may safely separate ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he writes about education at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Think About Politics</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/how-to-think-about-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to Think About Politics,&amp;rdquo; my most recent essay, is being &lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/2009/07/how-to-think-about-politics/&#34;&gt;featured&lt;/a&gt; in the August issue of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foggedclarity.com/&#34;&gt;Fogged Clarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also pasted it below.  If you enjoy it, please consider linking to it, sharing it, or passing it along to others who might be interested.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;How to Think About Politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, question everything, beginning with the political ideas you inherited from your parents, family, community, church, and school.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create an inventory, in your mind or on paper, of these ideas: what are your strong, visceral, “gut” feelings about the political parties, religion in schools, the legalization versus criminalization of abortion, taxation, drug laws, and so on? What about your ideas about other races and social classes, and about race and class relations in general? Interrogate your emotional, pre-rational political ideology: why do you think it is the case that some people are poor, others wealthy, and others starving? Do you admire military power, or are you suspicious of it? How do you react to talk of America’s present and past wars – World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step to becoming a serious political thinker is to distance yourself, at least temporarily, from what might be called your “political inheritance” – the political ideas and values that you were infused with as a child and young adult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of these ideas may be worth keeping, of course, and it is perfectly acceptable to venture into the wilderness of new ideas and then return, older and wiser, to where you began – but it is unacceptable to never waver, even in thought, from the political ideas you grew up with. You must rediscover these ideas to make them truly your own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second step is to understand your own interests and distance yourself from them for the purposes of political thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your self-interest, whatever it may be, can probably be translated into a political and economic ideology: you are in a union, so you support unions and vote for pro-union politicians. You are an investment banker or venture capitalist, so you oppose anything – including unions – that could interfere with economic “efficiency,” that is, with your ability to “restructure” businesses and shift resources around to make a profit. You own a home in an almost entirely white, middle-class suburb where your kids attend a top-tier public school, so you oppose policies such as intradistrict school choice and property taxes that could, you feel, threaten your lifestyle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But mature political thinking requires that you think about politics in terms of the public good and what is best for society (or humanity, even) as a whole. That does not imply that mature political thinking requires a “liberal” political ideology: it is quite acceptable to believe, conservatively, that radical or revolutionary changes to the status quo would do more harm than good, or that the way things are should be tweaked and adjusted rather than significantly changed, or that the public welfare is best served through deregulation, lowered taxes, and the privatization of public institutions. But whatever political ideology you adopt, you must, if you want to begin thinking seriously about politics, adopt it for some reason other than the health of your pocketbook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, it often happens that people consciously or unconsciously wrap their self-interests in a veil of ideology – they disguise the fact that their political views are a function of their self-interest by speaking in terms of the public good, and often they even believe their own disguise. But serious thinkers must honestly examine their own views and biases, look at their own ideas with critical eyes, and constantly work to create distance between their self-interest and their political views. If these overlap, it must be by accident and coincidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Question yourself, your ideology, your vocabulary, and the beliefs behind your beliefs. And also question every overt and covert political statement, every candidate’s speech, every newspaper opinion column, every dinner-table rant, every historical narrative, and even every piece of art or literature. Politics touches everything and everything touches politics. Cultivate your awareness of the political dimension of the world, a dimension that is often hidden beneath the surface of things. A map, for example, seems straightforward and self-evident – but what part of the world did the mapmaker select as central? Which continents’ sizes are distorted?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And speaking of looking beneath the surface of things: advanced political thinking requires a partial distancing from the rancorous spats and celebrity politics that are all-too-often the central focus of 24-hour cable news stations, political talk shows, and the most popular political blogs. Thinking politically does not mean choosing a side, stepping into the echo chamber, and becoming one more unimaginative partisan foot-soldier – it is better to keep one foot in the fray and one foot in the slightly-removed world of philosophy, theory, scholarship, history, and literature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For me, this means reading both conservative and liberal blogs and websites, but favoring those that are more thoughtful and less reactive. More importantly, it means monitoring the amount of online, print, and cable news I consume, and giving primacy of place in my reading to good books – which are intrinsically more thought-out, edited, careful, and less bound to a specific historical moment than even the best newspapers and websites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third step toward mature political thinking involves understanding that we look at political issues through certain lenses – lenses of theory, of history, and of our biases and ideologies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best political thinkers do not get trapped in one lens. Rather, like an ophthalmologist conducting an eye examination, they shift from lens to lens and look at a problem through as many lenses as possible in order to identify which lens best clarifies the problem and points the way to a possible solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s take the contemporary debate about school reform and vouchers as an example. Conservatives use the analogy of market economics to argue that if we privatize schools and school services and create a more competitive school system, the outcome will be better and more educationally efficient; liberals argue that it is a profound mistake to think about schooling in economic terms, and that we should focus on improving the public schools, which reflect our moral commitment to providing equal educational opportunity to every American child. But why not look at education through both lenses – the lens of economics and the lens of ethics? And also the lenses of history and law?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take practically any political or economic problem and gather a room full of academic specialists: one each in political philosophy, political psychology, law, evolutionary biology, theology or religious studies, women’s studies, history, economics, sociology, and anthropology. Each of these experts will speak intelligently about the issue, looking at it through the lens of their discipline. And each will have something valuable to contribute to the debate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And so we arrive at a final guideline for engaging in serious political thought: become a lifelong self-educator, and never stop critically examining your own political ideas and those you find in contemporary debates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Political issues are infinitely complex, and the political loudmouths of our world who claim to have it all figured out are cashing in on a lie. You, their target consumer, have the power to reject the narrow wares they peddle and turn to better, more thoughtful sources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If there is one slogan and sound-bite that is worth adopting, it is this: “Well, it isn’t really that simple.”&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent posts on education at Wide Awake Minds</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-posts-on-education-at-wide-awake-minds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few of my recent posts at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, in case you missed them:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/few-of-things-you-can-do-in-great.html&#34;&gt;A few of the things you can do in a great university&lt;/a&gt;, in which I argue that if students want to make the most of their school years in general and their college years in particular, they must take ownership of their education and elect to do what is difficult.  I propose a few of the ways in which college students can do so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/thinking-critically-about-critical.html&#34;&gt;Thinking critically about critical pedagogy&lt;/a&gt;, in which I encourage my readers to recognize the reality and complexity of cultural and institutional racism, but also to think critically about the theoretical lenses of critical pedagogy (a framework aimed at correcting racism and other power disparities).  This post sparked a great discussion in the comment section as well as some fruitful email exchanges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/beyond-preparing-our-kids-for-21st.html&#34;&gt;Beyond &amp;ldquo;preparing our kids for 21st-century jobs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - a call to do away with sloganeering about education as job-preparation, and a brief sketch of the case for universal liberal education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/quotes-from-deborah-meiers-in-schools.html&#34;&gt;Ideas about education from Deborah Meier&lt;/a&gt;, one of the greatest progressive educators of our time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/2009/07/building-collection-of-language_09.html&#34;&gt;On language learning textbooks&lt;/a&gt; - A personal account of my love of language learning textbooks, and what I have learned from them about how and why we should learn world languages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;Wide Awake Minds&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to link to it on your blog or social network or pass it along to someone who might be interested in reading it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark C. Taylor on &#39;reforming higher education&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/re-mark-c.-taylor-on-reforming-higher-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markctaylor.com/&#34;&gt;Mark C. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, contrarian philosopher and chair of Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Religion, caused a firestorm in the academic community with his op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;End the University as We Know It&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt;.  The op-ed remains at the top of the NYT&amp;rsquo;s most-emailed list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are few better places to have a debate about the philosophy of education than the University of Chicago, where the Core Curriculum and the school&amp;rsquo;s historical emphasis on liberal education and distaste for vocational education permeates everything.  On the U of C men&amp;rsquo;s cross country email list, five current and former runners had weighed in on Taylor&amp;rsquo;s piece by this morning.  My thoughts were these:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.  You can&amp;rsquo;t wish away the disciplines.  I would argue that you can familiarize yourself with several disciplines and do interdisciplinary work, but &amp;ldquo;interdisciplinary&amp;rdquo; means within and among the disciplines.  Examining a problem or topic in the abstract before locating oneself in a discipline, or in several disciplines, could easily lead to amateurism and reinventing the wheel, and it would likely lead to missing or mistaking the assumptions upon which existing scholarship has been built.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does it make sense to look at questions through as many  disciplinary lenses as possible?  Absolutely.  And yet the critical advantage provided by writing within a discipline, and what an ad hoc interdisciplinary analysis of a topic risks missing, is clarity of assumptions.  You always know the outlines of where a Chicago School economist or a realist in IR theory or a Frankfurt School critic is coming from, and that helps you understand the nuances and innovations of his or her argument.  If you begin a research project with the idea that you are writing something above and beyond the disciplines, something entirely new, chances are good that 1. you are mistaken, 2. you will do work that has been done more thoroughly before, and 3. you will be forced to make arbitrary choices at every step.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.  Taylor bases his argument on economic grounds, not educational or philosophy of education grounds.  And so he speaks of academic journals and University presses in terms of &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for their &amp;ldquo;products,&amp;rdquo; as if they were inferior versions of Newsweek and Random House.  If we are to do interdisciplinary work, then we must learn when and how to apply the conceptual lenses of each discipline appropriately.  By choosing to give primacy to a view of American higher education as seen through the disciplinary lenses of economics, Taylor implicitly endorses the value choices or axioms that form the foundation of contemporary economic thinking and suggests that these should govern our thinking about higher education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true that we can learn something new about higher education by looking at it through economic lenses, but I would suggest that the central purposes of higher education differ from the purposes of the market (efficiency, profit, increased &amp;ldquo;utility&amp;rdquo;/pleasure).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The twofold purpose of graduate programs is, first, to train scholars who can contribute, in whatever small way, to the sum of human knowledge, and second, to train these scholars to teach at the undergraduate level; if we judge that these are valuable and necessary functions in our society, as I believe we must, then we ought not to begin our critique of them with the question of what the consumer or the market &amp;ldquo;wants.&amp;rdquo;  I would also add that strong universities are at least partially public goods that add value to society and humanity at large, not just to the undergraduates they teach, and so it is a mistake to think of higher education as merely a collection of transactions between colleges and students.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.  If I am right in claiming that one of the central purposes of graduate education is to contribute to the sum of human knowledge - to train scholars, not just advanced students - then I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that Taylor&amp;rsquo;s idea of substituting Powerpoint presentations and video games for dissertations misses the point, as does his suggestion that we introduce non-academic vocational training into graduate education.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Ryan McCarl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Mark Taylor&amp;rsquo;s original op-ed is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/27/opinion/27taylor.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Reading Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/2008-reading-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  At the end of each of the past three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a post listing the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read over the course of the year in order to bring these books to the attention of others.  My lists from 2007 and 2006 are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2007/12/2007-book-recommendations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.blogspot.com/2006/12/nothing-like-reading-list-to-start-new.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve put the titles of the five books most important to me this year in bold, and I&amp;rsquo;ve linked each book to its Amazon.com page.  Enjoy!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Arons, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Compelling-Belief-Culture-American-Schooling/dp/0870235249/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899752&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Compelling Belief: The Future of American Schooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (education/religion/politics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Doniger, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Implied-Spider-Wendy-Doniger/dp/0231111711/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899795&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics and Theology in Myth&lt;/a&gt; (religion / mythology)&lt;br /&gt;Du Bois, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899814&amp;amp;sr=1-4&#34;&gt;Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt; (history / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frank, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Falling-Behind-Rising-Inequality-Wildavsky/dp/0520252527/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230899838&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Falling Behind: How Rising Inequality Harms the Middle Class&lt;/a&gt; (economics / politics)&lt;br /&gt;Frankel, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Faith-Freedom-Religious-Liberty-Critical/dp/0809015757/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Faith and Freedom: Religious Liberty in America&lt;/a&gt; (religion / politics / law)&lt;div&gt;Gibran, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Prophet-Kahlil-Gibran/dp/000100039X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900039&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; philosophy / religion)&lt;br /&gt;Hamsun, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900186&amp;amp;sr=1-3&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Harrison, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Returning-Earth-Novel-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802143318/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Returning to Earth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harrison, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/True-North-Jim-Harrison/dp/0802142060/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900175&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;True North&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;br /&gt;Hemingway, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/a&gt; (2nd reading; literature)&lt;br /&gt;Kerouac, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dharma-Bums-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/0143039601/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900162&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/a&gt; (literature)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Laxness, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Independent-People-Halldor-Laxness/dp/0679767924/ref=pd_sim_b_1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Independent People&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Mann, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Man-Sea-Ernest-Hemingway/dp/0684801221/ref=pd_sim_b_3&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (literature)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Milosz, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Native-Realm-Self-Definition-Czeslaw-Milosz/dp/0374528306/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900582&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Native Realm: A Search for Self-Definition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt; (memoirs / literature / history)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Putney &amp;amp; Putney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Adjusted-American-Neurosis-Individual-Society/dp/0060900954/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900593&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;The Adjusted American: Normal Neurosis in the Individual and Society&lt;/a&gt; (psychology)&lt;br /&gt;Salomon &amp;amp; Valdez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900612&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt; (design / environment)&lt;br /&gt;Walzer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Unjust-Wars-Historical-Illustrations/dp/0465037070/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1230900722&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Just and Unjust Wars&lt;/a&gt; (3rd reading; politics / international relations)    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael McConnell on multiculturalism and educational choice</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/michael-mcconnell-on-multiculturalism-and-educational-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/michael-mcconnell-on-multiculturalism-and-educational-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite insistent demands by minority groups, principally Catholics, but including Jews, Presbyterians, Baptists, and Methodists, for equal funding for their free schools, the common school movement soon achieved a monopoly of public funding.  Many states even adopted constitutional provisions barring state funding of religious schools, and a federal constitutional amendment to that effect was narrowly defeated in Congress.  The opposition to particularistic private schools grew to the extent that, in the early twentieth century, some states passed laws forbidding the education of children in languages other than English and banning private schools altogether.  These efforts were promptly overturned by the Supreme Court, on the ground that &amp;ldquo;[t]he fundamental theory of liberty upon which all governments in this union repose excludes any general power of the state to standardize its children by forcing them to accept instruction from public teachers only.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;Pierce v. Society of Sisters&lt;/em&gt;, 1925)&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The leading elementary and secondary school textbooks virtually neglect any mention of religious influences or ideas in history, ethics, or social studies.  Thus, the &amp;ldquo;public values&amp;rdquo; inculcated by the public schools are not, in fact, the values held by the large majority of the American public, but the values held by a secular minority.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It is not possible, practically or theoretically, for public schools to be &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; with respect to contentious questions of morality, politics, and religion.  The more the school attempts to be evenhanded, the more it will appear to endorse a position of relativism, or worse, cynicism.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;No shifts in constitutional doctrine governing the conduct of the public schools can solve this problem, because it inheres in the nature of things.  The Supreme Court can alter the character of public education, making it more religious or more secular, but it cannot make public education genuinely more pluralistic.  A common school is a common school.  That is its blessing and its curse.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;While fears of church-state constitutional problems are often cited by opponents of educational choice, those fears are groundless.  Whatever may be the flaws in the educational choice idea, it should be debated on its merits and not rejected on spurious constitutional grounds.  In fact, far from offending the First Amendment, an educational choice plan is much more consistent with the pluralistic vision of the First Amendment than is granting secular schools a monopoly of public funds.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The common school movement now teaches our children, unintentionally, to be value-less, culture-less, root-less, and religion-less.  It can no longer achieve its crowning purpose of providing a unifying moral culture in the face of our many differences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_W._McConnell&#34;&gt;Michael W. McConnell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Multiculturalism, Majoritarianism, and Educational Choice: What Does Our Constitutional Tradition Have to Say?,&amp;rdquo; University of Chicago Legal Forum 1991.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Alfie Kohn and Virginia Woolf</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons policymakers seek to impose detailed curriculum mandates.  They may fundamentally distrust educators: Much of the current standards movement is just the latest episdoe in a long, sorry history of trying to create a teacher-proof curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;These days almost anything can be done to students and to schools, no matter how ill-considered, as long as it is done in the name of raising standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s convenient for us to assume that kids who cut corners are just being lazy, because then it&amp;rsquo;s the kids who have to be fixed.  But perhaps they&amp;rsquo;re just being rational.  They have adapted to an environment where results, not intellectual exploration, are what count.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Assessment is used less to support learning than to evaluate and compare people.  &amp;hellip;(Standardized testing) screens and sorts students for the convenience of industry (and higher education).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What happens to schools when they are plunged into the marketplace?  To begin with, they must shift much of their time and resources to, well, marketing.  (It is those who sell themselves skillfully, not those who are especially good at what they do, who tend to succeed in a competitive market.)  Moreover, the pressure to make themselves look better presents a temptation to screen out less desirable students, those whose education takes more effort or expense.  &amp;ldquo;The problem with public schools,&amp;rdquo; remarked author John Chubb, &amp;ldquo;is that they must take whoever walks in the door.&amp;rdquo;  The philosophical core of the privatization movement for which Chubb speaks is neatly revealed in the use of the word &lt;em&gt;problem &lt;/em&gt;in that sentence.  &lt;em&gt;[Note: I disagree with this statement, but it is the among the best anti-voucher arguments I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alfie Kohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Essays-Standards-Grading-Follies/dp/0807032670&#34;&gt;What Does it Mean to Be Well Educated?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Highly recommended.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And, thanking Mr. Ramsay for it and Mrs. Ramsay for it and the hour and the place, crediting the world with a power which she had not suspected - that one could walk away down that long gallery not alone any more but arm in arm with somebody - the strangest feeling in the world, and the most exhilarating&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Here she saddened, darkened, and came back to her chair, there could be no disputing this: an unmarried woman (she lightly took her hand for a moment), an unmarried woman has missed the best of life.  The house seemed full of children sleeping and Mrs. Ramsay listening; shaded lights and regular breathing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;How strangely he was venerable and laughable at one and the same time.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;She bore about with her, she could not help knowing it, the torch of her beauty; she carried it erect into any room that she entered; and after all, veil it as she might, and shrink from the monotony of bearing that it imposed on her, her beauty was apparent.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The very stone one kicks with one&amp;rsquo;s boot will outlast Shakespeare.  His own little light would shine, not very brightly, for a year or two, and would then be merged in some bigger light, and that in a bigger still.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All at once he realised that it was this: it was this: - she was the most beautiful person he had ever seen.  &amp;hellip;For the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; a man digging in a drain stopped digging and looked at her, let his arm fall down and looked at her; for the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; felt the wind and the cyclamen and the violets for he was walking with a beautiful woman.  He had hold of her bag.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Virginia Woolf&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;To the Lighthouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nuclear Peace and its Consequences for China&#39;s Rise</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/the-nuclear-peace-and-its-consequences-for-chinas-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just put the finishing touches on my M.A. thesis, bringing one of the most stressful months of my life to a satisfying close.  10,181 words, 45 pages, three entirely different drafts, and an ungodly amount of writing and revision.  I am happy with the finished product and will turn it in tomorrow morning, then post a link to it online.  My faculty advisor was &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Mearsheimer&#34;&gt;John Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt;, the best professor I&amp;rsquo;ve had at the U of C and one of the most influential international relations scholars in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The thesis:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I argue that security conflict between the U.S. and China can be managed short of war, regardless of how strong China becomes. This is the case because of the phenomenon known as the “nuclear peace”; because every great power in the contemporary international system possesses a secure, second-strike nuclear capability, the best prediction we can make is that every possible conflict between the U.S. and China - or any pair of contemporary great powers - will be stopped short of war because of nuclear deterrence, which raises the costs of war to unacceptably high levels, outweighing all potential political gains to be had by conquest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this behind me, I&amp;rsquo;m turning my mind away from school and on to other things, with the exception of my Japanese and Norwegian coursework.  I still need to finish Thomas Mann&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading several books on education: Alfie Kohn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;What Does It Mean to Be Well Educated?, &lt;/em&gt;Nel Nodding&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Philosophy of Education&lt;/em&gt;, and Myron Lieberman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Educational Morass, &lt;/em&gt;among others.  I am extremely excited for this weekend, as I am going home to Muskegon, MI to hang out with my wonderful family for the first time since March.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I feel as though an enormous burden has been lifted from me.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Mann, Golley, and Eliot</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-mann-golley-and-eliot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Must-read: the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/span&gt; on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/24/us/24land.html?hp&#34;&gt;severe case of protracted bullying&lt;/a&gt;.  This is real, and it&amp;rsquo;s an enormous problem.  There is a spectrum of school violence ranging from verbal harassment and bullying all the way to school shootings, and it needs to be taken more seriously and addressed more quickly at every stage.  An atmosphere of security and mutual respect in classrooms is essential to students&amp;rsquo; well-being and ability to learn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A human being lives out not only his personal life as an individual, but also, consciously or subconsciously, the lives of his epoch and contemporaries.  &amp;hellip;All sorts of personal goals, purposes, hopes, prospects may float before the eyes of a given individual, from which he may then glean the impulse for exerting himself for great deeds; if the impersonal world around him, however, if the times themselves, despite all their hustle and bustle, provide him with neither hopes nor prospects, if they secretly supply him with evidence that things are in fact hopeless, without prospect or remedy, if the times respond with hollow silence to every conscious or subconscious question, however it may be posed, about the ultimate, unequivocal meaning of all exertions and deeds that are more than exclusively personal - then it is almost inevitable&amp;hellip;that the situation will have a crippling effect, which, following moral and spiritual paths, may even spread to that person&amp;rsquo;s physical and organic life.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Two days of travel separate this young man (and young he is, with few firm roots in life) from his everyday world, especially from what might be called his duties, interests, worries, and prospects - separate him far more than he had dreamed possible as he rode to the station in a hansom cab.  Space, as it rolls and tumbles away between him and his native soil, proves to have powers normally ascribed only to time; from hour to hour, space brings about changes very like those time produces, yet surpassing them in certain ways.  Space, like time, gives birth to forgetfulness, but does so by removing an individual from all relationships and placing him in a free and pristine state - indeed, in but a moment it can turn a pedant and a philistine into something like a vagabond.  Time, they say, is water from the river Lethe, but alien air is a similar drink; and if its effects are less profound, it works all the more quickly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;All divine attributes have been taken over by human hands,&amp;rdquo; (Hirato Renkichi) wrote.  &amp;ldquo;Today, the engine of God is the engine of the city, and partakes in the activities of humanity&amp;rsquo;s millions.&amp;rdquo;  Almost every sentence of this document seems to anticipate Paul Virilio&amp;rsquo;s 1997 equation of &amp;ldquo;new technologies&amp;rdquo; with the &amp;ldquo;three traditional characteristics of the Divine: ubiquity, instantaneity, and immediacy.&amp;rdquo;  Although Virilio refers here to a much later technological revolution, the logic of his thinking echoes the poetics of Hirato Renkichi.  &amp;hellip;For Hirato, the powers of the divine had come to reside in &amp;ldquo;the impulsive candor of the machine, in its light, its heat, its ceaseless rhythms.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gregory Golley&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See: Realism, Science, and Ecology in Japanese Literary Modernism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When a poet&amp;rsquo;s mind is perfectly equipped for its work, it is constantly amalgamating disparate experience; the ordinary man&amp;rsquo;s experience is chaotic, irregular, fragmentary.  The latter falls in love, or reads Spinoza, and these two experiences have nothing to do with each other, or with the noise of the typewriter or the smell of cooking; in the mind of the poet these experiences are always forming new wholes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;T.S. Eliot&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Metaphysical Poets,&amp;rdquo; quoted in Golley, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;When Our Eyes No Longer See&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hermann Hesse&#39;s &#39;Beneath the Wheel&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hermann-hesses-beneath-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hermann-hesses-beneath-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematics, as far as he was concerned, was a Sphinx charged with deceitful puzzles whose cold malicious gaze transfixed her victims, and he gave the monster a wide berth.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What would many happy citizens and trustworthy officials have become but unruly, stormy innovators and dreamers of useless dreams, if not for the effort of their schools?  In young beings there is something wild, ungovernable, uncultured which first has to be tamed.  It is like a dangerous flame that has to be controlled or it will destroy.  Natural man is unpredictable, opaque, dangerous, like a torrent cascading out of uncharted mountains.  At the start, his soul is a jungle without paths or order.  And, like a jungle, it must first be cleared and its growth thwarted.  Thus it is the school&amp;rsquo;s task to subdue and control man with force and make him a useful member of society, to kindle those qualities in him whose development will bring him to triumphant completion.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For he was aware that in the academy he would have to be even more ambitious if he wanted to outstrip his new fellow students.  Why did he want to surpass them actually?  He didn&amp;rsquo;t really know himself.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;This magnificent monastery, hidden behind hills and woods, has long been reserved for the exclusive use of the students of the Protestant Theological Academy in order that their receptive young spirits will be surrounded by an atmosphere of beauty and grace.  Simultaneously the young people are removed from the distracting influence of their towns and families and are preserved from the harmful sight of the active life.  So it is possible to let them live under the definite impression that their life&amp;rsquo;s goal consists exclusively of the study of Hebrew and Greek and sundry subjects and to turn the thirst of young souls toward pure and ideal studies and enjoyments.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;If someone else were to approach him and vigorously seek to win his friendship, he would respond gladly.  Like a wallflower he stayed in the background waiting for someone to fetch him, someone more courageous and stronger than himself to tear him away and force him into happiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hermann Hesse&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beneath the Wheel&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from recent reading: Robert Jackson, Nate Shaw</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-recent-reading-robert-jackson-nate-shaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-recent-reading-robert-jackson-nate-shaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Struggles to coerce uniformity of sentiment in support of some end thought essentially to their time and country have been waged by many good, as well as by evil, men.  &amp;hellip;Those who begin coercive elimination of dissent soon find themselves exterminating dissenters.  Compulsory unification of opinion achieves only the unanimity of the graveyard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Robert Jackson, writing for the U.S. Supreme Court&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Virginia_State_Board_of_Education_v._Barnette&#34;&gt;West Virginia State Board of Education v. Barnette&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(1943)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Court found that the underlying issue was not any claimed conflict between liberty of conscience and the state&amp;rsquo;s ability to survive in time of crisis.  The issue was not weak versus strong government, but, rather, seeing the strength of America in &amp;ldquo;individual freedom of mind&amp;rdquo; rather than in &amp;ldquo;officially disciplined uniformity for which history indicates a disappointing and disastrous end.&amp;rdquo;  Enforced conformity, far from teaching the value of liberty, would &amp;ldquo;strangle the free mind at its source and teach youth to discount important principles of our government as mere platitudes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jordan Lorence and Harvey A. Silverglate&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefire.org/&#34;&gt;FIRE&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Guide to First-Year Orientation and Thought Reform on Campus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a whole, if children got book learnin enough they&amp;rsquo;d jump off of this country; they don&amp;rsquo;t want to plow, don&amp;rsquo;t want no part of no sort of field work.  That&amp;rsquo;s the way it runs here.  The biggest majority runs off to some place where they can get a public job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And I never did forget none of his treatments toward me.  You forever remember the wrongs done to you as long as you live.  But it&amp;rsquo;s just like forgivin if you just go on in this world and don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;So my daddy married Maggie Reed and him and her was the father and mother of thirteen children - my old daddy was a rooster, he was a humdinger.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;My grandmother and other people that I knowed grew up in slavery time, they wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with their feredom.  They felt like motherless children - they wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied but they had to live under the impression that they were.  Had to act in a way just as though everything was all right.  But they would open up every once in a while and talk about slavery time - they didn&amp;rsquo;t know nothin about no freedom then, didn&amp;rsquo;t know what it was but they wanted it.  And when they got it they knew that what they got wasn&amp;rsquo;t what they wanted, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t freedom, really.  Had to do whatever the white man directed em to do, couldn&amp;rsquo;t voice their heart&amp;rsquo;s desire.  That was the way of life that I was born and raised into.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, years ago I heard that President Lincoln freed the colored people; but it didn&amp;rsquo;t amount to a hill of beans.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He was imprisoned in slavery for fifteen years - slavery were equal or worser than prison, but both of em bad and the poor colored man knows more about them two subjects than anybody.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And when I got to be a little old boy, when I got big enough to catch on to what people said, and even to the words of the old people, and the Bible, it was instilled in me many a time: the bottom rail will come to the top someday.  I taken that to mean a change in the later years, durin of my lifetime maybe.  I believe, if that day come, the poor generation on earth will banish away their toils and snares.  But won&amp;rsquo;t nobody do it for them but themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I was big enough and old enough to abominate what I seed.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t a slave but he lived like one.  Because he had to take what the white people gived to get along.  That much of slavery ways was still hangin on.  According to slave days you wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed the privilege to seek knowledge without the white man, master man, allowin you.  And that was the rule durin of my daddy&amp;rsquo;s lifetime and through my life, to be sure.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;They claimed they had a note against him and they took all he had.  In those days, it was out of the knowledge of the colored man to understand that if you gived a man a note on everything you had, exactly how you was subject to the laws.  Because the colored man wasn&amp;rsquo;t educated in the laws for his use; they was a great, dark secret to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nate Shaw&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Theodore Rosengarten (ed), &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/All-Gods-Dangers-Life-Nate/dp/0226727742/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1201377890&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;All God&amp;rsquo;s Dangers: The Life of Nate Shaw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hamsun, Du Bois, and Salomon</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-du-bois-and-salomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hamsun-du-bois-and-salomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-Happy &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/watch?v=PbUtL_0vAJk&#34;&gt;Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/a&gt; Day!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Honest and earnest criticism from those whose interests are most nearly touched - criticism of writers by readers, of government by those governed, of leaders by those led - this is the soul of democracy and the safeguard of modern society.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In fact the burden belongs to the nation, and the hands of none of us are clean if we bend not our energies to righting these wrongs.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The opposition to Negro education in the South was at first bitter, and showed itself in ashes, insult, and blood; for the South believed an educated Negro to be a dangerous Negro.  And the South was not wholly wrong; for education among all kinds of men always has had, and always will have, an element of danger and revolution, of dissatisfaction and discontent.  Nevertheless, men strive to know.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To be a poor man is hard, but to be a poor race in a land of dollars is the very bottom of hardships.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;W.E.B. Du Bois&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Souls-Black-Norton-Critical-Editions/dp/039397393X/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200937222&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;The Souls of Black Folk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His emotion had made him a boy again, a child sitting quietly with folded arms.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s spring, I&amp;rsquo;m walking into the new season,&amp;rsquo; Rolandsen answered over his shoulder as he went by.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;On the other hand, he was not God, he could not contain his heart if it insisted on flying away in the spring.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The nights too were bright and sunny.  It was weather for dreamers, for young people to flit about in restless excitement.  They wandered the roads at night, singing and beating the air with sallow-twigs.  And from all the isles and skerries came the sound of birds: guillemots and oyster-catchers and gulls and eiderducks.  The seal thrust his dripping head up out of the water and looked around, then dived back down again to his own world.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;He went to the sexton&amp;rsquo;s house to look for Olga.  Now that it was spring Rolandsen had to have a sweetheart; it was no easy matter to hold his own great heart in check.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Alas, Rolandsen was ever hopeful; it took very little to rouse his expectations.  But it had to be admitted that he was also good at bearing disappointments; he was proud and resilient and his spirit was never broken.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dreamers-Directions-Classics-Knut-Hamsun/dp/0811213218&#34;&gt;Dreamers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some people are always getting a bigger boat, but rarely sail.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All these books boil down to the same message: &amp;lsquo;Resist the urge to buy.&amp;rsquo;  Once you learn how to do it, it becomes second nature.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Most people find that stuff does indeed expand to fill the space provided.  Do you want to encourage this tendency with the stuff in your house?  Extra space will cost you in several ways: money and times to decorate, clean, and maintain; energy to heat and cool all that space; and outdoor space (the more you put under roof, the less you&amp;rsquo;ll have outside).  There&amp;rsquo;s also the house law of diminishing returns: the difference between having one bathroom or none is enormous, but between two or three may be negligible.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Living smaller frees up&amp;hellip;time and money to pursue fun.  Having good friends is a proven mood elevator.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Polls show that most Americans believe we must earn about twice the median income to be solidly middle class - that is, we believe that what we earn, on average, is just not enough.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shay Salomon and Nigel Valdez&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Little-House-Small-Planet-Possibilities/dp/1592288685/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1200937031&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Little House on a Small Planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dewey, Hoyt, and Freud</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 01:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-dewey-hoyt-and-freud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the past provide the only means at command for understanding the present.  &amp;hellip;The institutions and customs that exist in the present and that give rise to present social ills and dislocations did not arise overnight.  They have a long history behind them.  Attempt to deal with them simply on the basis of what is obvious in the present is bound to result in adoption of superficial measures which in the end will only render existing problems more acute and more difficult to solve.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Growth depends upon the presence of difficulty to be overcome by the exercise of intelligence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Dewey&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Experience and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts from a history of the Great Depression:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching had investigated college athletics earlier in the year (1929) and found them to be the same across the country - &amp;ldquo;sodden with commercialism.&amp;rdquo;  Of 112 schools investigated, only 28 did not offer improper subsidies to athletes.  But instead of hanging their heads in shame, many colleges defended their athletic activities.  A Brown University professor attacked the foundation for meddling.  &amp;hellip;The Big Ten&amp;rsquo;s commissioner of athletics defended the practice of buying college players.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One telephone operator in one of the city&amp;rsquo;s largest hotels wore a new sealskin coat.  Her spending was typical.  She was playing the stock market on a broker&amp;rsquo;s margin account, and boasted neither a bank savings account, insurance, nor a penny in the world except what she earned from week to week.  But would she take her profits and convert them to bonds, as President Hoover wanted her and all Americans to do?  She would not even consider it, for the gambling fever had her, as it had a million other Americans.  The fever had her and them in red-cheeked, bright-eyed frenzy. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For billions of dollars were lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thursday&#34;&gt;that day&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the young telephone operator in the New York hotel who had invested everything she owned in her sealskin coat and in a margin account on the stock exchange.  A hotel resident, unable to complete a telephone call that night, had gone to the switchboard himself, to overhear her talking to her broker, her voice breaking and eyes bathed in tears.  All the telephone operator had left at the end of this Black Thursday was her sealskin coat and her job.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;That night the relatives of Abraham Germansky, a wealthy real estate man who lived in Mount Vernon, New York, put in a frantic call to police to help them find Germansky.  He had last been seen late Thursday on Wall Street, tearing up ticker tape and scattering it along the sidewalk.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hunger was not debatable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin P. Hoyt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Tempering Years &lt;/span&gt;(a history of America between 1929 and 1939)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is clear that in their play children repeat everything that has made a great impression on them in real life, and that in doing so they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefreedictionary.com/abreact&#34;&gt;abreact&lt;/a&gt; the strength of the impression and, as one might put it, make themselves master of the situation.  But on the other hand, it is obvious that all their play is influenced by a wish that dominates them the whole time - the wish to be grown-up and to be able to do what grown-up people do.  It can also be observed that the unpleasurable nature of an experience does not always unsuit it for play.  If the doctor looks down a child&amp;rsquo;s throat or carries out some small operation on him, we may be quite sure that these frightening experiences will be the subject of the next game; but we must not in that connection overlook the fact that their is a yield of pleasure from another source.  As the child passes over from the passivity of the experience to the activity of the game, he hands on the disagreeable experience to one of his playmates and in this way revenges himself on a substitute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Beyond the Pleasure Principle&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
