<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/family/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Solomon&#39;s &#39;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-solomons-judaism-a-very-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s1600-h/judaism.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5394862253055997906&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/St5mos2Q99I/AAAAAAAAA2c/CCU7mksrFPs/s400/judaism.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 215px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 200px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin Buber and Emanuel Levinas put their faith in the God of relationships.  &lt;em&gt;Alles Leben ist Begegnung&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;all life is encounter&amp;rsquo;), declared Buber, and the important thing is to get your relationship with God and with people right (I-Thou, rather than I-It); from that relationship, which is the essence of Revelation, ethical action flows; laws and rules are feeble attempts to capture revelation, and doomed to inadequacy.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Genesis 1:27 states clearly enough: &amp;lsquo;So God created humankind in his own image; in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&amp;rsquo; This implies that in using our concept of God to model human behavior we should not distinguish between male and female.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Emil Fackenheim grounds his theology in the actual resistance of Shoah [Holocaust] victims to whom no realistic hope remained: &amp;lsquo;A philosophical Tikkun [&amp;lsquo;repair&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;restoration&amp;rsquo;] is possible after the Holocaust because a philosophical Tikkun already took place, however fragmentarily, during the Holocaust itself&amp;rsquo;; the rebirth of Israel, and a new constructive dialogue with a self-critical Christianity, are essential to this process.  Fackenheim is also noted for his statement that there should be a 614th commandment, surplus to the 613 of tradition - to survive as Jews, to remember, never to despair of God, lest we hand Hitler a posthumous victory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Is there such a thing as a &amp;lsquo;just war&amp;rsquo;, and if so, what are the conditions of engagement?  Out of this debate emerged the novel concept of &lt;em&gt;tohar ha-nesheq&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;lsquo;purity of arms&amp;rsquo;), which demands &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt; that the fighting force take special risks to avoid harm to non-combatants and to minimize enemy casualties.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Many Jews, including secular ones, see Israel as the fulfilment of the &amp;lsquo;national&amp;rsquo; aspirations of the Jewish people; after thousands of years of minority status, of being alienated from the host societies, and in many  cases actually prevented from becoming full citizens of the lands in which they lived, they feel that they have at last &amp;lsquo;come home&amp;rsquo; and are able to control their own destiny within the normal limitations of independent statehood.  Israel is perceived as a secure haven for persecuted Jews; had Israel existed during the years of the Holocaust, Jews would have had somewhere to turn to.  Moreover, Israel provides the opportunity to live a fulfilling Jewish life free from the inhibitions and restrictions of minority status.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Large numbers of men and women have abandoned organized religion, some because they have found it intellectually untenable, more because they have found it emotionally unsatisfying, most because they have found that its demands inhibit the personal freedom which they regard as a fundamental human right.  If Western Christianity has been most strongly affected, Western Judaism runs it a close second, for both have their home in the lands which modernity and the Enlightenment were nurtured.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The downside of the emphasis on family values is the danger of marginalizing the stranger, the single, and the unattached.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;. They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/html/staff/hjs/nsolomon.html&#34;&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ct=res&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CAwQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FJudaism-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions%2Fdp%2F0192853902&amp;amp;ei=4GXeSo_3FYOk8AaKwvVy&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGAV2jscXmj3uoFSGTQwfG8MHXsPA&#34;&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from the stories of John Cheever</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-the-stories-of-john-cheever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s1600-h/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5391933763386061634&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/StP_MKsPs0I/AAAAAAAAA2E/luW_vbAcPKA/s400/john-cheever-coffee.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 307px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 400px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was after four then, and I lay in the dark, listening to the rain and to the morning trains coming through.  They come from Buffalo and Chicago and the Far West, through Albany and down along the river in the early morning, and at one time or another I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled on most of them, and I lay in the dark thinking about the polar air in the Pullman cars and the smell of nightclothes and the taste of dining-car water and the way it feels to end a day in Cleveland or Chicago and begin another in New York, particularly after you&amp;rsquo;ve been away for a couple of years, and particularly in the summer.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I took the eight-ten train into town in the morning and returned on the six-thirty.  I knew enough to avoid the empty house in the summer dusk, and I drove directly from the station parking lot to a good restaurant called Orpheo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Cure&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sun is in your hair.  It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful color.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Chaste Clarissa&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I felt that he was a captive of financial and sentimental commitments, like every other man I know, and that he was no more free to fall in love with a strange woman he saw on a street corner than he was to take a walking trip through French Guiana or to recommence his life in Chicago under an assumed name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is divorce so dreadful and of all the things that hold a marriage together how many of them are good?&amp;rdquo; She sat down at the table.  &amp;ldquo;In Grenoble,&amp;rdquo; she said, &amp;ldquo;I wrote a long paper on Charles Stuart in French.  A professor at the University of Chicago wrote me a letter.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t read a French newspaper without a dictionary today, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to follow any newspaper, and I am ashamed of my incompetence, ashamed of the way I look.  Oh, I guess I love you, I do love the children, but I love myself, I love my life, it has some value and some promise for me and Trencher&amp;rsquo;s roses make me feel that I&amp;rsquo;m losing this, that I&amp;rsquo;m losing my self-respect.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Walking down Lexington Avenue, we heard the drone bass of a church organ sound from the sky, and we and the others on the sidewalk looked up in piety and bewilderment, like a devout and stupid congregation, and saw a formation of heavy bombers heading for the sea.  As it got late, it got cold and clear and still, and on the stillness the waste from the smokestacks along the East River seemed to articulate, as legibly as the Pepsi-Cola plane, whole words and sentences.  Halcyon.  Disaster.  They were hard to make out.  It seemed the ebb of the year - an evil day for gastritis, sinus, and respiratory disease - and remembering other winters, the markings of the light convinced me that it was the season of divorce.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I think that the seriousness of the day affected the children, and when they returned to the house, they were quiet.  The seriousness of it kept coming to me with the feeling that this change, like a phenomenon of speed, was affecting our watches as well as our hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Now when I come home in the evenings, Ethel is still sitting on the stool by the sink cleaning vegetables.  I go with her into the children&amp;rsquo;s room.  The light there is bright.  The children have built something out an orange crate, something preposterous and ascendant, and their sweetness, their compulsion to build, the brightness of the light are reflected perfectly and increased in Ethel&amp;rsquo;s face.  Then she feeds them, bathes them, and sets the table, and stands for a moment in the middle of the room, trying to make some connection between the evening and the day.  Then it is over.  She lights the four candles, and we sit down to our supper.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Season of Divorce&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is true of even the best of us that if an observer can catch us boarding a train at a way station; if he will mark our faces, stripped by anxiety of their self-possession; if he will appraise our luggage, our clothing, and look out of the window to see who has driven us to the station; if he will listen to the harsh or tender things we say if we are with our families, or notice the way we put our suitcase onto the rack, check the position of our wallet, our key ring, and wipe the sweat off the back of our necks; if he can judge sensibly the self-importance, diffidence, or sadness with which we settle ourselves, he will be given a broader view of our lives than most of us would intend.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Summer Farmer&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Petterson, &#39;Out Stealing Horses&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-petterson-out-stealing-horses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t switch on the ceiling light at once but leave the room in twilight so the yellow flames in the stove flicker brightly over the floor and walls. The sight of them slows my breathing down and makes me calm as it must have done for men through thousands of years: let the wolves howl, here by the fire it’s safe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But each time he came home he had changed a little, and I had to concentrate hard to hold on to him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My father looked almost happy then, and I could see by the way he looked at me that I did, too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And she waves briefly and slams the car door and it starts to roll down the slope. I go up the steps and turn off the yard light and walk through the hall to the kitchen. Lyra is at my heels, but even when she is behind me the room feels a bit empty. I look out at the yard, but there is nothing but my own reflection in the dark glass.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He is watching the news. I don’t know when I last watched the news. I did not bring a television set out here with me, and I regret it sometimes when the evenings get long, but my idea was that living alone you can soon get stuck to those flickering images and to the chair you will sit on far into the night, and then time merely passes as you let others do the moving. I do not want that. I will keep myself company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;‘Would you rather I hadn’t come?’ she says again, insistently.&lt;br /&gt;‘I don’t know,’ I say, and that is also true; I don’t know what to think of her coming out here, it was not part of my plan, and then it strikes me: now she will go away and never come back. That thought fills me with such sudden terror that I quickly say:&lt;br /&gt;‘No, that’s not true. Don’t go.’&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I get up. Six fifteen. Lyra leaves her place beside the stove and goes to the kitchen door to wait. She turns her head and looks at me, and there is a trustfulness in that look I probably do not deserve. But maybe that is not the point, to deserve it or not, perhaps it just exists, that trust, disconnected from who you are and what you have done, and is not to be measured in any way. That’s a nice thought. Good dog, Lyra, I think, good dog.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Per Petterson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Out Stealing Horses &lt;/em&gt;(highly recommended; check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Out-Stealing-Horses-Per-Petterson/dp/1555974708/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1197353675&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon.com)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
