<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libertarianism on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/libertarianism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libertarianism on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/libertarianism/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Great Depression and the New Deal</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 02:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/rethinking-the-great-depression-and-the-new-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in the history of the 1930s, and&amp;nbsp;I just finished Eric Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/IdP1dDU&#34;&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;It has become increasingly clear to me that there are major holes in the dominant historical narrative about the Great Depression, the New Deal, and the Roosevelt administration. &amp;nbsp;The standard, high-school-textbook version of the story goes something like this: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Greedy stock market speculators caused the stock market crash of 1929, which triggered the worst depression in American history; President Herbert Hoover believed in an outdated&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;laissez-faire&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;economic philosophy, so he did nothing; thankfully, President Roosevelt was elected, and his New Deal policies saved capitalism and helped the common man survive the Great Depression; and finally, World War II was an enormous boon to the U.S. economy, and it finally solved the problem once and for all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Those of us with a preference for economic liberty and peace should be greatly disturbed by this story. &amp;nbsp;If true, it suggests that&amp;nbsp;the best ways to fix a broken economy are&amp;nbsp;(1) total war, including conscription; and (2) dramatic increases in government taxation, spending, regulation, and redistribution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thankfully, there are convincing reasons to believe that the standard narrative is wrong. &amp;nbsp;There is a lot more I need to read on the topic, but here are some resources and ideas that I look forward to exploring further:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Murray N. Rothbard,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/rothbard/agd/contents.asp&#34;&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(free PDF and ebook)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terry.uga.edu/~selgin/econ4710/Econ4710Syllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;The Economics of America&amp;rsquo;s Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (course syllabus in PDF format with many links to readings). &amp;nbsp;My interest in this topic is largely attributable to a fantastic lecture I heard Selgin deliver in June.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-David Gordon, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/3349&#34;&gt;What you must read about the Great Depression&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Mises Daily,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;2/22/09&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-George Selgin,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/article.aspx?record=157&amp;amp;month=5&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of Hall and Ferguson&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;-Robert P. Murphy,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/PWGB3Mb&#34;&gt;The Politically Incorrect Guide to the Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stephen Davies, &amp;ldquo;Top 3 Myths About the Great Depression and the New Deal,&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnliberty.org/&#34;&gt;LearnLiberty.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/7QLoeehMw0w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my next post, I will share excerpts from Rauchway&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Great Depression and the New Deal&lt;/i&gt;, which - unlike the libertarian works linked to above - is firmly on the side of the standard narrative.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying about Libya</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lying-about-libya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lying about Libya,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; appeared today in &lt;i&gt;Mises Daily&lt;/i&gt;, a publication of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Ludwig von Mises Institute&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;You can read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s1600/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OSqQaB4n0OI/ThIpiCkqabI/AAAAAAAABDo/neK15FX9j-Y/s320/LibyaOnGlobe.jpg&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;What was sold to the American public as a humanitarian intervention morphed almost immediately into unreserved support of one side in Libya&amp;rsquo;s civil war and a commitment to overthrowing Libya&amp;rsquo;s existing government.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;To decide whether a military action undertaken in our name is prudent and just, we must adopt a skeptical stance toward politicians&amp;rsquo; stories and rationalizations. We must attempt to see through these to the reality of the situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;Stories can change, and new excuses can be spun, but once a war is launched there is no predicting the course it will take or the consequences it will have. Wars rarely go according to plan; they set in motion a course of events that no one person or group of people can hope to control.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mises.org/daily/5419/Lying-about-Libya&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the entire article.  Please consider posting it on Facebook or Twitter, or otherwise passing it along to others if you enjoy it.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My op-ed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Use of Predators Sets Dangerous Precedent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I criticize President Obama&amp;rsquo;s decision to authorize drone warfare in Libya.  I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s1600/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;132&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hFtV-K6_pCs/Tgybs957h9I/AAAAAAAABDg/VXDjlkN-cvQ/s200/predator-drone.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;The expediency of drones makes it all-too-tempting for governments to use them frequently and carelessly, brushing aside the ethical questions they raise and ignoring the long-term security consequences their use could entail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2011/06/29/use-of-predators-sets-dangerous-precedent/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full article.  Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Klein, Warren, Chirelstein, and Gluck</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-klein-warren-chirelstein-and-gluck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-klein-warren-chirelstein-and-gluck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Customs grow out of social processes whose details are highly individuated in regards to the type of activity, the individuals involved, their reputational pedigree, the knowledge they have about each other, and so on. &amp;nbsp;Viewing cultural evolution as deeply and densely rooted process may make one doubt the wisdom of government attempts to fine tune, guide, or supplant it. &amp;nbsp;It is highly unlikely that the blunt instruments of government will be well suited to cultivating the growth of delicate, teeming, unique interactions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Daniel B. Klein&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Assurance and Trust in a Great Society.&amp;rdquo; &amp;nbsp;FEE Occasional Paper Two.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I kneeled to the crickets trilling&lt;br /&gt;underfoot as if about&lt;br /&gt;to burst from their crusty shells;&lt;br /&gt;and like a child again&lt;br /&gt;marveled to hear so clear&lt;br /&gt;and brave a music pour&lt;br /&gt;from such a small machine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Penn Warren&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;Touch Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some assert that strict enforcement of contracts is really a way of showing respect for the dignity and freedom of other individuals by taking them at their word.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Marvin A. Chirelstein&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;Concepts and Case Analysis in the Law of Contracts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look at her, touching his cheek&lt;br /&gt;to make a truce, her fingers&lt;br /&gt;cool with spring rain;&lt;br /&gt;in thin grass, bursts of purple crocus -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;even here, even at the beginning of love,&lt;br /&gt;her hand leaving his face makes&lt;br /&gt;an image of departure&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and they think&lt;br /&gt;they are free to overlook&lt;br /&gt;this sadness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Louise Gluck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;The Garden&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Nozick&#39;s &#39;Experience Machine&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-nozicks-experience-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 02:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/robert-nozicks-experience-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is political philosopher &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iep.utm.edu/nozick/&#34;&gt;Robert Nozick&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s incredible allegory of the &amp;ldquo;Experience Machine,&amp;rdquo; from his book &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Anarchy-State-Utopia-Robert-Nozick/dp/0465097200/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1304101535&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Anarchy, State, and Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.  The allegory makes a case against hedonism, the idea that sensory pleasure is the highest good:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;Suppose there were an experience machine that would give you any experience you desired. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Superduper neuropsychologists could stimulate your brain so that you would think and feel you were writing a great novel, or making a friend, or reading an interesting book. All the time you would be floating in a tank, with electrodes attached to your brain. Should you plug into this machine for life, preprogramming your life’s experiences? If you are worried about missing out on desirable experiences, we can suppose that business enterprises have researched thoroughly the lives of many others. You can pick and choose from their large library or smorgasbord of such experiences, selecting your life’s experiences for, say, the next two years. After two years have passed, you will have ten minutes or ten hours out of the tank, to select the experiences of your &lt;i&gt;next&lt;/i&gt; two years. Of course, while in the tank you won’t know that you’re there; you’ll think it’s all actually happening. Others can also plug in to have the experiences they want, so there’s no need to stay unplugged to serve them. (Ignore problems such as who will service the machines if everyone plugs in.) Would you plug in? &lt;i&gt;What else can matter to us, other than how our lives feel from the inside?&lt;/i&gt; Nor should you refrain because of the few moments of distress between the moment you’ve decided and the moment you’re plugged. What’s a few moments of distress compared to a lifetime of bliss (if that’s what you choose), and why feel any distress at all if your decision &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the best one?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What does matter to us in addition to our experiences? First, we want to &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; certain things, and not just have the experience of doing them. In the case of certain experiences, it is only because first we want to do the actions that we want the experiences of doing them or thinking we’ve done them. (But &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; do we want to do the activities rather than merely to experience them?) A second reason for not plugging in is that we want to &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; a certain way, to be a certain sort of person. Someone floating in a tank is an indeterminate blob. There is no answer to the question of what a person is like who has long been in the tank. Is he couragous, kind, intelligent, witty, loving? It’s not merely that it’s difficult to tell; there’s no way he is. Plugging into the machine is a kind of suicide. It will seem to some, trapped by a picture, that nothing about what we are like can matter except as it gets reflected in our experiences. But why should we be concerned only with how our time is filled, but not with what we are?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thirdly, plugging into an experience machine limits us to a man-made reality, to a world no deeper or more important than that which people can construct. There is no actual contact with any deeper reality, though the experience of it can be simulated. Many persons desire to leave themselves open to such contact and to a plumbing of deeper significance. This clarifies the intensity of the conflict over psychoactive drugs, which some view as mere local experience machines, and others view as avenues to a deeper reality; what some view as equivalent to surrender to the experience machine, others view as following one of the reasons &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to surrender!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We learn that something matters to us in addition to experience by imagining an experience machine and then realizing that we would not use it. We can continue to imagine a sequence of machines each designed to fill lacks suggested for the earlier machines. For example, since the experience machine doesn’t meet our desire to be a certain way, imagine a transformation machine which transforms us into whatever sort of person we’d like to be (compatible with our staying us). Surely one would not use the transformation machine to become as one would wish, and thereupon plug into the experience machine! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So something matters in addition to one’s experiences and what one is like. Nor is the reason merely that one’s experiences are unconnected with what one is like. For the experience machine might be limited to provide only experiences possible to the sort of person plugged in. Is it that we want to make a difference in the world? Consider then the result machine, which produces in the world any result you would produce and injects your vector input into any joint activity. I won’t pursue here the fascinating details of these or other machines. What is most disturbing about them is their living of our lives for us. Is it misguided to search for particular additional functions beyond the competence of machines to do for us? Perhaps what we desire is to live (an active verb) ourselves, in contact with reality. (And this, machines cannot do for us.) Without elaborating on the implications of this, which I believe connect surprisingly with issues about free will and causal accounts of knowledge, it’s merely worth noting the intricacy of the question of what matters for people other than their experiences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Nozick&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Anarchy-State-Utopia-Robert-Nozick/dp/0465097200/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1304101535&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Anarchy, State, and Utopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Hamsun, Friedman, &amp; Lawrence</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-hamsun-friedman--lawrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 19:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-hamsun-friedman--lawrence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An hour later, my thoughts are full of joy. Even little things affect me: a veil flutters on a hat, a lock of hair comes undone, two eyes close with laughter - and I am moved. Oh, this day, this day!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When you came, there was sympathy in your face and your eyes shone, you gave me your hand. Now your eyes are indifferent again. Am I mistaken?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are you, burning out your life for the sake of a little schoolgirl, and your nights are full of desolate dreams. And a sultry wind enwraps your head, a stale and musty wind. Whilst the sky trembles with a marvellous blue, and the mountains are calling.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mile below me I see the sea. It is raining and I am up in the hills; an overhanging rock shelters me from the rain. I smoke my pipe, smoke one pipe after another, and every time I light up the tobacco curls up from the ash like little glowing worms. So is it also with the thoughts that teem in my head. In front of me on the ground lies a bundle of dry twigs, a shattered bird&amp;rsquo;s nest. And as with that nest, so it is with my soul.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Knut Hamsun, &lt;em&gt;Pan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The consumer is protected from coercion by the seller because of the presence of other sellers with whom he can deal. The seller is protected from coercion by the consumer because of other consumers to whom he can sell. The employee is protected from coercion by the employer because of other employers for whom he can work, and so on. And the market does this impersonally and without centralized authority.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Indeed, a major source of objection to a free economy is precisely that it does this task so well. It gives people what they want instead of what a particular group thinks they ought to want. Underlying most arguments against the free market is a lack of belief in freedom itself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In particular, we shall always want to enter on the liability side of any proposed government intervention, its neighborhood effect in threatening freedom, and give this effect considerable weight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Milton Friedman, &lt;em&gt;Capitalism and Freedom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pomegranate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For all that, the setting suns are open.&lt;br /&gt;The end cracks open with the beginning:&lt;br /&gt;Rosy, tender, glittering within the fissure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do you mean to tell me there should be no fissure?&lt;br /&gt;No glittering, compact drops of dawn?&lt;br /&gt;Do you mean it is wrong, the gold-filmed skin, integument, shown ruptured?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For my part, I prefer my heart to be broken.&lt;br /&gt;It is so lovely, dawn-kaleidoscopic within the crack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-D.H. Lawrence&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
