<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aging on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/aging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aging on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/aging/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Benedict Anderson, Gottfried Benn, and Bob Altemeyer</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-benedict-anderson-gottfried-benn-and-bob-altemeyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving weekend!  I am spending it in Boulder, CO, one of the most beautiful cities in America.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Static Poems&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Deafness to imperatives&lt;br /&gt;is profundity in the wise man,&lt;br /&gt;children and grandchildren&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t bother him,&lt;br /&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t alarm him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To represent a particular outlook,&lt;br /&gt;to act,&lt;br /&gt;to travel hither and yon&lt;br /&gt;are all signs of a world&lt;br /&gt;that doesn&amp;rsquo;t see clearly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Adult authoritarians tend to be highly ethnocentric and heavy users of the &amp;ldquo;consensual validation pill&amp;rdquo; (Newcomb, 1961).  They travel in tight circles of like-minded people so much, they often think their views are commonly held in society, that they are the &amp;ldquo;Moral Majority&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Silent Majority.&amp;rdquo;  It has been hard to miss the evidence that certain kinds of religious training have sometimes helped produce their ethnocentrism and authoritarianism.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;(They) are scared.  They see the world as a dangerous place, as society teeters on the brink of self-destruction from evil and violence.  This fear appears to &lt;em&gt;instigate&lt;/em&gt; aggression in them.  Second, right-wing authoritarians tend to be highly self-righteous.  They think themselves much more moral and upstanding than others - a self-perception considerably aided by self-deception, their religious training, and some very efficient guilt evaporators (such as going to confession).  This self-righteousness &lt;em&gt;disinhibits&lt;/em&gt; their aggressive impulses, and releases them to act out their fear-induced hostilities&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bob Altemeyer&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Other &amp;lsquo;Authoritarian Personality&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Bad&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Seeing a cold beer when it&amp;rsquo;s hot out,&lt;br /&gt;and not being able to afford it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hearing the waves beat against the shore on holiday at night,&lt;br /&gt;and telling yourself it&amp;rsquo;s what they always do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Very bad: being invited out,&lt;br /&gt;when your own room at home is quieter,&lt;br /&gt;the coffee is better,&lt;br /&gt;and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to make small talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And worst of all:&lt;br /&gt;not to die in summer,&lt;br /&gt;when the days are long&lt;br /&gt;and the earth yields easily to the spade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Gottfried Benn&lt;br /&gt;(in &lt;em&gt;Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt;.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reading a newspaper is like reading a novel whose author has abandoned any thought of a coherent plot.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The Reformation&amp;hellip;owed much of its success to print-capitalism.  Before the age of print, Rome easily won every war against heresy in Western Europe because it always had better lines of communication than its challengers.  But when in 1517 Martin Luther nailed his theses to the chapel-door in Wittenberg, they were printed up in German translation, and &amp;lsquo;within 15 days [had been] seen in every part of the country.&amp;rsquo;  In the two decades 1520-1540 three times as many books were published in German as in the period 1500-1520, an astonishing transformation to which Luther was absolutely central.  His works represented no less than one third of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; German-language books sold between 1518 and 1525.  &amp;hellip;&amp;lsquo;We have here for the first time a truly mass readership and a popular literature within everybody&amp;rsquo;s reach.&amp;rsquo;  In effect, Luther became the first best-selling author &lt;em&gt;so known&lt;/em&gt;.  Or, to put it another way, the first writer who could &amp;lsquo;sell&amp;rsquo; his &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; books on the basis of his name.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In pre-print Europe, and, of course, elsewhere in the world, the diversity of spoken languages, those languages that for those speakers were (and are) the warp and woof of their lives, was immense; so immense, indeed, that had print-capitalism sought to exploit each potential oral vernacular market, it would have remained a capitalism of petty proportions.  But these varied idiolects were capable of being assembled, within definite limits, into print-languages far fewer in number.  The very arbitrariness of any system of signs for sounds facilitated the assembling process.  &amp;hellip;Nothing served to &amp;lsquo;assemble&amp;rsquo; related vernaculars more than capitalism, which, within the limits imposed by grammars and syntaxes, created mechanically reproduced print languages capable of dissemination through the market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These print-languages laid the bases for national consciousnesses in three distinct ways.  First and foremost, they created unified fields of exchange and communication below Latin and above the spoken vernaculars.  Speakers of the huge variety of Frenches, Englishes, or Spanishes, who might find it difficult or even impossible to understand one another in conversation, became capable of comprehending one another via print and paper.  In the process, they gradually became aware of the hundreds of thousands, even millions, of people in their particular language-field, and at the same time that &lt;em&gt;only those&lt;/em&gt; hundreds of thousands, or millions, so belonged.  These fellow-readers, to whom they were connected through print, formed, in their secular, particular, visible invisibility, the embryo of the nationally imagined community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Benedict Anderson&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Imagined Communities&lt;/em&gt; (one of the most fascinating and insightful books I have ever read - a book that can change the way you understand the world.)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell, Herman Melville, and John D. Caputo</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-herman-melville-and-john-d.-caputo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Next Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wisdom, said William James,&lt;br /&gt;Is learning what to overlook.  And I am wise&lt;br /&gt;If that is wisdom.&lt;br /&gt;Yet somehow, as I buy All from these shelves&lt;br /&gt;And the boy takes it to my station wagon,&lt;br /&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve become&lt;br /&gt;Troubles me even if I shut my eyes.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Imaginings within my imagining,&lt;br /&gt;I too have taken&lt;br /&gt;The chance of life.  Now the boy pats my dog&lt;br /&gt;And we start home.  Now I am good.&lt;br /&gt;The last mistaken,&lt;br /&gt;Ecstatic, accidental bliss, the blind&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness that, bursting, leaves upon the palm&lt;br /&gt;Some soap and water -&lt;br /&gt;It was so long ago&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The overt Godlessness of our world is a latent Godliness.  To an eye keen for things theological, religion is most present where it is least visible.  That &amp;ldquo;secularism&amp;rdquo; blinds us to the theological order everywhere implicit in the secular order is the &amp;ldquo;central&amp;rdquo; player in (Mark C.) Taylor&amp;rsquo;s dialectic.  &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; is full of illuminating narratives generated by this hypothesis, the central story being how much &amp;ldquo;modernity&amp;rdquo; goes back to the Reformation: Luther&amp;rsquo;s assertion of subjectivity, his rejection of tradition in favor of personal experience, his media-savvy insistence on the vernacular and use of the printing press&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John D. Caputo&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;Review of Mark C. Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;After God&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Journal of the American Academy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; 77:1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Look not too long in the face of the fire, O man! Never dream with thy hand on the helm! Turn not thy back to the compass; accept the first hint of the hitching tiller; believe not the artificial fire, when its redness makes all things look ghastly. To-morrow, in the natural sun, the skies will be bright; those who glared like devils in the forking flames, the morn will show in far other, at least gentler, relief; the glorious, golden, glad sun, the only true lamp - all others but liars!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nevertheless the sun hides not Virginia&amp;rsquo;s Dismal Swamp, nor Rome&amp;rsquo;s accursed Campagna, nor wide Sahara, nor all the millions of miles of deserts and of griefs beneath the moon. The sun hides not the ocean, which is the dark side of this earth, and which is two thirds of this earth. So, therefore, that mortal man who hath more of joy than sorrow in him, that mortal man cannot be true - not true, or undeveloped. With books the same. The truest of all men was the Man of Sorrows, and the truest of all books is Solomon&amp;rsquo;s, and Ecclesiastes is the fine hammered steel of woe. &amp;ldquo;All is vanity.&amp;rdquo; ALL.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;There is a wisdom that is woe; but there is a woe that is madness. And there is a Catskill eagle in some souls that can alike dive down into the blackest gorges, and soar out of them again and become invisible in the sunny spaces. And even if he for ever flies within the gorge, that gorge is in the mountains; so that even in his lowest swoop the mountain eagle is still higher than other birds upon the plain, even though they soar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Herman Melville&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/moby/&#34;&gt;Moby-Dick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;90 North&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I see at last that all the knowledge&lt;br /&gt;I wrung from the darkness - that the darkness flung me -&lt;br /&gt;Is worthless as ignorance: nothing comes from nothing,&lt;br /&gt;The darkness from the darkness.  Pain comes from the darkness&lt;br /&gt;And we call it wisdom.  It is pain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Randall Jarrell&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Edward Abbey and John Cheever</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-edward-abbey-and-john-cheever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 00:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-edward-abbey-and-john-cheever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We make the coffee with river water, dipping a canful from among the rocks and letting it set for a time until the silt settles to the bottom.  For entertainment we have the murmur of the river, the drone of cicada and amphibians, the show of nighthawks plunging through the evening gulping bugs.  Afterwards we sit by the fire until the fire gives out, listening, smoking, analyzing socioeconomic problems:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look here, Newcombe,&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;do you think it&amp;rsquo;s fitting that you and I should be here in the wilds, risking our lives amidst untold hardships, while our wives nad loved ones lounge at their ease back in Albuquerque, enjoying the multifold comforts, benefits and luxuries of modern contemporary twentieth century American urban civilization?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edward Abbey&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Desert Solitaire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The light there was like a blow, and the air smelled as if many wonderful girls had just wandered across the lawn.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Common Day&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had already put on the football uniform, and the weight of it, the heaviness of the pants and the shoulder guards, had worked a change in me, as if in putting on these old clothes I had put off the reasonable anxieties and troubles of my life.  It felt as if we had both returned to the years before our marriage, the years before thew war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Chucky Ewing had got hold of a balloon and was trying to organize a scrimmage line in the middle of the floor.  The others were dancing a samba.  And I knew that Lawrence was looking bleakly at the party as he had looked at the weather-beaten shingles on our house, as if he saw here an abuse and a distortion of time; as if in wanting to be brides and football players we exposed the fact that, the lights of youth having been put out in us, we had been unable to find other lights to go by and, destitute of faith and principle, had become foolish and sad.  And that he was thinking this about so many kind and happy and generous people had me angry, made me feel for him such an unnatural abhorrence that I was ashamed, for he is my brother and a Pommeroy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Cheever&lt;br /&gt;  -&amp;ldquo;Goodbye, My Brother&amp;rdquo;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems and lines by Randall Jarrell</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems-and-lines-by-randall-jarrell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems-and-lines-by-randall-jarrell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;The Orient Express&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One looks from the train&lt;br /&gt;Almost as one looked as a child.  In the sunlight&lt;br /&gt;What I see still seems to me plain,&lt;br /&gt;I am safe; but at evening&lt;br /&gt;As the lands darken, a questioning&lt;br /&gt;Precariousness comes over everything.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Deutsch Durch Freud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have you too sometimes, by the fire, at evening,&lt;br /&gt;Wished that you were - whatever you once were?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;A Girl in a Library&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An object among dreams, you sit here with your shoes off&lt;br /&gt;And curl your legs up under you; your eyes&lt;br /&gt;Close for a moment, your face moves toward sleep&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;You are very human.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One sees it, in the glass, in one&amp;rsquo;s own eyes.&lt;br /&gt;In rooms alone, in galleries, in libraries,&lt;br /&gt;In tears, in searchings of the heart, in staggering joys&lt;br /&gt;We memorize once more our old creation,&lt;br /&gt;Humanity: with what yawns the unwilling&lt;br /&gt;Flesh puts on its spirit, O my sister!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I wake, but before I know it it is done,&lt;br /&gt;The day, I sleep.  And of days like these the years,&lt;br /&gt;A life is made.  I nod, consenting to my life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meteorite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Star, that looked so long among the stones&lt;br /&gt;And picked from them, half iron and half dirt,&lt;br /&gt;One; and bent and put it to her lips&lt;br /&gt;And breathed upon it till at last it burned&lt;br /&gt;Uncertainly, among the stars its sisters -&lt;br /&gt;Breathe on me still, star, sister.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal update and four quotes</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-personal-update-and-four-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited about the weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking straight from work to Union Station tomorrow afternoon, and then the usual, happy routine of a quick trip home: the #370 &lt;em&gt;Pere Marquette &lt;/em&gt;accompanied by caffeine and books (and, since it&amp;rsquo;s summer, a wonderful sunset over the harbor in St. Joseph, MI), a late-night outing to Pints &amp;amp; Quarts and Pablo&amp;rsquo;s Tacos with Muskegon friends, a Saturday morning trip to eat breakfast and shop for used books in Grand Haven, a few intense games of ping-pong with Tyler, and a run on the beach. Early Sunday morning, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on the return train to Chicago and it will all seem surreal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two unique and wonderful things about this trip. First: my family got a new dog, a black retriever named Maggie, whom I will have the pleasure of meeting for the first time tomorrow night. And second: on Saturday night, two friends and I are going to a Counting Crows and Collective Soul concert in Grand Rapids.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Quotes from tonight&amp;rsquo;s reading: &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I am saying is this: the score is not what matters. Life does not have to be regarded as a game in which scores are kept and somebody wins. If you are too intent on winning, you will never enjoy playing. If you are too obsessed with success, you will forget to live. If you have learned only how to be a success, your life has probably been wasted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Love and Living&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When that time was over and the good-bys said, I had to go through the same lost loneliness all over again, and it was no less painful than at first. There seemed to be no cure for loneliness save only being alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blackberries for Amelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the far stars, of which we now are told&lt;br /&gt;That ever faster they do bolt away,&lt;br /&gt;And that a night may come in which, some say,&lt;br /&gt;We shall have only blackness to behold.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have no time for any change so great,&lt;br /&gt;But I shall see the August weather spur&lt;br /&gt;Berries to ripen where the flowers were -&lt;br /&gt;Dark berries, savage-sweet and worth the wait -&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And there will come the moment to be quick&lt;br /&gt;And save some from the birds, and I shall need&lt;br /&gt;Two pails, old clothes in which to stain and bleed,&lt;br /&gt;And a grandchild to talk with while we pick.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;em&gt;Richard Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can only imagine that the lonely man peoples his driving dreams with friends, that the loveless man surrounds himself with lovely loving women, and that children climb through the dreaming of the childless driver. And how about the areas of regrets? If only I had done so-and-so, or had not said such-and-such - my God, the damn thing might not have happened. Finding this potential in my own mind, I can suspect it in others, but I will never know, for no one ever tells. And this is why, on my journey which was designed for observation, I stayed as much as possible on secondary roads where there was much to see and hear and smell, and avoided the great wide traffic slashes which promote the self by fostering daydreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;John Steinbeck&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from John Steinbeck&#39;s &#39;Travels with Charley&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A dog, particularly an exotic like Charley, is a bond between strangers.  Many conversations en route began with &amp;ldquo;What degree of a dog is that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dairy man had a Ph.D. in mathematics, and he must have had some training in philosophy.  He liked what he was doing and he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be somewhere else - one of the very few contented people I met in my whole journey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then a submarine slipped to the surface half a mile away, and the day lost part of its brightness.  Farther away another dark creature slashed through the water, and another; of course they are based in New London, and this is their home.  And perhaps they are keeping the world&amp;rsquo;s peace with their venom.  I wish I could like submarines, for then I might find them beautiful, but they are designed for destruction, and while they may explore and chart the sea bottom, and draw new trade lines under the Arctic ice, their main purpose is threat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to be a center for concern?  A kind of second childhood falls on so many men.  They trade their violence for the promise of a small increase of life span.  In effect, the head of the house becomes the youngest child.  And I have searched myself for this possibility with a kind of horror.  For I have always lived violently, drunk hugely, eaten too much or not at all, slept around the clock or missed two nights of sleeping, worked too hard and too long in glory, or slobbed for a time in utter laziness.  I&amp;rsquo;ve lifted, pulled, chopped, climbed, made love with joy and taken my hangovers as a consequence, not as a punishment.  I did not want to surrender fierceness for a small gain in yardage.  My wife married a man; I saw no reason why she should inherit a baby. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I saw in their eyes something I was to see over and over in every part of the nation - a burning desire to go, to move, to get under way, anyplace, away from any Here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Ftt&amp;rdquo; usually means he would like to salute a bush or a tree.  I opened the cab door and let him out, and he went about his ceremony.  He doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it to do it well.  It is my experience that in some areas Charley is more intelligent than I am, but in others he is abysmally ignorant.  He can&amp;rsquo;t read, can&amp;rsquo;t drive a car, and has no grasp of mathematics.  But in his own field of endeavor, which was now practicing, the slow, imperial smelling over and anointing of an area, he has no peer.  Of course his horizons are limited, but how wide are mine?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley in Search of America &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Personal note: Steinbeck is my favorite American writer, and &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley &lt;/em&gt;is on track to become one of my absolute favorite books; I&amp;rsquo;m especially excited about it because my family just got a second dog, a black retriever named Maggie.  I&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet Maggie for the first time when I go home to Muskegon on Friday for a Counting Crows concert.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lines by Levertov, Wilbur, Lowell, and Stafford</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lines-by-levertov-wilbur-lowell-and-stafford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/lines-by-levertov-wilbur-lowell-and-stafford/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Overland to the Islands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go - much as that dog goes,&lt;br /&gt;intently haphazard.  The&lt;br /&gt;Mexican light on a day that&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lsquo;smells like autumn in Connecticut&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;makes iris ripples on his&lt;br /&gt;black gleaming fur - and that too&lt;br /&gt;is as one would desire - a radiance&lt;br /&gt;consorting with the dance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Under his feet&lt;br /&gt;rocks and mud, his imagination, sniffing,&lt;br /&gt;engaged in its perceptions - dancing&lt;br /&gt;edgeways, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing&lt;br /&gt;the dog disdains on his way,&lt;br /&gt;nevertheless he&lt;br /&gt;keeps moving, changing&lt;br /&gt;pace and approach but&lt;br /&gt;not direction - &amp;lsquo;every step an arrival&amp;rsquo;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Denise Levertov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;The Undead&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To prey on life forever and not possess it,&lt;br /&gt;As rock-hollows, tide after tide,&lt;br /&gt;Glassily strand the sea.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Richard Wilbur&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Katherine&amp;rsquo;s Dream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Where are you?  You were with me and are gone.&lt;br /&gt;All the forgiven couples hurry on&lt;br /&gt;To dinner and their nights, and none will stop.&lt;br /&gt;I run about in circles till I drop&lt;br /&gt;Against a padlocked bulkhead in a yard&lt;br /&gt;Where faces redden and the snow is hard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;-Robert Lowell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;For Sale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Poor sheepish plaything,&lt;br /&gt;organized with prodigal animosity,&lt;br /&gt;lived in just a year -&lt;br /&gt;my Father&amp;rsquo;s cottage at Beverly Farms&lt;br /&gt;was on the market the month he died.&lt;br /&gt;Empty, open, intimate,&lt;br /&gt;its town-house furniture&lt;br /&gt;had on a tiptoe air&lt;br /&gt;of waiting for the mover&lt;br /&gt;on the heels of the undertaker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ready, afraid&lt;br /&gt;of living alone till eighty,&lt;br /&gt;Mother mooned in a window,&lt;br /&gt;as if she had stayed on a train&lt;br /&gt;one stop past her destination.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;-Robert Lowell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Strokes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The left side of her world is gone -&lt;br /&gt;the rest sustained by memory&lt;br /&gt;and a realization: There are still the children.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going down our porch steps her pastor&lt;br /&gt;calls back: &amp;lsquo;We are proud of her recovery,&lt;br /&gt;and there is a chiropractor up in Galesburg&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The birthdays of the old require such candles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;-William Stafford&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
