<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gender on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/gender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gender on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 18:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/gender/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A limited ecumenism</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/a-limited-ecumenism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;A limited ecumenism,&amp;rdquo; appeared today in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt;, the newsletter of the Martin Marty Center at the University of Chicago Divinity School.  It discusses the Catholic Church&amp;rsquo;s recent outreach to traditionalist Anglicans.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is a free online publication sent out twice a week to over 7,000 scholars, ministers, students, and others interested in the intersection of religion and public life; you can subscribe to it at the Sightings &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.uchicago.edu/web/info/sightings&#34;&gt;subscription page&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; is also online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&#34;&gt;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/martycenter/publications/sightings/archive_2009/1105.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Limited Ecumenism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As reported in &lt;em&gt;Sightings&lt;/em&gt; last Monday, the Vatican announced two weeks ago that it was setting up a new canonical structure, or Apostolic Constitution, to facilitate the conversion of disaffected Anglican traditionalists to Catholicism; the converts will be able to “enter full communion with the Catholic Church while preserving elements of the distinctive Anglican spiritual and liturgical patrimony,” in the Vatican’s words.  Married former Anglican clergy will be allowed to become Catholic Priests, though not Bishops.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Vatican portrayed the move as a response to requests from Anglicans and as representative of its broader “commitment to ecumenical dialogue.” Rowan Williams, the Archbishop of Canterbury and symbolic leader of the Anglican Church, and Vincent Nichols, the Catholic Archbishop of Westminster, released a statement confirming the Vatican’s narrative: “The Apostolic Constitution is further recognition of the substantial overlap in faith, doctrine and spirituality between the Catholic Church and the Anglican tradition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But what leaders of the two churches depicted as an historic, ecumenical move toward Christian unity, others saw as something considerably more complex.  Andrew Sullivan, a Catholic writer who has often been critical of Pope Benedict XVI’s leadership, used economic analogies in describing the move as a power grab.  “Married priests are fine…as long as they help build market share,” he wrote, paraphrasing what he sees as the Vatican’s new position on clerical chastity.  The move “essentially junks an entire tradition of ecumenical dialogue in favor of a quick and sudden merger and acquisition.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Such analogies, while jarring, may be worth exploring further.  Organizations and societies learn from each other’s successful practices, and religious organizations are no exception.  The language and efficiency of the Vatican’s announcement made the policy appear to be as carefully scripted and “rolled-out” as a new product by an electronics manufacturer or a new policy by a political leader.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Holy See demonstrated that it, too, can masterfully employ the techniques of “spin,” omnipresent in both consumer and political marketing.  And still other political analogies may apply:  Is the Vatican practicing religious realpolitik, strengthening itself at the expense of a weakened and divided adversary?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, this development may tell us more about the contemporary Catholic Church than about divisions in the Anglican Church.  Perhaps most interestingly, the Vatican&amp;rsquo;s plan suggests that current Catholic leadership sees liturgical procedures and even the chastity of priests as somewhat flexible, but its stands against homosexuality and the ordainment of women as fixed and beyond debate – indeed, even as a source of common ground with other socially conservative Christian groups.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of the Christian churches place a high value on reconciliation and unity.  But few see unification as an aim that trumps the aims of conscience, that is, of right doctrine and right orientation toward God.  In evaluating the Vatican’s move, observers will have to ask themselves whether reconciliation ought to come at the price of continuing and even strengthening the exclusion of women and gays from full and equal membership in the Church.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;References:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Donadio, Rachel and Laurie Goodstein, “Vatican Bidding to Get Anglicans to Join Its Fold,” New York Times, 10/21/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/21/world/europe/21pope.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Holy See Press Office, “Note of the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith about Personal Ordinariates for Anglicans Entering the Catholic Church,” 10/20/09. Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en.&#34;&gt;http://212.77.1.245/news_services/bulletin/news/24513.php?index=24513&amp;amp;po_date=20.10.2009&amp;amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nichols, Vincent and Rowan Williams, “Joint Statement by The Archbishop of Westminster and The Archbishop of Canterbury,” 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sullivan, Andrew, “Married Priests Are Fine…,” The Daily Dish, 10/20/09.  Online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archbishopofcanterbury.org/2572#&#34;&gt;http://andrewsullivan.theatlantic.com/the_daily_dish/2009/10/married-priests-are-fine-.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ryanmccarl.com/&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator.  He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Alfie Kohn and Virginia Woolf</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-alfie-kohn-and-virginia-woolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons policymakers seek to impose detailed curriculum mandates.  They may fundamentally distrust educators: Much of the current standards movement is just the latest episdoe in a long, sorry history of trying to create a teacher-proof curriculum.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;These days almost anything can be done to students and to schools, no matter how ill-considered, as long as it is done in the name of raising standards.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s convenient for us to assume that kids who cut corners are just being lazy, because then it&amp;rsquo;s the kids who have to be fixed.  But perhaps they&amp;rsquo;re just being rational.  They have adapted to an environment where results, not intellectual exploration, are what count.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Assessment is used less to support learning than to evaluate and compare people.  &amp;hellip;(Standardized testing) screens and sorts students for the convenience of industry (and higher education).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;What happens to schools when they are plunged into the marketplace?  To begin with, they must shift much of their time and resources to, well, marketing.  (It is those who sell themselves skillfully, not those who are especially good at what they do, who tend to succeed in a competitive market.)  Moreover, the pressure to make themselves look better presents a temptation to screen out less desirable students, those whose education takes more effort or expense.  &amp;ldquo;The problem with public schools,&amp;rdquo; remarked author John Chubb, &amp;ldquo;is that they must take whoever walks in the door.&amp;rdquo;  The philosophical core of the privatization movement for which Chubb speaks is neatly revealed in the use of the word &lt;em&gt;problem &lt;/em&gt;in that sentence.  &lt;em&gt;[Note: I disagree with this statement, but it is the among the best anti-voucher arguments I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alfie Kohn&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Educated-Essays-Standards-Grading-Follies/dp/0807032670&#34;&gt;What Does it Mean to Be Well Educated?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Highly recommended.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And, thanking Mr. Ramsay for it and Mrs. Ramsay for it and the hour and the place, crediting the world with a power which she had not suspected - that one could walk away down that long gallery not alone any more but arm in arm with somebody - the strangest feeling in the world, and the most exhilarating&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Here she saddened, darkened, and came back to her chair, there could be no disputing this: an unmarried woman (she lightly took her hand for a moment), an unmarried woman has missed the best of life.  The house seemed full of children sleeping and Mrs. Ramsay listening; shaded lights and regular breathing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;How strangely he was venerable and laughable at one and the same time.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;She bore about with her, she could not help knowing it, the torch of her beauty; she carried it erect into any room that she entered; and after all, veil it as she might, and shrink from the monotony of bearing that it imposed on her, her beauty was apparent.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The very stone one kicks with one&amp;rsquo;s boot will outlast Shakespeare.  His own little light would shine, not very brightly, for a year or two, and would then be merged in some bigger light, and that in a bigger still.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;All at once he realised that it was this: it was this: - she was the most beautiful person he had ever seen.  &amp;hellip;For the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; a man digging in a drain stopped digging and looked at her, let his arm fall down and looked at her; for the first time in his life Charles Tansley felt an extraordinary pride; felt the wind and the cyclamen and the violets for he was walking with a beautiful woman.  He had hold of her bag.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Virginia Woolf&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;To the Lighthouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
