<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peace on Ryan McCarl</title>
    <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/tags/peace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peace on Ryan McCarl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 19:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/peace/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Two cents about COIN</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/two-cents-about-coin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;Two cents about COIN,&amp;rdquo; appeared today on &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;. It discusses the the growing faith of U.S. political and military leaders in the military doctrine of COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find the op-ed &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/11/06/two-cents-about-coin/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as pasted below; if you enjoy it, please consider sharing it on your Facebook wall, mentioning it on Twitter, or linking to it on your blog. Thanks, as always, for reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Cents About COIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The war in Afghanistan, according to Gen. Stanley McChrystal’s recent assessment, is &amp;ldquo;a situation that defies simple solutions or quick fixes.  Success demands a comprehensive counterinsurgency (COIN) campaign.&amp;rdquo;  McChrystal and other American leaders calling for a &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; of additional U.S. troops into Afghanistan to mirror the alleged success of the &amp;ldquo;surge&amp;rdquo; in Iraq are voicing their belief that the doctrinal framework for the original surge – COIN, or manpower-intensive counterinsurgency warfare – is a widely-applicable tool in asymmetric warfare that the U.S. ought to employ in Afghanistan. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Top decisionmakers in the U.S. military, including Gen. McChrystal and Gen. David Petraeus, continue to express their faith in the doctrine, which they played major roles in creating.  Prominent Republicans in Congress, who almost unanimously support sending more troops to Afghanistan, have endorsed a nation-building strategy that relies heavily on COIN over a counterterrorism strategy that focuses on targeting al-Qaeda and other militants from a distance.  Several key figures in the Obama administration also appear to favor that approach. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It may be true that, as military expert Stephen Biddle said in recent Congressional testimony, &amp;ldquo;the U.S. is an unusually experienced counterinsurgent force today,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the new Army/Marine counterinsurgency doctrine…is the product of a nearly unprecedented degree of internal debate, external vetting, historical analysis, and direct recent combat experience.&amp;rdquo;   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But these very factors that have encouraged so many highly capable U.S. leaders to sign on to &amp;ldquo;COIN&amp;rdquo; should cause observers to be wary of the doctrine and the currency it increasingly enjoys in the American political debate.  After all, the more enthusiastic we are about the potential of COIN warfare, the more blind we will be to its costs, which are enormous. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We can and must think about contemporary problems – such as what strategy the U.S. should pursue in Afghanistan – through the lenses of relevant theories and historical analogies.  But it is foolish to think within the box of a single analogy, such as the Iraq &amp;ldquo;surge,&amp;rdquo; or a single theory, such as the idea that we can succeed at counterinsurgency and nation-building by deploying generous numbers of ground troops and focusing on winning the &amp;ldquo;hearts and minds&amp;rdquo; of local communities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our need to make quick decisions and cope with a complex world creates a powerful incentive for us to create &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; default beliefs, habits, choices, or courses of action that we adopt almost without thinking.  And yet when those in the halls of power make major decisions on the basis of such &amp;ldquo;rules of thumb,&amp;rdquo; the results can sometimes be disastrous.  It behooves political observers to be aware of new decision-making habits, and the spread of some new piece of &amp;ldquo;conventional wisdom,&amp;rdquo; in their leaders. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to remember that military leaders have a major incentive to endorse a COIN approach in Afghanistan.  According to General Petraeus and other experts, most successful COIN operations require very high numbers of U.S. troops on the ground – numbers that may be politically and logistically impossible for the Obama administration to accept. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because the number of troops that can be reasonably demanded for a COIN operation is essentially limitless, mission failure can be blamed on the executive branch for not sending enough troops rather than on military leaders, the combat environment, or the COIN playbook itself.  As Gen. McChrystal wrote in his assessment: &amp;ldquo;Success is not ensured by additional forces alone, but continued underresourcing will likely cause failure.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Organizational psychology and the logic of bureaucracies provide more clues into the wave of COIN-fever that appears to have struck so many of our political and military leaders.  Simply put, it was neither easy nor cheap for the military to develop COIN doctrine as we attempted to salvage the war in Iraq in recent years, and now COIN feels like hard-won wisdom that we should put to the test in another theater of war.  It’s a classic case of sunk costs: it is felt that we paid too much for COIN to abandon it now. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Policymakers’ belief in the power of COIN may encourage them to see military solutions where none exist.  If the U.S. opts to send tens of thousands of additional ground troops to Afghanistan in order to pursue a comprehensive COIN strategy, it will be taking on a great deal of risk and incurring substantial additional costs in pursuit of a highly uncertain outcome.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/www.ryanmccarl.com&#34;&gt;Ryan McCarl&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and educator. He has an M.A. in International Relations from the University of Chicago, and he maintains a blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com/&#34;&gt;www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Jonathan Glover&#39;s &#39;Humanity&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/excerpts-from-jonathan-glovers-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s1600-h/humanity.jpg&#34; onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5386584471912125922&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dbkE5wB5Kaw/SsD-CbD1FeI/AAAAAAAAA10/2619Ms5d150/s400/humanity.jpg&#34; style=&#34;cursor: hand; cursor: pointer; float: left; height: 240px; margin: 0 10px 10px 0; width: 240px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is one of the best and most important books I have ever read.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Excerpts below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;An extimate for the period from 1900 until 1989 is that war killed 86 million people.  Eighty-six million is a small proportion of all those alive during the ninety years, and is a small number compared to those who have died from hunger and preventable diseases.  All the same, death in twentieth-century war has been on a scale which is hard to grasp.  &amp;hellip;If these deaths had been spread evenly over the period, war would have killed around 2,500 people every day.  That is over 100 people an hour, round the clock, for ninety years.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;One of this book&amp;rsquo;s aims is to replace the thin, mechanical psychology of the Enlightenment with something more complex, something closer to reality.  A consequence of this is to defend the Enlightenment hope of a world that is more peaceful and humane, the hope that by understanding more about ourselves we can do something to create a world with less misery.  &amp;hellip;We need to look hard and clearly at some monsters inside us.  But this is part of the project of caging and taming them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Our entanglements with people close to us erode simple self-interest.  Husbands, wives, lovers, parents, children and friends all blur the boundaries of selfish concern.  Francis Bacon rightly said that people with children have given hostages to fortune.  Inescapably, other forms of friendship and love hold us hostage too.  The deeper levels of relationships are denied to people who hold large parts of themselves back.  And to give yourself means that part of you belongs to the person you care for.  There is a constant pull towards new kinds of sympathy and commitment.  Narrow self-interest is destabilized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Happiness depends on psychological integration, or wholeness.  We need to be at peace with ourselves.  Inner conflict is a threat to happiness.  Disharmony involves slavery to madness, and allows the beast in man to gain control.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Claims to be treated with respect are often linked to standing within a group.  The claim of an outsider may be minimal.  Sympathy has similar limitations.  The sympathies which really engage us are often stubbornly limited and local.  I may move mountains for my child, but perhaps I will not cross the street to be a good Samaritan to a stranger.  Sympathy may hardly extend to those outside a particular community.  These limitations help to explain a moral gap which is increasingly evident.  Many moralities are &amp;ldquo;internal,&amp;rdquo; giving weight to the interests of those inside a community, but doing little against the common indifference or even hostility towards those outside.  It is increasingly obvious that this moral gap is a human disaster.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;(In 1991), Amnesty International recorded protests against human rights abuses in over 50 countries, the protests to thirteen countries making specific reference to torture.  These are the kinds of thing that many of us have a vague background awareness of, without there being much publicity unless the perpetrators are some currently loathed regime, or unless some highly visible Westerner is among the victims.  The reality is that in many countries torture of the most revolting cruelty happens routinely, often under the auspices of governments with good relations with Europe and the United States, sometimes using equipment knowingly supplied by Western companies.  There is little reason to think torture is in retreat.  The festival of cruelty is in full swing.  What is it about human beings that makes such acts possible?  Three factors seem central.  There is a love of cruelty.  Also, emotionally inadequate people assert themselves by dominance and cruelty.  And the moral resources which restrain cruelty can be neutralized.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;For some, especially when the victims are women, the pleasure of cruelty is sexual.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Ideas about how to live should be shaped partly by awareness of collective disasters.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Atrocities are easier if the human responsibilities are weakened.  Torturers have to suppress sympathy, or &amp;ldquo;squeamishness&amp;rdquo; as they come to think of it.  One way is to stress that victims do not belong.  They are usually assigned to some other, stigmatized, group.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;We are a species both brutal and sickened by brutality.  This conflict between our cruelty and our aspirations goes as far as we can see back in human history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jonathan Glover&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Humanity-Moral-History-Twentieth-Century/dp/0300087152&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Moral History of the Twentieth Century&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Hugo Black and Lon L. Fuller</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hugo-black-and-lon-l.-fuller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-hugo-black-and-lon-l.-fuller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every departure from the principles of the law&amp;rsquo;s inner morality is an affront to man&amp;rsquo;s dignity as a responsible agent.  To judge his actions by unpublished or retrospective laws, or to order him to do an act that is impossible, is to convey to him your indifference to his powers of self-determination.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;I believe that if we were forced to select the principle that supports and infuses all human aspiration we would find it in the objective of maintaining communication with our fellows.  &amp;hellip;How and when we accomplish communication with one another can expand or contract the boundaries of life itself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lon_L._Fuller&#34;&gt;Lon L. Fuller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;The Morality of Law&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Court&amp;rsquo;s justification for consulting its own notions rather than following the original meaning of the Constitution, as I would, apparently is based on the belief of the majority of the Court that for this Court to be bound by the original meaning of the Constitution is an intolerable and debilitating evil; that our Constitution should not be &amp;ldquo;shackled to the political theory of a particular era,&amp;rdquo; and that to save the country from the original Constitution the Court must have constant power to renew it and keep it abreast of this Court&amp;rsquo;s more enlightened theories of what is best for our society. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It seems to me that this is an attack not only on the great value of our Constitution itself but also on the concept of a written constitution which is to survive through the years as originally written unless changed through the amendment process which the Framers wisely provided. Moreover, when a &amp;ldquo;political theory&amp;rdquo; embodied in our Constitution becomes outdated, it seems to me that a majority of the nine members of this Court are not only without constitutional power but are far less qualified to choose a new constitutional political theory than the people of this country proceeding in the manner provided by Article V.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Hugo Black&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Harper v. Virginia State Board of Education&lt;/em&gt; (dissent); 383 U.S. 663 (1966)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No one may be compelled against his conscience to render war service involving the use of arms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Basic Law for the Federal Republic of Germany&lt;/em&gt;, Article IV&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I cannot consider the Bill of Rights to be an outworn 18th Century &amp;lsquo;strait jacket&amp;rsquo; as the Twining opinion did. Its provisions may be thought outdated abstractions by some. And it is true that they were designed to meet ancient evils. But they are the same kind of human evils that have emerged from century to century wherever excessive power is sought by the few at the expense of the many. In my judgment the people of no nation can lose their liberty so long as a Bill of Rights like ours survives and its basic purposes are conscientiously interpreted, enforced and respected so as to afford continuous protection against old, as well as new, devices and practices which might thwart those purposes. I fear to see the consequences of the Court&amp;rsquo;s practice of substituting its own concepts of decency and fundamental justice for the language of the Bill of Rights as its point of departure in interpreting and enforcing that Bill of Rights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Justice Hugo Black&lt;br /&gt; &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Adamson v. California&lt;/em&gt; (dissent); 332 U.S. 46 (1946) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;All excerpts from Lloyd,&lt;/em&gt; Introduction to Jurisprudence (4th ed., 1979).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Should Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/u.s.-should-resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;Resist the Urge to Confront Kim Jong-Il&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning.  In it, I make the case that any honest examination of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s policy options regarding North Korea must begin with the acknowledgment that, first, war is not an option, and second, that the strategies of isolation and sanctions have been tried and have failed for 60 years.  Accordingly, our only chance for a resolution of the North Korean issue is through direct talks with the North aimed at a comprehensive peace settlement and an official end to the Korean War.  This is not a pleasant option, but it is the right one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read the article and the argument &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/30/resist-the-urge-to-confront-kim-jong-il/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; please feel free to comment directly on the site, through a letter to the editor, or via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ryan.mccarl@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.  If you enjoy the article, please link to it or forward it to others who might be interested in reading it.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War: The More We Spend on It, the More We Get</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/war-the-more-we-spend-on-it-the-more-we-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/war-the-more-we-spend-on-it-the-more-we-get/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/14/war-the-more-we-spend/&#34;&gt;War: The More We Spend on It, the More We Get&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;http://antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; this morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In it, I write:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;President Obama and Defense Secretary Gates’ $534 billion defense budget proposal is aimed at building a &amp;ldquo;21st-century military,&amp;rdquo; that is, a military designed to fight asymmetrical &amp;ldquo;small wars,&amp;rdquo; conduct anti-terrorism operations, and battle insurgencies. It shuffles a significant number of pieces around the chessboard, to be sure, but like its predecessors, it is an enormous waste of resources and wealth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we took a radically different, need-based approach to defense funding, and asked ourselves about the legitimate, just, and necessary aims of American power, and how much money we must allocate to defense to accomplish those aims, it is unlikely that we would wind up where we are now, with 20 percent of our national budget allocated to defense and accounting for a shameful 45 percent of the world’s spending on war and preparation for war.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Insofar as Obama and Gates are shaking up the military-industrial status quo, they deserve some credit. But the simple fact that their defense budget represents an increase in an already criminal level of funding for warmaking and its instruments demonstrates that whatever special interests are threatened by the new budget, this budget will create new special interests of its own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is needed is a dramatic cut in defense spending. To think that this would represent a decrease, rather than an increase, in America’s security is a reflex rather than the product of reflection; the safest world is one in which spending on war is minimized as much as possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read the whole article &lt;a href=http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/06/14/war-the-more-we-spend/&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings from Hemingway, O&#39;Connor, and K. Shapiro</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/readings-from-hemingway-oconnor-and-k.-shapiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s heart tightened as the trout moved.  He felt all the old feeling.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;His muscles ached and the day was hot, but Nick felt happy.  He had left everything behind, the need for thinking, the need to write, other needs.  It was all back of him.  From the time he had gotten down off the train and the baggage man had thrown his pack out of the open car door things had been different.  Seney was burned, the country was burned over and changed, but it did not matter.  It could not all be burned.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The road ran on, dipping occasionally, but always climbing.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Inside the tent the light came through the brown canvas.  It smelled pleasantly of canvas.  Already there was something mysterious and homelike.  Nick was happy as he crawled inside the tent.  He had not been unhappy all day.  This was different though.  Now things were done.  There had been this to do.  Now it was done.  It had been a hard trip.  He was very tired.  That was done.  He had made his camp.  He was settled.  Nothing could touch him.  It was a good place to camp.  He was there, in the good place.  He was in his home where he had made it.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Nick laughed.  It made a good ending to the story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ernest Hemingway&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Big Two-Hearted River: Part I&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &amp;lsquo;heroes of the spirit,&amp;rsquo; Elijah shows the conventional rabbi Baroka, are not the ostentatiously pious, not even the learned and devout like Baroka himself&amp;hellip;.  They may appear to be quite ordinary individuals, not even religious in a conventional sense, whose quiet deeds enhance the quality of life around them - the carers, the compassionate, those who use their talents to ease the burden of humanity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Norman Solomon&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Judaism: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tide of darkness seemed to sweep him back to her, postponing from moment to moment his entry into the world of guilt and sorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery O&amp;rsquo;Connor&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Everything That Rises Must Converge&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But no appeal has yet been made to the vast American middle class, the majority class, to detach itself from our competitive industrial insanity.  It is indeed our industrial way of life that lends sanction to militarism and colonialism, Preparedness and suppression of human rights.  Our enemy, strange as it may sound to American ears, is the Standard of Living.  We worship at the altar of the White Rhinoceros, the American kitchen.  Standard of Living is the holy of holies in whose name every other evil is committed.  To lower this standard or to equalize it among the peoples of the world is our greatest need.  And the first step is to disassociate ourselves from the industrial-scientific madness which rules our lives twenty-four hours a day.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;To remove ourselves from the world of competition is of paramount importance to the individual and to the nation.  Competition is the most terrible vice of modern society.  Competition is the disease of the West and is the source of our violence.  Non-violence means non-competition.  &amp;hellip;It cannot be employed by governments because governments are by definition committed to violence.  Nonviolence is not a prerogative of governments but of men, even of one man.  One nonviolent man, like Gandhi or Christ, can change history.  Governments can only keep history on the march.  &lt;em&gt;Ahimsa&lt;/em&gt; can stop history.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Vinoba Bhave, the greatest living disciple of Gandhi, who travels throughout India asking for land for the peasantry from the great landlords and receiving it, says: &amp;ldquo;I desire to humiliate neither the rich nor the poor&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;  This is the opposite of communist expropriation or of capitalist competition.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Instead of class war and hatred as preached by the communists or industrial-scientific competition as preached by us, to survive we must behave nonviolently and in the spirit of love.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Karl Shapiro&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;To Revive Anarchism&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Creative Glut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of Range: The ethics of U.S. drone strikes in Pakistan</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/out-of-range-the-ethics-of-u.s.-drone-strikes-in-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My latest op-ed, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;Out of Range&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; appeared in this morning&amp;rsquo;s edition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/index1234.html&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt;.  In it, I explore the ethical dilemma of the U.S.&amp;rsquo;s ongoing campaign of drone strikes in Pakistan.  This is shaping up to be one of the hottest contemporary debates in foreign policy circles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I write: &amp;ldquo;Technology and wealth have made it possible for the U.S. to exercise decisive military power anywhere in the world.  But our technology and our wealth often outrun our wisdom, our prudence, and our moral sensibilities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;With the exception of the pacifist and nonviolent traditions, most of our moral thinking about war acknowledges that there are at least some circumstances under which violence and killing, including organized political violence (or war), is morally acceptable.  But are our theories about the ethics of warmaking up to the task of determining when, if ever, it is permissible to kill a relatively impotent enemy from a safe and anonymous distance, by robot or missile?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;For their operators, controlling these &amp;lsquo;drones&amp;rsquo; must not be so different from playing a video game – something almost fictional, bearing at most a tangential relationship to the reality of face-to-face killing and dying that informed our ability to understand the depth of the tragedies of previous wars we have fought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you enjoy the &lt;a href=&#34;http://original.antiwar.com/mccarl/2009/05/14/out-of-range/&#34;&gt;op-ed&lt;/a&gt;, please take a moment to pass it along to others who might be interested.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other columnists featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antiwar.com/&#34;&gt;Antiwar.com&lt;/a&gt; today: University of Chicago international relations theorist &lt;a href=&#34;http://mearsheimer.uchicago.edu/&#34;&gt;John J. Mearsheimer&lt;/a&gt; (also my former M.A. thesis advisor!), legendary New Left activist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tomhayden.com/&#34;&gt;Tom Hayden&lt;/a&gt;, University of Michigan historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.juancole.com/&#34;&gt;Juan Cole&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Editor at Time.com &lt;a href=&#34;http://tonykaron.com/&#34;&gt;Tony Karon&lt;/a&gt;, and Salon.com contributor and Constitutional lawyer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Greenwald&#34;&gt;Glenn Greenwald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edna St. Vincent Millay&#39;s &#39;Conscientious Objector&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/edna-st.-vincent-millays-conscientious-objector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/edna-st.-vincent-millays-conscientious-objector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I discovered one of the best poems on war I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read the other day while reading David P. Barash&amp;rsquo;s &lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Approaches-Peace-Reader-Studies/dp/0195123867&#34;&gt;Approaches to Peace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, an excellent edited volume on peace and conflict studies:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight:bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;Conscientious Objector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;Edna St. Vincent Millay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-size: small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I shall die, but&lt;br /&gt;that is all that I shall do for Death.&lt;br /&gt;I hear him leading his horse out of the stall;&lt;br /&gt;I hear the clatter on the barn-floor.&lt;br /&gt;He is in haste; he has business in Cuba,&lt;br /&gt;business in the Balkans,&lt;br /&gt;many calls to make this morning.&lt;br /&gt;But I will not hold the bridle&lt;br /&gt;while he cinches the girth.&lt;br /&gt;And he may mount by himself:&lt;br /&gt;I will not give him a leg up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Though he flick my shoulders with his whip,&lt;br /&gt;I will not tell him which way the fox ran.&lt;br /&gt;With his hoof on my breast, I will not tell him where&lt;br /&gt;the black boy hides in the swamp.&lt;br /&gt;I shall die, but that is all that I shall do for Death;&lt;br /&gt;I am not on his pay-roll.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I will not tell him the whereabouts of my friends&lt;br /&gt;nor of my enemies either.&lt;br /&gt;Though he promise me much,&lt;br /&gt;I will not map him the route to any man&amp;rsquo;s door.&lt;br /&gt;Am I a spy in the land of the living,&lt;br /&gt;that I should deliver men to Death?&lt;br /&gt;Brother, the password and the plans of our city&lt;br /&gt;are safe with me; never through me&lt;br /&gt;Shall you be overcome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard Zinn on World War II</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/howard-zinn-on-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve intended to read Howard Zinn&amp;rsquo;s revisionist history of the United States - &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; - for years, and I finally buckled down and started it this week. It is an excellent and eye-opening book, to say the least, and I found myself becoming absorbed in and largely agreeing with the narrative of the first few chapters - his interpretation of the &amp;ldquo;discovery&amp;rdquo; and colonization of America. Although I&amp;rsquo;m usually not willing to follow Zinn to his ultimate conclusions, I find his eagerness to tear down the myths and falsehoods surrounding the idea of &amp;ldquo;American exceptionalism&amp;rdquo; refreshing - especially after the nationalist fervor of a Presidential election season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zinn reminds us that Americans are fallible human beings like any others, capable of acts of greatness as well as acts of shame.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I skipped ahead to find out what Zinn had to say about World War II - the war most often held up in America as an example of America&amp;rsquo;s unique greatness, of America-as-savior-and-beacon-of-hope. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from what I found:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, if the entrance of the United States into World War II was (as so many Americans believed at the time, observing the Nazi invasions) to defend the principle of nonintervention in the affairs of other countries, the nation&amp;rsquo;s record cast doubt on its ability to uphold that principle.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;br /&gt;As Bruce Russett says: &amp;ldquo;Throughout the 1930s the United States government had done little to resist the Japanese advance on the Asian continent.&amp;rdquo; But: &amp;ldquo;The Southwest Pacific area was of undeniable economic importance to the United States - at the time most of America&amp;rsquo;s tin and rubber came from there, as did substantial qualities of other raw materials.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;A State Department memorandum on Japanese expansion, a year before Pearl Harbor, did not talk of the independence of China or the principle of self-determination. It said: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;our general diplomatic and strategic position would be considerably weakened - by our loss of Chinese, Indian, and South Seas markets (and by our loss of much of the Japanese market for our goods, as Japan would become more and more self-sufficient) as well as by insurmountable restrictions upon our access to the rubber, tin, jute, and other vital materials of the Asian and Oceanic regions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The plight of Jews in German-occupied Europe, which many people thought was at the heart of the war against the Axis, was not a chief concern of Roosevelt.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Was the war being fought to establish that Hitler was wrong in his ideas of white Nordic supremacy over &amp;ldquo;inferior&amp;rdquo; races? The United States&amp;rsquo; armed forces were segregated by race.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In one of its policies, the United States came close to direct duplication of Fascism. This was in its treatment of the Japanese-Americans living on the West Coast. After the Pearl Harbor attack, anti-Japanese hysteria spread in the government. One Congressman said: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m for catching every Japanese in America, Alaska, and Hawaii now and putting them in concentration camps&amp;hellip;. Damn them! Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of them!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt did not share this frenzy, but he calmly signed Executive Order 9066, in February 1942, giving the army the power, without warrants or indictments or hearings, to arrest every Japanese-American on the West Coast - 110,000 men, women, and children - to take them from their homes, transport them to camps far into the interior, and keep them there under prison conditions.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Hatred against the enemy, against the Japanese particularly, became widespread. Racism was clearly at work. &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; magazine, reporting the battle of Iwo Jima, said: &amp;ldquo;The ordinary unreasoning Jap is ignorant. Perhaps he is human. Nothing&amp;hellip;indicates it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, there was a mass base of support for what became the heaviest bombardment of civilians ever undertaken in any war: the aerial attacks on German and Japanese cities.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Italy had bombed cities in the Ethiopian war; Italy and germany had bombed civilians in the Spanish Civil War; at the start of World War II German planes dropped bombs on Rotterdam in Holland, Convetry in England, and elsewhere. Roosevelt had described these as &amp;ldquo;inhuman barbarism that has profoundly shocked the conscience of humanity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These German bombings were very small compared with the British and American bombings of German cities. &amp;hellip;The English flew at night with no pretense of aiming at &amp;ldquo;military&amp;rdquo; targets; the Americans flew in the daytime and pretended precision, but bombing from high altitudes made that impossible. The climax of this terror bormbing was the bombing of Dresden in early 1945, in which the tremendous heat generated by the bombs created a vacuum into which fire leaped swiftly in a great firestorm through the city. More than 100,000 died in Dresden. [See Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slaughterhouse Five&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out Zinn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/A-Peoples-History-of-the-United-States/Howard-Zinn/e/9780060838652/?itm=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent readings on Iraq, myth, politics and more</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/recent-readings-on-iraq-myth-politics-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two must-reads on current events:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/25/opinion/25brooks.html?ex=1364184000&amp;amp;en=6f0f5b78ddcf3275&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt; on the Obama-Clinton race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/bushswar/?campaign=pbshomefeatures_1_frontlinebrbushswar_2008-03-25&#34;&gt;Bush&amp;rsquo;s War&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a PBS Frontline documentary with extraordinary cinematography and interviews with key players involved in the political decisions surrounding the invasion and occupation of Iraq.  I highly recommend watching it (it&amp;rsquo;s free online), or at least poking around the website a bit.  The site includes an annotated video timeline and transcripts from over 400 interviews.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biography, psychology, sociology, history,&amp;rdquo; (historian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yale.edu/history/faculty/demos.html&#34;&gt;John Demos&lt;/a&gt;) has written: &amp;ldquo;four corners of one scholar&amp;rsquo;s compass, four viewpoints overlooking a single field of past experience.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;hellip;Once you have decided on such a multi-disciplinary approach, where do you stop?  How wide do you open your arms?  &amp;hellip;If you opt to be eclectic, there is no limit to scholarship, no end to your book.  Yet you know you are working closer to some sort of truth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contemporarywriters.com/authors/?p=auth67&#34;&gt;Hilary Mantel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Review of John Demos, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Unredeemed Captive&lt;/span&gt;; quoted in Doniger, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He was really a little fresh with that girl, I was mortified there for a moment.  But then what he said about human dignity, afterward, sounded so spiffing, like formal oratory.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And, then, I&amp;rsquo;m not all that rash about forming opinions.  I look at people and think: So that&amp;rsquo;s how you are?  Well, fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Magic Mountain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The chameleon quality of myth works in opposition to the more monolithic and dogmatic aspects of religion; where myth encourages a wide range of beliefs, dogma would narrow that range.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_Buber&#34;&gt;Martin Buber&lt;/a&gt; made this point very well indeed:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;All positive religion rests on an enormous simplification of the manifold and wildly engulfing forces that invade us: it is the subduing of the fullness of existence.  All myth, in contrast, is the expression of the fullness of existence, its image, its sign; it drinks incessantly from the gushing fountains of life.  Hence religion fights myth where it cannot absorb and incorporate it.  &amp;hellip;It is strange and wonderful to observe how in this battle religion ever again wins the apparent victory, myth ever again wins the real one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;In the dark of bigotry, all the people you hate look alike.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;The assumption that all members of a class are alike has been used in many cultures to demean the sexual or racial Other.  After all, the essence of prejudice has been defined as the assumption that an unknown individual has all the characteristics of the group to which he or she belongs.  &amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re all alike,&amp;rdquo; is always an offensive phrase.  Racism and sexism are alike in their practice of clouding the judgment so that the Other is beneath contempt, or at least beneath recognition; they dehumanize, deindividualize, the racially and sexually Other.  &amp;ldquo;All Japanese look alike&amp;rdquo; is the racist counterpart to the sexist &amp;ldquo;In the dark, all cats are gray.&amp;rdquo;  The use of large numbers to obscure humanity, particularly political Others, is a well-known sexist trick, too: Mozart/Da Ponte&amp;rsquo;s Don Giovanni boasted, famously, that he had seduced a thousand and three women in Spain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://divinity.uchicago.edu/faculty/doniger.shtml&#34;&gt;Wendy Doniger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=NWR_oog_RgEC&amp;amp;dq=the+implied+spider+politics+%26+theology+in+myth&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=k49xzsNGpR&amp;amp;sig=wketva1GWjvujr7wVbxqE2nmq24&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Implied Spider: Politics &amp;amp; Theology in Myth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (highly recommended)&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great quotes from recent reading</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/great-quotes-from-recent-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We keep the wall between us as we go.&lt;br /&gt;To each the boulders that have fallen to each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Frost&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mending Wall&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;World peace cannot be safeguarded without the making of creative efforts proportionate to the dangers which threaten it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Robert Schumann&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;The Schumann Declaration&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I asked her, urgently, if she could see my face, and she said: &amp;ldquo;See it?&amp;rdquo; And, smiling: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s reflected in my eyes, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(じゃ、私の顔が見えるかいと一心に聞くと、見えるかいって、そら、そこに、写ってるじゃありませんかと、にこりと笑ってみせた。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Natsume Soseki&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;The First Night&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And home, where passion lived and died,&lt;br /&gt;Becomes a place where she can hide,&lt;br /&gt;While all the town and harbor side&lt;br /&gt;Vibrate with her seclusion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edwin Arlington Robinson&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&amp;ldquo;Eros Turannos&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite all of these examples of colloquialism and apparent simplicity in Frost&amp;rsquo;s poetry, we should not be deceived into thinking of Frost as a rustic or a primitive.  On the contrary, Frost was a sophisticated writer who was well versed in Latin poetry and who knew as well as any poet of his time how to make effective use of formal and rhetorical strategies.  From his early career on, Frost prided himself on being &amp;ldquo;one of the most notable craftsmen of my time,&amp;rdquo; as he wrote in his 1913 letter to John Bartlett.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Christopher Beach&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Twentieth-Century American Poetry&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;In Those Days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;In those days - they were long ago -&lt;br /&gt;The snow was cold, the night was black.&lt;br /&gt;I licked from my cracked lips&lt;br /&gt;A snowflake, as I looked back&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Through branches, the last uneasy snow.&lt;br /&gt;Your shadow, there in the light, was still.&lt;br /&gt;In a little the light went out.&lt;br /&gt;I went on, stumbling - till at last the hill&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hid the house.  And, yawning,&lt;br /&gt;In bed in my room, alone,&lt;br /&gt;I would look out: over the quilted&lt;br /&gt;Rooftops, the clear stars shone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How poor and miserable we were,&lt;br /&gt;How seldom together!&lt;br /&gt;And yet after so long one thinks:&lt;br /&gt;In those days everything was better.&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Randall Jarrell&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Randall Jarrell and Knut Hamsun</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-and-knut-hamsun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-randall-jarrell-and-knut-hamsun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I lie in my own bed,&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;He whispers, &amp;ldquo;dreaming&amp;rdquo;; and he thinks to wake.&lt;br /&gt;The old mistake.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;A Field Hospital&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We read our mail and counted up our missions-&lt;br /&gt;In bombers named for girls, we burned&lt;br /&gt;The cities we had learned about in school-&lt;br /&gt;Till our lives wore out; our bodies lay among&lt;br /&gt;The people we had killed and never seen.&lt;br /&gt;When we lasted long enough they gave us medals;&lt;br /&gt;When we died they said, &amp;ldquo;Our casualties were low.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;They said, &amp;ldquo;Here are the maps&amp;rdquo;; we burned the cities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From&lt;/em&gt; Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;Losses&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A machine-gun away&lt;br /&gt;Are men with our faces.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;Jews at Haifa&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here too, though death is hushed, though joy&lt;br /&gt;Obscures, like night, their wars,&lt;br /&gt;The beings of this world are swept&lt;br /&gt;By the Strife that moves the stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;/em&gt;Randall Jarrell, &amp;ldquo;The Breath of Night&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Note: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randall_Jarrell&#34;&gt;Jarrell&lt;/a&gt; was an American control tower operator during World War II.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The letter shot through me like a stream of light, and I heard myself give a little cry, a meaningless sound of joy: the letter was from the editor, my piece was accepted, being set in type immediately!  &amp;ldquo;A few minor changes&amp;hellip;a couple of typographical errors corrected&amp;hellip;shows real ability&amp;hellip;will appear tomorrow&amp;hellip;ten kroner.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I laughed and cried, leaped in the air and ran down the street, stopped and beat my legs, swore wholesale at no one about nothing.  And time went by.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For a few minutes I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a single sad thought.  I forgot my troubles and felt peaceful looking at the harbor that lay serene and lovely in the dusk.  I had the habit of cheering myself up by reading through the article I had just written, which always seemed to my afflicted brain the very best piece I had done.  I pulled my my manuscript out of my pocket, held it up close to my eyes, and read through one page after the other.  Finally I grew tired and put the papers in my pocket.  Everything was still; the sea stretched away like bluish mother-of-pearl, and small birds flew silently past me, going from one place to another.  A policeman walked up and down a little way off.  Otherwise, not a person could be seen, and the entire harbor was silent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knut Hamsun&lt;br /&gt;  &amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Hunger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortimer J. Adler on war and peace</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/mortimer-j.-adler-on-war-and-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our view of war, then, must be broadened to include both armed conflict and battles of diplomacy, economic aid, and propaganda. War is war, whether it is &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cold.&amp;rdquo; The struggle for power and prestige among the nations goes on all the time. Only the means vary, and whether these be armed force or diplomatic pressure or other nonviolent means depends on the occasion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It follows, then, that peace is not merely a negative thing - the absence of armed conflict. What real, positive peace among the nations would be we may see by considering the state of affairs in local, state, and national communities. In our civil society, peace and order, not war, are the normal state of things. The whole meaning and purpose of civil society is peace and order. Civil government creates civil peace. Individuals who violate the law are disturbers of the peace and are dealt with accordingly.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;Contrary to a lot of loose talk, it is peace and not war that is proper to human nature. Cicero and many other thinkers rightly point out that fighting and snarling are the way of brute beasts, while talking things over and listening to reason are the proper way for men. Peace is required not only for our material survival but also for a really human existence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;Mortimer J. Adler, &lt;em&gt;Great Ideas from the Great Books&lt;/em&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from John Steinbeck&#39;s &#39;Travels with Charley&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/quotes-from-john-steinbecks-travels-with-charley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A dog, particularly an exotic like Charley, is a bond between strangers.  Many conversations en route began with &amp;ldquo;What degree of a dog is that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dairy man had a Ph.D. in mathematics, and he must have had some training in philosophy.  He liked what he was doing and he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be somewhere else - one of the very few contented people I met in my whole journey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then a submarine slipped to the surface half a mile away, and the day lost part of its brightness.  Farther away another dark creature slashed through the water, and another; of course they are based in New London, and this is their home.  And perhaps they are keeping the world&amp;rsquo;s peace with their venom.  I wish I could like submarines, for then I might find them beautiful, but they are designed for destruction, and while they may explore and chart the sea bottom, and draw new trade lines under the Arctic ice, their main purpose is threat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to be a center for concern?  A kind of second childhood falls on so many men.  They trade their violence for the promise of a small increase of life span.  In effect, the head of the house becomes the youngest child.  And I have searched myself for this possibility with a kind of horror.  For I have always lived violently, drunk hugely, eaten too much or not at all, slept around the clock or missed two nights of sleeping, worked too hard and too long in glory, or slobbed for a time in utter laziness.  I&amp;rsquo;ve lifted, pulled, chopped, climbed, made love with joy and taken my hangovers as a consequence, not as a punishment.  I did not want to surrender fierceness for a small gain in yardage.  My wife married a man; I saw no reason why she should inherit a baby. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I saw in their eyes something I was to see over and over in every part of the nation - a burning desire to go, to move, to get under way, anyplace, away from any Here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Ftt&amp;rdquo; usually means he would like to salute a bush or a tree.  I opened the cab door and let him out, and he went about his ceremony.  He doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it to do it well.  It is my experience that in some areas Charley is more intelligent than I am, but in others he is abysmally ignorant.  He can&amp;rsquo;t read, can&amp;rsquo;t drive a car, and has no grasp of mathematics.  But in his own field of endeavor, which was now practicing, the slow, imperial smelling over and anointing of an area, he has no peer.  Of course his horizons are limited, but how wide are mine?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-John Steinbeck, &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley in Search of America &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Personal note: Steinbeck is my favorite American writer, and &lt;em&gt;Travels with Charley &lt;/em&gt;is on track to become one of my absolute favorite books; I&amp;rsquo;m especially excited about it because my family just got a second dog, a black retriever named Maggie.  I&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet Maggie for the first time when I go home to Muskegon on Friday for a Counting Crows concert.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems &amp; fragments from Hopkins, Yeats, Housman, and Hardy</title>
      <link>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems--fragments-from-hopkins-yeats-housman-and-hardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 21:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryanmccarl.com/post/poems--fragments-from-hopkins-yeats-housman-and-hardy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;When You Are Old&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When you are old and grey and full of sleep,&lt;br /&gt;And nodding by the fire, take down this book,&lt;br /&gt;And slowly read, and dream of the soft look&lt;br /&gt;Your eyes had once, and of their shadows deep;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How many loved your moments of glad grace,&lt;br /&gt;And loved your beauty with love false or true,&lt;br /&gt;But one man loved the pilgrim soul in you,&lt;br /&gt;And loved the sorrows of your changing face;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And bending down beside the glowing bars,&lt;br /&gt;Murmur, a little sadly, how Love fled&lt;br /&gt;And paced upon the mountains overhead&lt;br /&gt;And hid his face amid a crowd of stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;William Butler Yeats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Thou Art Indeed Just, Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mine, O thou lord of life, send my roots rain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Gerald Manley Hopkins&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Into My Heart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Into my heart an air that kills&lt;br /&gt;From yon far country blows:&lt;br /&gt;What are those blue remembered hills,&lt;br /&gt;What spires, what farms are those?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That is the land of lost content,&lt;br /&gt;I see it shining plain,&lt;br /&gt;The happy highways where I went&lt;br /&gt;And cannot come again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;A.E. Housman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Channel Firing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The world is as it used to be:&lt;br /&gt;All nations striving strong to make&lt;br /&gt;Red war yet redder.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;Thomas Hardy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;No Worst, There is None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Comforter, where, where is your comforting?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gerald Manley Hopkins&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;From&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Grandeur&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The world is charged with the grandeur of God.  &amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;And though the last lights off the black West went&lt;br /&gt;Oh, morning, at the brown brink eastward, springs -&lt;br /&gt;Because the Holy Ghost over the bent&lt;br /&gt;World broods with warm breast and with ah! bright wings.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;
Ryan McCarl
Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Wide Awake Minds: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;
Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.ryanmccarl.com&lt;/a&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/ryanmccarl&lt;/a&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://fb.wideawakeminds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
